<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>Some Party is a newsletter sharing the latest in independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated more-or-less weekly by Adam White. Each edition explores punk, garage, psych, and otherwise uncategorizable indie rock, drawing lines from proto to post and taking some weird diversions along the way.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2025-06-08T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Back on Drugs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-06-09-back-on-drugs/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-06-09-back-on-drugs/</id>
    <published>2025-06-08T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T12:47:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="jim_s_plumbing_and_electrical"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jimsplumbingandelectrical.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jim's Plumbing and Electrical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Business&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Back on Drugs&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/UGNJDApTW-4?si=ZB-lii4-vGnMcBCn" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://jimsplumbingandelectrical.bandcamp.com/album/the-business" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Members of underground Ottawa legends &lt;a href="https://newswears.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears&lt;/a&gt; recently resurfaced as &lt;a href="https://jimsplumbingandelectrical.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jim&amp;#39;s Plumbing and Electrical&lt;/a&gt;. While the name&amp;#39;s new, the band retains the best qualities of their predecessor. While New Swears&amp;#39; party-ready punk often felt like it was on the verge of spinning out of control, that choice was deliberate. The band proved, despite their brand, almost effortlessly tight. New Swears played with a kind of hard-won, inter-member telepathy that comes from years in the trenches. While Jim&amp;#39;s Plumbing takes a few stylistic detours (less gas, more grass), the shuffle hasn&amp;#39;t thrown out what worked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over four songs &lt;em&gt;The Business&lt;/em&gt; finds the new outfit tight and polished. They&amp;#39;re less hitched to any hyphenated subgenre of punk this time out, instead embracing a relaxed 70s barroom sound that gives their indulgences more time to breathe. The self-aware sleaze of their old outfit is still deeply ingrained in their DNA, but it&amp;#39;s taken a shower and is now wearing a clean shirt. You can never quite shake the smoke, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The record&amp;#39;s lead single feels like a statement of intent. &amp;quot;Back on Drugs&amp;quot; arrived alongside a wonderfully entertaining video based on a debaucherous slice of Canadian sports history. The band explained:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In June 1990, the Canadian Government released the Dubin Inquiry, a federally sanctioned investigation of the use of drugs and banned substances in elite athletics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sparked by Olympic Sprinter Ben Johnson&amp;#39;s bomb-drop of a disqualification after winning gold in the Men&amp;#39;s 100m dash at the Seoul Olympics. This government publication also details the tale of the 1988 Men&amp;#39;s Olympic Weightlifting team&amp;#39;s rampant drug related issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before leaving Canada for the games, the team submitted urine samples checking their systems for banned substances. Some of these screenings were found to be inconclusive, triggering necessary retesting. Unfortunately, some of these athletes had continued their steroid use immediately after their initial submissions. This caused a panic amongst the team leading two ingenious strategies. First, the consumption of as much beer as possible to flush the steroids out of their systems. The second, buying catheters to inject urine into their bladders to be expelled during testing. Neither of these plans worked.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim&amp;#39;s Plumbing and Electrical plays as a five-piece here. Alex Jakimczuk recorded, mixed, and mastered the new material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://newswears.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears&lt;/a&gt; last released &lt;em&gt;Night Mirror&lt;/em&gt; in 2019 through &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;. In the years since, members of the group took an alt-country turn with &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/scorpion.king.band/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Scorpion King&lt;/a&gt; and issued a series of scene-rooted video projects through the &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/the.clubhouse.recording.club/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Clubhouse Recording Club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2742204467/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jimsplumbingandelectrical.bandcamp.com/album/the-business"&gt;The Business by Jim's Plumbing and Electrical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="neil_haverty"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neilhaverty.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Neil Haverty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Man Down&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Pv-Zfw2KlcA?si=Qnv9YBYxnqlYnl2M" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://neilhaverty.bandcamp.com/track/man-down" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://neilhaverty.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Neil Haverty&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s been through the wringer. The narrative arc of indie bands, particularly esoteric late-2000s regional acts, is often brief. While it&amp;#39;s not surprising that &lt;a href="http://bruce-peninsula.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bruce Peninsula&lt;/a&gt; spent years off the grid, their absence goes beyond the usual &amp;quot;got a real job&amp;quot; narrative. While that&amp;#39;s indeed part of the story — Haverty&amp;#39;s spent a decade composing for film and television; he&amp;#39;s also spent the better part of that time battling leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diagnosis and his subsequent struggles factor heavily into &amp;quot;Man Down,&amp;quot; Neil&amp;#39;s first solo single in over ten years. The vocalist&amp;#39;s brooding growl should be instantly familiar to anyone who followed Bruce Peninsula&amp;#39;s striking string of rootsy, gospel-tinged records. On the sombre track, he grapples with the messy reality of healing, addressing the clumsy fits-and-starts of recovery and re-prioritizing a life:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Man Down&amp;#39; reminds me how close I came to death, and how sure I was that it would fundamentally change my life. But the truth is, most things stayed the same. The ideals I formed while sick - about living differently, more intentionally - they blur and come in and out of focus with time. This song wrestles with that realization: that survival doesn&amp;#39;t always mean transformation, and that clinging to our old patterns is as human as anything else.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Haverty recorded with Bruce Peninsula drummer Leon Taheny (Owen Pallett, Austra) producing. &amp;quot;Man Down&amp;quot; also features string arrangements by &lt;a href="https://merganzer.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Merganzer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Mika Posen (Timber Timbre, Jennifer Castle). Among the track&amp;#39;s delicate bed of keys and analog synth, the recording incorporates field recordings captured at the Museo Galileo in Florence. Phil Demetro mastered the single.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bruce Peninsula last issued &lt;em&gt;No Earthly Sound&lt;/em&gt; in 2020, their third full-length following 2011&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Open Flames&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=874639320/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neilhaverty.bandcamp.com/track/man-down"&gt;Man Down by Neil Haverty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="bologna_colorado"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bolognacolorado.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bologna Colorado&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Get to the Point&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/loxv_ZdeGtE?si=uOuuJ3_npK5O0H2M" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halifax rockers &lt;a href="https://www.bolognacolorado.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bologna Colorado&lt;/a&gt; sound like a band out of time on their new single &amp;quot;Get To The Point.&amp;quot; The generous take is that it feels like a long-lost proto-punk gem, a lightning-in-a-bottle product of amped-up youth brimming with sneering grit and overblown guitars. Realistically, the track would fit perfectly into the early-2000s garage revival - that short-lived moment when the mainstream woke up to bands like The Hives as they scrambled to repeat the success of the Strokes and White Stripes. It&amp;#39;s also the era when a naive, college-aged version of me held out hope that the universe would finally award the New Bomb Turks for doing it faster and better for decades, &lt;em&gt;BUT I DIGRESS&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wherever you place it, &amp;quot;Get to the Point&amp;quot; is a visceral thrill, heavy on attitude and gleefully absent of deeper meaning. Speaking to &lt;a href="https://www.thecoast.ca/arts-music/the-beauty-behind-bologna-colorado-34744022" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Coast&lt;/a&gt;, bassist Adam Otmar acknowledges, &amp;quot;it&amp;#39;s just kind of a loud scream song...there&amp;#39;s not much to it.&amp;quot; While it may be a trifle, the recording finds the band at their sonic best, reaching a level of crisp, kinetic fidelity that their past work only hinted at. Frontman Cole Chalifoux notes that the band&amp;#39;s earlier records, 2024&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;No Refund&lt;/em&gt; and 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Entertainment Section&lt;/em&gt;, contain, by contrast, &amp;quot;songs that have a lot of meaning that we take very seriously.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Formed in 2022, Bologna Colorado features Cole Chalifoux on vocals and guitar, Adam Otmar on bass, Emily Denesyk on keys, and Will Adams on drums. The new track follows their first two records and November&amp;#39;s one-off single, &amp;quot;Forget My Ex.&amp;quot; Chalifoux also records solo as &lt;a href="https://georgemooring.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;George Mooring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;div class='aspect-ratio'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/loxv_ZdeGtE?si=O87FoSSRpOgqYXhy" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="man_made_hill"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://manmadehill.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Man Made Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delicious Logo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://manmadehill.bandcamp.com/album/delicious-logo" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than twenty albums in Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://manmadehill.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Man Made Hill&lt;/a&gt; remains impressively elusive, delivering askew outsider art that&amp;#39;s ever enigmatic and, more often than not, gently threatening. The newly delivered &lt;em&gt;Delicious Logo&lt;/em&gt; is the second entry in a new era that finds Randy Gagne plying their craft in a professional studio. Mirroring the assembly of 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Mirage Repair&lt;/em&gt;, this latest album again sees the artist working with producer Jeremy Greenspan (Junior Boys, Jessy Lanza).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The twelve-song set is the artist&amp;#39;s first with Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;. In a writeup by Kevin Hainey, the label boasts &amp;quot;a tsunami windfall of sleazy synth pop, jagged funk, and sinister existential disco that veers in and out of comprehension.&amp;quot; You can see the glitchy fever-dream video for the lead single &amp;quot;Trophy Shop&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vJk6fL8aGxI" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, along with a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VbbHoWSvNBU" class="" target="_blank"&gt;visualizer&lt;/a&gt; for the unsettling love song &amp;quot;Never Give Up.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The set features appearances from experimental Russian-Estonian artist Lolina (fka Inga Copeland, ex-Hype Williams),  percussionist Sean Dunal (&lt;a href="https://sexymerlin.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sexy Merlin&lt;/a&gt;), and Allie Blumas (&lt;a href="https://alma999.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;ALMA&lt;/a&gt;, ex a.k.a Alma, ex-&lt;a href="https://doomsquad.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;DOOMSQUAD&lt;/a&gt;). The Katz sisters from Hamilton staple Sourpussy sing lead on a cover of &amp;quot;Best Times,&amp;quot; the 1986 theme from the cult Canadian sorority slasher flick &lt;em&gt;Killer Party&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3684375567/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://manmadehill.bandcamp.com/album/delicious-logo"&gt;DELICIOUS LOGO by Man Made Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="dealbreaker"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://1800dealbreaker.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dealbreaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;King Size&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://1800dealbreaker.bandcamp.com/album/king-size" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welland punks &lt;a href="https://1800dealbreaker.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dealbreaker&lt;/a&gt; celebrated their first anniversary with King Size, a digital/cassette compilation of their inaugural studio work. The set gathers material from the &lt;em&gt;Run It Again&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Quick Split&lt;/em&gt; EPs, along with the recent &amp;quot;Power Moves&amp;quot; single. The latter recently debuted as the theme song for comedian Mike Burns&amp;#39; podcast of the same name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dealbreaker came together last year, featuring longtime Welland scene members Connor Johnstone (vocals), Nick Giammarco and Bil Huffman (guitars), Josh Van Hezewyk (bass), and Scott Brady (drums). There are some deep-cut local roots in that group. Giammarco, in particular, played in &lt;a href="https://canyoncarvers.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Canyon Carvers&lt;/a&gt;, who seemed to open every other Niagara show for a while. Johnstone&amp;#39;s visible with the &lt;a href="https://quitealright.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Quite Alright&lt;/a&gt; design studio, working with a raft of Ontario bands. Dealbreaker is, in the best sense of the word, a garage band through and through - longtime friends convening on weekends to churn out brash songs with constant momentum, one foot in the 90s, and shout-along choruses written with the audience in mind. The band dove into their backstory in a recent chat at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/85548/interviews-making-memories-with-dealbreaker" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews&lt;/a&gt; with my pal Em Moore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look for the group in July at &lt;a href="https://buddiesfest.bandzoogle.com/buddies" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Buddies Fest&lt;/a&gt; in Tillsonburg, Ontario, appearing alongside ALL, Dillinger Four, The Flatliners, Greg Norton and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2589801567/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://1800dealbreaker.bandcamp.com/album/king-size"&gt;King Size by Dealbreaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_tenenbaums"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Tenenbaums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;#39;s time to bring shame…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com/album/it-s-time-to-bring-shame-2" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raucous Ottawa punk trio &lt;a href="https://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Tenenbaums&lt;/a&gt; recently returned with &lt;em&gt;It&amp;#39;s time to bring shame&lt;/em&gt;, a new six-song EP and their first collected work since 2020. The digital set arrived on May 7, five years to the day since the loss of their bandmate, Mike V, and the album serves as a tribute to their fallen comrade. Mike fronted the punk act &lt;a href="https://muelkik.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Muelkik&lt;/a&gt;, which later evolved into &lt;a href="http://flaws613.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Flaws&lt;/a&gt; with members of the Tenenbaums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band (Ky, Sheesh, and Alex) recorded outside of Winchester, Ontario, using Mike&amp;#39;s old gear. Stefan Jurewicz mixed and mastered the set. Despite the sombre pretext, the EP has a wild, lo-fi charm and boundless energy. That crystallizes in the EP&amp;#39;s minute-long midway mark - a breakneck hardcore track with a title so gloriously unwieldy (and on-brand for this newsletter) that I&amp;#39;m throwing it in a blockquote for posterity:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Turned out a punk is a great podcast but the fact that they haven&amp;#39;t had John K. Samson on is really disappointing. I even emailed them and never got a reply and it&amp;#39;s just really disappointing. Although, I hear he doesn&amp;#39;t do interviews...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;#39;s time to bring shame&lt;/em&gt; follows the group&amp;#39;s early 2020s set &lt;em&gt;God damn it, you&amp;#39;ve got to be kind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1239504273/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com/album/it-s-time-to-bring-shame-2"&gt;it's time to bring shame… by The Tenenbaums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="pig_pen"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/foreverpigpenforever/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pig Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Rabid Beach&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Mental Mentality&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Rabid Beach&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Kcq5ITRlAC8?si=RO5uKMlPb22_nLmY" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://flatspotrecords.bandcamp.com/album/fsr83-mental-madness" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t let me bamboozle you into thinking this next update is timely; it&amp;#39;s most certainly not. When I&amp;#39;m this late to publish, I tend to throw things out rather than strive for completeness, but there are so many Some Party regulars at play here that I&amp;#39;d be remiss not to include it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Long before &lt;em&gt;The Bear&lt;/em&gt; and even his viral online presence, &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/mattymatheson" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Matty Matheson&lt;/a&gt; was the executive chef at Toronto&amp;#39;s Parts &amp;amp; Labour. The restaurant became a hub for the city&amp;#39;s underground music scene, with its regular basement shows. Despite his place at that epicentre, music has sat mainly on the periphery of Matty&amp;#39;s brand since his rise to fame. No longer. The bombastic personality dives back in headfirst with his supergroup &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/foreverpigpenforever/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pig Pen&lt;/a&gt;. The new band finds Matheson on vocals backed by &lt;a href="https://www.theonlybandever.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Alexisonfire&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.wademacneil.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Wade MacNeil&lt;/a&gt; on guitar, the inseparable Outfit brothers Ian and &lt;a href="https://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt; on drums and guitar, and bassist Tommy Major (&lt;a href="https://tommyandthecommies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tommy and the Commies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt;). The band played their rowdy debut show at Sneaky Dees in late April (you can see Stephen McGill&amp;#39;s shots at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/85467/photos-pig-pen-at-sneaky-dees-in-toronto-on-04-25" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews&lt;/a&gt;), and an album out later this month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band&amp;#39;s debut full-length, &lt;em&gt;Mental Madness&lt;/em&gt;, arrives June 27 through &lt;a href="https://flatspotrecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Flatspot Records&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing a classically-minded set of tough-as-nails East Coast hardcore. It&amp;#39;s not Matty&amp;#39;s first time embodying that role - he played in the late 90s Niagara hardcore band Hanging Hearts - but it&amp;#39;s certainly the first time he&amp;#39;s done so at his current level of fame. The group came together during the pandemic, writing 10 songs in a day and recording them the next.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can hear &amp;quot;Mental Mentality&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Rabid Beach&amp;quot; streaming now, with the latter celebrated in an animated video by Jesi Jordan. On the dark subject matter, Matty commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You can be having a beautiful day, surrounded by friends, and your brain can continuously ruin it. No matter how good or bad your life is, you can still hate yourself. I&amp;#39;ve got to ask myself why am I feeling the ways I&amp;#39;m feeling?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band offers friendship as a solution, with Matty noting &amp;quot;Our love of each other is what makes it.&amp;quot; Daniel Romano shared that sentiment in a press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;There&amp;#39;s a sense of community in that hardcore scene we came up in, and those early enlightenments, they stay with you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the members&amp;#39; busy day jobs, Pig Pen shows are likely to be few and far between. Your next chance to see them will be at Birmingham, Alabama&amp;#39;s Furnace Fest this October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2198603989/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://flatspotrecords.bandcamp.com/album/fsr83-mental-madness"&gt;FSR83 - Mental Madness by Pig Pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="daniel_romano_s_outfit"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://danielromano.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano's Outfit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Even If It&amp;#39;s Obscure&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Sweet Dew Of The Kingdom&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://danielromano.bandcamp.com/album/even-if-its-obscure-sweet-dew-of-the-kingdom" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concurrent with the Pig Pen news, several of those same players issued a new two-song single as &lt;a href="https://danielromano.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&amp;#39;s Outfit&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Even If It&amp;#39;s Obscure&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Sweet Dew Of The Kingdom&amp;quot; landed as a limited edition 7&amp;quot; through &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;. The set finds the band in full psychedelic pop mode. Their florid announcement leans into that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We, Outfit, present this collection of mystical protest songs at forty five rotations per minute. The first side holds in its weaving harmonies the ancient and simple plea to honour the mysterious actuality of yourself and yourothers. Listen deeply, For love is of its own accord. The second side functions as a reminder that material and linear behaviours are actively against nature and ultimately fall of their own weight. It is a call to celebrate wonder and to resist distracted, sedentary &amp;#39;pleasures.&amp;#39; Truth moves, so it must be followed. Feed on the fruit not on the flower.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tracks feature the band as a quartet, with the aforementioned Daniel, Ian, and Tommy in their usual roles, joined by &lt;a href="https://carsonmchone.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carson McHone&lt;/a&gt; on percussion and vocals. As a big fan of Tommy and the Commies, it&amp;#39;s nice to hear the Major take such a prominent vocal role in the pre-chorus of &amp;quot;Sweet Dew.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded these tracks at Red Telephone in Sweden, with Kenneth Roy Meehan assisting in the mix. The songs are the first new material we&amp;#39;ve heard from The Outfit since last year&amp;#39;s full-length &lt;em&gt;Too Hot To Sleep&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3784101620/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://danielromano.bandcamp.com/album/even-if-its-obscure-sweet-dew-of-the-kingdom"&gt;Even If It's Obscure / Sweet Dew Of The Kingdom by Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="steven_lambke_and_jimmie_kilpatrick"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://stevenlambke.bandcamp.com/album/friendship-traces" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke and Jimmie Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friendship Traces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://stevenlambke.bandcamp.com/album/friendship-traces" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;, a pair of the label&amp;#39;s core artists recently united for a collaborative side-project. &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://jimmiekilpatrick.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmie Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt; recently unveiled &lt;em&gt;Friendship Traces&lt;/em&gt;, an instrumental album that promises:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;[a] post-dub, post-minimalist, post-guitar, post-mixtape playground of bespoke drum samples, melodica, and distorted bass.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the artists are playing in a relaxed realm, they stress the intentionality of each decision. Counter to the increasing trend in machine-generated &amp;quot;chill out&amp;quot; music, the artists state that &amp;quot;even at its most abstract it remains inescapably engaged with song.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The record finds Jimmie establishing a base with drum programming and synthesizers, with Lambke adding melodica, bass, and additional live percussion. Lambke commented on the back-and-forth nature of the songwriting:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;They arrived like letters. What&amp;#39;s in the envelope? Beats and sounds, falling out like glitter. A conversation began, question and response. I played the Fender bass and the Suzuki melodion over the tracks that Jimmie sent. The bass as grounding, the melodion as air, air in a small room in front of a microphone, all the clicks and clacks of plastic and my breathing. The simplicity of the tools, the slippery-ness of their position, half-instrument, half-toy, reminds me to play, reminds me of a shared presence, a &amp;#39;thereness&amp;#39; in the world.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jimmie worked with an Elektron Digitakt drum sampler to generate the bed of each track, seeking to craft a palette of acoustic, rather than synthesized, sounds. He shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I was thinking about acousmatic music while we were working on this record. Music that is created through divorcing sounds from their original context via tape-editing-studio-techniques originated in the 1950s. These techniques include slowing sounds down, speeding sounds up, playing sounds backwards, layering sounds and copying and repeating sounds. This is how I created all the drum sounds on the record. What sounds like a bass drum might have originally been the sound of a knock on the door, that was slowed, filtered, cut up and manipulated using attack, sustain, decay and release envelopes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ten-song set is available digitally or as a limited run of 50 cassettes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album arrives on the heels of Kilpatrick&amp;#39;s new full-length &lt;em&gt;Jimmie&lt;/em&gt;, his first solo outing since shedding his &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt; moniker. Lambke, of &lt;a href="http://theconstantines.wordpress.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Constantines&lt;/a&gt; fame, last issued &lt;em&gt;Volcano Volcano&lt;/em&gt; in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=50213717/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://stevenlambke.bandcamp.com/album/friendship-traces"&gt;Friendship Traces by Steven Lambke and Jimmie Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Satellite</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-05-02-satellite/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-05-02-satellite/</id>
    <published>2025-05-01T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-02T11:55:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="jimmie_kilpatrick"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jimmiekilpatrick.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmie Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jimmie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Satellite&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jc_-Ve26XA0?si=4oaKkYPNozQ09QlB" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://jimmiekilpatrick.bandcamp.com/album/jimmie" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve lost all semblance of time. I&amp;#39;m not even referring to this newsletter overshooting its deadline by a whole month (although I am nodding at that). I&amp;#39;m talking about the six years which have allegedly passed since the last &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt; record. I&amp;#39;m skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pandemic fucked with our collective sense of continuity, but even taking that into account, I can&amp;#39;t acknowledge that it&amp;#39;s been so long. &lt;a href="https://jimmiekilpatrick.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmie Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t fit the usual narrative - the ebb-and-flow of album cycles and band activity. Jim&amp;#39;s songs boast the kind of muscle-memory familiarity you&amp;#39;d reserve for an old friend, picking up right where you left off. Has it been six years since we last spoke? I don&amp;#39;t believe it. Jim&amp;#39;s never left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That known quality could cut both ways. Will a neophyte listener pick up that &amp;quot;Gum&amp;quot; again finds the artist referencing &amp;quot;Confessions of a Futon-Revolutionist&amp;quot;? Unless they&amp;#39;re steeped in a very narrow stripe of the Canadian indie universe, probably not, but it&amp;#39;s also not necessary. Jim may be an underground hero, but his subtle references and overt tributes never feel like a shibboleth. He sings with infectious sincerity and an everyman charm. There&amp;#39;s no code to crack. Whatever universal language sits at the core of good rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll, Jim speaks it fluently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Brandon, Manitoba artist sheds his old stage name on the twelve-song &lt;em&gt;Jimmie&lt;/em&gt;, but it&amp;#39;s less a reinvention than an affirmation. Jim remains affably plainspoken while weaving in new textures. While the artist sources experimental sounds from elaborate auditory sculptures, he deploys them with considerable restraint. Kilpatrick may have bolstered his avant-garde bona fides (while pursuing a Master of Fine Arts under none other than Sonic Youth&amp;#39;s Lee Ranaldo), but his enthusiasm for new noises never gets ahead of his instincts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These techniques are most overt on the album-opening &amp;quot;Tape Loop,&amp;quot; recorded using a fifteen-foot, six-device art installation. &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; press release elaborates:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;With one player recording the sound of the other five players, as they amplify various points along the loop&amp;#39;s timeline, the installation worked like an accelerated Alvin Lucier &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Am_Sitting_in_a_Room" class="" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Am Sitting in a Room&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; machine. With each rotation of the loop the recording degraded and shifted, reinforcing and amplifying dominant room-tones. Tape loop is an aural documentation of time and place but also holds analog technology as a metaphor for the human body - constantly decaying, from time to time in need of repair, and eventually dying.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any pretension implied by that description isn&amp;#39;t evident in the finished song. While the source sounds of &lt;em&gt;Jimmie&lt;/em&gt; seem weighty on paper, they&amp;#39;re in conversation, if not outright contrast, with the artist&amp;#39;s warm accessibility and earnest delivery. The lead single, &amp;quot;Satellite,&amp;quot; exemplifies that discipline. While the track opens with the novel drones of a mechanically-bowed electric guitar sculpture, it quickly shifts into a triumphant, propulsive anthem. For years Jim&amp;#39;s collaborated with Ryan Peters of cult Vancouver rockers &lt;a href="https://ladyhawk.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ladyhawk&lt;/a&gt;, and the squelching lineage of that band shines through here. You can see the track visualized in a new video by &lt;a href="https://colinmedley.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Colin Medley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peters co-produced and performs on the record, which also features contributions from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/josecontrerasmusik/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;José Contreras&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;, cellist &lt;a href="https://www.leannezacharias.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Leanne Zacharias&lt;/a&gt; (Christine Fellows), &lt;a href="https://espanola.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Espanola&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/agoldrules/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Aaron Goldstein&lt;/a&gt; (pedal steel go-to for Bry Webb and Danny Romano), and Newfoundland vocalist &lt;a href="https://jeninamacgillivray.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jenina MacGillivray&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed has the record out now on vinyl. The new album follows up on 2019&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2724260788/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jimmiekilpatrick.bandcamp.com/album/jimmie"&gt;Jimmie by Jimmie Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_dirty_nil"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Gallop of the Hounds&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/album/gallop-of-the-hounds" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the topic of familiar comforts, I&amp;#39;ve had the pleasure of listening to Luke Bentham belt &amp;#39;em out since the band&amp;#39;s early days. &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s now so far into their career that we could carve out distinct eras (each, uncoincidentally, lining up with the rotation of another bassist). It&amp;#39;s that time again, and with the band&amp;#39;s low-end in flux, they&amp;#39;re again tweaking their formula.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The relentless &amp;quot;Gallop of the Hounds&amp;quot; sets the stage for &lt;em&gt;The Lash&lt;/em&gt;, the Dundas band&amp;#39;s ten-song studio album and their fifth. It promises a stripped-down, back-to-basics approach, contrasting with 2023&amp;#39;s intently indulgent &lt;em&gt;Free Rein To Passions&lt;/em&gt;. Look for it on July 25 through &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Bentham shared a story from a recent trip to the Vatican, revealing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I was in a very dusty part of the basement, and they had these crazy bronze reliefs that were some of the most brutal things I&amp;#39;ve ever seen. There was a particular one called The Horrors of War. It was two guys fighting over a knife. That image ended up guiding a lot of this record.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That sensibility is reflected in the medieval brutality on display in the album&amp;#39;s cover art, laid out in a cassette-first format by UK designer &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jacksabbat/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jack Sabbat&lt;/a&gt;. The Nil completed &lt;em&gt;The Lash&lt;/em&gt; in just a few weeks, recording at Hamilton&amp;#39;s Boxcar Sound with Vince Soliveri (The Drew Thomson Foundation, Pillea).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a press release, drummer Kyle Fisher joked about the cathartic bent of their latest material, stating, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ve been telling people that this is Luke&amp;#39;s therapy record.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1645480148/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/album/gallop-of-the-hounds"&gt;Gallop of the Hounds by The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="casper_skulls"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://casperskulls.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Casper Skulls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kit-Cat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Numbing Mind&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/YiFqkatMUr0?si=1znRZFm4ES60KMu3" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://casperskulls.bandcamp.com/album/kit-cat" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April, the indie rock trio &lt;a href="https://casperskulls.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Casper Skulls&lt;/a&gt; returned with a new full-length. The 11-song &lt;em&gt;Kit-Cat&lt;/em&gt; arrived through &lt;a href="https://www.nextdoorrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Next Door Records&lt;/a&gt; and found the band embracing new chapters in their lives. The record finds the husband-and-wife core of Melanie St. Pierre-Bednis and Neil Bednis relocating to Sudbury and welcoming their first child. Meanwhile, multi-instrumentalist/drummer Fraser McClean spent time on the road, serving as a guitar tech for Toronto heavyweights PUP and Tokyo Police Club while performing in the acerbic noise-punk act &lt;a href="https://burnerband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Burner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St. Pierre-Bednis shared some insight on the band&amp;#39;s collective headspace, noting that they endeavoured to make the record &amp;quot;super fun with no expectations.&amp;quot; The resulting set, tracked over six days at Sudbury&amp;#39;s Deadpan Studios, is just that. Well-mannered and inviting, &lt;em&gt;Kit-Cat&lt;/em&gt; is a remarkably breezy listen and a refreshingly unburdened counterpoint to troubling times. The record shines brightest when Melanie and Neil sync up on vocals, as on the shoegaze-tinged &amp;quot;Roddy Piper&amp;quot; and the hooky chorus of the album-opening &amp;quot;Spindletop.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The record features guest contributions from Augusta Veno (&lt;a href="https://thelonelyparade.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lonely Parade&lt;/a&gt;) and producer Matt Weiwel. You can see the single &amp;quot;Numbing Mind&amp;quot; highlighted in a playful video from director &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/bosmobosmobosmo/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bosmo&lt;/a&gt; that reflects &amp;quot;technology&amp;#39;s role in fostering a self-obsessed and vain culture&amp;quot; by casting the group in a series of retro television roles. Neil commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We felt the video was a fun summation of the song&amp;#39;s meaning. It shows that Mel and I are just as guilty, distracted, and addicted to technology and content as everyone else.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kit-Cat&lt;/em&gt; follows the band&amp;#39;s acclaimed 2021 album &lt;em&gt;Knows No Kindness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3956000558/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://casperskulls.bandcamp.com/album/kit-cat"&gt;Kit-Cat by Casper Skulls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_riptides"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theriptides.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Riptides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Burn after Listening&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theriptides.bandcamp.com/album/burn-after-listening" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March, Ottawa punk veterans &lt;a href="https://theriptides.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Riptides&lt;/a&gt; unleashed &lt;em&gt;Burn After Listening&lt;/em&gt;, a pandemic-born collection that distills years of pent-up tension into a finely-tuned three-chord assault with both feet firmly planted in the 90s sound. Did you once own at least four Ikea &lt;em&gt;Gnedby&lt;/em&gt; CD towers brimming with EpiFat classics in cracked jewel cases? No judgement, fellow traveller! This one&amp;#39;s for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following up on 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Canadian Graffiti&lt;/em&gt;, the album serves as the long-running band&amp;#39;s first outlet to react to years of turbulence. They shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This record was born in the weirdest time. There was so much uncertainty, and it gave us room to really go deep. Lyrically, it&amp;#39;s satire, reflection, and frustration—wrapped up in fast hooks and shout-along choruses...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every song has its own identity, but together they make up a record that keeps you on your toes. We still sound like us, but this one pushed us creatively—sometimes into uncomfortable places. But that&amp;#39;s what punk is all about, right?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Riptides brought their new material to one of the genre&amp;#39;s modern meccas, recording in the storied Blasting Room in Fort Collins, Colorado, with prolific engineers Andrew Berlin and Jason Livermore (Descendents, NOFX, et al.). &lt;a href="https://teenagebottlerocket.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Teenage Bottlerocket&lt;/a&gt; drummer Darren Chewka and guitarist Kody Templeman perform on the punchy pop-punk single &amp;quot;Bad Habit.&amp;quot; The record also features guest vocals from Austrian mainstay Heavy Kevy (The Apers, Insanity Alert) and Merel Schaap from Rotterdam punk act Lone Wolf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the sound I grew up on. Pick your pantheon of melodic pop-punk favourites, and there&amp;#39;s a high chance you&amp;#39;ll hear the reflected, lovingly, in The Riptides.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1102286574/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theriptides.bandcamp.com/album/burn-after-listening"&gt;Burn After Listening by The Riptides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="matthew_doc_dunn"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew "Doc" Dunn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Tally Ho!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/album/love-raiders" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruminative psych-rock troubadour &lt;a href="https://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew &amp;quot;Doc&amp;quot; Dunn&lt;/a&gt; has a sprawling double LP ready for the summer. Due June 2 through &lt;a href="https://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cosmic Range Records&lt;/a&gt;, Dunn calls the 22-track &lt;em&gt;Love Raiders&lt;/em&gt; his &amp;quot;rural glam opus&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;a real labour of love.&amp;quot; In his announcement, the prolific Toronto player shared his hope to &amp;quot;raise some synapse and bring some light&amp;quot; with the new release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can preview the songs &amp;quot;Forbidden Life&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Tally Ho!&amp;quot; now. The former&amp;#39;s a slow-burning, country-fried acid-folk ballad, while the latter kicks over the amps with a fuzzed-out assist from Dinosaur Jr. legend J Mascis. Dunn co-produced the album with longtime collaborator Asher Gould-Murtagh (&lt;a href="https://mrjoy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mr. Joy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://dr-joy.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dr. Joy&lt;/a&gt;). The record features further contributions from &lt;a href="https://briantysoe.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Brian Tysoe&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://masayamasaya.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mas Aya&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Brandon Valdivia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Known for fronting the acclaimed psych-jazz combo &lt;a href="http://thecosmicrange.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Cosmic Range&lt;/a&gt;, Dunn is following up on 2023&amp;#39;s solo outing &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Light&lt;/em&gt;. Last year, he took part in the legendary &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt; Singles Club, issuing the songs &amp;quot;Your Feel&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Look In&amp;quot; on 7&amp;quot; vinyl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=694626965/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/album/love-raiders"&gt;LOVE RAIDERS by Matthew Dunn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="chris_page"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Split Seconds On Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/album/split-seconds-on-earth-4" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, Ottawa singer-songwriter &lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Page&lt;/a&gt; issued his new solo album, with &lt;em&gt;Split Seconds On Earth&lt;/em&gt; clocking in as the artist&amp;#39;s seventh outing under his name. The ten-song collection curates and finalizes material that first surfaced as a long-running series of digital singles, issued monthly since the lockdown days of 2020. Some Party covered that run religiously, so it&amp;#39;s nice to see many of those songs - some of the artist&amp;#39;s best - finally get a proper place in his discography. There&amp;#39;s a warm gravity to Page&amp;#39;s solo work, an earned quality that comes from years in the trenches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Page recorded the new album throughout 2024 between his home studio in Ottawa&amp;#39;s Vanier neighbourhood (lovingly dubbed &amp;quot;Las Vanier Haus Of Fuzz&amp;quot;). Dave Draves, Chris&amp;#39; bandmate from the early-2000s group power-pop group &lt;a href="https://campradio.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Camp Radio&lt;/a&gt;, mixed and mastered at Little Bullhorn. Toronto singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://lilyfrost.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lily Frost&lt;/a&gt; appears on the track &amp;quot;Plagiarism Fun.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 10-song record is the latest milestone in a lengthy underground career stretching back to the 90s-era Glengarry, Ontario garage-punk outfit &lt;a href="https://thestandgt.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Stand GT&lt;/a&gt;. In recent years, Page has performed as half of the droney noise-rock duo &lt;a href="https://expandafuzz.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Expanda Fuzz&lt;/a&gt; with Leila Younis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2022, Chris Page issued &lt;em&gt;Those Aren&amp;#39;t Stars Above Your Head&lt;/em&gt;, an acoustic reworking of the self-titled 2016 Camp Radio album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2937647507/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/album/split-seconds-on-earth-4"&gt;Split Seconds On Earth by Chris Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="barnacle"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://barnaclemtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Barnacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;The Edge&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Pharmacy&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://barnaclemtl.bandcamp.com/album/the-edge-pharmacy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal sea-punks &lt;a href="https://barnaclemtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Barnacle&lt;/a&gt; continue their resurgence with a new two-song single, previewing their upcoming album &lt;em&gt;Live From Rock Bottom&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;quot;The Edge&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Pharmacy&amp;quot; arrived in April, showcasing the evolution since their 2024 LP, &lt;em&gt;Such a Waste&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both tracks carry the band&amp;#39;s signature lo-fi sound, anchored by reverb-drenched vocals. This time, they&amp;#39;re employed on songs that feel decidedly darker - with the claustrophobic noise-wall &amp;quot;Pharmacy,&amp;quot; in particular, feeling particularly bleak. It&amp;#39;s a dark shift from a band that made their name with a SpongeBob-shitposting beach-goon aesthetic. If you&amp;#39;ve dug the aggressive weirdness of Sudbury&amp;#39;s Teleporters and Psychbike, you&amp;#39;ll find a similar vibe here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2902802448/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://barnaclemtl.bandcamp.com/album/the-edge-pharmacy"&gt;The Edge / Pharmacy by Barnacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Luna FM</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-26-luna-fm/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-26-luna-fm/</id>
    <published>2025-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-26T21:17:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="the_burning_hell"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/ghost-palace" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; are two or three albums into a dance with the apocalypse. Their early attempts maintained a nervous edge while wrestling with the unspeakable, treating societal collapse with gallows humour and powerless anxiety. The specific means to our collective doom was never the focus, though, and Mathias Kom lent his dense wordplay to chronicling ground-level stories of the survivors. Sometimes, that manifested as playful anti-folk songs cataloging the messy cultural detritus left in our wake. As that vision matured, as on 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Garbage Island&lt;/em&gt;, the focus shifted from humanity and addressed the surviving birds (it&amp;#39;s not their first rodeo, either).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt;, the disaster, whatever it is (and we&amp;#39;re free to take our pick), feels further out of focus, never forgotten but almost mundane in its inevitability. The Burning Hell&amp;#39;s outlook remains less dystopian than it is curiously bemused. This is best expressed in the funky psych-rock highlight &amp;quot;Luna FM,&amp;quot; told from the perspective of the moon&amp;#39;s premiere and loneliest DJ. It&amp;#39;s a one-way dialogue between the bored radio operator and a listenership that&amp;#39;s maybe entirely vanished. The song&amp;#39;s one of several stylistic swings on the 11-song record, which hops nimbly between tropical beach jams, quirky synth-rock, and even twangy, fiddle-driven country. Kom&amp;#39;s lyricism remains an unparalleled firehose of cultural references and wry outsider observations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt; arrived in early March through &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://bbislandmusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;BB*Island&lt;/a&gt;. The Burning Hell&amp;#39;s core remains the PEI-based pair of singer/songwriter Mathias Kom and the multi-talented Ariel Sharratt. Their band again features St. John&amp;#39;s-based producer/instrumentalist &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; and fiddler/vocalist Maria Peddle. Guest composer &lt;a href="https://carliehowell.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carlie Howell&lt;/a&gt; (The Electric Storm Collective, Beverly Glenn-Copeland) appears on the record alongside &lt;a href="http://theconstantines.wordpress.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Constantines&lt;/a&gt; guitarist &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/josecontrerasmusik/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;José Contreras&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;, and Amy Nicoll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a critic (or whatever I am), I realize that the external state of world affairs shouldn&amp;#39;t colour my objective view of a piece of art. Still, existential threats abound, and it&amp;#39;s hard not to perceive the band&amp;#39;s exploration of post-apocalyptic idiosyncracies as an expression of hope. We&amp;#39;re still here, after all. I think The Burning Hell ultimately finds our dishevelled humanity endearing, with Kom never succumbing to angst or bitterness in the face of upheaval and near-certain ruin. Given the vibe in the country, it&amp;#39;s something we could all aspire to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2494821677/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/license_id=4342/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/ghost-palace"&gt;Ghost Palace by The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="jake_nicoll"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Hold&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/album/on-hold" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;#39;re in the orbit of &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;, we should take note that &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; recently issued a solo EP to mark a significant milestone. Released in early February, the five-song &lt;em&gt;On Hold&lt;/em&gt; captures the nervous anticipation of impending parenthood. Nicoll wrote and recorded the set while he and partner Pamela Mackenzie waited for the birth of their first child last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EP&amp;#39;s opener, &amp;quot;Waiting Room,&amp;quot; directly references the Fugazi anthem of the same name, pairing vintage synths and gated drums with samples from the hospital&amp;#39;s phone tree. &amp;quot;Galloping Horses&amp;quot; builds a synth-pop earworm around the pulse of a fetal heart monitor, giving the young Mackenzie Nicoll their first album credit. The high BPM of the Doppler drives the track towards a &amp;quot;synthy love-child of Kraftwerk and Men Without Hats.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 25-minute collection follows Nicoll&amp;#39;s 2024 release &lt;em&gt;Lonely Mission&lt;/em&gt;, an accomplished full-length that focused the producer on &amp;quot;the larger questions of life and the future of this warming planet.&amp;quot; That music emerged from pandemic-era isolation on Nicoll&amp;#39;s family farm in Ontario, where Jake built a cabin studio with a workshop full of vintage recording equipment. In 2023, Jake and Pamela issued the split indie-folk album &lt;em&gt;End Daze&lt;/em&gt; under the name &lt;a href="https://pamiandjake.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pami and Jake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3551138994/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/album/on-hold"&gt;ON HOLD by Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="michael_cloud_duguay"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com/album/wobbly-yonder" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peterborough luminary &lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt; recently announced &lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt;, a new solo LP arriving April 25 through &lt;a href="https://watchthatendsthenight.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Watch That Ends The Night&lt;/a&gt;. The album finds the introspective singer-songwriter amassing a staggering roster of 19 collaborators from across the Canadian indie spectrum. That list includes the aforementioned Mathias Kom, Ariel Sharratt, and Jake Nicoll of &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; (if the through-line in this edition of Some Party wasn&amp;#39;t already obvious, I&amp;#39;ve been sitting on a serendipitous tangle of connective tissue). You can preview the album through the lushly orchestrated dream-pop of &amp;quot;Immutable White Light.&amp;quot; On the single, the artist revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Immutable White Light&amp;#39; is about the seemingly fixed nature of our internal lives, and the inability to witness spiritual progress in oneself except for in hindsight. It is about how, in my darkest moments, my true inner self was never lost but was obfuscated by external concerns. It&amp;#39;s about how grace and light can be found through connection with a higher power and one&amp;#39;s authentic self.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Only Angel In Sight,&amp;quot; co-written by Toronto&amp;#39;s Sara Jarvie-Clark (&lt;a href="https://analoguesofmay.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Analogues of May&lt;/a&gt;), is also available to stream. The press release describes a slow-burning folk epic that &amp;quot;explores themes of social paranoia and inhibition&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;the psychedelic experience and fuzzy contracts of fledgling romance.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While increasingly prolific, Duguay doesn&amp;#39;t issue new material lightly. It often feels that each step in the artist&amp;#39;s career is hard-won and the subject of much consternation. &lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt; has similar roots, stemming from a traumatic 2009 experience when Duguay performed as part of The Burning Hell at Slovakia&amp;#39;s Pohoda Festival. A catastrophic storm struck the event, claiming two lives and injuring dozens. &amp;quot;The experience cracked something open in me,&amp;quot; recalls Duguay, who stepped away from music for an extended period following the incident. The artist&amp;#39;s output in the years since often explicitly addresses mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album finds Duguay reconnecting with The Burning Hell principles, with Kom and Sharratt sharing performance and production credits. Furthermore, at their urging the Duguay recorded with &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Scamper&lt;/em&gt;, a solar-powered studio built in a 70s-era camper RV. This mobile setup allowed the artist to record exclusively in unconventional spaces, from beaches to an abandoned farmhouse to the lantern room of PEI&amp;#39;s East Point Lighthouse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eight-song &lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt; features appearances from &lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;, Andrew MacKelvie (&lt;a href="https://newhermitage.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;New Hermitage&lt;/a&gt;, Scions), Jamie Kronick (Scattered Clouds), &lt;a href="https://carliehowell.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carlie Howell&lt;/a&gt; (Beverly Glenn-Copeland), &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/josecontrerasmusik/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;José Contreras&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;a href="https://owendaviesmusic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Owen Davies&lt;/a&gt;, among others. Stylistically, the record leaps from ambient interludes to anthemic rock and hushed folk ballads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This release follows a productive 2024 for Duguay, which saw him crystallize his &amp;quot;experimental heartland totalism&amp;quot; on the full-length &lt;em&gt;Succeeder&lt;/em&gt;. That year also saw the acclaimed debut of the experimental ensemble &lt;a href="https://scions.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Scions&lt;/a&gt;. They issued &lt;em&gt;To Cry Out In The Wilderness&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;a href="https://www.ideefixerecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Idée Fixe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1329027024/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com/album/wobbly-yonder"&gt;Wobbly Yonder by Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="eliza_niemi"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/album/progress-bakery" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s new LP is something special. It so singularly captivates that I&amp;#39;ve spent the past week listening to either &lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; on repeat or nothing. In 2025, we cling to whatever slight reprieve we can find. You all know why. It&amp;#39;s survival. That Niemi can hook you while favouring quiet moments and sparse arrangements makes her new album a welcome salve. Whether she intended it that way doesn&amp;#39;t much matter. It could be a happy accident, but it&amp;#39;s a perfect counterpoint to the turmoil du jour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; arrived last week through &lt;a href="https://vainmina.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Vain Mina&lt;/a&gt; and the UK-based &lt;a href="https://tinangelrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tin Angel Records&lt;/a&gt;, delivering 15 songs that percolate with clever observations and a deft sense of minimalism that&amp;#39;s always friendly, never austere. The record features a notable cast of Toronto indie musicians, including &lt;a href="https://mothertongues.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mother Tongues&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Jeremy Ray, Evan Cartwright (Tasseomancy, US Girls), &lt;a href="https://louieshort.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Louie Short&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://littlekid.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Little Kid&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Kenny Boothby, Ed Squires of the &lt;a href="https://badgeepoque.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Badge Époque Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;, Steven McPhail from &lt;a href="https://mrjoy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mr. Joy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://dorotheapaas.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dorothea Paas&lt;/a&gt; among others. Short and Ray co-produced the album alongside Niemi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; follows Niemi&amp;#39;s 2022 solo debut, &lt;em&gt;Staying Mellow Blows&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;#39;ve undoubtedly heard her on various Canadian records over the past few years, often adding depth on the cello. Pre-pandemic, she co-led the Montreal indie rock act &lt;a href="https://mauno.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mauno&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; surpasses it all, and it&amp;#39;s one of the early standouts of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=900516666/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/album/progress-bakery"&gt;Progress Bakery by Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cassia_hardy"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cassia Hardy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Empress&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/track/empress" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wares.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Wares&lt;/a&gt; principle &lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cassia Hardy&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a long-in-the-works ode to the defunct Edmonton venue, The Empress Ale House. The venue had a 13-year run from 2007 through 2020, employing many musicians from the city&amp;#39;s local scene. &amp;quot;Empress&amp;quot; builds Hardy&amp;#39;s specific recollections to reflect on the community&amp;#39;s broader loss of shared cultural spaces. The artist describes the rollicking-yet-wistful noise-pop track as &amp;quot;a composite photo of a few places close to my heart as a patron and a worker.&amp;quot; She elaborates:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Head and shoulders above them was The Empress. I can still see the way it looked at last call, when the house lights went up. Animal skulls lined the blood red walls, the dark wooden tables at once sticky and slippery. We served beer by the imperial pint, free pretzels, and a petrified $30 hungry man dinner in the freezer to satisfy the license.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As unique as it was, like so many other places, the landlords got greedy and didn&amp;#39;t know what they were messing with. Some folks who went might never know what happened, some might not care to, and more and more will never have seen it at all. Sometimes the sweet things in life don&amp;#39;t burn out or fade away, they are taken.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt McKeen recorded the song, which Hardy dedicates to Empress owner Sue Kiernan. It&amp;#39;s the first we&amp;#39;ve heard from Cassia since Wares&amp;#39; 2023 singles &amp;quot;Graceless/Cloudless,&amp;quot; which followed their 2020 album &lt;em&gt;Survival&lt;/em&gt;. The new tune arrives via &lt;a href="https://www.mintrecs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1261248389/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/track/empress"&gt;Empress by Cassia Hardy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brutal Planet</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-05-brutal-planet/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-05-brutal-planet/</id>
    <published>2025-03-04T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-06T12:20:35-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is it March? Wow, I&amp;#39;m late to publish. What can I say? Existential threats are distracting as hell. Here&amp;#39;s what some of our nationally renown guitar deviants have been up to while I&amp;#39;ve been staring into the void.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="golden_shitters"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Golden Shitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brutal Planet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/G8VF9o_XVt4?si=IyVaxju2sl31o6Lu" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com/album/brutal-planet" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamilton&amp;#39;s scuzzy punk supergroup &lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Golden Shitters&lt;/a&gt; are back with &lt;em&gt;Brutal Planet&lt;/em&gt;, their sophomore 12&amp;quot; arriving this Friday through &lt;a href="https://uglypoprecords.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ugly Pop Records&lt;/a&gt;. The collection promises twelve songs delivered with proudly lowbrow charm in the lunkheaded lineage of the Ramones. Through that lens, the Shitters channel The Spits&amp;#39;s deadpan drone and Screeching Weasel&amp;#39;s bratty snot. It&amp;#39;s a tried-and-true sound, but so perfect in its inception, there&amp;#39;s a reason we always come back to it. You can see the title track celebrated in a new video (yes, that&amp;#39;s Patrick and Ripley from &lt;a href="https://packratpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pack Rat&lt;/a&gt; in the starring roles).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this round, the Shitters maintain their core lineup of Matt Ellis (&lt;a href="https://anxiouspleasers.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Anxious Pleasers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://the-vapids.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Vapids&lt;/a&gt;) and Dave Tyson (&lt;a href="https://darktrip.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dark Trip&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey &amp;amp; the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt;) trading off guitar, bass, and vocals, backed by &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Kyle Fisher on drums. The group self-recorded with Dave mixing and Sean Pearson (TV Freaks, the Black Halos) mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ugly Pop lauds the band&amp;#39;s old-school approach, likewise promising a no-gimmicks run on black vinyl. They boast:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;all the reckless speed and raw tunes, plus tasty guitar flash and lyrics very much of our time. This stuff will never, ever get old as long as it&amp;#39;s executed with the spirit and power found here in spades... It&amp;#39;s punk rock with bad taste and a B-movie bathroom budget.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows Golden Shitters&amp;#39; 2024 EP &lt;em&gt;Love Blows&lt;/em&gt;, a digital-only live record captured at Hamilton&amp;#39;s Vertagogo, and their self-titled 2023 LP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1744127730/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com/album/brutal-planet"&gt;Brutal Planet by Golden Shitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="loud_hands"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Loud Hands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loud Hands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com/album/loud-hands" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamilton also recently saw the full-length debut of &lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Loud Hands&lt;/a&gt;, a grungy indie-rock quartet. The project features brothers Shane and Matt Cabral sharing guitar and vocal duties, backed by a rhythm section featuring their cousin, drummer Zander Lamothe, and bassist/vocalist David O&amp;#39;Connor. You&amp;#39;ll likely recognize the latter as the bombastic Sweet Dave of powerhouse punks &lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;. His role here is comparatively one of restraint, appearing almost as a mentor to what&amp;#39;s otherwise a family affair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dave announced the project and the band&amp;#39;s first show a few weeks back, graciously calling Loud Hands:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...the silver lining in an otherwise dark cloud. A tiny little rosebud growing out of a crack in the concrete. Two brothers, a cousin and me. Brothers writing songs together has a magic that I can&amp;#39;t really explain but I&amp;#39;m so happy to be a part of it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;O&amp;#39;Connor recorded the group last year, with mixing and mastering handled in Australia by the ever-present Mikey Young (Dumb, Itchy Self, Motorists). You can find the ten-song self-titled set streaming everywhere and available to download at Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4026334281/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com/album/loud-hands"&gt;Loud Hands by Loud Hands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="private_lives"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Psychic Beat&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3IOsHbW5np4?si=0KsxXUXUjoOkAUE_" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com/album/salt-of-the-earth" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal power pop/garage punk/post-something-or-other quartet &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt; have their sophomore album on deck. &lt;em&gt;Salt of the Earth&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 21 through Cincinnati&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/feelitrecordshop/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Feel It Records&lt;/a&gt;, as previewed through the peppy new single &amp;quot;Psychic Beat.&amp;quot; The song shows some welcome carryover of the attitude-driven girl-group energy vocalist Jackie Blenkarn once used to great effect with the &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s one of 10 songs from the new record. You can see it performed in an appropriately jittery new video from Alan Hildebrandt of &lt;a href="https://www.studiodelscorpio.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Studio Del Scorpio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Private Lives features Blenkarn backed by her spouse Chance Hutchison (&lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar, with bassist Josh Herlihey (&lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt;), and drummer Drew Demers (also of PRIORS) holding down the low-end. Hutchison engineered and mixed the album with the aforementioned Mikey Young mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows the group&amp;#39;s 2023 debut &lt;em&gt;Hit Record&lt;/em&gt;, and promises a further evolution from the band&amp;#39;s origins as Chance and Jackie&amp;#39;s lockdown-era timekiller. Paperface Zine&amp;#39;s Joe Massaro lauds the album for &amp;quot;undercutting power pop conventions and challenging itself track after track.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3624111497/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com/album/salt-of-the-earth"&gt;Salt of the Earth by Private Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="dvtr"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;DVTR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Né pour flâner&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SMpuGuhrxf0?si=fP2-n2VLo8tQW1l6" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/track/n-pour-fl-ner" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new single from frenetic Quebec synth-punk duo &lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;DVTR&lt;/a&gt; offers a reprieve from the heavier topics with an ode to idleness. &amp;quot;Né pour flâner&amp;quot; (born to loiter) arrived earlier this month via &lt;a href="https://lisbonluxrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lisbon Lux Records&lt;/a&gt;, alongside a camcorder video chronicling the band&amp;#39;s recent Asian tour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group commented on their uncharacteristically upbeat approach to the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve been lashing out at everything with our music recently: patriarchy, the death industry, corrupt cops, the goddamn Olympics and whatnot. 2025 is kumbaya, so here&amp;#39;s some POSITIVE energy, with a track about something DVTR loves, for once. Loitering! Let&amp;#39;s bring loitering back in style, ok bye.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new single follows a busy year that saw DVTR tour Japan, South Korea, the UK, and Europe while making festival appearances at major events like Osheaga. They capped 2024 with a sold-out hometown gig at Montreal&amp;#39;s Foufounes Électriques and took home three awards at the &lt;a href="https://musiqueindependante.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;GAMIQ&lt;/a&gt; gala (including punk album of the year).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hailed as a cross between the B-52s and Jay Reatard, DVTR features Demi Lune (Laurence G-Do) and Jean Divorce (JC Tellier), both formerly of the Montreal electropop act &lt;a href="https://lecouleurmusic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Le Couleur&lt;/a&gt;. Tellier also has roots in the Chicoutimi rock group &lt;a href="https://gazoline.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gazoline&lt;/a&gt;. The band released their &lt;em&gt;Bonjour (BIS)&lt;/em&gt; EP in November 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3030189920/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/track/n-pour-fl-ner"&gt;Né pour flâner by DVTR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="real_sickies"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Real Sickies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under a Plastic Bag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch at &amp;quot;Triage&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/RtU50jgpjME?si=eX4dOFYNQglC7G9W" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com/album/under-a-plastic-bag" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edmonton pop-punk mainstays &lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Real Sickies&lt;/a&gt; are readying their fifth full-length. &lt;em&gt;Under a Plastic Bag&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 14 through &lt;a href="https://stomprecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt;, with the singles &amp;quot;Triage&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Should&amp;#39;ve Seen It Coming&amp;quot; now streaming. The new material finds the band expanding from their well-honed foundation of Ramones and Buzzcocks worship to incorporate new wave, power pop, and indie rock flavours. The album finds the Sickies working with producer Josh Wells (&lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blackmountain.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Black Mountain&lt;/a&gt;), who played a prominent role in guiding the group&amp;#39;s new direction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discussing &amp;quot;Triage,&amp;quot; the record&amp;#39;s first single, the producer commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This song reminds me, at first, of being on adderall. Random thoughts, itchy eyes, the urge to rock really fast. But then, the song settles into a sick, focused motorik jam. Here we get some alien percussion floating down from another universe to join in and rocket ahead. For a moment, the human jam fuses with the aliens, but then the relationship deteriorates, the humans get mad and break out, the whole thing ending with a total meltdown.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Director Jesse Nash treats the single to a clever new video treatment featuring miniature models handcrafted by vocalist Ben Disaster. Ben wrote the song with the perspective of having just survived a major car accident with his family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band also recently shared a video for the track &amp;quot;Should Have Seen It Coming.&amp;quot; That piece, directed by Tyler Hall, finds the band finds the Sickies performing in an unheated garage in -20 degree weather. On the song, Ben Disaster shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s about patterns, not being able to accept consequences, or finally coming to. There&amp;#39;s not much more meaning to it other than just smashing one&amp;#39;s own teeth with a microphone. Musically it explores some new emotions. Maybe. Hindsight right?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows up on 2022&amp;#39;s EP &lt;em&gt;Danny, It&amp;#39;s Not Your Birthday&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Love is for Lovers&lt;/em&gt; LP from the year prior.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3403063035/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com/album/under-a-plastic-bag"&gt;Under a Plastic Bag by REAL SICKIES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="autogramm"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Randy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/album/randy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;, the Vancouver-rooted new wavers recently shared a new single through &lt;a href="https://dirtcultrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dirt Cult&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goodwillrecords.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Goodwill Records&lt;/a&gt;. The goodhearted &amp;quot;Randy&amp;quot; is another in the band&amp;#39;s impressive streak of synth-driven earworms. The track, originally slated for inclusion on 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Music That Humans Can Play&lt;/em&gt;, finds the group offering tongue-in-cheek lyrical encouragement to the ambitions of the drummer&amp;#39;s cat (&amp;quot;If you think you wanna jump up on that countertop, well baby you&amp;#39;ve got the tools&amp;quot;). Josh &amp;quot;The Silo&amp;quot; Wells explained:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s a letter to a good friend, in need of a little confidence push. Everyone needs an ego boost sometimes. Even if they&amp;#39;re a cat.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DEVO-indebted &amp;quot;Randy&amp;quot; arrives backed by a cover of &amp;quot;Jenny&amp;#39;s In A Sleep World,&amp;quot; a 1979 track by Canadian punk legends &lt;a href="https://thediodes.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Diodes&lt;/a&gt;. A press release notes that the Toronto pioneers have enthusiastically endorsed Autogramm&amp;#39;s take.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vinyl 7&amp;quot; follows the band&amp;#39;s recent single &amp;quot;Diana&amp;quot; and arrives as they prepare for a March tour of Spain. Autogramm features Jiffy Marx (&lt;a href="https://nightcourtpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Night Court&lt;/a&gt;), The Silo (Black Mountain, Destroyer), CC Voltage (&lt;a href="https://thespitfires.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Spitfires&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theblackhalos.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Black Halos&lt;/a&gt;), and Lars Von Seattle (&lt;a href="https://www.breadandbutterrules.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bread &amp;amp; Butter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1980083757/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/album/randy"&gt;Randy by Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="packs"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PACKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Before I Was Bleeding&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com/track/before-i-was-bleeding" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s Madeline Link recently shared a new one-off single from her compellingly slow-burning &lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PACKS&lt;/a&gt; project. &amp;quot;Before I Was Bleeding&amp;quot; provides a wonderfully tranquil detour for whatever chaos you&amp;#39;re navigating, underscored by a bass clarinet Link plays on the recording. Madeline sings and plays acoustic guitar on the sparse tune, accompanied by Diego Parragué of Chile&amp;#39;s Laos Kollective on keys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new song surfaced a few weeks ago for the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/packstheband" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; subscribers. It follows &lt;em&gt;Melt The Honey&lt;/em&gt;, PACKS&amp;#39; January 2024 full-length through &lt;a href="https://firetalkrecs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fire Talk Records&lt;/a&gt; (a quick follow-up to their &lt;em&gt;Crispy Crunchy Nothing&lt;/em&gt; LP from just a few months prior). &lt;em&gt;Honey&lt;/em&gt; found Link writing and recording between Toronto, Mexico City, and Chile. PACKS&amp;#39; full-band lineup for those sessions featured guitarist Dexter Nash, bassist Noah O&amp;#39;Neil, and drummer Shane Hooper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2007191187/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com/track/before-i-was-bleeding"&gt;before i was bleeding by PACKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="monk"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dark Side of the Mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/DyNC1It07bI?si=PhZ7LzcgQ4ZhGp_s" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com/album/dark-side-of-the-mind" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mindfulness-minded LA-via-Sudbury hardcore project &lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monk&lt;/a&gt; returns next month with &lt;em&gt;Dark Side of the Mind&lt;/em&gt;, their second EP for &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;. The set lands April 25, with two punishing advance singles streaming now: the title track (featuring Brendan Murphy of Hamilton metalcore veterans &lt;a href="https://counterpartshc.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Counterparts&lt;/a&gt;) and &amp;quot;Chains.&amp;quot; Jovanni Martinez directed the video for the former.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vocalist Frank Bach (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/viciouscyclesudbury/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Vicious Cycle&lt;/a&gt;) commented on the EP&amp;#39;s thematic direction, particularly the title track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Dark Side delves into the struggle of self-exploration and confronting the hidden, often darker, aspects of the mind. If &lt;em&gt;Rock&lt;/em&gt; was the light side, this is the opposite— questioning one&amp;#39;s understanding of life and grappling with the emotional weight of guilt, trauma, and unresolved pain, encouraging you to confront your fears, doubts, and unspoken truths. The song is about the courage it takes to face inner struggles and make peace with the haunting aspects of the human psyche.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band self-produced the new collection, recording at Camera Varda (the Welland, Ontario studio of The Outfit&amp;#39;s Romano brothers) and LA&amp;#39;s Pirate Studios. Alex Jacobellli mixed at Sunsick Studio, with Jon Drew mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monk solidified their lineup in the time since 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Rock&lt;/em&gt; EP. That early iteration saw Bach collaborate remotely with Daniel and Ian Romano of &lt;a href="https://attackinblack.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Attack In Black&lt;/a&gt;. The band now features LA-local backing from guitarist Scott Savarie (&lt;a href="https://cureforyouth.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cure for Youth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blacklungs.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Black Lungs&lt;/a&gt;), bassist Connor McKenna (&lt;a href="https://headspin-zone.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Headspin&lt;/a&gt;), and drummer Jesse Kalamian (Hatespeech).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1870714553/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com/album/dark-side-of-the-mind"&gt;Dark Side of the Mind by Monk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_good_brothers"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thegoodbrothers.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Good Brothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class="split"&gt;&amp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thesadies.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Sadies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Now That You&amp;#39;re Gone&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/dyfw_TOLMiE?si=iYBso-_zwbSlqy8M" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2022 death of Dallas Good continues to echo through the Canadian music landscape, but the latest tribute to the beloved musician comes from somewhere very personal. Legendary country trio &lt;a href="https://thegoodbrothers.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Good Brothers&lt;/a&gt;, featuring Dallas&amp;#39; father and uncles, returned with their first new music since 2017 to pay tribute to the late &lt;a href="https://www.thesadies.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sadies&lt;/a&gt; guitarist. &amp;quot;Now That You&amp;#39;re Gone,&amp;quot; a collaboration with the surviving Sadies members, arrived in February to mark the third anniversary of Dallas&amp;#39; passing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Good Brothers formed in the early 70s, rising to fame after touring on the legendary Festival Express train alongside legends like Janice Joplin, The Band, and the Grateful Dead. The trio features Dallas&amp;#39; father, Bruce, and his uncles, Brian and Larry Good. On the new song, Bruce shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;After the sudden passing of my son Dallas, I hoped that expressing my feelings through music might soften the blow of such a profound loss. This song became my therapy and helped diminish the everlasting pain.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collective performs the single in a new video from director &lt;a href="https://www.coreykellyimages.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Corey Kelly&lt;/a&gt;. The Good Brothers recently linked up with Collingwood, Ontario producer &lt;a href="https://grahamtrude.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Graham Trude&lt;/a&gt; to record for his &lt;a href="https://countrycorerecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Countrycore Records&lt;/a&gt; label. Their next record will follow up on 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Wide Awake Dreamin&amp;#39;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sadies released the Polaris shortlisted &lt;em&gt;Colder Streams&lt;/em&gt; - the last album Dallas played on - in July of 2022 through &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.yeproc.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yep Roc Records&lt;/a&gt;.Now operating as a trio, guitarist/vocalist Travis Good, bassist Sean Dean, and drummer Mike Belitsky recently issued a full-length of new material in collaboration with Dallas&amp;#39; longtime creative partner &lt;a href="https://rickwhitearchive.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rick White&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/artists/erics_trip" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eric&amp;#39;s Trip&lt;/a&gt;, Elevator). The 13-song &lt;em&gt;Rick White and the Sadies&lt;/em&gt; arrived last summer through &lt;a href="https://bluefogrecordings.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Blue Fog Recordings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;div class='aspect-ratio'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dyfw_TOLMiE?si=iYBso-_zwbSlqy8M" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Outta My Head</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-02-11-outta-my-head/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-02-11-outta-my-head/</id>
    <published>2025-02-10T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-11T17:16:36-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know, I always assumed the Dominion would outlast this newsletter but a lot can change in a week. I&amp;#39;ll endeavour to keep publishing as long as we remain a viable nation, but if they need my help manning the old batteries at Queenston, I happen to know the Heights like the back of my hand. Expect delays in that case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push on, brave York volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_boojums"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Boojums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Love&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Outta My Head&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com/track/outta-my-head-video-version" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I&amp;#39;ve been at this for too long, but I rarely stumble across a band that so thoroughly grabs my attention that I drop whatever I&amp;#39;m doing and dive frantically into research. I&amp;#39;m almost ashamed to admit I mindlessly scrolled into &lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Boojums&lt;/a&gt; on Instagram. You never want to credit the stinkin&amp;#39; algorithm with a legitimate find - particularly as a writer. It doesn&amp;#39;t help sell the relevance of my dying medium to give that credit where it&amp;#39;s due, but I&amp;#39;m honest to a fault.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Promoting their first two singles, the band shared a few performance videos showcasing segments of &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Love&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Outta My Head.&amp;quot; The clips find the trio crammed awkwardly in the viewport as if performing in a closet. &lt;a href="https://williestratton.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Willie Stratton&lt;/a&gt; glances uncomfortably into the camera with a vague sense of menace while the group crashes through their over-driven power-pop gems. Through deft planning or a fortuitous low-budget, the band introduces themselves with a lo-fi veneer that feels refreshingly, arrestingly real. If that&amp;#39;s all a put-on, some faux-amateurism, then so be it. It&amp;#39;s working for them, and it&amp;#39;s working for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hailing from Port Hawkesbury in Cape Breton Island, The Boojums haven&amp;#39;t been around for more than a year, but their roster boasts lengthy discographies. Guitarist/vocalist Willie Stratton is a fixture of the Halifax scene, recording a mix of folk, rockabilly, and lovesick blues over several records, most recently 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Drugstore Dreamin&amp;#39;&lt;/em&gt;. He&amp;#39;s also played in the surf-rock act &lt;a href="https://beachbait.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Beach Bait&lt;/a&gt;, among others. Bassist/vocalist Sara Eve is a member of the gritty garage/punk quartet &lt;a href="https://www.skunkmotel.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Skunk Motel&lt;/a&gt; and Toronto instrumental act &lt;a href="https://www.thesurfrajettes.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Surfrajettes&lt;/a&gt;. Mabou-based drummer &lt;a href="https://petermacinnis.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Peter MacInnis&lt;/a&gt; boasts a solo career to rival Stratton&amp;#39;s. He last released the quirky indie-folk record &lt;em&gt;Late Night Blues Vibe&lt;/em&gt; and plays regularly with the Inverness garage-folk quartet &lt;a href="https://beechhill.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Beech Hill&lt;/a&gt;. You may have also seen him on the YouTube comedy series &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzBZsyBwld-BSwPOi3U37nA?view_as=subscriber" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cape Breton Chats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Their vast social reach notwithstanding, the Boojums have remained relatively confined to the Maritimes. That changes on March 25 with an appearance at Toronto&amp;#39;s Longboat Hall as part of &lt;a href="https://wearebusybodies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;We Are Busy Bodies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; 20th anniversary celebrations. They&amp;#39;ll play alongside Toronto bummer-pop favourites &lt;a href="https://nofrillsmusic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Frills&lt;/a&gt; and Welsh indie rockers &lt;a href="https://thebugclub.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Bug Club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=221485291/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com/track/dont-wanna-love"&gt;Don't Wanna Love by The Boojums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="washing_machine"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silver Tongue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/album/silver-tongue" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halifax post-punk trio &lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt; have a new full-length on deck. &lt;em&gt;Silver Tongue&lt;/em&gt; arrives on April 18, building on the college rock revival of their early work to arrive somewhere lush and moody. While R.E.M. remains a touchpoint, this time out, Washing Machine cites the influence of lavish 80s sophisti-pop groups like Prefab Sprout. The pensive pre-release singles &amp;quot;Worn Apparition&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Vivian&amp;#39;s Way&amp;quot; showcase that evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band shared some insight on the 8-track album&amp;#39;s lyrical approach, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Thematically, Silver Tongue is misled by a host of zealous and tragic protagonists. Unreliable narrators lose the plot in a crisis of communication while searching for the upper hand and the right words.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washing Machine&amp;#39;s current lineup features Noel Macdonald (&lt;a href="http://moonhalifax.tumblr.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Moon&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar and vocals, Glen Leck (&lt;a href="http://hungryrecords.bandcamp.com/album/shorelines" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Working Titles&lt;/a&gt;) on bass, guitar, and keys, and Justin Crowe (&lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://heavenlyblue.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Heavenly Blue&lt;/a&gt;) on drums. Another Booji Boy, Adam Ledrew, makes a guest appearance on organ and synth. The band recorded over two sessions at Dartmouth&amp;#39;s Fang studio with engineers Thomas Stajcer (Safeword, Daveband) and Alex Burris, with additional tracking by Leck and Ledrew. Noel Macdonald mixed the record at Rotary Club, with Carl Saff mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washing Machine has a string of Maritime dates lined up to support the record, including stops in Moncton and Charlottetown before their April 19 release show at Halifax&amp;#39;s Propeller Arcade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album follows Washing Machine&amp;#39;s 2022 sophomore LP &lt;em&gt;Cheat the Pattern&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2895552108/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/album/silver-tongue"&gt;Silver Tongue by Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="edgar_breau"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Edgar Breau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Cornpone the King of Jive&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com/track/cornpone-the-king-of-jive" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Edgar Breau&lt;/a&gt;, founder of the cult Hamilton proto-punk group &lt;a href="https://www.simplysaucer.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Simply Saucer&lt;/a&gt;, is back with a rollicking new single. &amp;quot;Cornpone the King of Jive&amp;quot; layers the artist&amp;#39;s trademark psych grit atop a playful bed southern rock, crafting a lively, sardonic commentary on &amp;quot;populist leaders, lovable outlaws, and the morally duplicitous figures who hold the public&amp;#39;s fascination.&amp;quot; We could name a few.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Breau wrote and recorded the track at Dany Laj&amp;#39;s Montreal studio, the La La Pop Shoppe. Laj likewise brought his band, The Looks, to back Breau on the track, with Laj contributing guitar, Jeanette Dowling on bass, and Alex Pauzé drumming. The Hamilton legend spoke about the contributions of his newfound collaborators:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The song started out as a simple fingerstyle acoustic tune, but in the studio, it became a monster stomping rocker. Dany&amp;#39;s lead guitar playing really brought it to life, and I&amp;#39;m proud of how the arrangement turned out.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last summer, &lt;a href="http://danylaj.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dany Laj and the Looks&lt;/a&gt; shared &amp;quot;Meet Me On The Floor,&amp;quot; a one-off power-pop single that marked their return to action following the pandemic. Edgar Breau last issued a self-titled solo record in 2020 and a reissue of &lt;em&gt;Shadows of Ecstasy&lt;/em&gt;, his first post-Saucer solo album recorded in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1051557152/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com/track/cornpone-the-king-of-jive"&gt;Cornpone the King of Jive by Edgar Breau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cult_crime"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cult Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Desperation&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com/track/desperation" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cult Crime&lt;/a&gt; have their debut full-length on deck through &lt;a href="https://uglypoprecords.bigcartel.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ugly Pop Records&lt;/a&gt;. Due March 3, the nine-song LP promises a potent blend of early punk influences. The label took the courtesy of listing the big names, so I didn&amp;#39;t have to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...snarling, hard-nosed punk that recalls 1981 hardcore on both sides of the Atlantic, seasoning classic LA a la Adolescents/TSOL/pre-Henry Flag with a dash of primo Blitz. No mere genre exercise, these are tough but memorable songs delivered with hooks and skill.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those hooks and skills come, in part, from Matt Menard, veteran of a laundry list of killer Windsor and Toronto bands. That includes the lo-fi punk act &lt;a href="https://nofixforyou.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Fix&lt;/a&gt;, psych-punks &lt;a href="https://psychicvoid.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Psychic Void&lt;/a&gt;, and the hardcore group &lt;a href="https://brainitch.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Brain Itch&lt;/a&gt;. Cult Crime recorded with &lt;a href="https://jimmyvapid.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmy Vapid&lt;/a&gt; of veteran Burlington goons &lt;a href="https://the-vapids.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Vapids&lt;/a&gt;. Josh Kaiser mastered the set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can crash through the lead single &amp;quot;Desperation&amp;quot; now, delivering equal parts speed and snot in just under two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=4124347039/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com/track/desperation"&gt;Desperation by Cult Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="outtacontroller"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Outtacontroller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Cheap Pop&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com/track/cheap-pop" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halifax punk quartet &lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Outtacontroller&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the year with &amp;quot;Cheap Pop,&amp;quot; another in their reliably strong series of fuzzed-out power-pop gems. As with past efforts, the band said little about the track outside of the usual promise of more to come. I remain delightfully baffled at how consistently great this band sounds. Their nonchalant ability to craft Buzzcocks-quality hooks time after time feels entirely underappreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outtacontroller features vocalist/guitarists Terry A&amp;#39;hearn and James O&amp;#39;Toole, bassist AJ Boutilier, and drummer Sean Parsons. Late last year, the band convened in their Bunker studio to start work on the full-length follow-up to their 2022 LP &lt;em&gt;Come Alive&lt;/em&gt;. There&amp;#39;s no word yet on their release plans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year saw a few one-off singles from the group, including &amp;quot;Gimme Nothin&amp;#39;&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;I Got Mine.&amp;quot; They issued the &lt;em&gt;Just a Scratch&lt;/em&gt; EP in 2023 through Madrid&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/jarama45rpmrecs/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jarama 45RPM Recs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1768926132/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com/track/cheap-pop"&gt;Cheap Pop by OUTTACONTROLLER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="doctor_mother_father"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Doctor Mother Father&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Break the Same&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/album/break-the-same" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saint John power trio &lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Doctor Mother Father&lt;/a&gt; recently shared &amp;quot;Break the Same,&amp;quot; the crunchy first single from their upcoming EP &lt;em&gt;It All Depends On How You Wanna Hurt&lt;/em&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s teasing &amp;quot;an energizing soundtrack to hard times in the maritimes in the midst of a crashing economy.&amp;quot; You&amp;#39;ll have to wait until June to hear that in full, but this track certainly delivers on that promise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corey Bonnevie (&lt;a href="https://lylm.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Little You, Little Me&lt;/a&gt;) wrote and recorded the EP at his &lt;a href="https://monopolizedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monopolized Records&lt;/a&gt; studio, backed by bassist Kortni Nicols (&lt;a href="https://lionsault.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lionsault&lt;/a&gt;) and drummer Colin Ferris (Sheik, Cool Dudes Fighting, Butcher). The new material follows Doctor Mother Father&amp;#39;s 2024 full-length &lt;em&gt;Feelin&amp;#39; Fine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=804292490/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/album/break-the-same"&gt;Break the Same by Doctor Mother Father&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="living_mad"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Living Mad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ungreatful Fucks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com/album/ungrateful-fucks" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;#39;s been a good week if I can pepper a column with multiple references to &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt; personnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Living Mad&lt;/a&gt; is a scrappy new hardcore side-project from frequent collaborators Cody Googoo and Luke Mumford. The duo issued the three-song &lt;em&gt;Ungrateful Fucks&lt;/em&gt; tape through the former&amp;#39;s cassette label Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Talk Records. It&amp;#39;s loud, fast, and says all it needs to in under four minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cody&amp;#39;s everywhere these days, performing on recent records from &lt;a href="http://gemstones.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gemstones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://heavenlyblue.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Heavenly Blue&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://mutatedvoid.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mutated Void&lt;/a&gt;, in styles ranging from throwback garage rock to nigh-unlistenable skate thrash. Mumford surfaces more often in a production capacity but has a list of credits that&amp;#39;s just as long. That includes stints with &lt;a href="https://negativerage.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Negative Rage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://geneticangry.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Genetic Angry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://markvodka.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Mark Vodka Group&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://musicbyllc.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;LeDrew, Luke &amp;amp; Crowe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new tape landed the same week that &lt;a href="http://sewerciderecords.limitedrun.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sewercide Records&lt;/a&gt; finally issued the long-awaited split between Googoo&amp;#39;s searing &lt;a href="https://misanthropicmutantmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Misanthropic Minds&lt;/a&gt; and the Finnish hardcore band &lt;a href="https://hapeahardcore.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Häpeä&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;#39;ll hear three new tracks from each band on the 7&amp;quot;, which is shipping now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1365956358/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com/album/ungrateful-fucks"&gt;Ungrateful Fucks by Living Mad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="yesterday_s_man"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yesterday's Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com/album/yesterdays-man" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To date, and without intent, I somehow overlooked every update regarding the Vancouver duo &lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Man&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;ll see if I correct that and can get us up to speed. If you&amp;#39;re of the right age, I suspect you&amp;#39;ll find the band&amp;#39;s deft revival of early-2000s indie pop downright calming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group features Gal Av-Gay of the slacker-punks &lt;a href="https://dumbband.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dumb&lt;/a&gt; paired with their spouse Alie Lynch (&lt;a href="https://allmoonsaresuper.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Supermoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://movieland.bandcamp.com/album/blows-up" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Movieland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://kidnapkids.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Kidnap Kids&lt;/a&gt;). The couple&amp;#39;s played together for years, touring North America a few times with &lt;a href="https://tvugly.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TV Ugly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://megamall.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Megamall&lt;/a&gt;. Both also appeared as members of DJ On&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://nonla.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Non La&lt;/a&gt; act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 12-song self-titled &lt;em&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Man&lt;/em&gt; arrived on New Year&amp;#39;s Day through the &lt;a href="https://monotapes.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mono Tapes&lt;/a&gt; label, delivering what the band describes as &amp;quot;classic indie rock,&amp;quot; the product of years of under-the-radar collaboration (filtered, as all things are, through the trials of the pandemic). The duo self-produced the record, with Dominick Civiero mixing and Greg Mindorff mastering. In the label&amp;#39;s words:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The songs are meant to sound comforting and familiar, while the lyrics evoke the dark inner turmoil and consequential warm relief that comes from isolation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writer Alex Hudson commented on &amp;quot;Fleetwood Mac,&amp;quot; the album&amp;#39;s first single, noting that it &amp;quot;throws back to the golden age of blog-rock without sounding nostalgic.&amp;quot; I couldn&amp;#39;t agree more, and if early-2000s Mint Records holds a place in your heart, you&amp;#39;ll be right at home here. It&amp;#39;s a delight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=949951061/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com/album/yesterdays-man"&gt;Yesterday's Man by Yesterdays Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>controlfreak69</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-01-25-controlfreak69/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-01-25-controlfreak69/</id>
    <published>2025-01-24T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-05T13:26:27-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="gloin"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gloin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;controlfreak69&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/aHW4VlgfoCA?si=8lbHQFlzddCQUvAV" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/album/all-of-your-anger-is-actually-shame-and-i-bet-that-makes-you-angry" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toronto post-punk quartet &lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gloin&lt;/a&gt; recently unveiled their sophomore full-length. The sardonically titled &lt;em&gt;All of your anger is actually shame (and I bet that makes you angry)&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 28 through &lt;a href="https://www.mothland.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mothland&lt;/a&gt;, marking the Montreal psych label&amp;#39;s 50th release. You can preview the twelve-song set through the livewire single &amp;quot;controlfreak69,&amp;quot; accompanied by a curious (and I&amp;#39;d say &lt;em&gt;aggressively&lt;/em&gt; uneventful) new video from director Ryan Faist (aka &lt;a href="https://ohboywonder.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;boy wonder&lt;/a&gt;). Vocalist John Watson sounds impressively frantic over the track&amp;#39;s thumping industrial dance beat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album finds the band further evolving their dense, noisy darkwave  with a newfound embrace of electronic flourishes (Toronto&amp;#39;s Odonis Odonis mined similar territory for a spell). Gloin commented on the improvisational fluidity of their writing process in a press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We wrote the whole album as a collective, influenced by shared experiences. Half was written electronically with usually one person bringing in ideas that we all elaborated on together. We jammed a lot, finding things we liked that we later pieced together, while also saving pieces that we might be able to plug into a future song. One method for a few of the songs was for all of us to write a complete piece, and then switch up instruments.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group recorded with &lt;a href="http://tallies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tallies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Dylan Frankland (Fucked Up, Partner) between Palace Sound and Wychwood Sound, with Phil Demetro mastering in Toronto. Ryan Faist also shot the album&amp;#39;s cover image, which pays homage to the work of the famed New York photographer Gregory Crewdson. The band says it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;inspired by the mundanity of life,&amp;quot; depicting &amp;quot;the middle of nowhere.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gloin features guitarist/vocalist John Watson, bassist/vocalist Victoria Byers, drummer Simon Kou, and Richard Garnham on synths. The new record follows their 2022 LP &lt;em&gt;We Found This&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2057416087/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/album/all-of-your-anger-is-actually-shame-and-i-bet-that-makes-you-angry"&gt;All of your anger is actually shame (and I bet that makes you angry) by Gloin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="population_ii"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Population II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Le thé est prêt&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com/album/maintenant-jamais" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal psych trio &lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Population II&lt;/a&gt; can&amp;#39;t stand still. The band issued two dynamic EPs in 2024 and already have their next full-length on deck. &lt;em&gt;Maintenant Jamais&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 28 through &lt;a href="https://www.bonsound.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bonsound&lt;/a&gt;. You can hear the lead single, &amp;quot;Le thé est prêt,&amp;quot; streaming now. Compared to the noise-punk racket of their recent EP, it&amp;#39;s striking how groovy and refined the band sounds here. The nine-song collection promises an ambitious fusion of the band&amp;#39;s late-60s influences; they cite Soft Machine, the MC5, and the avant-garde Quebecois group L&amp;#39;Infonie in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record finds Population II again working with producer Dominic Vanchesteing (Marie Davidson, Chocolat, Peter Peter), who&amp;#39;s helped focus and refine their approach. He mixed the record with Philippe Roberge, with Pascal Shefteshy mastering. Population II features vocalist/drummer Pierre-Luc Gratton, guitarist/keyboardist Tristan Lacombe, and bassist Sébastien Provençal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album follows a productive few years in which Population II issued their acclaimed sophomore LP &lt;em&gt;Électrons libres du québec&lt;/em&gt; and the decidedly heavier follow-up &lt;em&gt;Serpent Échelle&lt;/em&gt; EP. They capped off 2024 with a collaborative split with the Montreal hardcore group &lt;a href="https://mulchmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mulch&lt;/a&gt;. The thrilling &lt;em&gt;Mulchulation II&lt;/em&gt; split came out in October and remains in near-daily rotation at Some Party HQ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=840746434/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com/album/maintenant-jamais"&gt;Maintenant Jamais by POPULATION II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="swimming"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Swimming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Reports&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;You Smell Like Phys Ed&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Reports&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/UANQFYlMjdI?si=eP46qFuIprJKUXMp" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/track/reports" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St. John&amp;#39;s trio &lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Swimming&lt;/a&gt; continue to deftly channel Midwestern emo on their sophomore full-length. &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt; lands February 21 on vinyl &lt;a href="https://nofuneral.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Funeral Records&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://barelythererecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Barely There&lt;/a&gt; handling the cassette release. You can now hear two advance singles from the ten-song set: &amp;quot;You Smell Like Phys Ed&amp;quot; and the newly unveiled &amp;quot;Reports.&amp;quot; A video for the latter showcases intimate 8mm footage shot by guitarist Liam Ryan during the slow return to live music in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The melancholic &amp;quot;Reports&amp;quot; predates the band, with roots in Liam Ryan and drummer Jacob Cherwick&amp;#39;s college years. The band issued a press release detailing the song&amp;#39;s evolution:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Spending years on the shelf, &amp;#39;Reports&amp;#39; was dusted off and re-worked into what would become one of the band&amp;#39;s strongest pop offerings. The song&amp;#39;s lyrics echo the band members&amp;#39; experience coming of age on the isolated island of Newfoundland while technology reshaped the way the world communicates. On Reports, Swimming surrounds their infectious indie rock melodies with layers of fuzzed out guitars &amp;amp; driving bass, complimented by Cherwick&amp;#39;s angular drumming. The song culminates in a cathartic percussion break set atop a bed of atmospheric shoegaze inspired guitars.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like &amp;quot;Reports,&amp;quot; several songs from the aptly-titled &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt; are refinements of earlier material, some previously heard on the group&amp;#39;s 2019 demo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt; in Newfoundland over two years, with Washington&amp;#39;s Dylan Hanwright (Great Grandpa, Gulfer) mixing and Will Killingsworth (Orchid, Jerome&amp;#39;s Dream) mastering. Swimming features guitarist Liam Ryan, drummer Jacob Cherwick, and bassist Nick Hunt. The new record follows their 2021 debut &lt;em&gt;That&amp;#39;s OK&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=977262591/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/track/reports"&gt;Reports by Swimming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="plastic_act"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Everywhere I Go&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/J6H9Qcfhg-M?si=ez5r6_5M0QChOTDs" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com/album/now" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josh Herlihey&amp;#39;s proto-punk vehicle &lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt; returned this week with their three-song sophomore EP, issued through the Austrian label &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/bachelorrecords/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bachelor Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can stream the Montreal band&amp;#39;s latest everywhere and see the playful A-side, &amp;quot;Everywhere I Go,&amp;quot; showcased in a new video. The clip fittingly marries the song&amp;#39;s nostalgic Velvet Underground vibes with the analog grit of vintage film grain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Plastic Act started as a purely solo affair, this outing finds Herlihey backed by &lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Drew Demers on drums and Chance Hutchison on backing vocals. The band recorded with Adrian Popovich (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/_frvits_/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;FRVITS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;American Lips&lt;/a&gt;) engineering and mixing, with Dave Forcier (&lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Steve Adamyk Band&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://civicivic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;CIVIC&lt;/a&gt;) mastering. &lt;a href="https://packratpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pack Rat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Patrick McEachnie penned liner notes celebrating the release, dubbing it &amp;quot;something you&amp;#39;ve almost heard on a compilation of NY underbelly rock.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Herlihey plays in the Montreal post-punk quartet &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt; alongside Jackie Blenkarn (&lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;), Chance Hutchison, and Drew Demers. Plastic Act&amp;#39;s self-titled debut EP arrived in 2023 through &lt;a href="https://braingumrecords.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Brain Gum Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3958742349/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com/album/now"&gt;Now! by Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="prism_shores"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out From Underneath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/album/out-from-underneath" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Montreal jangle-pop quartet &lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt; unveiled &lt;em&gt;Out From Underneath&lt;/em&gt;, a new full-length issued through Madrid&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://meritoriorec.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Meritorio Records&lt;/a&gt;. The 10-song set delivers a solid blend of lo-fi indie pop, linking strands of Teenage Fanclub, early shoegaze, and the hallowed sounds of genre pillars like the C86 comps and Flying Nun Records.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Album notes at Bandcamp elaborate on the record&amp;#39;s themes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Lyrically, the album tackles young adult ennui and the adjustment of settling in an unfamiliar city, detailing the growing pains experienced during a time of upheaval. It is contemplative and chock-full of emotional depth — a nighttime album that channels self-reflexive melancholy into some form of catharsis.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded primarily with Andrew Woods at Royal Subs, with additional production from Howard Bilerman at Montreal&amp;#39;s Hotel2Tango. Harris Newman mastered at Grey Market. Prism Shores features Jack MacKenzie on guitar and vocals, Ben Goss (&lt;a href="https://poisonspear514.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Poison Spear&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://antibodieschtn.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Antibodies&lt;/a&gt;) on bass, Luke Pound on drums, and Finn Dalbeth on guitar. The album features guest appearances from &lt;a href="https://ktlaine.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;KT Laine&lt;/a&gt; on vocals, Owen Fairbairn on violin, and finds Woods chipping in on a half dozen instruments in the studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows Prism Shores&amp;#39; 2022 LP &lt;em&gt;Inside My Diving Bell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2986837649/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/album/out-from-underneath"&gt;Out From Underneath by Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="fucked_up"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Disabuse&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Listen on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/G1zkDC3L16k?si=jnbgz6l2tQ_t9j1Q" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Purchase from &lt;a href="https://fuckedup.merchtable.com/music/7/disabuse-7/?" class="" target="_blank"&gt;the band&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given how much we used to pour over rumours and fret about their future, I appreciate that we&amp;#39;re now way past the point of &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; having some discernable arc to their career: they&amp;#39;ve swapped the uncertainty and the crush of expectations for an unrelenting drive for &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;. After issuing (give or take) three full-lengths and an assortment of adjuncts in 2024, the Toronto flagbearers kick off 2025 with a new 7&amp;quot; as part of &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop Records&lt;/a&gt; legendary singles series. The vinyl&amp;#39;s set for release on March 14, but you can hear the blistering A-side &amp;quot;Disabuse&amp;quot; now. The track eschews the band&amp;#39;s maximalist tendencies, tapping directly into their punk roots and keeping their experimental tendencies at bay. The label calls them &amp;quot;unlikely light-speed cuts of pure hardcore,&amp;quot; sharing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;These tracks bleed off the record, having been born from the indelible stamp of Poison Idea&amp;#39;s 1990 anti-oppression anthem &amp;#39;Discontent&amp;#39; and Japanese punk legends Paintbox&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;The Door.&amp;#39; Sitting at the chaotic crossroads of punk, hardcore, and grunge.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damian Abraham wrote the A-side for his daughter, grappling with the harm of bullying and intimidation. &amp;quot;Self Driving Man&amp;quot; plays on the flip,  which finds the band wrestling &amp;quot;the out of control automation of our world.&amp;quot; The label is issuing the 7&amp;quot; on emerald vinyl with two cover variants: one in the band&amp;#39;s usual style and one that pays homage to Poison Idea&amp;#39;s 1990 Sub Pop single, &amp;quot;Taken By Surprise.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The release follows a characteristically prolific year that saw Fucked Up issue &lt;em&gt;Another Day&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Someday&lt;/em&gt;, and the limited-to-24-hours experiment &lt;em&gt;Who&amp;#39;s Got The Time &amp;amp; A Half?&lt;/em&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s current lineup features vocalist Damian Abraham, guitarists Mike Haliechuk and Josh Zucker, bassist Sandy Miranda, and drummer Jonah Falco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;div class='aspect-ratio'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G1zkDC3L16k?si=jgnfBjc4vH6r795U" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="pup"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/k11G7mmlz48?si=3O6VRzesMdkEPpdR" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://puptheband.bandcamp.com/track/paranoid" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt; generate their own gravity these days, so I assume my two-week late write-up&amp;#39;s entirely superfluous. I&amp;#39;m a completionist, though, and &amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot; finds the quartet in such fine, angsty form I&amp;#39;d feel remiss for ignoring it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The song, A-side of a self-released 7&amp;quot; available to the band&amp;#39;s fan club, arrived with the latest in PUP&amp;#39;s series of famously ambitious videos. The clip, directed by longtime collaborator Jeremy Schaulin-Rioux, follows the lyrics in real-time as they appear on merch, venue signage, jacket patches, and assorted graffiti scrawled on the walls of Sneaky Dee&amp;#39;s. Don&amp;#39;t be fooled by the vertically oriented phone footage; there&amp;#39;s nothing slapdash here. It&amp;#39;s a dizzying piece featuring several intricate, long shots that must have been a nightmare to choreograph in the legendary Toronto venue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The song finds the group working with the prolific producer John Congleton. In a mailing, Stefan Babcock commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The lyrics are pretty self explanatory on this one, I don&amp;#39;t need to go deep. I will say though, that my favourite part of the song is in the breakdown, I&amp;#39;m screaming some pretty sad shit and Nestor just decided who cares I&amp;#39;m gonna play the melody for &amp;#39;The Lion Sleeps Tonight&amp;#39; over the vocals and that&amp;#39;s fucking funny. I laugh every time I hear it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Congleton, the legend (and our friend, nbd, we hang with legends all the time) produced and recorded this thing at his place in LA. I think I did 3 vocal takes. After the 3rd one I was like &amp;#39;man I sound BAD&amp;#39;, and he was like &amp;#39;perfect, I love when you sound bad, we&amp;#39;re keeping it&amp;#39;. I like John.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot; arrived in a run of 500 records, which I assume are entirely sold out. PUP features vocalist/guitarist Stefan Babcock, guitarist Steve Sladkowski, bassist Nestor Chumak, and drummer Zack Mykula. Their last proper full-length was 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;THE UNRAVELING OF PUPTHEBAND&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1273244095/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://puptheband.bandcamp.com/track/paranoid"&gt;Paranoid by PUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_dirty_nil"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;I Hate The Internet&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;True Devotion&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Listen on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/NWLiqs7JjCw?si=gypzSPqzsrGOd3xq" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise, acolytes of &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; need no reminder from me. The Dundas power trio launched their now-in-progress US tour with a surprise digital release through &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can hear both &amp;quot;I Hate The Internet&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;True Devotion&amp;quot; streaming everywhere now, adored by truly epic cover art from fantasy punk illustrator Rizki Akber (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/eye_dust/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eye Dust&lt;/a&gt;). While the former doesn&amp;#39;t delve too deeply, the chorus voices such a prevailing sentiment that the band&amp;#39;s conceivably written the backing track to a million future Instagram reels. It&amp;#39;s fuel for more Internet, if you get my drift - a content ouroboros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tracks are the Nil&amp;#39;s first originals since issuing &lt;em&gt;Free Rein to Passions&lt;/em&gt; in 2023. The joyfully hedonistic Ontario rock group features vocalist/guitarist Luke Bentham, drummer Kyle Fisher, and bassist Sam Tomlinson.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
