<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter sharing the latest in independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated every Sunday evening by Adam White. Some Party features punk, garage, psych, and otherwise uncategorizable indie rock, drawing lines from proto to post and every weird diversion along the way.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-07-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The New Sincerity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-07-21-the-new-sincerity/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-07-21-the-new-sincerity/</id>
    <published>2019-07-20T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-22T22:15:04-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve got a bad habit of taking song titles and lyrical excerpts, most likely out of context, and using those to buttress whatever half-baked life philosophy I&amp;#39;ve internalized. I drove around Cape Breton, searching for the right moment to propose to my girlfriend to the chorus of Attack In Black&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Northern Towns.&amp;quot; I started this newsletter frustrated with the treadmill of  daily music news to my read of Daniel Romano&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Modern Pressure.&amp;quot; Like so many of my peers, I parsed mantras from the Constantines&amp;#39; &amp;quot;Young Lions&amp;quot; to fit every imaginable purpose. Those are just my on-brand Cancon examples. My teenage years were no better. I&amp;#39;m loath to admit sitting around in a K-car in a St. Catharines mall parking lot, listening to Less Than Jake&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Al&amp;#39;s War&amp;quot; and deciding it spoke precisely to how much we needed to escape the fact that we were sitting around in a K-car in a St. Catharines mall parking lot. Heck, I stocked a produce freezer as a know-it-all 14-year-old while &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m So Bored With the U.S.A.&amp;quot; confirmed my obviously flawless take on mid-90s geopolitics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s &amp;quot;The New Sincerity&amp;quot; feels like one of those songs. I&amp;#39;m not entirely sure what it means, but I am absolutely ready for the new sincerity. Sign me up. Nothing else makes much sense. The tattoo goes here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As for Jimmie&amp;#39;s interpretation, he commented on his website:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Are you ready for The New Sincerity? We&amp;#39;ve released a new single from my forth coming record. Available for streaming here. Essentially, it&amp;#39;s the record&amp;#39;s manifesto. It&amp;#39;s actually a manifesto I wrote for an art history class. I got an A+!!! Hopefully you like it as much as my prof did. The song was inspired by a T-shirt Paul Henderson made for me at a Sackville art party. Thanks Paul. Thanks Post-Post-Modernism. Thanks You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records. Thank you fine listener.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;All clear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The song&amp;#39;s the second single release from the fast-approaching sequel to 2011&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister&lt;/em&gt;, aptly titled &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt;. The album arrives on &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; on Friday, August 2, coinciding with Jimmie&amp;#39;s triumphant return to Sackville, New Brunswick&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; as the Saturday night headliner the following evening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While Jimmie&amp;#39;s regularly released music since that fan-favourite album (most recently &lt;em&gt;Field of Trampolines&lt;/em&gt; in 2016 and the first &lt;a href="https://theheatdeath.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Heat Death&lt;/a&gt; record last year ), the new full length serves as a direct response to that the original &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister&lt;/em&gt;. Jimmie commented earlier that he intended to &amp;quot;recreate the immersive experience of making the original&amp;quot; by working with a full band in a self-contained studio session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This record features Jim Kilpatrick backed by Ryan Peters of &lt;a href="https://ladyhawk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ladyhawk&lt;/a&gt;, Jay Baird of &lt;a href="http://domakesaythink.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Do Make Say Think&lt;/a&gt;, and José Miguel Contreras of &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;. It was recorded and produced by Contreras at The Chat Chateaux in Toronto. The album&amp;#39;s first single &amp;quot;Cool All The Time,&amp;quot; featured a guest monologue from &lt;a href="https://chadvangaalen.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chad VanGaalen&lt;/a&gt;, with the work also featuring instrumentation from the Cons&amp;#39; &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://humanmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Human Music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Cole Woods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="300" height="80" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media" data-src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/2tRbUU73ThEj2m4JxlZUNM" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2tRbUU73ThEj2m4JxlZUNM" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Shotgun Jimmie - &amp;quot;The New Sincerity&amp;quot; @ Spotify (sorry!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;, the Halifax quartet spearheaded by Noel Macdonald (&lt;a href="http://moonhalifax.tumblr.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Moon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://longweekends.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Long Weekends&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://donlovely.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Don Lovely&lt;/a&gt;) has a new single online titled &amp;quot;Act of War.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the band&amp;#39;s first follow-up to their 2018 full-length &lt;em&gt;Walk It Back&lt;/em&gt;, which saw Macdonald establish an indie rock sound heavily influenced by 80s new wave and college rock, taking queues from classics like The Smiths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Washing Machine features Macdonald on guitar and vocals backed by members of the astonishingly interconnected Halifax heavy music scene: guitarist Dylan Chew (&lt;a href="https://unrealthought.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Unreal Thought&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://frailhands.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Frail Hands&lt;/a&gt;), bassist Cody Googoo (&lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://alienation902.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Alienation&lt;/a&gt;), and drummer Tom Burke (&lt;a href="https://kingsgirls.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;King&amp;#39;s Girls&lt;/a&gt;, Frail Hands).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=914935222/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/track/act-of-war"&gt;Act of War by Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/track/act-of-war" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Washing Machine - &amp;quot;Act of War&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto avant-pop artist &lt;a href="https://scotthardware.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Scott Hardware&lt;/a&gt; has signed with &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; for a new album due in 2020. While still untitled, the record has a debut single out now in the form of &amp;quot;Bound Together.&amp;quot; The new track combines acoustic instrumentation with the electronic effects Hardware&amp;#39;s spent the past few years iterating on. The song was recorded live off the floor with Carlyn Bezic (of the synthpop duo &lt;a href="http://ice-creamtheband.tumblr.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt;) and Simone Tisshaw-Baril (Darlene Shrugg, Fake Palms, Partner) as his rhythm section. &lt;a href="https://deidre999.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deidre Nox&lt;/a&gt; provides backing vocals on the track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Bound Together&amp;quot; is Hardware&amp;#39;s first new release since 2016&amp;#39;s full-length &lt;em&gt;Mutate Repeat Infinity&lt;/em&gt;. Scott commented on the sweeping, cinematic new direction explored in the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Originally the new music was supposed to be house-inspired but I wanted to take out the drums and move towards the emotional core of dance music without a beat distracting. It still references Detroit electro and house in smaller ways, while scratching my itch to be able to write songs that were timeless enough be played with one instrument and one voice (and also incorporate my love for meta experimental music, production-wise.)&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Scott Hardware&amp;#39;s been a long-running member of the Toronto music community, with roots in the experimental Kensington Market-based psych group &lt;a href="https://ostrichtuning.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ostrich Tuning&lt;/a&gt;. He started recording solo in 2013 while living in Berlin, experimenting with drum machines as &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/scotthardware/sets/ken-park-you-think-about-it" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ken Park&lt;/a&gt;. Relocating back to Toronto in 2015, Hardware pushed into dance music with &lt;em&gt;Mutate Repeat Infinity&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;quot;Bound Together&amp;quot; seems to show a new synthesis of these often divergent ventures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/652760204&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/telephoneexplosion/bound-together-master-1" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Scott Hardware - &amp;quot;Bound Together&amp;quot; @ Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week at Punknews, I premiered a new song from Toronto&amp;#39;s up and coming three-piece &lt;a href="https://pacerto.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pacer&lt;/a&gt;. Their stand-alone single &amp;quot;Rapture&amp;quot; sounds absolutely exuberant, which is surprising given it was conceived in the wake of a psychotic episode suffered by lead vocalist Shawn Kosmo. The trio, which features Kosmo on vocals and guitar backed by bassist Dan Pearce and drummer Evan Matthews, draws from 80s college rock and 70s proto-punk, with a particular love for the Replacements and Pixes shining through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The press release digs into the band&amp;#39;s spin on the potentially touchy subject matter driving the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Rapture&amp;quot; is a song about psychosis and mental health, but instead of channeling the weight of the topic, the group seeks to tap into their exuberant side to purge the demons. The song sheds the stigma of discussing mental health by channeling that energy in the studio and on stage. Shaw n&amp;#39;s lived experiences with mental health disorders has challenged him to find a way to explore new avenues for coping with difficult subjects. If he can&amp;#39;t talk about them, then he&amp;#39;ll sing about them at the top of his lungs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;...As a band with a queer-identifying frontman, Pacer also believes that the future of rock and roll is bright for those who aren&amp;#39;t straight or gender conforming.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pacer last released the digital singles &amp;quot;Bangers&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Piledriver&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;Lose,&amp;quot; both of which can be found at &lt;a href="http://pacerto.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;. Before stepping into the spotlight with Pacer, you may have encountered Shawn Kosmo&amp;#39;s work as a video director, having put together clips for bands like PONY, Twist, and Tommy and the Commies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3510664849/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pacerto.bandcamp.com/track/rapture"&gt;Rapture by Pacer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/70332/torontos-pacer-get-cathartic-on-new-single-rapture" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Pacer - &amp;quot;Rapture&amp;quot; @ Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sydney J. Koke, bassist for Vancouver indie-pop trio &lt;a href="https://thecourtneys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Courtneys&lt;/a&gt; and prolific experimental punk group &lt;a href="https://shearingpinx.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shearing Pinx&lt;/a&gt;, has a new solo recording available. Released under the so-ridiculous-it&amp;#39;s-amazing stage-name &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/slaylormoon/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slaylor Moon&lt;/a&gt;, the song &amp;quot;Mothgirl&amp;quot; finds Koke unleashing an eerie electronic soundscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The song&amp;#39;s part of a new 7-song EP to be released by &lt;a href="http://www.mapledeathrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Maple Death Records&lt;/a&gt; as a limited-run cassette with hand-made art. The release, titled &lt;em&gt;Zone Of Pure Resistance&lt;/em&gt;, will be Koke&amp;#39;s first solo release. It arrives this Friday, July 26.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The label strung together a truly epic string of wild adjectives when describing this one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Scientist of the brain turned scientist of psychic soundscapes, Sydney Koke (Shearing Pinx/The Courtneys), Strasbourg via Vancouver artist, specialises in a form of queer, spooky, and dislocated electronic abstraction assembled from the disparate substrates of early 2000s experimental electronic music, old school rave, 70s industrial, no wave, and noise rock: a dorky cyborg symbiosis of polyhedral no-tempo MPC rhythms, flickering future tones of marine microorganism holographic glimmer, and intimately vague spacer-woman vocals delivered with cold intention, generating an ultraviolet personal microcosm of queer sexuality, formalist aesthetics, and multi-directional emotive imaginals – a volatile exploratory spectrum with a consistent sense of (developing) identity and curiosity.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1508796402/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=3313374173/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mapledeathrecords.bandcamp.com/album/zone-of-pure-resistance"&gt;Zone Of Pure Resistance by Slaylor Moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://mapledeathrecords.bandcamp.com/track/mothgirl" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Slaylor Moon - &amp;quot;Mothgirl&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I lead with Vancouver hardcore group &lt;a href="https://chainwhip.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chain Whip&lt;/a&gt; in last week&amp;#39;s newsletter, and since then they&amp;#39;ve shared a new pair of &lt;em&gt;14 Lashes&lt;/em&gt; tracks. You can preview the songs &amp;quot;On a Rope&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Talk&amp;quot; over at &lt;a href="https://chainwhip.bandcamp.com/album/14-lashes" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve of course been bullish on this record, but don&amp;#39;t take my word for it. Here&amp;#39;s what Fucked Up&amp;#39;s Jonah Falco had this to say about &lt;em&gt;14 Lashes&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Like a door opening to an alternate universe where Suburban Mutilation released the most influential hardcore LP of the 80s, and DOA were conveniently disappeared so the melody cum velocity and Richard Nixon-esque gargle of Joey Shithead could be reimagined in the various voids of the Twenty-teens as tidy new hc punk lp by CHAIN WHIP. Not fast enough to only be brutal, but not modest enough to be anything but pummelling. Full of burly, crunchy, tight corners, this is the musical equivalent of thrifting an Eames chair -- you recognize it a mile away, it&amp;#39;s still a classic, and it&amp;#39;s just landed in our laps for next to nothing.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Chain Whip is Josh Nickel of &lt;a href="https://fashionism.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fashionism&lt;/a&gt; (and the &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste&lt;/a&gt; label) on vocals, Joel Butler of &lt;a href="https://nervoustalk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nervous Talk&lt;/a&gt;/Corner Boys on guitar, Brett Thompson of &lt;a href="https://stresseating.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stress Eating&lt;/a&gt; on bass, and Patrick Bertrand of &lt;a href="https://cornerboys.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Corner Boys&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="http://www.hoseheadrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hosehead Records&lt;/a&gt;) on drums. A European release of the LP has been slated for &lt;a href="https://sabotagerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sabotage Records&lt;/a&gt; sometime later this year. The digital version arrives everywhere on August 31.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1589867902/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2736482408/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chainwhip.bandcamp.com/album/14-lashes"&gt;14 Lashes by Chain Whip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://chainwhip.bandcamp.com/track/on-a-rope" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chain Whip - &amp;quot;On a Rope&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto jangle-pop quartet &lt;a href="http://ducksunlimitedband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ducks Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; are preparing an EP for release later this year. Last week the band dropped a preview in the form of &amp;quot;Get Bleak,&amp;quot; a track featuring guest vocals from Laura Hermiston of &lt;a href="https://www.twistofficial.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Twist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lead vocalist Tom Mcgreevy spoke to &lt;a href="https://www.pastemagazine.com/articles/2019/07/exclusive-ducks-unlimited-new-single-get-bleak.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paste&lt;/a&gt; about the new track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Get Bleak is a song about this idea that moving somewhere else is going to solve all your problems. It&amp;#39;s something that I&amp;#39;ve heard expressed by a lot of friends in one way or another, especially as more and more people are getting priced out of cities like Toronto, New York and London. There can be plenty of good reasons to leave the place that you&amp;#39;re from or somewhere you&amp;#39;ve made your home for a long time, but I think there&amp;#39;s this &amp;#39;grass is always greener&amp;#39; thing that in my experience, and anecdotally from people I know, just isn&amp;#39;t true. It&amp;#39;s hard to move to a new place, and you&amp;#39;re still going to be you when you get there with the same issues and hang-ups, plus you&amp;#39;re going to miss the people who care about you, and they&amp;#39;re going to miss you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=193437734/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ducksunlimitedband.bandcamp.com/track/get-bleak-single"&gt;Get Bleak (single) by Ducks Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://ducksunlimitedband.bandcamp.com/track/get-bleak-single" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Ducks Unlimited - &amp;quot;Get Bleak&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Thousand Islands Records&lt;/a&gt; have signed Edmonton skate-punk act &lt;a href="http://loserpoints.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Loser Points&lt;/a&gt;. The label will be home to the band&amp;#39;s upcoming third LP. &amp;quot;Tribes&amp;quot; is the first single from that currently untitled set, and you can preview it online now. If you were into that classic-era Fat Wreck roster from the mid-90s, this should bring back plenty of warm SoCal memories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Loser Points last released the full-length &lt;em&gt;Denial &amp;amp; Error&lt;/em&gt; in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3193780104/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://loserpoints.bandcamp.com/track/tribes"&gt;Tribes by Loser Points&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://loserpoints.bandcamp.com/track/tribes" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Loser Points - &amp;quot;Tribes&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Kitchener&amp;#39;s dynamic indie-pop/shoegaze quartet &lt;a href="https://hyness.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hyness&lt;/a&gt; has a wealth of new material online. First, they&amp;#39;ve collected their recent &amp;quot;Shame&amp;quot; single with three other tracks, releasing them online together as the &lt;em&gt;RIVER&lt;/em&gt; EP. One of those recordings is a rendition of &amp;quot;Molly&amp;#39;s Lips,&amp;quot; the Vaselines song that Nirvana famously covered. Hyness latest material was recorded, mixed, and mastered by Joe Shugan at the Starlight Social Club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Shame&amp;quot; first surfaced back in January, but the catchy power-pop tune&amp;#39;s getting another push with a new video by director Erik O&amp;#39;Neill. You can check it out over at YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hyness features guitarist/vocalist Amy Addams, drummer Colin White, guitarist/vocalist Marcus Addams, and bassist Dan Honsberger. Back in January Hyness took part in a split 7&amp;quot; with St. Catharines fuzz-pop act &lt;a href="https://strangeshakes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Strange Shakes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=377888339/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://hyness.bandcamp.com/album/river-ep"&gt;RIVER EP by Hyness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://hyness.bandcamp.com/album/river-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Hyness - &lt;em&gt;RIVER&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J_6kJLkEjZA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/J_6kJLkEjZA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Hyness - &amp;quot;Shame&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto indie-pop group &lt;a href="http://nylonspirit.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nylon Spirit&lt;/a&gt; has a new song online titled &amp;quot;Dumb For U.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the young group&amp;#39;s second song after their laid-back alt-rock debut, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m Bored.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Nylon Spirit features Norman Regucera, Matt Tomasi, Noah Aviles-Betel, and Chris Creglia. Regucera and Tomasi previously played together in the stoner rock group &lt;a href="https://acidpriest.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Acid Priest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3267524908/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://nylonspirit.bandcamp.com/track/dumb-for-u"&gt;Dumb For U by Nylon Spirit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://nylonspirit.bandcamp.com/track/dumb-for-u" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Nylon Spirit - &amp;quot;Dumb For U&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Following several months of previews, &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt; has finally detailed the debut solo full length from &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt; lead Drew Thomson. &lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Drew Thomson Foundation&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s debut will be self-titled and is set for a September 6 release. With the confirmation came another new single, &amp;quot;Phone Ring.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A complete contrast from the high-stress, often acidic punk of Single Mothers, the Foundation lets Drew show off some considerable pop songwriting chops. These two worlds aren&amp;#39;t being kept entirely separate though, as the former&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;People are Pets&amp;quot; has been reworked on this album as a Rufus Wainwright-styled piano ballad. Thomson worked on the record with producer Alex Newport at his Los Angeles studio (Pissed Jeans, City and Colour, Frank Turner).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thomson&amp;#39;s recent sobriety factors heavily into the record. He commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;By drinking a decade away, I also pushed away a lot of people close to me. People had been telling me to quit for years and I never listened to them. You really have to want to get sober and believe it&amp;#39;s for the best. I don&amp;#39;t ask anyone else in the band to avoid drinking, but if I have one or two I slip back into that other world, so I just avoid it completely. It&amp;#39;s been a huge benefit. I write more, I work better, I&amp;#39;m less reactive, and easier to be around. I just have to handle self-doubt on my own. I don&amp;#39;t want to base everything I do around sobriety, but it&amp;#39;s been the biggest thing in my life lately, and made everything with the Foundation possible.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This record follows up The Drew Thomson Foundation&amp;#39;s 2018 EP &lt;em&gt;Stay&lt;/em&gt;, as well as the recent Single Mothers record &lt;em&gt;Through a Wall&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-x1GN25y1ag" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/-x1GN25y1ag" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Drew Thomson Foundation - &amp;quot;Phone Ring&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Winnipeg garage rock/psych quartet &lt;a href="https://holyvoidband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Holy Void&lt;/a&gt; will release their debut full-length at the end of the month through &lt;a href="http://www.transistor66.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Transistor 66&lt;/a&gt;. Titled &lt;em&gt;Naught&lt;/em&gt;, the 8-song record was recorded over the last two years at Winnipeg&amp;#39;s Exchange District Studios. The group, featuring Grant Trippel, Michael Henderson-Castle, Danny Hacking, and Kyle Loewen, made efforts to avoid digital tech for these sessions, recording to the album to 2&amp;quot; tape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band recently donned their most satanic togas for the &amp;quot;Covered in Blood&amp;quot; video. Shot and edited by Delf Gravert, the clip premiered at the &lt;a href="https://www.cupsncakespod.com/news/2019/7/19/video-premiere-holy-void-covered-in-blood" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cups N Cakes Network&lt;/a&gt; alongside the band&amp;#39;s latest tour dates. Their trek supporting &lt;em&gt;Naught&lt;/em&gt; will bring them throughout Ontario and as far east as Montreal, with the group returning home for a set at Manitoba&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.rainbowtroutmusicfestival.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Rainbow Trout Music Festival&lt;/a&gt; later in August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/otYWKdQ708Y" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/otYWKdQ708Y" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Holy Void - &amp;quot;Covered in Blood&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HawaiiCBM</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-07-14-hawaiicbm/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-07-14-hawaiicbm/</id>
    <published>2019-07-13T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-16T09:31:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://chainwhip.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chain Whip&lt;/a&gt; recently shared the first track from their upcoming full-length &lt;em&gt;14 Lashes&lt;/em&gt;, premiering the fast and tough &amp;quot;HawaiiCBM&amp;quot; over at &lt;a href="https://www.noecho.net/features/chain-whip-14-lashes" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Echo&lt;/a&gt;. Picking up where their EP left off, the new material finds the band digging deep into some classic hardcore sounds, marrying the punch of the early Californian scene and some combative UK influences. The group brings together Josh Nickel of &lt;a href="https://fashionism.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fashionism&lt;/a&gt; (and the &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste&lt;/a&gt; label) on vocals, with Joel Butler of &lt;a href="https://nervoustalk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nervous Talk&lt;/a&gt;/Corner Boys on guitar, Brett Thompson of &lt;a href="https://stresseating.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stress Eating&lt;/a&gt; on bass, and Patrick Bertrand of &lt;a href="https://cornerboys.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Corner Boys&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="http://www.hoseheadrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hosehead Records&lt;/a&gt;) on drums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Chain Whip recorded this set with Braden Decorby, who previously worked on their EP. Daniel Husayn mixed and mastered the new material at the North London Bomb Factory. The record arrives on August 5.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking to No Echo, the band commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We wrote &amp;#39;HawaiiCBM&amp;#39; after the technological glitch of January 13th, 2018, when everyone on the island received cell-phone alerts that a missile attack was imminent on American soil. I kept on thinking about the ridiculous amount of influence that some people have to expose our fragility. I also kept thinking about what it must have been like to say &amp;#39;Oh oops. Sorry. — my mistake. No missile coming.&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;So many people fetishize these moments. Like &amp;#39;Bring it on!&amp;#39; kind of stuff and I think that&amp;#39;s such stupid posturing. Still, it&amp;#39;s probably better to die in a nuclear holocaust than through the slow destruction of climate change I guess. Still, I&amp;#39;d like to try and enjoy some more of my time here.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This week a handful of additional songs from &lt;em&gt;14 Lashes&lt;/em&gt; are set to premiere, with one destined to surface right here at Some Party. I&amp;#39;ll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/647185101&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/josh-nickel-366733816/chain-whip-hawaiicbm" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chain Whip - &amp;quot;HawaiiCBM&amp;quot; @ SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Celebrated electronic duo &lt;a href="http://atribecalledred.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;A Tribe Called Red&lt;/a&gt; returned last week with a powerful new single titled &amp;quot;The OG,&amp;quot; which features DJs Tim &amp;quot;2oolman&amp;quot; Hill and Ehren &amp;quot;Bear Witness&amp;quot; Thomas collaborating with &lt;a href="http://www.blackbearsingers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Bear&lt;/a&gt;, a group of Pow Wow singers and drummers from Manawan, Quebec.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The song was inspired by, and features audio samples of, Cree lawmaker Romeo Saganash speaking to the House of Commons. Last September, while debating the future of the Trans Mountain Pipeline, the NDP MP, took Prime Minister Justin Trudeau to task using some infamously colourful language:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;When the prime minister says that this pipeline expansion will be done no matter what, and his minister adds that Canada will not be able to accommodate all Indigenous concerns, what that means is that they have decided to willfully violate their constitutional duties and obligations...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Mr. Speaker, sounds like a most important relationship, doesn&amp;#39;t it? Why doesn&amp;#39;t the prime minister just say the truth and tell Indigenous peoples that he doesn&amp;#39;t give a fuck about their rights?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Saganash represents the Abitibi—Baie-James—Nunavik—Eeyou riding, which encompasses much of northern Quebec. In a statement Bear Witness commented on that event:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;It would be impossible to overstate the impact that Romeo Saganash&amp;#39;s words had on the Indigenous world and on us personally. We feel that the stand he took that day in parliament needs to be remembered, memorialized and commemorated. This is a celebration of that moment. Romeo, the Halluci Nation salutes you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A Tribe Called Red last released &lt;em&gt;We Are The Halluci Nation&lt;/em&gt; in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zgsuWSxs1fw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/zgsuWSxs1fw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: A Tribe Called Red - &amp;quot;The OG&amp;quot; (featuring Black Bear) @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week the enigmatic Toronto songwriter Ben Cook unveiled more music from his upcoming &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt; record, &lt;em&gt;GUV 1&lt;/em&gt;. He shared the track &amp;quot;Roll With Me,&amp;quot; a song that label &lt;a href="http://www.runforcoverrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover Records&lt;/a&gt; described as &amp;quot;a 100% certified rocker&amp;quot; akin to &amp;quot;Elliott Smith power pop.&amp;quot; You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;GUV 1&lt;/em&gt; is due to arrive on August 2 from Run For Cover. The 8-song set, which follows up 2018&amp;#39;s heavily stylized &lt;em&gt;2 Sad 2 Funk&lt;/em&gt;, will serve as the first in a two-album series, with its counterpart due in the fall. Ben Cook&amp;#39;s, of course, well known for his more aggressive outings, be it as the frontman of the Toronto hardcore unit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt; or as one of the many moving parts that comprise the critically acclaimed &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3776892109/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://youngguv.bandcamp.com/album/guv-i"&gt;GUV I by Young Guv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://youngguv.bandcamp.com/album/guv-i" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Young Guv - &amp;quot;Roll With Me&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Amiable Montreal pop-punks &lt;a href="https://lostlove.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lost Love&lt;/a&gt; have a new two-song single online via Germany&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://uncle-m.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Uncle M Records&lt;/a&gt;. The set features the tracks &amp;quot;Glenn Spaghetti Legs&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Ontarien Demandé,&amp;quot; both of which were recorded during the sessions that resulted in last year&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Good Luck Rassco&lt;/em&gt; LP. The former seems to be a reference to when Glenn Danzig was knocked out by North Side Kings singer Danny Marianinho. Remember that? The Internet most certainly does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Good Luck Rassco&lt;/em&gt; came out on May 25 via &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt; and the French label &lt;a href="http://guerilla.limitedrun.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Guerilla Asso&lt;/a&gt;. It followed up the band&amp;#39;s 2016 album &lt;em&gt;Comfortable Scars&lt;/em&gt;. These new tracks were mixed by Kyle McAulay and mastered by Ryan Schwabe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lost Love is slated to play &lt;a href="https://beaus.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beau&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.beausoktoberfest.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oktoberfest&lt;/a&gt; this September in Vankleek Hill, Ontario. They&amp;#39;ll play the punk-focused Black Forest Stage alongside bands like &lt;a href="https://mobinagalore.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mobina Galore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://thepenskefileband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Penske File&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://audiovisceralvkh.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Audio Visceral&lt;/a&gt;. Across the fairgrounds, the event&amp;#39;s main stage will feature the Vancouver indie-rock supergroup &lt;a href="http://www.thenewpornographers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The New Pornographers&lt;/a&gt; headlining on Friday, with Toronto hip-hop luminary &lt;a href="https://www.shadk.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shad&lt;/a&gt; closing the shindig on Saturday night. The music festival&amp;#39;s a significant charitable fundraiser in the region as well, bringing in over $711,000 since 2009 for local causes. Some Party&amp;#39;s a co-sponsor of the Black Forest Stage this year, which is really just an excuse for me to plant myself in the nexus of awesome that forms between that stage, the half-pipe, and the bar. Oktoberfest runs September 20 and 21.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3568855595/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://unclem.bandcamp.com/album/glenn-spaghetti-legs"&gt;Glenn Spaghetti Legs by Lost Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://unclem.bandcamp.com/album/glenn-spaghetti-legs" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Lost Love - &lt;em&gt;Glenn Spaghetti Legs&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This week I had the privilege of sharing the haunting, grungy new single from Toronto&amp;#39;s low-fi duo &lt;a href="https://low--sun.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Low Sun&lt;/a&gt;. The band, self-described as &amp;quot;post-industry / loser rock,&amp;quot; are a week away from the release of their new EP, the appropriately-titled &lt;em&gt;New/Shiny&lt;/em&gt;. That record arrives on July 20 from &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt; on cassette.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;New/Shiny&lt;/em&gt; is Low Sun&amp;#39;s follow-up to their 2017 drone-rock album &lt;em&gt;Reservoir of Impermanent Light&lt;/em&gt;. While the tour supporting that record brought the band through Eastern Europe, Japan, and Hong Kong, that momentum didn&amp;#39;t make the follow-up any easier. The group spent 8 months with a new bass player, only to lose them just before another European tour, this time supporting Czech hardcore band DNO. Out of necessity Low Sun was reborn as a duo, rewrote their EP from the ground up, and started this, their second life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Low Sun features the brothers Peter and Robert Johnson, who together run Art of the Uncarved Block (&lt;a href="https://mildewmildew.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mildew Mildew&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://madelink.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PAX&lt;/a&gt;) and previously played together as Shahman. When asked about &amp;quot;Cold Light and a Fare,&amp;quot; the band commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I don&amp;#39;t remember much, but I remember it being the end of something. I recall the light more than anything. And the feeling. That feeling that sticks to you like the humidity that makes the walls sweat.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Low Sun will launch the tape with a pair of shows next weekend. They&amp;#39;ll play &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/353502888697541/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Weekend At Bernie&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; in their hometown alongside Milwaukee&amp;#39;s Large Print, Toronto power-pop act &lt;a href="http://www.prettymatty.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pretty Matty&lt;/a&gt;, and Blankscreen on July 20. The next day they&amp;#39;ll be in Ottawa with Large Print for a show at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/381471695813556/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pressed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/607648560&amp;amp;color=%232d2123&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true" class="lazyload"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/70296/low-sun-shares-cold-light-and-a-fare-schedules-release-shows-in-toronto-and-ottawa" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Low Sun - &amp;quot;Cold Light and a Fare&amp;quot; @ Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Matty Grace&lt;/a&gt; recently premiered the first track from her upcoming solo record, a song titled &amp;quot;Connaught//Chebucto.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s due to be part of an EP titled &lt;em&gt;Rumination Year&lt;/em&gt;, which is expected sometime later in the year. The song features production, mixing, mastering, and additional instrumentation from Dave Williams of &lt;a href="https://crusades666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crusades&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://surrendersounds.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Surrender&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Grace has played in several Halifax-based punk and hardcore groups over the years, a list that includes the &lt;a href="https://fatstupids.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fat Stupids&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://weekenddads.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Weekend Dads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Outtacontroller&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://cutie902.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cutie&lt;/a&gt;. Her main band &lt;a href="https://futuregirls.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Future Girls&lt;/a&gt; last released the full-length &lt;em&gt;Motivation Problems&lt;/em&gt; in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Future Girls are slated to play the inaugural edition of Ottawa&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/sidebysidewknd/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Side by Side Weekend&lt;/a&gt; on the last weekend of July, sharing the Saturday night stage at Black Squirrel Books with &lt;a href="https://bbqtband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BBQT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://thethrill613.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Thrill&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://panicattack.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Panic Attack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1943390729/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/track/connaught-chebucto"&gt;Connaught//Chebucto by Matty Grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/track/connaught-chebucto" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Matty Grace - &amp;quot;Connaught//Chebucto&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Side By Side will also see an appearance by local punk outfit &lt;a href="http://flaws613.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flaws&lt;/a&gt;, a trio made up from former members of &lt;a href="https://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Tenenbaums&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://muelkik.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Muelkik&lt;/a&gt;. The group recently released a 7 song set at Bandcamp titled &lt;em&gt;Rose&lt;/em&gt;. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Flaws will play the Thursday night stage at Black Squirrel with &lt;a href="https://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WLMRT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://nushu.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nüshu&lt;/a&gt;, and Bug Bites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Side by Side runs from July 25 through the 28th at the nearby venues &lt;a href="https://www.blacksquirrelbooks.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Squirrel Books&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.houseoftarg.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;House of TARG&lt;/a&gt;. The event will feature performances from bands like the &lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Adamyk Band&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://dboyintl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dboy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://cellfromthegrave.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CELL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lifeinvacuum.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Life In Vacuum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://bonniedoon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonnie Doon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://joncreeden.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jon Creeden &amp;amp; The Flying Hellfish&lt;/a&gt; among others. Some Party and Punknews.org are giving away a pair of weekend passes to the festival this week, so if you want in on that make sure you &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/S4H9j78ZKoW4Jz4d7" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;enter the draw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1076473148/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flaws613.bandcamp.com/album/rose"&gt;rose by Flaws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://flaws613.bandcamp.com/album/rose&amp;quot;" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Flaws - &lt;em&gt;Rose&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The irreverent Ottawa &amp;quot;pop-punk gang&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://necktunes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;NECK&lt;/a&gt; play classic punk rock that pairs Dead Milkmen style snark with a healthy dose of Ramones worship. I&amp;#39;ve had the trio&amp;#39;s brisk new 10-song LP in my hands for a few months, and it&amp;#39;s a blast. While &lt;em&gt;You Don&amp;#39;t Think It&amp;#39;s Evil...&lt;/em&gt; technically arrived in April on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/uncledrecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Uncle D Records&lt;/a&gt; it didn&amp;#39;t show up online until this past week. You can check it out now at Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;You Don&amp;#39;t Think It&amp;#39;s Evil...&lt;/em&gt;  follows up NECK&amp;#39;s 2015 LP &lt;em&gt;Hate To Read&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2958174483/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://necktunes.bandcamp.com/album/you-dont-think-its-evil"&gt;You Don't Think It's Evil by NECK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://necktunes.bandcamp.com/album/you-dont-think-its-evil" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Neck - &lt;em&gt;You Don&amp;#39;t Think It&amp;#39;s Evil...&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Halifax-bred indie rock act &lt;a href="https://mauno.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mauno&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online, showcasing their latest single &amp;quot;Take Care.&amp;quot; The track&amp;#39;s set to appear on the band&amp;#39;s upcoming full-length &lt;em&gt;Really Well&lt;/em&gt;, due August 2 from &lt;a href="https://tinangelrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tin Angel Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In a statement Eliza Niemi commented on the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Take Care&amp;#39; is a play on words — it&amp;#39;s about caregiving as a woman, and also about saying goodbye. It is about filling the role of taking care of someone and self-identifying through that, while simultaneously resenting the expectation of having to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The chorus begins hinting at waiting for a relationship to finally feel reciprocal, and ends with the reveal of me actually waiting for it to fall apart / knowing all along that it was doomed.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The record finds Niemi and co-vocalist Nick Everett splitting songwriting duties across 11 new tracks that the four-piece recorded at &lt;a href="https://chadvangaalen.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chad VanGaalen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Yoko Eno studio. They&amp;#39;re following up their 2017 &lt;a href="http://ideefixerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Idée Fixe&lt;/a&gt; release &lt;em&gt;Tuning&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band will unleash &lt;em&gt;Really Well&lt;/em&gt; while making an appearance at &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; in Sackville, New Brunswick. They join a slate of performers this year that includes &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lalforest.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;LAL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://thenoisymountain.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WHOOP-Szo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://snottynoserezkids.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Snotty Nose Rez Kids&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theweatherstation.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Weather Station&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://haviahmighty.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Haviah Mighty&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://apolloghosts.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Apollo Ghosts&lt;/a&gt;. Sappy runs from August 2 to the 4th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JkWtXbL3WbY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/JkWtXbL3WbY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Mauno - &amp;quot;Take Care&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Three-piece Toronto pop-punk act &lt;a href="https://sixteenscandals.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sixteen Scandals&lt;/a&gt; have a new single online titled &amp;quot;Middle C.&amp;quot; The hooky track serves as the irreverent trio&amp;#39;s first new material to surface in the wake of their 2017 EP &lt;em&gt;Dorkmanteau&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;d be a safe bet to expect it as part of their sophomore full-length when it arrives in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://aestheticmagazinetoronto.com/2019/07/11/exclusive-premiere-stream-sixteen-scandals-new-single-middle-c/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Aesthetic Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, the band commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Middle C&amp;#39; is all about getting stuck in a job or relationship that makes you miserable, but feels too comfortable to leave. Most of us are so busy just trying to make rent, or staring at our phones all night to realize that our lives are caught in this cycle of suck. The drive to find purpose or some sort of meaning within our current socio-economic climate is a recurring theme in our music.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The video, a &lt;em&gt;Fight Club&lt;/em&gt; parody, was shot by Josh Bradford of Silverstein. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SISI9m9Ikcg" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SISI9m9Ikcg" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Sixteen Scandals - &amp;quot;Middle C&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dunville, Ontario indie rock quartet &lt;a href="https://donvail.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Don Vail&lt;/a&gt; have a new video online for &amp;quot;Institutionalized,&amp;quot; the second single from the band&amp;#39;s new album &lt;em&gt;Stand of Tide&lt;/em&gt;. The clip was directed by Justis Krar of &lt;a href="https://www.immvproductions.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;IMMV Productions&lt;/a&gt;. The group commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s probably the closest thing to a pop song we&amp;#39;ve ever done, and we love it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Don Vail&amp;#39;s been around for almost a decade as the solo recording vehicle of Mitch Bowden. This record finds the project fleshed out to a full four-piece band featuring drummer Victor Malang, guitarist Matthew Fleming, and keyboardist/vocalist Kori Pop. &lt;em&gt;Stand of Tide&lt;/em&gt; is Don Vail&amp;#39;s first record since 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Fades&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8KA8pimgTxA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/8KA8pimgTxA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Don Vail - &amp;quot;Institutionalized&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In the midst of their headlining UK tour, &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt; have a new single out titled &amp;quot;Metropolis.&amp;quot; In a statement frontman Drew Thomson revealed that the song actually predates the band&amp;#39;s most recent full-length, 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Through A Wall&lt;/em&gt;, explaining:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Metropolis&amp;#39; was recorded just before Through A Wall at Lincoln County Social Club in Toronto, Ontario. It’s a collaboration between Peter Landi and myself. I had recently moved apartments and my old landlord had sold the building we lived in and kicked everyone out. There was a real estate boom and we were all seemingly in the middle of it. Peter came to me with the song and once we were in the studio the lyrics came right away. I was just venting. A few years before I was living in my van. Sometimes it takes all the energy you have just to keep the lights on.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Through a Wall&lt;/em&gt; was released on &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="http://www.bsmrocks.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Big Scary Monsters&lt;/a&gt; overseas. Drew&amp;#39;s spent much of this year teasing the upcoming full-length from his solo pop-rock vehicle &lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Drew Thomson Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, which is expected in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MmQ5oFkx6kc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/MmQ5oFkx6kc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Single Mothers - &amp;quot;Metropolis&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://bruce-peninsula.com/2016/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bruce Peninsula&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://mishabower.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Misha Bower&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for the song &amp;quot;Trying to Have it All,&amp;quot; the title track to her recent debut solo album. It was filmed by Travis Welowszky at the Western Fair in London, Ontario. Bower commented on how the setting resonated:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The bigger ride, the better prize, the chance that life will deliver an experience that quenches desire once and for all.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trying to Have It All&lt;/em&gt; was co-produced by Bower and Will Kidman of the &lt;a href="https://theconstantines.wordpress.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Constantines&lt;/a&gt;, with Kidman also playing guitar and keys as a member of her studio band. That group featured Cons bassist Dallas Wehrle along with &lt;a href="https://royalcity.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal City&lt;/a&gt; drummer Nathan Lawr, backing vocalist Lisa Conway, and strings from Mika Posen, Kelly Larochette, Jill Sauerteig, and Julia Narveson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kT-rxIgDY2w" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/kT-rxIgDY2w" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Misha Bower - &amp;quot;Trying to Have It All&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://neckingband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Necking&lt;/a&gt; has a video online featuring &amp;quot;Big Mouth,&amp;quot; the lead single from their recently released &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt; debut, &lt;em&gt;Cut Your Teeth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In an earlier interview with Exclaim, drummer and lyricist Melissa Kuipers commented on the song, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Big Mouth&amp;#39; is the dollar store version of &amp;#39;Our Lips are Sealed&amp;#39; by the Go-Go’s covered by Hilary and Haylie Duff. It’s about having a mediocre time with someone and them leaving convinced you’re obsessed with them. This song is the brave face you put on after you’ve overshared and overstayed your welcome.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can check the &lt;a href="http://www.justingradin.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Justin Gradin&lt;/a&gt; directed video below (Gradin was behind some memorable recent work for &lt;a href="http://autogramm.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://lievancouver.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lié&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Necking features vocalist Hannah Kay, bassist Sonya Rez, guitarist Nada Hayek, and the above-mentioned Melissa Kuipers. &lt;em&gt;Cut Your Teeth&lt;/em&gt; was recorded with producer Jesse Gander (Needles//Pins, Japandroids, White Lung).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZKnnKZUpqRA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ZKnnKZUpqRA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Necking - &amp;quot;Big Mouth&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://crgillespie.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;C.R. Gillespie&lt;/a&gt;, bassist of the Toronto noise-punk band &lt;a href="https://greys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Greys&lt;/a&gt;, has a new collection of ambient/synthpop experiments out on cassette. Titled &lt;em&gt;Tlön&lt;/em&gt;, it arrives on the Metachroma Currency Ltd label. &lt;em&gt;Tlön&lt;/em&gt; follows a 2017 release from Gillespie titled &lt;em&gt;Séance Works&lt;/em&gt;. These new songs were all written, recorded, mixed, and mastered solo by Colin at the Glass Home in Toronto between June of 2017 and this past December.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Greys released &lt;em&gt;Age Hasn&amp;#39;t Spoiled You&lt;/em&gt;, their third full length, earlier this year on &lt;a href="http://carparkrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Carpark Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=174822376/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://crgillespie.bandcamp.com/album/tl-n"&gt;Tlön by C.R. Gillespie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://crgillespie.bandcamp.com/album/tl-n" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: C.R. Gillespie - &lt;em&gt;Tlön&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://beckyninkovic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Becky Ninkovic&lt;/a&gt; of the Abbotsford, BC dance-punk group &lt;a href="https://yousayparty.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You Say Party&lt;/a&gt;, has a solo record on the way titled &lt;em&gt;Woe&lt;/em&gt;. It arrives on August 23 from &lt;a href="http://paperbagrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paper Bag Records&lt;/a&gt;, preceded by the new single and video for &amp;quot;The Carrier.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Woe&lt;/em&gt; has its roots in tragedy, stemming from the 2010 death of You Say Party drummer Devon Clifford, who suffered a fatal brain hemorrhage on stage in Vancouver while performing with the now-defunct group. The press-release delves into the difficult journey Ninkovic&amp;#39;s been on since:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;From that devastating moment, Becky found herself deep in a mental health crisis triggered by trauma and grief. &lt;em&gt;Woe&lt;/em&gt; is a collection of songs that share in ache and loss: loss of her band family, loss of a clear identity, loss of an old belief system, loss of her body transformed through motherhood and loss of life. The process took many years. Wordless melodies and beats gestated through time, though they were never intended for public release, the songs somehow pushed their way to the surface. Finally, Becky began to develop a sense of resiliency, hope for her artistic process — and for life itself-through therapeutic work, motherhood and the process of recording her new album.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A pair of BC shows have been confirmed in support of the album, July 25 in Abbotsford at the &lt;a href="https://jaminjubilee.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jam In Jubilee&lt;/a&gt; festival and August 24 in New Westminister. The performances are to feature a backing choir and multi-media elements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jq3oIDw9b4I" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Jq3oIDw9b4I" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Becky Ninkovic - &amp;quot;The Carrier&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto garage-rock trio &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheMooksTO" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Mooks&lt;/a&gt; have a new video online for &amp;quot;Not Around,&amp;quot; one of the six tunes from their recent EP &lt;em&gt;I Hope That You Feel The Same.&lt;/em&gt; Chris Brown directed the clip for the cooly restrained, retro-minded song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Mooks recorded their new EP with Calvin Hartwick at Dreamhouse Studios in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n_DAWY7QM_Q" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/n_DAWY7QM_Q" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Mooks - &amp;quot;Not Around&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve yet to write much about raucous Ottawa punk group &lt;a href="https://liquidassets.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Liquid Assets&lt;/a&gt;, and outside of a two-song November demo there hasn&amp;#39;t been much yet to share. Last week a well-recorded live video surfaced of the group, capturing the quartet&amp;#39;s entire set at Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/acoolmove/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;A Cool Move&lt;/a&gt; festival (they&amp;#39;re on stage at La Vitrola). You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PEnJuVhOsJE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/PEnJuVhOsJE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Liquid Assets live at A Cool Move 2019 @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moody Stables</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-07-07-moody-stables/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-07-07-moody-stables/</id>
    <published>2019-07-06T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-08T21:35:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You may recall &lt;a href="https://bedwettersanonymous.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bedwetters Anonymous&lt;/a&gt;, the high-strung BC punk band behind the excellent (and strangely titled) February release &lt;em&gt;R.U. EXPERIENCING DISCOMFORT (?)&lt;/em&gt;. I found Bedwetters through a write-up from the Vancouver scene report &lt;a href="https://www.neonwaste.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Waste&lt;/a&gt;. In Josh Nickel&amp;#39;s piece, he rattled off a half dozen related groups, bands local enough that I didn&amp;#39;t recognize any of them but a treasure trove of threads to follow. I took the names down and socked them into one of the messy research documents I keep to feed future newsletters. The most enigmatic entry on that list of those was, by far &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://codyellen.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Industrial Priest Overcoats&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; a name that either shallowly betrayed the band&amp;#39;s genre or a swerve setting up further mysteries. It&amp;#39;s the latter, and their new record came to light last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Industrial Priest Overcoats is the solo recording project of Trevor McEachran, who sings and plays bass in Bedwetters. A member of the Splatsin Nation, McEachran describes his new record as &amp;quot;10 tracks of intergenerational trauma, identity crises, and recovery.&amp;quot; Titled &lt;em&gt;The Years Barely Left a Trace&lt;/em&gt;, the set expresses those themes through heavily Wire-influenced post-punk, punctuated by that same warbling, urgent vocals that made the &lt;em&gt;DISCOMFORT&lt;/em&gt; tape feel so immediate. Home-recorded, weirdo-pop records like these always carry a ton of personality, but they can suffer from a lack of direction, jumping wildly from idea to idea before any can really settle in. As a whole, IPO&amp;#39;s lengthy catalogue isn&amp;#39;t immune from that, but Trevor&amp;#39;s choice of subject matter (touching on his history of mental illness and homelessness from an indigenous perspective) grounds these songs with some needed emotional weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A cassette release of &lt;em&gt;The Years Barely Left a Trace&lt;/em&gt;, along with an accompanying comic are due later this year. This album follows a four-song EP of covers released back in May and the 2018-released full-length &lt;em&gt;Self Esteem Junction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3202169077/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://codyellen.bandcamp.com/album/the-years-barely-left-a-trace"&gt;The Years Barely Left a Trace by INDUSTRIAL PRIEST OVERCOATS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://codyellen.bandcamp.com/album/the-years-barely-left-a-trace" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Industrial Priest Overcoats - &lt;em&gt;The Years Barely Left a Trace&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A new piece up at &lt;a href="https://www.ottawashowbox.com/2019/06/new-music-compassion-fatigue-by-ornaments/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Showbox&lt;/a&gt; profiles &lt;em&gt;Compassion Fatigue&lt;/em&gt;, the recent 6-song EP from the Ottawa three-piece &lt;a href="http://ornamentsband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ornaments&lt;/a&gt;. The band trades in muscular garage rock with some melodic punk influences, crafting slow-building anthems that, when paired with David Pierce&amp;#39;s growling vocals, are going to stir up more than a few Constantines comparisons. As Showbox points out, the ear-worm intro to the album-opening single &amp;quot;Like Men&amp;quot; is rather memorable. Don&amp;#39;t let this one slip by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Released in mid-June, &lt;em&gt;Compassion Fatigue&lt;/em&gt; features guitarist/vocalist Pierce with drummer Kevin Kozachanko and bassist Andrew Grosvenor. The new EP was recorded, mixed, and mastered by Mike Bond at Wolf Lake Studios and The Bond Cave (Mike recorded the latest Steve Adamyk Band LP). Outside of the two-song &amp;quot;Comearound&amp;quot; single from 2017, this EP serves as Ornaments&amp;#39; first new material since their full-length &lt;em&gt;Blood Vessels&lt;/em&gt; from all the way back in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1916668936/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ornamentsband.bandcamp.com/album/compassion-fatigue"&gt;Compassion Fatigue by Ornaments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://ornamentsband.bandcamp.com/album/compassion-fatigue" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Ornaments - &lt;em&gt;Compassion Fatigue&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ottawa peace-punk four-piece &lt;a href="https://dogmapeacepunk.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dogma&lt;/a&gt; has a new song online as well. Titled &amp;quot;Zealot,&amp;quot; it&amp;#39;s the first preview of the band&amp;#39;s next release (whatever that may be) and their first studio material to follow the 2018 demo EP that served as their debut. It should be evident from their cover art (not to mention their sound) that Dogma&amp;#39;s working directly and faithfully from the Crass-inspired anarcho playbook. Dogma sounds so vital and almost joyfully punk here that the hero worship doesn&amp;#39;t bother me one bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=777076797/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dogmapeacepunk.bandcamp.com/album/zealot"&gt;Zealot by Dogma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://dogmapeacepunk.bandcamp.com/album/zealot" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Dogma - &amp;quot;Zealot&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Dartmouth folk-rock/shoegaze group &lt;a href="http://diamondtown.bandcamp.com/album/the-voice-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Diamondtown&lt;/a&gt; has a new EP online, combining their recent digital singles with unreleased new material as &lt;em&gt;The Voice&lt;/em&gt;. The group&amp;#39;s an extension of &lt;a href="https://husbandknife.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Husband &amp;amp; Knife&lt;/a&gt;, a duo featuring KC Spidle of the beloved Halifax indie-rock group &lt;a href="http://dogdaymusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dog Day&lt;/a&gt; and Evan Cardwell. Diamondtown builds on that foundation with the addition of Kate O&amp;#39;Neill and &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/artists/erics_trip" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Eric&amp;#39;s Trip&lt;/a&gt; member / Moonsocket soloist Chris Thompson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking to &lt;a href="http://www.theeastmag.com/2019/07/02/new-music-diamondtown-weigh-your-life-against-time-with-the-voice/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The East&lt;/a&gt; about the new collection, Spidle commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I think everything I write stems back to my Christian upbringing, lots of spiritual conflict, and existential confusion that comes out. It&amp;#39;s a subconscious creative journey I go on when writing lines... I believe the conflict is a bit more personal, just a certain traditional mindset that I always try to shake and I do it pretty successfully, I think.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Voice&lt;/em&gt; follows the band&amp;#39;s late-2018 debut, &lt;em&gt;Life Goes On&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Diamondtown will be among the performers at this year&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; in Sackville, New Brunswick. Running from August 2 to 4, the event will also feature the likes of &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://snottynoserezkids.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Snotty Nose Rez Kids&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theweatherstation.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Weather Station&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://haviahmighty.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Haviah Mighty&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://apolloghosts.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Apollo Ghosts&lt;/a&gt;. Tying all these threads together, I should note that last year&amp;#39;s festival saw a reunion set from Dog Day, while this year will see a solo performance from &lt;a href="https://juliedoiron.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Julie Doiron&lt;/a&gt; (who, of course, also got her start as a member of Eric&amp;#39;s Trip).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1486151688/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://diamondtown.bandcamp.com/album/the-voice-ep"&gt;The Voice EP by Diamondtown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://diamondtown.bandcamp.com/album/the-voice-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Diamondtown - &lt;em&gt;The Voice&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of Sappy performers, Montreal&amp;#39;s soulful home-recording savant &lt;a href="https://www.yvesjarvis.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yves Jarvis&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for the song &amp;quot;360.&amp;quot; The track appears on &lt;em&gt;The Same but by Different Means&lt;/em&gt;, which arrived this past March on &lt;a href="http://www.flemisheye.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flemish Eye&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="http://www.anti.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;ANTI-&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Yves Jarvis is the latest stage name for Jean-Sebastian Audet. He previously recorded as Un Blonde, releasing the critically-lauded &lt;em&gt;Good Will Come to You&lt;/em&gt; back in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xyl_Gf0T7-Q" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Xyl_Gf0T7-Q" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Yves Jarvis - &amp;quot;360&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Windsor, Ontario&amp;#39;s three-piece noise rock band &lt;a href="http://cellos.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cellos&lt;/a&gt; is set to appear on a split 7&amp;quot; with the Toronto noise-punk duo &lt;a href="https://notof.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Not Of&lt;/a&gt;. That record&amp;#39;s due on July 19 from &lt;a href="http://nolistrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No List Records&lt;/a&gt; and Harbour House. Each band is contributing three new songs to the project, and you can take a listen to Cellos&amp;#39; scathing &amp;quot;Blight&amp;quot; below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In support of the new record the bands will pair up for a couple release shows, first in Toronto on July 19 at the Baby G (with Lilim) and then the following day in Montreal at Turbo Haus with Look Sacré and Like Swamps. On July 27 Cellos will play an album release party for the Kitchener space-rock group &lt;a href="http://hawkeyesdoom.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hawkeyes&lt;/a&gt; at the Starlight in Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2169873256/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://cellos.bandcamp.com/album/cellos-not-of-split"&gt;Cellos/Not Of Split by Cellos/Not Of&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://cellos.bandcamp.com/album/cellos-not-of-split" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Cellos - &amp;quot;Blight&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lethbridge, Alberta garage rock / &amp;quot;tropical glam&amp;quot; act &lt;a href="https://jblissette.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;J Blissette&lt;/a&gt; has a new song online titled &amp;quot;Burn It To The Ground (All These People Have Families).&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the second single of the year from the group, following &amp;quot;Relax&amp;quot; back in February. It&amp;#39;s part of a series of digital singles released in the wake of the band&amp;#39;s 2018 &lt;a href="http://www.pleasencerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pleasence Records&lt;/a&gt; full-length &lt;em&gt;Until I Go Blind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new track features frontman Jackson Tiefenbach on all instruments save the percussion, with drums provided by Clayton Smith. The band also notes &amp;quot;that one really hard guitar part&amp;quot; in the tune was played by Jon Martin. Martin recorded and mixed the song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=933434396/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://jblissette.bandcamp.com/track/burn-it-to-the-ground-all-these-people-have-families"&gt;Burn It To The Ground (All These People Have Families) by J Blissette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://jblissette.bandcamp.com/track/burn-it-to-the-ground-all-these-people-have-families" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: J Blissette - &amp;quot;Burn It To The Ground (All These People Have Families)&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;After fronting the post-punk/low-fi pop bands &lt;a href="https://mosslimer.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Moss Lime&lt;/a&gt; and Phern, Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://helenebarbier.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hélène Barbier&lt;/a&gt; is striking out solo. Her first LP under her own name, &lt;em&gt;Have You Met Elliott?&lt;/em&gt;, is due this Friday from &lt;a href="http://michelrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Michel Records&lt;/a&gt; (VICTIME, Bleu Nuit). The first single from that set was &amp;quot;The Good Thing,&amp;quot; which arrived alongside a video in May by director Katayoon Yousefbigloo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking to &lt;a href="https://exclaim.ca/music/article/montreals_h_l_ne_barbier_premieres_new_album_have_you_met_elliott" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;, where you can now stream the record in its entirety, Barbier commented on her recording process:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;​&amp;quot;I got a soundcard from my friends and started recording songs at home alone, thinking about the childish behaviours we sometimes hold onto as adults. The songs started turning into an album, and I got the opportunity to record with Peter Woodford again. &lt;em&gt;Have you met Elliott?&lt;/em&gt; is a reminder that, as my friend&amp;#39;s sister once told them when they were a child, &amp;#39;You can&amp;#39;t just cry to have candies.&amp;#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you met Elliott?&lt;/em&gt; was recorded to tape at the Bottle Garden (Tough Age, Bleu Nuit) and mixed at Value Sound. The album features Barbier on guitar, bass, organ, and vocals, with Christian Simmons on drums. In the studio they brought in guitarists Joe Chamandy, Emma Coldwell, and Matt Robidoux, with Elise Paradis appearing on violin. While Michel&amp;#39;s handling the Canadian release, the new album will arrive on Emotional Response in the U.S. and Caballito Records in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9rwMIpQYS0U" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/9rwMIpQYS0U" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Hélène Barbier - &amp;quot;The Good Thing&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://camfraser.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cam Fraser&lt;/a&gt; shows up in this newsletter quite a bit, being both the bassist for Toronto art-punks &lt;a href="https://hugeluge.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Luge&lt;/a&gt; and the guitarist/vocalist for the low-fi alt-country act &lt;a href="https://hobbytoronto.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hobby&lt;/a&gt;. He recently recorded and released a new solo set, a six-song collection titled &lt;em&gt;Sew&lt;/em&gt;. You can find it at Bandcamp now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This is the second recent EP from Fraser, with the singer/songwriter&amp;#39;s contemplative &lt;em&gt;All The World&amp;#39;s A Dream&lt;/em&gt; surfacing back in January of this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=59969086/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://camfraser.bandcamp.com/album/sew"&gt;Sew by Cam Fraser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://camfraser.bandcamp.com/album/sew" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Cam Fraser - &lt;em&gt;Sew&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Low-fi Ottawa indie rock act &lt;a href="https://emptynesters.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Empty Nesters&lt;/a&gt;, the solo studio project of Eric Liao, has another new track online following the May-released &amp;quot;Hippie Drip.&amp;quot; The new song, titled &amp;quot;Duster 2,&amp;quot; can be streamed at Bandcamp. This new material follows Liao&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Tired and Bored&lt;/em&gt; EP from this past February.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3746884070/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://emptynesters.bandcamp.com/track/duster-2"&gt;Duster 2 by Empty Nesters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://emptynesters.bandcamp.com/track/duster-2" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Empty Nesters - &amp;quot;Duster 2&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Guelph&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://onedimensionalband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bullshit Hardcore Band&lt;/a&gt; announced a hiatus a few weeks ago, described by the enigmatic duo as a &amp;quot;redirection of our subversive efforts to other outlets.&amp;quot; In the wind-down, the group&amp;#39;s been making an effort to share their previously unreleased recordings. The first of these was a punk record titled &lt;em&gt;Marksism&lt;/em&gt;, which arrived a few weeks ago. The latest release in this series is the second EP from the group&amp;#39;s dub alter-ego, the Bullshit Dub Soundsystem. Titled &lt;em&gt;No Gods. No Masters. No Treble&lt;/em&gt;, the new set comes with a warning:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;GB and LS made this in Dec &amp;#39;18 with 4-track tape, a reverb pedal, and a rigged up tape delay. CAUTION - the amount of low end on these recordings may shred your speakers - you&amp;#39;ve been warned.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This is the second Dub Soundsystem set following that side project&amp;#39;s debut in April of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2773681502/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://onedimensionalband.bandcamp.com/album/bullshit-dub-soundsystem-no-gods-no-masters-no-treble"&gt;bullshit dub soundsystem - No Gods.  No Masters.  No Treble by Bullshit Hardcore Band&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://onedimensionalband.bandcamp.com/album/bullshit-dub-soundsystem-no-gods-no-masters-no-treble" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bullshit Dub Soundsytem - &lt;em&gt;No Gods. No Masters. No Treble&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://anamaimusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;ANAMAI&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s the atmospheric, minimalist folk project from Anna Mayberry (formerly of Toronto sludge punks &lt;a href="https://hsy666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;HSY&lt;/a&gt;) and David Psutka (of &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/egyptrixx" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Egyptrixx&lt;/a&gt;). The duo recently released &amp;quot;The Holder,&amp;quot; their first new track in a few years, at Bandcamp. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;ANAMAI last released the full-length &lt;em&gt;What Mountain&lt;/em&gt; in 2017. There&amp;#39;s been no word yet on where &amp;quot;The Holder&amp;quot; will land or when a new album may arrive. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=848563634/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://anamaimusic.bandcamp.com/album/the-holder"&gt;The Holder by ANAMAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://anamaimusic.bandcamp.com/album/the-holder" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: ANAMAI - &amp;quot;The Holder&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tube Reducer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-06-30-tube-reducer/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-06-30-tube-reducer/</id>
    <published>2019-06-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-03T12:48:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;For better or worse, the &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt; willfully operate outside the usual PR cycle, and while we knew that &lt;em&gt;Tube Reducer&lt;/em&gt;, their third full-length, was coming this summer, Friday&amp;#39;s arrival still felt like a surprise. With no fanfare and little in the way of pre-release hype, the Halifax punk group quietly shared the 15-song record online at Bandcamp, with a vinyl release not due until late August (it seems like even the band&amp;#39;s label is caught playing catch-up on this one). Booji Boys&amp;#39; stubborn sense of DIY is part of their charm though. They operate almost hyper-locally with a whiff of nostalgia for the mailorder days and a less incessantly online life (Bandcamp aside, don&amp;#39;t go looking for this on your streaming platform of choice). Sonically, &lt;em&gt;Tube Reducer&lt;/em&gt; finds the band playing true to form, once again delivering thrillingly blown-out recordings and barely intelligible vocals with subversively hooky songwriting somehow tying all that chaos together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tube Reducer&lt;/em&gt; follows up the band&amp;#39;s 2017 Christmas release &lt;em&gt;Weekend Rocker&lt;/em&gt; and their self-titled debut from earlier that year (both on Drunken Sailor). Along with an occasional home-dubbed cassette, the band&amp;#39;s also issued a pair of EPs of the past year years, 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Sweet Boy&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://www.cruelnoiserecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cruel Noise Records&lt;/a&gt; and the more recent &lt;em&gt;Unknown Pleathers&lt;/em&gt; 7&amp;quot; on Sewercide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band&amp;#39;s lineup once again features vocalist Alex Mitchell with guitarists Cody Googoo and Steve Earle, bassist Adam LeDrew, and drummer Justin Crowe. They recorded &lt;em&gt;Tube Reducer&lt;/em&gt; at Paul&amp;#39;s Hall in Glen Haven, Nova Scotia back in February, with LeDrew behind the boards in the studio and spearheading the mix. Luke Mumford of &lt;a href="https://negativerage.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Negative Rage&lt;/a&gt; mastered the album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="http://sewerciderecords.blogspot.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sewercide&lt;/a&gt;, the label recently announced that they were beginning work on a 7&amp;quot; compilation of east coast Canadian punk and hardcore. Look for it to feature new and exclusive material from the Booji Boys as well as the Charlottetown punk groups &lt;a href="https://antibodieschtn.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Antibodies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://warsh.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warsh&lt;/a&gt;, Halifax D-beat hardcore acts &lt;a href="https://fragmentpunk.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fragment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://cutie902.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cutie&lt;/a&gt;, Misanthropic Minds (Cody with his &lt;a href="https://alienation902.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Alienation&lt;/a&gt; bandmate Dave Brown), and B.P.S. (another shuffling of many of the personnel mentioned above). Sewercide commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;While it&amp;#39;s no surprise to us that the DIY punk/hardcore community here has been producing some incredible bands over the years, many haven&amp;#39;t been getting the attention they deserve internationally and some don&amp;#39;t even get the opportunity to release a record... this will be a small snapshot of what&amp;#39;s been going on with punk in our corner of the world and the first time a lot of these bands will be on vinyl.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That record, limited to 300 copies, should be out later this year. &lt;em&gt;Tube Reducer&lt;/em&gt; arrives on wax in late August from &lt;a href="http://www.drunkensailorrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drunken Sailor Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=760568684/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/album/tube-reducer"&gt;Tube Reducer by Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/album/tube-reducer" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Booji Boys - &lt;em&gt;Tube Reducer&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto art-punks &lt;a href="https://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WLMRT&lt;/a&gt; have unleashed their first full-length project, a 10-song cassette titled &lt;em&gt;WLMRT Forever&lt;/em&gt;. You can check the audio now on &lt;a href="http://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/album/wlmrt-forever" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; or snag one of the physical copies at the fast-approaching release show on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/904228303256681/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;July 6&lt;/a&gt; at the Monarch Tavern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://tallies.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tallies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Stephen Pitman produced the new record, with &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Steve Sidoli mastering. WLMRT features lead vocalist Shelby Wilson, bassist/vocalist Kat Mcgouran, guitarist Adam Bernhardt, drummer Alex Wood, and Ryan Hage on synths. The album includes several guests appearances, with &lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt; of Halifax indie-rock act &lt;a href="https://mauno.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mauno&lt;/a&gt; and Matt Post of Ottawa noise duo &lt;a href="https://buysomedeathsticks.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deathsticks&lt;/a&gt; among them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This is, without doubt, the best WLMRT&amp;#39;s sounded on record, and they&amp;#39;ve achieved that without losing the wild spontaneity that got our attention in the first place. The group&amp;#39;s dry, sardonic lyrics, which spill out in a frenzied stream of consciousness from Wilson as the band roils along, are as thrilling as ever. The five-piece is following up their 2018 &lt;a href="http://www.pleasencerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pleasence Records&lt;/a&gt; EP &lt;em&gt;Lube 2&lt;/em&gt; with this set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Later this month the band will headline a stage at the inaugural &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/377555466159265/permalink/380792492502229/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Side by Side Weekend&lt;/a&gt; in Ottawa, playing &lt;a href="https://www.blacksquirrelbooks.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Squirrel Books&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, July 25 with Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://nushu.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nüshu&lt;/a&gt; and locals &lt;a href="https://flaws613.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flaws&lt;/a&gt; and Bug Bites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3632858689/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/album/wlmrt-forever"&gt;WLMRT Forever by WLMRT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/album/wlmrt-forever" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: WLMRT - &lt;em&gt;WLMRT Forever&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;WLMRT&amp;#39;s sharing that July 6 release show with two bands, the similarly off-kilter punk group &lt;a href="https://imhughman.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hugh Man&lt;/a&gt; (celebrating their latest EP, &lt;em&gt;Hughs Man is it Anyway?&lt;/em&gt;), and the return of the hardcore quartet &lt;a href="http://sigil.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sigil&lt;/a&gt;. The latter features vocalist Bria Salmena and drummer Kris Bowering, both of the band &lt;a href="https://frigsmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FRIGS&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href="http://ytstlabs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yamantaka // Sonic Titan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Brandon Lim and Erik Jude of &lt;a href="https://deliluh.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deliluh&lt;/a&gt;. The group&amp;#39;s 9-song full-length, titled &lt;em&gt;Slow Ulcer&lt;/em&gt;, will arrive on cassette for the show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sigil&amp;#39;s been kicking around for a few years now, stemming from a time when Lim and Jude both played as part of the dark-as-hell sludge punk outfit &lt;a href="https://hsy666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;HSY&lt;/a&gt;. The DNA of that band&amp;#39;s pretty evident here, with &lt;em&gt;Slow Ulcer&lt;/em&gt; sounding absolutely caustic. Salmena trades the measured and moody vibes of the recent FRIGS record for a thrashing, throat-shredding growl here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3082932268/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://sigil.bandcamp.com/album/slow-ulcer"&gt;SLOW ULCER by SIGIL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://sigil.bandcamp.com/album/slow-ulcer" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Sigil - &lt;em&gt;Slow Ulcer&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Spirited Saint John rock group &lt;a href="http://papalvisit.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Papal Visit&lt;/a&gt; released a live EP last week. Titled &lt;em&gt;Prepare for Your Reversal&lt;/em&gt;, the set was recorded this past March in their hometown. Founded initially as a long-distance recording project by vocalist Adam Mowery and bassist Pierre Cormier (when the former had relocated to Halifax), the band&amp;#39;s live lineup has gone through several incarnations. This show, in particular, featured guitarists Chris Braydon and Jason Ogden with drummer Geoffrey Smith. From that group, I&amp;#39;m told, you can connect family tree limbs to a good majority of the city&amp;#39;s musical output. This 6-song set features an assortment of cuts from across the band&amp;#39;s discography, including their most recent full-length, 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Golden Grove&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Papal Visit&amp;#39;s among the performers slated for this year&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; in Sackville, New Brunswick. Running from August 2 to 4, the event will also feature the likes of &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://snottynoserezkids.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Snotty Nose Rez Kids&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theweatherstation.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Weather Station&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://haviahmighty.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Haviah Mighty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.yvesjarvis.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yves Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://apolloghosts.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Apollo Ghosts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2280282262/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://papalvisit.bandcamp.com/album/prepare-for-your-reversal-live-in-saint-john"&gt;Prepare For Your Reversal - Live in Saint John by PAPAL VISIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://papalvisit.bandcamp.com/album/prepare-for-your-reversal-live-in-saint-john" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Papal Visit - &lt;em&gt;Prepare for Your Reversal&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto synthpop duo &lt;a href="http://ice-creamtheband.tumblr.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt; has a new single out titled &amp;quot;Peanut Butter&amp;quot; with an accompanying video by director Miss World (aka Natalie Chahal). In a statement the band&amp;#39;s Carlyn Bezic commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wrote &amp;#39;Peanut Butter&amp;#39; about a man I served when I was bartending, who thought that ordering an expensive scotch meant he could treat me and my coworkers like dirt. That interaction felt like a microcosm of the world at large: that those with the most power and the most money are, underneath it all, spoiled babies. Peanut butter is a stand-in for their values, getting slathered on everything from the messy hands of a child, leaving us to clean it up.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ice Cream features Bezic and Amanda Crist. The new track was produced by Tony Price, with Steve Chahley mixing and engineering. Ice Cream&amp;#39;s debut full-length, &lt;em&gt;Love, Ice Cream&lt;/em&gt;, came out back in 2016. It was followed by the &amp;quot;Dial Tone&amp;quot; single a year later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XVWRTLJeDZo" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XVWRTLJeDZo" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Ice Cream - &amp;quot;Peanut Butter&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week saw a new song surface from &lt;a href="http://organeyes.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Organ Eyes&lt;/a&gt;, the Ottawa-based recording project lead by Cam Steacy. The track, a slow-burning post-punk tune titled &amp;quot;Once Bitten,&amp;quot; was written and recorded in the same sessions that resulted in 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Chasing Paper&lt;/em&gt; full-length.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=65699720/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://organeyes.bandcamp.com/track/once-bitten"&gt;Once Bitten by Organ Eyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://organeyes.bandcamp.com/track/once-bitten" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Organ Eyes - &amp;quot;Once Bitten&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Keeping with the ocular theme, Toronto&amp;#39;s synth-heavy noise-punk outfit &lt;a href="https://eyeballsmusic.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Eyeballs&lt;/a&gt; have a new two-song single online, featuring the songs &amp;quot;Weightlifting&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Woke Up Like This.&amp;quot; These tracks mark the band&amp;#39;s first recordings since 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Bad Art&lt;/em&gt; full-length, with &amp;quot;Weightlifting&amp;quot; due for an upcoming EP titled &lt;em&gt;Fun Hell&lt;/em&gt;. Eyeballs feature Jenn Kitagawa on vocals, synth and drums, and Britton Proulx on all of those plus the bass. &amp;quot;Weightlifting&amp;quot; also features the mononymous Koko on vocals (and a Korg Kaossilator synth, to be very specific). The group recorded their new stuff with Asher Gould-Murtagh (ZONES, Beliefs).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3870848666/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://eyeballsmusic.bandcamp.com/album/weightlifting-woke-up-like-this"&gt;Weightlifting / Woke Up Like This by Eyeballs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://eyeballsmusic.bandcamp.com/album/weightlifting-woke-up-like-this" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Eyeballs - &amp;quot;Weightlifting&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Canada Day saw the release of &lt;em&gt;Upper Canada Blues&lt;/em&gt;, the third full-length in recent months from the prolific &lt;a href="https://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew &amp;quot;Doc&amp;quot; Dunn&lt;/a&gt;. The new set follows two solo records the Toronto-based artist released in fast succession in late-2018, &lt;em&gt;Lightburn&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;See Horses Run&lt;/em&gt;. Like those albums, &lt;em&gt;Upper Canada Blues&lt;/em&gt; funds Dunn playing jammy psych-rock with early-70s Americana vibes. These recordings feature Dunn backed by &lt;a href="https://www.jamesmatthewvii.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;James Matthew VII&lt;/a&gt; (of No Warning, fka Blind Matty) and Brian Tysoe. They were recorded last summer by Tony Price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The album arrives alongside a Laura-Lynn Petrick-directed video for the song &amp;quot;Ribbons,&amp;quot; featuring dancer Nyda Kwasowsky. The clip premiered last week at &lt;a href="https://nowtoronto.com/music/doc-dunn-wlmrt-daniel-caesar/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;NOW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dunn&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://yousgirls.blogspot.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Girls&lt;/a&gt;-backing psych-jazz combo &lt;a href="http://thecosmicrange.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Cosmic Range&lt;/a&gt; recently released &lt;em&gt;The Gratitude Principle&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://ideefixerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Idée Fixe Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h3z7NUOzios" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/h3z7NUOzios" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Matthew &amp;#39;Doc&amp;#39; Dunn - &amp;quot;Ribbons&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3212866665/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/album/upper-canada-blues"&gt;UPPER CANADA BLUES by Matthew 'Doc' Dunn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://cosmicrangerecords.bandcamp.com/album/upper-canada-blues" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Matthew &amp;#39;Doc&amp;#39; Dunn - &lt;em&gt;Upper Canada Blues&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;80s-flavoured Vancouver power-pop trio &lt;a href="http://autogramm.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt; has a new single out titled &amp;quot;Bad Day,&amp;quot; available from Spain&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://jarama45rpmrecs.bandcamp.com/album/bad-day" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Spain&amp;#39;s Jarama 45RPM Recs&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s backed by the b-side &amp;quot;Quiero Estar Sedado,&amp;quot; a Spanish language cover of the Ramones classic &amp;quot;I Wanna Be Sedated.&amp;quot; These new tracks were recorded and mixed at the Balloon Factory by Joshua Wells and mastered at the North London Bomb Factory by Daniel Husayn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Autogramm features Jiffy Marx of Hard Drugs and &lt;a href="https://bloodmeridiancanada.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Blood Meridian&lt;/a&gt; on vocals, guitar and synth, the globetrotting CC Voltage (of Berlin&amp;#39;s Dysnea Boys, London&amp;#39;s Loyalties, and BC acts Spitfires and &lt;a href="https://theblackhalos.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Black Halos&lt;/a&gt;) on bass, and The Silo, previously of Black Mountain, Lightning Dust, and Destroyer, on drums. The new music follows the band&amp;#39;s 2018 full-length &lt;em&gt;What R U Waiting 4?&lt;/em&gt;, which arrived last fall on &lt;a href="http://www.nevadomusic.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nevado Music&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=914997937/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://autogramm.bandcamp.com/album/bad-day-quiero-estar-sedado"&gt;Bad Day / Quiero Estar Sedado by Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://autogramm.bandcamp.com/album/bad-day-quiero-estar-sedado" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Autogramm - &amp;quot;Bad Day&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Quiero Estar Sedado&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Popular Toronto punk quartet &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for the &lt;em&gt;Morbid Stuff&lt;/em&gt; song &amp;quot;Sibling Rivalry.&amp;quot; Martin MacPherson directed and animated the piece based on drawings and stories by frontman Stefan Babcock. The visuals chronical Babcock annual camping trips with his sister, along with their escalating and dysfunctional quest to &amp;quot;out-dumb each other.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 11-song &lt;em&gt;Morbid Stuff&lt;/em&gt; was recorded at the Union Sound Company last spring with producers Dave Schiffman (Thrice, The Bronx) and Darren McGill. It saw a release earlier this year on Rise Records in the States and the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.littledipperart.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Little Dipper&lt;/a&gt; imprint in Canada. The album, the group&amp;#39;s third, was recently voted onto the Polaris Music Prize long list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WFzMJtsMbfw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/WFzMJtsMbfw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: PUP - &amp;quot;Sibling Rivalry&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Chance Hutchison of the Montreal garage-punks &lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt; and the Devo-core &lt;a href="https://sonicavenues.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sonic Avenues&lt;/a&gt; offshoot &lt;a href="https://newvogue.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Vogue&lt;/a&gt; has a new collection of demo recordings online. Released under the name &lt;a href="http://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cosmic Club&lt;/a&gt;, the set features 8 slices of tweaked-out robot pop that should certainly satisfy if you&amp;#39;re into any of Hutchison&amp;#39;s main gigs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;PRIORS recently released their sophomore full-length &lt;em&gt;New Pleasure&lt;/em&gt; (and an immediate follow-up EP titled &lt;em&gt;Call For You&lt;/em&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://www.slovenly.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slovenly&lt;/a&gt;. The group&amp;#39;s been prepping their next LP for a late 2019/early 2020 release. Tour announcements in both Canada and the US are expected soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1635728372/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com/album/demo"&gt;DEMO by Cosmic Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com/album/demo" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Cosmic Club - &lt;em&gt;Demo&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto three-piece punk group &lt;a href="https://biglosers.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Losers&lt;/a&gt; were the subject of a new short by producer/director Slone McGowan of &lt;a href="https://leekprod.ca/losers-welcome-to-help/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;LEEK&lt;/a&gt;. The 12-minute clip serves as both a mini-documentary and live music video, chronicling the band&amp;#39;s short career to date and the creation of their recent debut cassette &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Help&lt;/em&gt;. Alongside interviews with the trio, the film features footage of the band playing on the floor of Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://hendersonbrewing.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Henderson Brewing Company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The group recorded &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Help&lt;/em&gt; with producer &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/musicbyturnbull/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jesse Turnbull&lt;/a&gt; at Worst In The City. The EP was released this past April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/342929537?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/342929537" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Losers - &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Help&lt;/em&gt; doc @ Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Whitby-based grunge-punk act &lt;a href="https://chastitysongs.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chastity&lt;/a&gt; recently revealed plans for the follow up to their 2018 debut &lt;em&gt;Death Lust&lt;/em&gt;. The new record will carry the title &lt;em&gt;Home Made Satan&lt;/em&gt; and arrives on September 13 from &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.capturedtracks.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Captured Tracks&lt;/a&gt;. The group released the soaring new single &amp;quot;Sun Poisoning&amp;quot; alongside the announcement, accompanied by a video directed by Justin Singer and frontman Brandon Williams. Filmed in Toronto&amp;#39;s High Park, it stars Holden Abraham, son of Fucked Up&amp;#39;s Damian Abraham, and Daphne Flowers. Like much of Chastity&amp;#39;s output, the song has one foot firmly in the 90s, and you can easily imagine it topping the charts back in the alternative rock era. Williams commented on the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wrote a song called &amp;#39;Sun Poisoning&amp;#39; in 2013, and Kacey Musgraves provoked inspiration in me to bring this back, her lyric &amp;#39;happy and sad at the same time.&amp;#39; A classic songwriter trope, melancholy, but in my adaptation I wanted to express the feeling of trying to smile when you know your teeth are bleeding. &amp;#39;Do you want to see how easily my teeth bleed?&amp;#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The press release notes that &lt;em&gt;Home Made Satan&lt;/em&gt; is meant to serve as the second part of a three-record trilogy. It was recorded in London, Ontario with Williams&amp;#39; full live band in the two-week gap between the group&amp;#39;s recent European and North American tours. The album will feature 10 new tracks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Chastity recently released an EP titled &lt;em&gt;Death Lust Cuts&lt;/em&gt;, featuring four additional songs trimmed from their debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CcmEVsRqVVM" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/CcmEVsRqVVM" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Chastity - &amp;quot;Sun Poisoning&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto three-piece garage-rock group &lt;a href="https://winelips.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wine Lips&lt;/a&gt; have a new video online for the song &amp;quot;Fly Swatter,&amp;quot; from the band&amp;#39;s recent sophomore full-length &lt;em&gt;Stressor&lt;/em&gt;. It follows a similarly energetic clip for their &amp;quot;Shark Eyes&amp;quot; single from earlier this year. Vocalist/guitarist Cam Hilborn commented on the track when speaking to &lt;a href="https://exclaim.ca/music/article/wine_lips_jump_high_in_new_fly_swatter_music_video" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;, and there&amp;#39;s no metaphor here:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wrote &amp;#39;Fly Swatter&amp;#39; after we experienced a really bad fly problem in our apartment. There was literally hundreds of flies all over the house and it was driving us crazy so I spent a night exterminating them one by one until they were gone.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Wine Lips, which features Hilborn with drummer Aurora Evans and bassist Bryan Coffey, are on tour now. Following some immediate upcoming shows in the US midwest they&amp;#39;ll take part in the Grey County psych music festival &lt;a href="https://www.crystallakesound.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crystal Lake&lt;/a&gt; later this month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nVwy77_GOy8" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/nVwy77_GOy8" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Wine Lips - &amp;quot;Fly Swatter&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dundas, Ontario power-trio &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thedirtynil/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; have continued with their summer covers series, releasing the second pair of &lt;em&gt;You&amp;#39;re Welcome&lt;/em&gt; tracks into the wild. This time out the band included covers of Van Halen&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;81 single &amp;quot;Unchained&amp;quot; and April Wine&amp;#39;s CanCon radio staple &amp;quot;Oowatanite.&amp;quot; The first volume in this series, released in late April, featured the band&amp;#39;s take on songs by contemporary San Francisco punk band Culture Abuse and Scottish alternative legends The Jesus and Mary Chain. That April Wine cover originally surfaced as the b-side to their &amp;quot;That&amp;#39;s What Heaven Feels Like&amp;quot; 7&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Dirty Nil&amp;#39;s spent much of the last year on the road supporting &lt;em&gt;Master Volume&lt;/em&gt;, their second LP of new material for &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt; following 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Higher Power&lt;/em&gt;. The 2018-released album just landed on the Polaris Music Prize long list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QMqzkeOxzI" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_QMqzkeOxzI" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Dirty Nil - &amp;quot;Oowatanite&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Every Flower I See</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-06-23-every-flower-i-see/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-06-23-every-flower-i-see/</id>
    <published>2019-06-22T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-01T07:14:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While Ben Cook makes more immediate noise as leader of the aggressive hardcore unit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt; (and as a player in the roiling cauldron of maximalism that is &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;), his low-key indie-pop solo persona persists as an intriguing source of contrast. The next &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt; record&amp;#39;s on its way, due August 2 from &lt;a href="http://www.runforcoverrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover Records&lt;/a&gt;. Titled &lt;em&gt;GUV I&lt;/em&gt;, the 8-song set follows up 2018&amp;#39;s enigmatic &lt;em&gt;2 Sad 2 Funk&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;If the first single&amp;#39;s any indication, the sound of the new record may fall closer to 2015&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Ripe 4 Luv&lt;/em&gt; than his last album. &lt;em&gt;2 Sad&lt;/em&gt; found Cook toying with dense vocal modulation, taking the production effects of modern pop music to schmaltzy extremes. That record found syrupy love songs shuffled among clips of 90s-style radio ads, collectively crafting this surreal culture-jamming vibe that I&amp;#39;d wager wasn&amp;#39;t everyone&amp;#39;s cup of tea. &lt;em&gt;Ripe&lt;/em&gt;, on the other hand, was a sweeter set of 70s-styled AM radio pop, still heavily stylized but built with more delicate parts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking about the new single, titled &amp;quot;Every Flower I See,&amp;quot; Cook commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Flowers have been a powerful and prominent symbol in my life for as long as I can remember. When I was young, my mom moved me and my little brother back to Toronto from the U.K. where she found a job working with plants and flowers in the back of a newspaper. She worked long hours there, but also somehow managed to keep an immaculate and beautiful garden of her own while raising us by herself. She&amp;#39;s actually still working that job today, and is probably in her garden right now. As I was finishing this record, I started to notice how flowers had unintentionally become an overarching theme for the album, both sonically and visually.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A video for &amp;quot;Every Flower I See&amp;quot; is now available. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Young Guv will tour the US with the Epitaph punk band Culture Abuse this summer. He&amp;#39;s also scheduled to play an aftershow for Los Angeles&amp;#39; Sound and Fury Festival next month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fhJOTAAWARc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/fhJOTAAWARc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Young Guv - &amp;quot;Every Flower I See&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Following up on their recent stage reunion, the experimental Montreal post-rock group &lt;a href="http://cstrecords.com/fly-pan-am/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fly Pan Am&lt;/a&gt; have formally announced their new record. &lt;em&gt;C&amp;#39;est ça&lt;/em&gt;, the band&amp;#39;s first album in 15 years, is slated to arrive on &lt;a href="http://cstrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Constellation Records&lt;/a&gt; on September 20. The label describes the new record as &amp;quot;blending tightly-wound Kosmische grooves, maximalist shoegaze noise, and bursts of sonic sabotage and deconstruction.&amp;quot; You can find the first single &amp;quot;Distance Dealer,&amp;quot; below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Fly Pan Am (or Le Fly Pan Am to be formal) formed in 1996 and were contemporaries of like-minded high-art bands like &lt;a href="http://www.brainwashed.com/godspeed/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Godspeed You! Black Emperor&lt;/a&gt;. The four-piece put out four records from 1998 through 2005 before calling quits in 2006. The group&amp;#39;s founding lineup featured guitarists Roger Tellier-Craig and Jonathan Parant, bassist J.S. Truchy, and drummer Felix Morel, with all members credited for working on the electronics and tape effects the group became known for. Multi-instrumentalist Eric Gingras (guitars, organs, percussion) expanded the band&amp;#39;s lineup in 2002. They last released the album &lt;em&gt;N&amp;#39;écoutez pas&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/617036550&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/constellation-records/fly-pan-am-distance-dealer" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Fly Pan Am - &amp;quot;Distance Dealer&amp;quot; @ SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto glam-pop artist &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/thisisnyssa" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nyssa&lt;/a&gt; has another cool new single online. &amp;quot;I Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Live On The Moon (Without U)&amp;quot; follows the May-released &amp;quot;Hey Jackie.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the second slate of new material Nyssa&amp;#39;s rolled ou to follow up 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Champion of Love&lt;/em&gt; EP. Like &amp;quot;Hey Jackie&amp;quot; before it, this track shows off the strong vein of 70s rock influence that&amp;#39;s surfaced in Nyssa&amp;#39;s confident electro-pop. The artist described the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;I Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Live On The Moon (Without U)&amp;#39; is a hypnotic blitzed-out lunar-soul glam shuffle, a sci-fi pulp satire call to arms—or call to the dance floor—in the age of climate catastrophe. Director/editor Matt Marotti projects a similar vision in the accompanying video with a cut-up, psychedelic freak-out montage.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That video can be found below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Nyssa&amp;#39;s among the performers slated to play Sackville, New Brunswick&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; on the first weekend of August. The festival just announced its latest slate of performers, with &lt;a href="https://juliedoiron.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Julie Doiron&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://timbaker.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tim Baker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s José Contreras, &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/lizbrainxdoug" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Liz Brain x Doug&lt;/a&gt;, Lillia, and Flour all named to the event&amp;#39;s musical roster. The literary side of the Sappy will feature readings by Marilyn Lerch, Kate Mildew, Annick MacAskill, and Ian Roy, along with a dramatic performance by Patrick Allaby. The event touted these latest additions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;It seems like we&amp;#39;re never quite finished! As some of our oldest, most inspirational and foundational friends return, as some new friends pay a surprise visit, we&amp;#39;re thrilled to welcome their legendary songs, their poetic wisdom, their story telling inventions, their sonic instigations, their bar-rock deconstructions to the Sappyfest 14 program. We hope for Sappyfest to be a conversation between everyone willing to share this space in the spirit of goodwill and with open hearts, across disciplines, genres, and forms of expression. We hope you will join us!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xGYIQLXD3Bw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xGYIQLXD3Bw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Nyssa - &amp;quot;I Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Live On The Moon (Without U)&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sappy boasts a sizable slate of Polaris long-listers among its lineup this year. Last week the 40 records vying for the 2019 &lt;a href="https://polarismusicprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Polaris Music Prize&lt;/a&gt; were announced at a ceremony at The Forks in Winnipeg. Sappy&amp;#39;s share of the list includes the Haisla Nation hip-hop duo &lt;a href="https://snottynoserezkids.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Snotty Nose Rez Kids&lt;/a&gt;, Brampton rapper &lt;a href="https://haviahmighty.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Haviah Mighty&lt;/a&gt;, former Hey Rosetta! lead &lt;a href="https://timbaker.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tim Baker&lt;/a&gt;, Toronto house music collective &lt;a href="https://lalforest.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;LAL&lt;/a&gt;, Montreal&amp;#39;s soulful home-recording savant &lt;a href="https://www.yvesjarvis.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yves Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;, and the Hull-based punk-jazz group &lt;a href="https://fetnat.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FET.NAT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A few punky Some Party favourites made the cut this year as well, with the latest from &lt;a href="https://dillydally.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dilly Dally&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thedirtynil/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; all represented. You can find the full list at the event&amp;#39;s website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In total, the Long List was chosen from 233 albums nominated by a 199 member jury of if journalists, broadcasters, bloggers, and programmers from across Canada (of which I am one, at least until someone comes to realize I don&amp;#39;t belong there).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;If I had to pick one record to single out as the most delightfully surprising inclusion on this year&amp;#39;s list, it would have to be the veteran Quebec metal group &lt;a href="http://voivod.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Voivod&lt;/a&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s 2018 full-length, &lt;em&gt;The Wake&lt;/em&gt;, their fourteenth studio album, earned the long-running group a spot among this year&amp;#39;s new rock hopefuls. Voting is underway now for the 10 album Short List, which will be announced on July 16. A grand jury will decide the eventual $50,000 prize winner, to be announced at a gala in Toronto on September 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ToK9VLJcxU" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/8ToK9VLJcxU" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Voivod - &amp;quot;Obsolete Beings&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One last Polaris note, and a local one for me. This year, for the second year running, the &lt;a href="https://www.niagaraparks.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Niagara Parks Commission&lt;/a&gt; will host a free, weekly summer concert series featuring Polaris acts playing at the brink of Niagara Falls in Queen Victoria Park. After a pair of kick-off performances this long weekend from Tanya Tagaq (on Friday night) and Hanna Georgas (on Canada Day), the &lt;a href="https://www.niagaraparks.com/events/event/the-niagara-stage/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Niagara Stage&lt;/a&gt; will settle into a weekly schedule with shows every Saturday evening at 8 PM (wrapping right before the fireworks). Last year I took my daughter there to see Weaves play and she hasn&amp;#39;t stopped talking about it (although she calls them The Weaves, which is just wrong).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This year will feature shows from Doug Paisley, Jennifer Castle, Elliott Brood, Tanika Charles, Iskwē, Milk &amp;amp; Bone, Kobo Town, the Fred Eaglesmith Roadshow, and Great Lake Swimmers. No Wild Side though, but there&amp;#39;s always next year. You can find the full schedule &lt;a href="https://www.niagaraparks.com/events/event/the-niagara-stage/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We as a city don&amp;#39;t participate much in the indie-oriented musical conversation in Canada, so as a local  this series is a rare reprieve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6SudJKLrOAw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6SudJKLrOAw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Iskwē - &amp;quot;Little Star&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week the sardonic Toronto art-punks &lt;a href="https://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WLMRT&lt;/a&gt; unveiled the  &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/By6B58OASQ7/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;cover and track listing&lt;/a&gt; for their upcoming 10-song full-length. Titled &lt;em&gt;Forever&lt;/em&gt;, the collection will arrive on cassette this July. WLMRT will debut the tape at a joint release show on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/904228303256681/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;July 6&lt;/a&gt; at Toronto&amp;#39;s Monarch Tavern. The band&amp;#39;s sharing the event with the weirdo punk outfit &lt;a href="https://imhughman.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hugh Man&lt;/a&gt; (celebrating their latest EP, &lt;em&gt;Hughs Man is it Anyway?&lt;/em&gt;), and the return of &lt;a href="http://sigil.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sigil&lt;/a&gt; (the side-project of &lt;a href="https://frigsmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FRIGS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Bria Salmena with ex-members of HSY](https://hsy666.bandcamp.com/)).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;WLMRT are following up their 2018 &lt;a href="http://www.pleasencerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pleasence Records&lt;/a&gt; EP &lt;em&gt;Lube 2&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="http://tallies.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tallies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Stephen Pitman produced the new record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;WLMRT are among the performers slated to play Ottawa&amp;#39;s inaugural &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/377555466159265/permalink/380792492502229/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Side by Side Weekend&lt;/a&gt; on the last weekend of July. The event, following the trail blazed by the now-defunct &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion&lt;/a&gt;, will stage four days of shows at the neighbouring venues &lt;a href="https://www.blacksquirrelbooks.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Squirrel Books&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.houseoftarg.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;House of TARG&lt;/a&gt;. This past week the festival&amp;#39;s organizers shared the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/sidebysidewknd/photos/a.2044142055694670/2131592326949642/?type=3&amp;amp;theater" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; for the full event, which features performances by the likes of the &lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Adamyk Band&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://dboyintl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dboy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://cellfromthegrave.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CELL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lifeinvacuum.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Life In Vacuum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://bbqtband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BBQT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://bonniedoon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonnie Doon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://joncreeden.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jon Creeden &amp;amp; the Flying Hellfish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Among the Saturday night performances, you&amp;#39;ll find a rare appearance by Ottawa&amp;#39;s dissonant noise group &lt;a href="http://roberta-bondar.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bondar&lt;/a&gt;. The group hasn&amp;#39;t performed together in 5 years. Bondar previously played under the name Roberta Bondar, last releasing the EP &lt;em&gt;Caustic&lt;/em&gt; in 2014. They took on an abbreviated version of the name after the Canadian astronaut kindly requested they stop muddying her brand. When they last convened, Bondar was comprised of Lidija Rozitis, Alex Maltby, Gary Franks, and Tyler Goodman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1238113231/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://roberta-bondar.bandcamp.com/album/caustic"&gt;Caustic by Bondar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://roberta-bondar.bandcamp.com/album/caustic" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bondar - &lt;em&gt;Caustic&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="https://bonniedoon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonnie Doon&lt;/a&gt;, the Ottawa punk band recently released a video for the song &amp;quot;Panty Twister,&amp;quot; from their excellent 2017 full-length &lt;em&gt;Dooner Nooner&lt;/em&gt;. The group commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We wanted to make a music video that showcased the opulence of being on a boat like in 90s rap videos and well... anything to do with sailing culture. Although as a punk band we are more like the underwater monstars, it was a really fun video to film, except when I got sea sick and was still eating shrimp in a shark suit with no railing to hold onto. The song is about getting your bathing suit all twisted from riding waterslides and this is our interpretation - see in it what you like! Some people say it is all a metaphor for cunnilingus.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Bassist Lesley Marshall directed the clip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dooner Nooner&lt;/em&gt; is one of the first records I wrote about when this newsletter kicked off in 2017. It endures as a fun mix of low-fi surf rock and sludgy post-punk, interspersed by frenzied X-Ray Spex-channelling craziness like you hear on this tune.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qIff7lGO8Fs" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/qIff7lGO8Fs" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Bonnie Doon - &amp;quot;Panty Twister&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s experimental prog-pop trio &lt;a href="http://absolutelyfree.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Absolutely Free&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online showcasing the title track of their newly released &lt;em&gt;Geneva Freeport&lt;/em&gt; EP.  Directed by &lt;a href="https://bilesister.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bile Sister&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Julie Reich, the clip wanders through a surreal 3D art gallery, evoking and parodying the record&amp;#39;s namesake (a warehouse complex in Switzerland that hides away an estimated $100 billion art collection).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The three-song EP came out last Friday on &lt;a href="http://ideefixerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Idée Fixe&lt;/a&gt;. It features contributions from Meg Remy of &lt;a href="http://yousgirls.blogspot.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Girls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://carldidur.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Carl Didur&lt;/a&gt; of the Toronto psych duo &lt;a href="https://zachtautomaat.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Zacht Automaat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v9N2q5ztOQo" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/v9N2q5ztOQo" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Absolutely Free - &amp;quot;Geneva Freeport&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week Guelph-based folk singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://inneswilson.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Innes Wilson&lt;/a&gt; unveiled the video for &amp;quot;Of Love and Lost,&amp;quot; the first single from his upcoming full-length &lt;em&gt;The Heart That Holds This Up&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s due on August 16 from &lt;a href="https://outofsoundrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Out of Sound Records&lt;/a&gt;. The musician commented on the project in the premiere at &lt;a href="http://www.liveinlimbo.com/2019/06/20/world-premiere/video-premiere-of-love-and-lost-by-innes-wilson.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Live In Limbo&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;This song is really about the vastness of love and also the emptiness of loss, which was important to communicate in the music video. I&amp;#39;ve always loved old movies and TV shows that would use miniatures instead of CGI, and my good friend Ross Millar has been making brilliantly detailed Sci-fi dioramas which I&amp;#39;ve marvelled at for years. With his intricate, static scenes, he would beautifully capture the loneliness and cold emptiness of space. It came to me that this could be exactly how I could tell the story of this song in a creative way. I pitched it to Ross and he was immediately on board. We exchanged our ideas, Ross built and designed the sets and then we brought in our pal John Forbes to film it. So three old buddies, each with our respective abilities, who saw the potential to do something very cool, got together and made this project a reality.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Wilson last released the &lt;em&gt;Seaview&lt;/em&gt; EP in 2018, which featured music tracked at &lt;a href="https://constructionanddestruction.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Construction &amp;amp; Destruction&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Quarantine studio with backing from members of &lt;a href="https://thenoisymountain.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WHOOP-Szo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Heart That Holds This Up&lt;/em&gt; was recorded with Halifax-based producer Adam Warren (Glory Glory, Pretty Normal, The Drug Rugs).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RQNsTjpXKUc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/RQNsTjpXKUc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Innes Wilson - &amp;quot;Of Love and Lost&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Elsewhere in Guelph, the Royal City&amp;#39;s enigmatic and clearly named &lt;a href="https://onedimensionalband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bullshit Hardcore Band&lt;/a&gt; have announced a hiatus, claiming:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The BSHC are going underground. This is not a retreat, but a redirection of our subversive efforts to other outlets.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Despite their intention to disappear off-grid, the duo still has a few previously unreleased recordings to get into the world. The first of these posthumous releases is an album&amp;#39;s worth of material titled &lt;em&gt;Marksism&lt;/em&gt;, which the band recorded in the fall of 2018. They commented that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;...as far as &amp;#39;hardcore&amp;#39; or guitar-based music we&amp;#39;ve made, our new album &amp;#39;Marksism&amp;#39; is our peak by a long shot.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The unit also has a second EP on the way from their dub alter-egos the Bullshit Dub Soundsystem. They issued their first diversion in that form back in April of 2018. A &amp;quot;really incredible collab&amp;quot; with an unnamed artist is also in the works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1178042305/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://onedimensionalband.bandcamp.com/album/marksism"&gt;Marksism by Bullshit Hardcore Band&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://onedimensionalband.bandcamp.com/album/marksism" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bullshit Hardcore Band - &lt;em&gt;Marksism&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal melodic pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://brandnewlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brand New Lungs&lt;/a&gt; have a new full-length out on &lt;a href="https://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Thousand Islands Records&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;Like Wildfire&lt;/em&gt;. You can now stream the 12-song record in its entirety at Bandcamp. Brand New Lungs features Louis-Charles Berthiaume, Alex Bergeron, Fred Normand, and Philippe Thibodeau.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This is a full-throated, 90s-styled rocker tailor-made for crowd sing-alongs. I&amp;#39;d love to wistfully claim &amp;quot;they don&amp;#39;t make them like this anymore,&amp;quot; but the impressively prolific Thousand Islands discography says otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2687144244/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/album/like-wildfire"&gt;Like Wildfire by Brand New Lungs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/album/like-wildfire" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Brand New Lungs - &lt;em&gt;Like Wildfire&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cool All The Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-06-16-cool-all-the-time/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-06-16-cool-all-the-time/</id>
    <published>2019-06-15T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-19T07:40:17-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;We&amp;#39;ve known for months that a sequel to &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister&lt;/em&gt; was in the works, but the formal announcement only came from &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; last week. While Jimmie&amp;#39;s regularly released music since that fan-favourite 2011 album (most recently with 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Field of Trampolines&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s always held a special place in the singer/songwriter&amp;#39;s discography. In the press release, Jimmie commented on the project:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I decided to make a sequel because I loved making the first one. I value the experience of making records as much as the end product. I know that I&amp;#39;m always trying to make something good, but I&amp;#39;m also aware that the process is the thing that I&amp;#39;ll think about and revisit in the future. With this album, I really wanted to recreate the immersive experience of making the original. The first one was recorded in Nova Scotia in a beautiful little town. The session had the feeling of a destination artist residency. We swam in the ocean and watched scientists cut the head off a shark; they were very eventful days. Maybe I also wanted an excuse to hang out with Jay and Ryan for a week. The three of us are spread out across the country, so being together is a rare treat. On the last day of the session we played a rock show at a tiny Toronto club. We literally went straight from the studio to the venue. It was completely packed with pals from all over; it was the best! I played the first &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister&lt;/em&gt; acoustic, then the full band performed &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt; from top to bottom. The show provided our session a very hard deadline and was probably the cause of some studio stress, but it was a perfect magical ending to the week.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The show he&amp;#39;s referring to happened last November at Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.tranzac.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tranzac&lt;/a&gt;. It was captured by &lt;a href="http://mechanicalforestsound.blogspot.com/2019/01/recording-shotgun-jimmie.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mechanical Forest Sound&lt;/a&gt; as part of their heroic series of Toronto field recordings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This record features the titular Jim Kilpatrick backed by Ryan Peters of &lt;a href="https://ladyhawk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ladyhawk&lt;/a&gt;, Jay Baird of &lt;a href="http://domakesaythink.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Do Make Say Think&lt;/a&gt;, and José Miguel Contreras of indie vets &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;. The album was recorded and produced by Contreras at The Chat Chateaux in Toronto (this is the second significant collaboration from José and Jimmie of late, as the two debuted their band &lt;a href="https://theheatdeath.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Heat Death&lt;/a&gt; in 2018). Guests on &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt; include the Constantines&amp;#39; &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt; (on Wurlitzer), and Cole Woods of &lt;a href="https://humanmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Human Music&lt;/a&gt; on synth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The album announcement arrived alongside the upbeat single &amp;quot;Cool All The Time,&amp;quot; which features a spoken monologue by &lt;a href="https://chadvangaalen.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chad VanGaalen&lt;/a&gt;. Jimmie reflected:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I think of Chad&amp;#39;s monologue like it&amp;#39;s our version of Chuck D on Sonic Youth&amp;#39;s Kool Thing. In hindsight, I should have named the Track &amp;#39;Kool All The Time&amp;#39;  &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 13 song &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt; arrives from You&amp;#39;ve Changed on August 2. The release coincides with Jimmie&amp;#39;s long-awaited return to Sackville, New Brunswick&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3731652709/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.bandcamp.com/album/transistor-sister-2"&gt;Transistor Sister 2 by Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.bandcamp.com/track/cool-all-the-time" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Shotgun Jimmie - &amp;quot;Cool All The Time&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hot damn! The debut EP from Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://goodgriefgang.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Good Grief&lt;/a&gt; is just gloriously fun. The four-piece churns out rollicking &amp;#39;77-style punk rock with such ferocity and lack of shame that it never stops to reflect on how ultimately goofy it is. I mean that as the highest compliment (it&amp;#39;s how I feel about Vancouver&amp;#39;s Chain Whip as well). Good Grief&amp;#39;s secret weapon though is vocalist Dan Ashworth, who just happens to be English, replete with a heavy accent that gives these four songs an extra kick (and even if he isn&amp;#39;t, his inflections fit the style they&amp;#39;re playing like a glove). I can&amp;#39;t listen to this without smiling like an idiot. The record even starts with a ridiculous theme song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band released &lt;em&gt;Outside the Off Licence&lt;/em&gt; last week with a hometown show I missed like an idiot. The record came out June 7 on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TrashBoyRecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Trash Boy Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=823827474/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://goodgriefgang.bandcamp.com/album/outside-the-off-licence"&gt;Outside the Off Licence by GOOD GRIEF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://goodgriefgang.bandcamp.com/album/outside-the-off-licence" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Good Grief - &lt;em&gt;Outside the Off Licence&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;After an agonizing wait (not really, but it was a long three or four days), Toronto trio &lt;a href="https://motorists.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Motorists&lt;/a&gt; have debuted with the single &amp;quot;Displacement Time.&amp;quot; The group features vocals from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/feelalrighttt/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feel Alright&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Craig Fahner, Jesse Locke of &lt;a href="https://tough-age.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tough Age&lt;/a&gt; behind the drum kit, and Matthew Learoyd (also of Feel Alright, along with a long list of Calgary bands like &lt;a href="https://stalwartsons.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stalwart Sons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://labcoast.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lab Coast&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://coldwater.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cold Water&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Locke previously commented on the band&amp;#39;s sound, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve played in Feel Alright before and decided to write some new songs together since Craig moved to Toronto. It ended up kind of sounding like &amp;#39;80s R.E.M. if they were a punk band or the Wipers with more jangle and Grass Widow harmonies for good measure. I think you might like it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Did I just lazily run the same pull quote in two consecutive newsletters? Indeed I did, friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1849221163/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://motorists.bandcamp.com/track/displacement-time"&gt;Displacement Time by Motorists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://motorists.bandcamp.com/track/displacement-time" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Motorists - &amp;quot;Displacement Time&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;East coast folk-rock storytellers &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; have a video online for their new single &amp;quot;No Peace.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s their half of a split 7&amp;quot; with German singer/songwriter Bernhard Karakoulakis, who plays under the name &lt;a href="https://boohoo.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Boo Hoo&lt;/a&gt;. The clip, filmed in Sackville, Berlin, Hamburg, and Bremen, features Ariel Sharratt as a superhero (who in the intro receives her marching orders from a milkshake-sipping Steven Lambke). A whole host of the band&amp;#39;s friends make appearances in the narrative, as do some high-production-value lizard people. The Burning Hell / Boo Hoo split can be found on the Frankfurt label &lt;a href="https://lousymoon.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lousy Moon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band, currently on tour in Europe, has been supporting a lathe-cut 10&amp;quot; titled &lt;em&gt;Birdwatching on Garbage Island&lt;/em&gt; on the road. As only 77 of these were ever made, it&amp;#39;s entirely sold out. While the group previously declined to share the songs on the Internet, they&amp;#39;ve since relented (a bit) and have the four tracks streaming on Bandcamp at this very moment. They&amp;#39;ll only be there through the end of the tour, though, then they&amp;#39;re &amp;quot;back in the vaults.&amp;quot; Give them a listen now, or you&amp;#39;re out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Burning Hell recorded the &lt;em&gt;Garage Island&lt;/em&gt; set in St. John&amp;#39;s at Jake Nicoll&amp;#39;s studio in the very early days of 2019. The record features vocalist/guitarist Mathias Kom, drummer/vocalist Ariel Sharratt, bassist Darren Browne, and Nicoll in several capacities. As with much of the band&amp;#39;s prolific body of work, these songs present themselves as somehow both adorable and provocative at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Burning Hell last full length was 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Revival Beach&lt;/em&gt;. In the spring the band announced that they were recording an album&amp;#39;s worth of duets with an organized labour theme. News on that one&amp;#39;s still to come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L-J4Hrq2p0A" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/L-J4Hrq2p0A" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Burning Hell - &amp;quot;No Peace&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2732528748/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/birdwatching-on-garbage-island"&gt;Birdwatching on Garbage Island by The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/birdwatching-on-garbage-island" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Burning Hell - &lt;em&gt;Birdwatching on Garbage Island&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal punk trio &lt;a href="https://lemon-grab.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lemongrab&lt;/a&gt; have a video online for &amp;quot;Too Many Bitches,&amp;quot; the lead track from their recent LP &lt;em&gt;It Doesn&amp;#39;t Sound Good But It Feels Awesome&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lemongrab&amp;#39;s new LP&amp;#39;s a great time, with a youthful mix of slacker rock and frantic pop-punk. &lt;a href="https://faithhealer.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Faith Healer&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://rennywilson.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Renny Wilson&lt;/a&gt; produced. The record features performances from vocalist Gaëlle Cordeau, guitarists Léonie Dishaw and Zale Burley, drummer Marilou Turgeon, and bassist Jérémie Cyr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7kyOwQcX9qY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/7kyOwQcX9qY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Lemongrab - &amp;quot;Too Many Bitches&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/figurewalking/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Figure Walking&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s a duo featuring Winnipeg singer/songwriter &lt;a href="http://gregmacpherson.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Greg MacPherson&lt;/a&gt; and drummer Rob Gardiner (Conduct, Pip Skid). They last released &lt;em&gt;The Big Other&lt;/em&gt; in 2017. While the follow up (titled &lt;em&gt;vertical/horizontal&lt;/em&gt;) is due later this summer from MacPherson&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://disintegrationrecords.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Disintegration Records&lt;/a&gt; label, the band shared an unexpected late remix of a &lt;em&gt;Big Other&lt;/em&gt; track last week. The song &amp;quot;Blue World&amp;quot; was reworked by the Philadelphia band &lt;a href="https://tulipomania.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tulipomania&lt;/a&gt; and producer/engineer Richard Hartline. In the track premiere at &lt;a href="https://jammerzine.com/first-listen-figure-walking-blue-world-remix/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jammerzine&lt;/a&gt;, MacPherson comments:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I love to imagine the world through the murky, silver-on-the-ocean-floor filter that is Tulipomania&amp;#39;s music. This remix of Blue World is astonishing for us, as a watching an eclipse with welder&amp;#39;s goggles and discovering the sun for the first time&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3186620899/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://disintegrationrecords.bandcamp.com/track/blue-world-remix"&gt;Blue World Remix by Disintegration Records&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://disintegrationrecords.bandcamp.com/track/blue-world-remix" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Figure Walking - &amp;quot;Blue World&amp;quot; (Tulipomania remix) @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Barrie, Ontario trio &lt;a href="https://thehighdives.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Highdives&lt;/a&gt; have a new a video online for their single &amp;quot;Sophomore,&amp;quot; directed by Adam Bialo. The track&amp;#39;s a slow-burning melodic punk tune that builds to a crescendo in its final third. It comes from the band&amp;#39;s recent debut full-length &lt;em&gt;Ocean Blood&lt;/em&gt;. You can watch it below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean Blood&lt;/em&gt; was recorded and produced by J. Andrew Shropshire (Indian Handcrafts) and mastered by Steve Rizun (The Flatliners, Junior Battles). The Highdives feature vocalist/guitarist Scott Murray, bassist Matt Galbraith, and drummer Shawn Moreau.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Highdives are slated to play the Black Forest Stage on the Friday night at &lt;a href="https://beaus.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beau&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; annual &lt;a href="https://www.beausoktoberfest.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oktoberfest&lt;/a&gt; when it returns on September 20. They&amp;#39;ll join &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://laffairepelican.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;L&amp;#39;Affaire Pélican&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://oakheartsmtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oakhearts&lt;/a&gt;, Northgang, and &lt;a href="http://thehallions.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Hallions&lt;/a&gt; that evening. The event raises money for several causes, with Black Forest, in particular, supporting the skateboards-for-youth program &lt;a href="http://ottawaskateboard.ca/for-pivots-sake/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;For Pivots Sake&lt;/a&gt;. The overall Oktoberfest will feature headlining sets from &lt;a href="http://www.thenewpornographers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The New Pornographers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.shadk.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shad&lt;/a&gt;. Some Party&amp;#39;s a sponsor of the Black Forest stage again this year, so stay tuned for some shenanigans in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yZpB9ogtj-4" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/yZpB9ogtj-4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Highdives - &amp;quot;Sophomore&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ross Miller of &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; and the mighty &lt;a href="https://sidemanhc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SIDEMAN&lt;/a&gt; has a new two-song single online from his side-project &lt;a href="https://itcantallbeblue.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Blue&lt;/a&gt;. The Welland artist is following up the five-song &lt;em&gt;Positive Attitude&lt;/em&gt; EP he released last fall. The new set features the simmering alt-rock track &amp;quot;Only Anger&amp;quot; backed with the decidedly more aggressive punk tune &amp;quot;True You.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week Miller&amp;#39;s main gig released &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/album/astro-ever-after" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Astro Ever After&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; a new standalone track from the &lt;em&gt;Master Volume&lt;/em&gt; sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4202464412/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://itcantallbeblue.bandcamp.com/album/only-anger"&gt;ONLY ANGER by BLUE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://itcantallbeblue.bandcamp.com/album/only-anger" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Blue - &lt;em&gt;Only Anger&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have a heck of a lot of info on the Vancouver three-piece &lt;a href="http://puddingvancouver.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pudding&lt;/a&gt;, other than the fact that they&amp;#39;ve played shows with more than a few bands I&amp;#39;m quite fond of, like &lt;a href="https://neckingband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Necking&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://bedwettersanonymous.bandcamp.com/album/r-u-experiencing-discomfort" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bedwetters Anonymous&lt;/a&gt;. The group released &lt;em&gt;Pop Over&lt;/em&gt;,  their first LP, just a week ago. Clocking in at 11 songs, it&amp;#39;s a great deal of fun, mixing some 90s alt-rock vibes with a helping of that modern slacker-punk sound (peddled by fellow Van bands like &lt;a href="https://dumbband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dumb&lt;/a&gt;). Pudding features bassist Darren Mountain, drummer/vocalist Cyndi Callow, and guitarist/vocalist Paula Moulton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1673555275/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://puddingvancouver.bandcamp.com/album/pop-over-2"&gt;Pop over by pudding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://puddingvancouver.bandcamp.com/album/pop-over-2" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Pudding - &lt;em&gt;Pop Over&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week Robert Ondzik released the second full length as his suave lounge-pop alter-ego &lt;a href="http://mrmerlot.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mr. Merlot&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;City Sex Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt; features a number of familiar faces from Vancouver&amp;#39;s indie-pop world, with &lt;a href="https://jayarner.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jay Arner&lt;/a&gt; co-writing and producing a record that features appearances from &lt;a href="https://www.mergerecords.com/destroyer" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Destroyer&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Nicolas Bragg, Jessica Delisle of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/energyslime/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Energy Slime&lt;/a&gt;, Adrienne Labelle from &lt;a href="https://garbagedreamz.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Garbage Dreams&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="https://allmoonsaresuper.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Supermoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://rolemach.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Role Mach&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Rich Sexton, Thom Lougheed of &lt;a href="https://milkmilkmilk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Milk&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="https://watermelon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Watermelon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://trashtronix.bandcamp.com/album/bad-to-the-tone" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tommy Tone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The wine-soaked record arrived alongside a video for the song &amp;quot;Catch a Feeling,&amp;quot; directed by Kyle Bowman. It features Ondzik and members of his backing band in full Shakespearean regalia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/misZ-hf1Osg" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/misZ-hf1Osg" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Mr. Merlot - &amp;quot;Catch a Feeling&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s sibling psych-dance trio &lt;a href="https://doomsquad.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;DOOMSQUAD&lt;/a&gt; recently played a live session for CBC Music, playing several songs from their recent full-length &lt;em&gt;Let Yourself Be Seen&lt;/em&gt;. They appeared alongside past-&lt;a href="https://polarismusicprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Polaris&lt;/a&gt; winner &lt;a href="https://lidopimienta.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lido Pimienta&lt;/a&gt; and guitarist &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/ejjismith/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ejji Smith&lt;/a&gt;. DOOMSQUAD&amp;#39;s Trevor Blumas commented on the occasion, boasting &amp;quot;this is like &lt;em&gt;The Last Waltz&lt;/em&gt; but for weirdos in Toronto.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;DOOMSQUAD&amp;#39;s set to play some cool Ontario festivals this summer, including Paris, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://strangewaves.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Strangewaves&lt;/a&gt; and the Grey County psych gathering &lt;a href="https://www.crystallakesound.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crystal Lake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="720" height="405" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen data-src="//www.cbc.ca/i/caffeine/syndicate/?mediaId=1528301123650" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/music/firstplaylive/first-play-live-doomsquad-let-yourself-be-seen-1.5151320" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: DOOMSQUAD - &amp;quot;Let Yourself Be Seen&amp;quot; @ CBC Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theflatliners.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flatliners&lt;/a&gt; lead &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CrustCrustwell" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Cresswell&lt;/a&gt; has a new solo track online titled &amp;quot;Gather My Thoughts.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the second new tune from the punk frontman in the past few months, following the in the same stylistic vein as the introspective &amp;quot;To The Wind.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Cresswell last went solo with his 2014 contribution to Joey Cape&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.oneweekrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;One Week Records&lt;/a&gt; project. The Flatliners most recently released an EP titled &lt;em&gt;Mass Candescence&lt;/em&gt; and the preceding &lt;em&gt;Inviting Light&lt;/em&gt; LP. Cresswell&amp;#39;s been touring as a part of Hot Water Music in recent months, filling in for singer/guitarist Chris Wollard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1851303141/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chriscresswell.bandcamp.com/track/gather-my-thoughts"&gt;Gather My Thoughts by Chris Cresswell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://chriscresswell.bandcamp.com/track/gather-my-thoughts" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chris Cresswell - &amp;quot;Gather My Thoughts&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s instrumental funk collective the &lt;a href="https://badgeepoque.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Badge Époque Ensemble&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for the song &amp;quot;Undressed In Solitude.&amp;quot; Directed by Alex Kingsmill, the clip features a collage of footage sourced entirely from the public domain Internet Archive. The 11-minute tune features guest vocals from the R&amp;amp;B artist &lt;a href="https://imjamesbaley.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;James Baley&lt;/a&gt;, and was described in an earlier press release as &amp;quot;an improbable collision between psych-era Stevie Wonder and the whimsically dark &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Planet&lt;/em&gt; score.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Ensemble&amp;#39;s lead by multi-instrumentalist Maximilian &amp;#39;Twig&amp;#39; Turnbull, formerly known as the psych artist &lt;a href="https://slimtwig.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slim Twig&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;#39;ve likely heard Twig as a songwriter and producer for both &lt;a href="http://yousgirls.blogspot.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Girls&lt;/a&gt; and the related rock band &lt;a href="https://darleneshrugg.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Darlene Shrugg&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#39;s a regular performer in the psych-jazz group &lt;a href="http://thecosmicrange.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Cosmic Range&lt;/a&gt; as well.
The self-titled Badge Époque Ensemble record was released recently on &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KgMNACv5X2A" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/KgMNACv5X2A" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Badge Époque Ensemble - &amp;quot;Undressed In Solitude&amp;quot; ft. James Baley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Edmonton punk group &lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Real Sickies&lt;/a&gt; have joined the &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt; family, with plans to release a new full-length on August 30. The group, which features ex-members of the late-90s/early-2000s street punk group &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wednesday_Night_Heroes" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wednesday Night Heroes&lt;/a&gt;, last released &lt;em&gt;Get Well Soon&lt;/em&gt; in 2018 through a whole host of labels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Real Sickies are fronted by Ben Disaster of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thisispop780/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;This Is Pop&lt;/a&gt;, a radio show on Edmonton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.cjsr.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CJSR&lt;/a&gt; and related &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thisispoprecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;label&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have any music to share from the deal yet, but here&amp;#39;s the band&amp;#39;s last record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 700px; max-width: 100%; height: 120px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=903415359/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://realsickies.bandcamp.com/album/get-well-soon"&gt;GET WELL SOON by REAL SICKIES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://realsickies.bandcamp.com/album/get-well-soon" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Real Sickies - &lt;em&gt;Get Well Soon&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Fredericton&amp;#39;s joyous and noisy art-punk trio &lt;a href="https://motherhoodmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Motherhood&lt;/a&gt; revealed two videos featuring their sing &amp;quot;Hard in the Paint&amp;quot; over the past week. First, there&amp;#39;s an acoustic performance filmed on a cafe patio in Brighton sometime last year. You can stream that from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscovrTVLondon/videos/450657599043196/UzpfSTE0OTY2MzE3NTA1MzUzNzoyNDYzNjI1MDYwMzIzOTky/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;DiscovrTV&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook. They followed that on Monday with a proper music video that turns the &lt;em&gt;Dear Bongo&lt;/em&gt; single into a beach dance party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band&amp;#39;s newest LP arrived this past March from the &lt;a href="https://www.forwardmusicgroup.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Forward Music Group&lt;/a&gt;. Motherhood features lead-vocalist/guitarist Brydon Crain, keyboardist Penelope Stevens, and drummer Adam Sipkema. Look for them on stage at the above-mentioned &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; this August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SYMDoac3ISE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SYMDoac3ISE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Motherhood - &amp;quot;Hard in the Paint&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto noise-punk trio &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt; have another new video online featuring a song from their upcoming singles collection &lt;em&gt;Automat&lt;/em&gt;. This time they&amp;#39;re featuring the track &amp;quot;Dry Up,&amp;quot; which first surfaced in 2009 as the b-side to their &lt;em&gt;Ripped On The Fence&lt;/em&gt; 7&amp;quot;. In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://consequenceofsound.net/2019/06/metz-dry-up-new-song-video-release" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Consequence of Sound&lt;/a&gt;, guitarist Alex Edkins commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;METZ have been making music together for over 10 years. It&amp;#39;s been a blur. We&amp;#39;ve very rarely allowed ourselves to look backward. We&amp;#39;ve been hyper-focused on always moving forward at breakneck speed, perpetually fixated on what&amp;#39;s next. The video for &amp;#39;Dry Up,&amp;#39; as well as the &lt;em&gt;Automat&lt;/em&gt; album, is an attempt to pause, take a breath, look backward and take stock of our past. It&amp;#39;s intended to express how grateful we are to be able to do what we do. It&amp;#39;s a love letter to the incredible places we&amp;#39;ve traveled, the beautiful people we&amp;#39;ve met, to community, music, and friendship.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The b-sides and rarities collection arrives on July 12 through &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop Records&lt;/a&gt;. METZ last released the Steve Albini engineered studio album &lt;em&gt;Strange Peace&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/23D631c7SAE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/23D631c7SAE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: METZ - &amp;quot;Dry Up&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href="http://mechanicalforestsound.blogspot.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mechanical Forest Sound&lt;/a&gt; earlier in the newsletter. Over the past week, the blog&amp;#39;s published some live cuts of new songs from a few of my favourite bands. Recent features there have showcased new material from &lt;a href="https://mechanicalforestsound.blogspot.com/2019/06/recording-wlmrt.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WLMRT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://mechanicalforestsound.blogspot.com/2019/06/record-teenanger.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt;, likely before you could hear those songs anywhere else. Joe Strutt&amp;#39;s performing an invaluable, seemingly inexhaustible, service to the Canadian music world over there. Please do check it out if you haven&amp;#39;t already.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
