<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter sharing the latest in independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated every Sunday evening by Adam White. Some Party features punk, garage, psych, and otherwise uncategorizable indie rock, drawing lines from proto to post and every weird diversion along the way.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-10-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Crimson Tide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-27-crimson-tide/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-27-crimson-tide/</id>
    <published>2019-10-26T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-28T22:07:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Some Party maintains an intentional blind spot for a handful of top-tier Canadian indie rock bands. It&amp;#39;s an omission rooted in the notion that such well-established acts probably won&amp;#39;t benefit from my attention. It&amp;#39;s also a convenient cop-out. I lost the plot on the Arcade Fires and Broken Social Scenes of the world some time ago, and I&amp;#39;ve yet to find the motivation to catch up on what I&amp;#39;ve missed. I&amp;#39;m not proud of it, but there&amp;#39;s some pinheaded part of my punk rock brain that seems to disengage with artists once they&amp;#39;ve passed a certain saturation point. It&amp;#39;s an early-2000s mindset, pre &lt;em&gt;poptimism&lt;/em&gt;, and certainly out of step with my online friends, all who seem to thrive on group commentary. Perhaps it goes deeper, some off-target mutation of the major label hangups that everyone else left in the 90s. I find I push myself to seek out weird local acts in place of, not in addition to, the cultural touchstones. What&amp;#39;s worse is I apply this bias somewhat arbitrarily, and that inconsistency&amp;#39;s more glaring here, where I&amp;#39;m the publication&amp;#39;s sole author.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;My relation with Dan Bejar&amp;#39;s celebrated solo vehicle &lt;a href="https://www.mergerecords.com/destroyer" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Destroyer&lt;/a&gt; is different. I&amp;#39;m an unabashed &lt;a href="http://www.thenewpornographers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Pornographers&lt;/a&gt; fan, and despite that band&amp;#39;s stature, they&amp;#39;ve been welcome Some Party material from the get-go. The scant mentions of Destroyer in this newsletter may seem like another bullheaded omission of an established act, but it comes from somewhere else entirely: a deep sense of shame. I bow to the conventional wisdom that Dan Bejar&amp;#39;s solo material is brilliant more often than not. I just happen to be tragically behind on it. While (I think) I&amp;#39;ve heard everything he&amp;#39;s released to date, I&amp;#39;ve made a horrible habit of skimming Destroyer records, acknowledging they require far more of my attention that I have to give, and then shelving them indefinitely. Looking at it now, I think I&amp;#39;ve been doing this since &lt;em&gt;Trouble in Dreams&lt;/em&gt;, which means I&amp;#39;m behind by over a &lt;em&gt;decade&lt;/em&gt; at this point. Ten years! What the hell have I been doing with myself? The cerebral, high-art character of Bejar&amp;#39;s work has, more than anything, made it easier to compartmentalize. These Destroyer records sit stacked like books on my nightstand. They deserve my time and attention, more worthy than most things, but I can never quite commit myself to the task. The books aren&amp;#39;t going anywhere, and the fast-food content of Netflix just so much &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; to laze into. I&amp;#39;ll get to them eventually, and heck, I&amp;#39;m probably not mature enough to fully appreciate them anyways. What I am is tired, and I can&amp;#39;t quite remember how Deep Space Nine ended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While my shortcomings and insecurities don&amp;#39;t have any particular bearing on the news of Destroyer&amp;#39;s upcoming record, I do appreciate you allowing me to get that off my chest. I&amp;#39;m sorry, Mr. Bejar. Je suis désolé, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dan Bejar&amp;#39;s Destroyer has returned with &amp;quot;Crimson Tide,&amp;quot; the deceptively upbeat first single from the upcoming &lt;em&gt;Have We Met&lt;/em&gt;. That record, due January 31 from &lt;a href="https://deadoceans.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dead Oceans&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.mergerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Merge&lt;/a&gt;, will be the band&amp;#39;s thirteenth LP. It follows 2017&amp;#39;s well-received &lt;em&gt;Ken&lt;/em&gt;, and 2015&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Poison Season&lt;/em&gt; before it. Given my shameful lag in tracking Destroyer&amp;#39;s career, I&amp;#39;ll defer to the press-release to help contextualize this one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have We Met&lt;/em&gt;, as Bejar puts it, &amp;#39;came together in such a crazy way – all equal parts ecstasy and terror&amp;#39;. Initially conceived (but quickly ditched) as a Y2K album, Bejar was without a clear concept in mind. So he said &amp;quot;fuck it&amp;quot; and let it all rip while brainstorming at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Culled from years&amp;#39; worth of saved writing, set aside for projects &amp;quot;beyond music,&amp;quot; and recorded at his kitchen table, &lt;em&gt;Have We Met&lt;/em&gt; harkens back to &lt;em&gt;Kaputt&lt;/em&gt;-era Bejar stringing together lyrics off hand while lounging on his couch. The resulting vocal sound exists in the sweet spot between two Destroyer worlds colliding: hints of the past, more strident Destroyer mixed in with a relaxed, new-aged Crooning one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;No re-recording. No cleaning up. The Destroyer band-orientated approach was shelved and frequent collaborator John Collins was tasked with the role of layering synth and rhythm sections over a stream-of-consciousness Bejar, as Nic Bragg added &amp;#39;completely unexpected and somehow comforting&amp;#39; three-dimensional, shredding guitar.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A cinematic video for &amp;quot;Crimson Tide&amp;quot; arrived from directors David Galloway and David Ehrenreich. You can find it below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9mFTgJQtCPk" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/9mFTgJQtCPk" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Destroyer - &amp;quot;Crimson Tide&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m married to a Wellander, and I don&amp;#39;t mean those new subdivisions encroaching on Pelham either. I&amp;#39;m talking the haggard east side of Welland: That inexplicable island of Francophone Ontario hollowed out from decades of plant closures but still stubbornly holding on. The rough and tumble landmarks of this area are the focus of the new &lt;a href="http://ancientshapes.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ancient Shapes&lt;/a&gt; video: the Rex, the Blue Star, the shuttered shops along King Street, the exhibition, the ghosts of the Atlas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I shared the defiant, perhaps tongue-in-cheek &amp;quot;Welland 2020&amp;quot; video to Facebook, to which my mother-in-law, never one to comment on my music nonsense, chimed in with &amp;quot;hope he&amp;#39;s right.&amp;quot; Here&amp;#39;s hoping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The song appears on &lt;em&gt;A Flower That Wouldn&amp;#39;t Bloom&lt;/em&gt;, the third full-length from the &lt;a href="http://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;-fronted punk group. The record came out just this past week on &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;. While Danny puts together these albums more-or-less solo in the studio, the live Shapes band includes Ian Romano, David Nardi, Vee Bell, and Roddy Rosetti.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mB_bFqg-TwQ" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/mB_bFqg-TwQ" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Ancient Shapes - &amp;quot;Welland 2020&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s ongoing tour brought them through St. John&amp;#39;s last week, with the popular quartet playing a show at the city&amp;#39;s Club One. Support for that gig came from local punks &lt;a href="http://ccconditionerrr.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Conditioner&lt;/a&gt;, and they made the most of the spotlight by releasing a pair of new songs to coincide with the event. The group, who last released a self-titled EP in 2017, have the new tracks &amp;quot;My Way Back (2 U)&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Room For Two&amp;quot; online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m utterly polish-averse when it comes to punk these days, so the new Conditioner jams hit just the right spot for me. There are some huge pop-punk hooks wrapped in these blown out, low-fi recordings. Micah Brown mixed and mastered these new tracks, which the band self-recorded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=746835120/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ccconditionerrr.bandcamp.com/album/singles"&gt;SINGLES by CONDITIONER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://ccconditionerrr.bandcamp.com/album/singles" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Conditioner - &amp;quot;My Way Back (2 U)&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Room For Two&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;If that&amp;#39;s got you in the mood for more satisfyingly shout-along low-budget punk, check the new recording from Ottawa trio &lt;a href="http://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Tenenbaums&lt;/a&gt;. The three-piece has a new track online titled &amp;quot;New Year, Who&amp;#39;s This?,&amp;quot; the group&amp;#39;s first studio recording since their 2015 EP &lt;em&gt;We&amp;#39;ll Always Have Milhouse&lt;/em&gt;. The Tenenbaums tracked this one with Matt Post of &lt;a href="https://buysomedeathsticks.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deathsticks&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NotMyCarRecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Not My Car&lt;/a&gt; label working the boards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=688001680/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com/track/new-year-who-s-this"&gt;New year, who’s this? by The Tenenbaums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://thetenenbaums.bandcamp.com/track/new-year-who-s-this" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Tenenbaums - &amp;quot;New year, who’s this?&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://thenoisymountain.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WHOOP-Szo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s highly anticipated &lt;em&gt;Warrior Down&lt;/em&gt; arrives this Friday. The final preview of the London/Guelph collective&amp;#39;s new record came last week in the form of the intense single &amp;quot;Long Braided Hair.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the third song we&amp;#39;ve heard from the grunge/folk/sludge record, and it arrived paired with a video from &lt;a href="https://www.stephyates.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steph V Yates&lt;/a&gt;. In a statement, guitarist/vocalist Adam Sturgeon recalled a story that inspired the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Our connection to the Earth Mother is through our hair, and it is our Mother who brings us to this earth. A Braid, 3 strands, mind, body and soul... sweetgrass, hair of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I remember getting a call on the distant telephone wires from my bandmate Kirsten. She was up north. Winter was settling in hard and she was upset. That day, her students who had been out of control for some time dropped a heavy weight onto her privileged disposition. They were sleeping on and under desks and they were bouncing off the walls. They were upset, angry and unable to hide their emotions. Sometime earlier she had overheard some of the other teachers griping about how disrespectful the children were being, and how discipline was a necessary force to overcoming their challenging circumstances. How using their language was somehow related to the kids picking on each other and to speak French or English was to abide by the rules of the school. Kirsten, as she always does, slipped quietly out of the staff room without a word. When this had continued for several stressful days, perhaps weeks she asked the children &amp;quot;what&amp;#39;s wrong?&amp;quot;. They did not answer, but their eyes told another story. This continued, until finally one day they answered almost as if in unison &amp;#39;We&amp;#39;re hungry&amp;#39;. You see, in the months previous a desperately needed breakfast program had been cancelled. By whom, I&amp;#39;m not sure. By the school board? By the volunteers who were burned out and moved back home to the south?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In our communities, it is our mothers and children that have bore the weight of colonialism. That our ways of life have been diminished by a system designed against us. A $7 can of pop, a $5 chocolate bar, and $9 bag of chips. A lullaby.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warrior Down&lt;/em&gt; drops Friday, November 1 on &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;. Kyle Ashbourne recorded and mixed the 10-song set at the Sugar Shack in London, ON, with additional drum tracking by Sturgeon and Nathan Lamb at the Out of Sound House. WHOOP-Szo features guitarist/vocalist Adam Sturgeon, Kirsten Kurvink Palm on guitar, synth, and vocals, bassist/keyboardist Joe Thorner, Andrew Lennox on 12-string guitar and synth, and drummer Eric Lourenco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new record follows 2016&amp;#39;s EP &lt;em&gt;Citizen&amp;#39;s Ban(ne)d Radio&lt;/em&gt;, a 2017 split with Halifax psych group &lt;a href="https://walrustheband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Walrus&lt;/a&gt;, and last year&amp;#39;s 7&amp;quot; single &lt;em&gt;The Dive&lt;/em&gt;. The WHOOP-Szo will &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/WHOOPszo/events/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;tour&lt;/a&gt; behind the record throughout November, playing shows with &lt;a href="https://chastitysongs.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chastity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://motherhoodmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Motherhood&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://fetnat.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FET.NAT&lt;/a&gt;, on various stops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LTqmoZJPyAA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LTqmoZJPyAA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: WHOOP-Szo - &amp;quot;Long Braided Hair&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver post-punk group &lt;a href="http://spectresvancouver.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Spectres&lt;/a&gt; has a new single out. The band&amp;#39;s new 7&amp;quot; showcases two songs recorded with Felix Fung back in 2017 at New Westminster&amp;#39;s Little Red Sounds. The release features the authentically 80s goth vibes of &amp;quot;Provincial Wake,&amp;quot; backed by Smiths-flavoured &amp;quot;Northern Towns.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s available through &lt;a href="https://sabotagerecords-shop.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sabotage Records&lt;/a&gt; now, and marks the band&amp;#39;s first new material since their 2016 LP &lt;em&gt;Utopia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Spectres have shown up in this publication a few times over the years, as the band&amp;#39;s shared members with both &lt;a href="https://sorepoints.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sore Points&lt;/a&gt; and the now-defunct &lt;a href="https://nightpeoplepunk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Night People&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3472350924/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://spectresvancouver.bandcamp.com/album/provincial-wake"&gt;Provincial Wake by Spectres&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://spectresvancouver.bandcamp.com/album/provincial-wake" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Spectres - &amp;quot;Provincial Wake&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Northern Towns&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week the Toronto synthpop duo &lt;a href="http://ice-creamtheband.tumblr.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt; released the third single from their upcoming record &lt;em&gt;Fed Up&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;quot;Dove&amp;#39;s Cry&amp;quot; arrived with a video directed by the band&amp;#39;s Carlyn Bezic, described as a &amp;quot;shopping fantasy, in which a liquid soap can produce self-love.&amp;quot; The track shows off one of the album&amp;#39;s more subdued tunes, standing in dramatic contrast to the club-ready first single &amp;quot;Peanut Butter&amp;quot; and the spaced-out &amp;quot;Modern Life.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fed Up&lt;/em&gt;, the band&amp;#39;s sophomore album, arrives November 15. The 8-song set follows up the group&amp;#39;s 2016 debut &lt;em&gt;Love, Ice Cream&lt;/em&gt;, with Tony Price co-producing the album with the band. Ice Cream features Carlyn Bezic and Amanda Crist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jMo2s8quWkw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jMo2s8quWkw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Ice Cream - &amp;quot;Doves Cry&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://handdrawndracula.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hand Drawn Dracula&lt;/a&gt; recently released &lt;em&gt;Hi-Action&lt;/em&gt;, the new full-length from Toronto &amp;#39;space-motorik&amp;#39; trio &lt;a href="https://mimico.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mimico&lt;/a&gt;. The album dropped alongside a video for &amp;quot;Tobacco Eyes,&amp;quot; one of six sprawling songs from the set. Directed by Christopher Mills (FRIGS, Tallies), the clip puts the band&amp;#39;s live performance through a kaleidoscope, with a sea of visual effects washing over the 7-plus minute track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The psych-rock trio recorded &lt;em&gt;Hi-Action&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href="http://domakesaythink.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Do Make Say Think&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Justin Small producing. They worked on the album at the famous Bathhouse Studio and Toronto&amp;#39;s Palace Sound. Mimico features the talents of Ben Oginz, Jeremiah Knight, and Nick Kervin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9wTUNoYl73g" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/9wTUNoYl73g" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Mimico - &amp;quot;Tobacco Eyes&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s been an uncertain road to the first studio recording from Halifax indie-pop group &lt;a href="https://thestaples77.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Staples&lt;/a&gt;, but after a period of inactivity, it&amp;#39;s finally here. The Staples arose following the implosion of garage punk act the &lt;a href="https://fatstupids.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fat Stupids&lt;/a&gt;, but the group hit a few stumbling blocks getting these recordings out. The band&amp;#39;s first release has finally arrived as a 7-song EP titled &lt;em&gt;Torn&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s worth the wait, though, as these songs are awash in cool vocal harmonies, making tracks like &amp;quot;Can&amp;#39;t&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Starry Skies&amp;quot; just remarkably compelling and full of character.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This recording features Matty Grace and Coleman Johnston of &lt;a href="https://futuregirls.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Future Girls&lt;/a&gt;, Craig Hamlin of &lt;a href="https://tongandeathgrip.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Togan Death Grip&lt;/a&gt;, with Tye Springall (of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/thenoisylifepodcast" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Noisy Life&lt;/a&gt; podcast among other projects). Grace and Hamlin both played in Fat Stupids before The Staples formed. It remains to be seen if The Staples get back on stage anytime soon, but here&amp;#39;s hoping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2810861228/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thestaples77.bandcamp.com/album/torn-ep"&gt;torn ep by The Staples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://thestaples77.bandcamp.com/album/torn-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Staples - &lt;em&gt;Torn EP&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto jangle-pop quartet &lt;a href="http://ducksunlimitedband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ducks Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; has signed with Spanish label &lt;a href="https://bobointegral.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bobo Integral&lt;/a&gt; for the release of their debut EP. Titled &lt;em&gt;Get Bleak&lt;/em&gt;, the four-song 7&amp;quot; is set to arrive on November 29. That four will include the previously previewed title track (which you may recall featured Laura Hermiston of &lt;a href="https://www.twistofficial.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Twist&lt;/a&gt;) and the new single &amp;quot;Anhedonia.&amp;quot; You can check that one out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ducks Unlimited will play a record release show on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2511481175738378/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;December 5&lt;/a&gt; in Toronto at The Baby G, with support from Mark Grundy&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.brokejoken.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Quaker Parents&lt;/a&gt; and Madeline Link&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://madelink.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PAX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RF2SqoXIEDE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/RF2SqoXIEDE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Ducks Unlimited - &amp;quot;Anhedonia&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Andrew Woods&amp;#39; off-kilter yacht-rock project &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/legalvertigo/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Legal Vertigo&lt;/a&gt; has a new single up. &amp;quot;Feelin&amp;#39; Finite&amp;quot; will appear on the project&amp;#39;s debut full-length &lt;em&gt;Tragic Future Film Star&lt;/em&gt; on November 15. It&amp;#39;s due from &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;. The new track was accompanied by a video directed by fellow singer/songwriter &lt;a href="http://basiabulat.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Basia Bulat&lt;/a&gt;. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Based in Montreal, Woods and Bulat have been collaborating on this project for a few years. The act originally performed under the name Napster Vertigo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/diXlpSWq3H4" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/diXlpSWq3H4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Legal Vertigo - &amp;quot;Feelin&amp;#39; Finite&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Back in September, we learned of &lt;em&gt;Lost Wisdom pt. 2&lt;/em&gt;, a sequel to the 2008 collaboration between Moncton singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://juliedoiron.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Julie Doiron&lt;/a&gt; and Phil Elverum&amp;#39;s Washinton-based &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PWElverum" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mount Eerie&lt;/a&gt;. A new song from the album is now online, titled &amp;quot;Belief pt. 2.&amp;quot; Elverum commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Belief pt. 2&amp;#39; is the last song on the album. It comes at the end of a meandering path through uncertainty, devotion, sad reminiscence, hopeful idealism; songs coursing over uneven terrain. This album conclusion is a flag planted, a declaration of belief in love no matter what, the culminating answer to all of the asking that came before. Eroded down by life&amp;#39;s changes to an elemental necessity, I make an offering of a final simple gesture of love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Julie and I recorded this song at night with the doors and windows all the way open, hoping to get the nighthawks and night air onto the recording. The other songs were recorded during the day, but this song is a night song. We tried to make our version of sacred music, under stars in the high dark cool air.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The record arrives on November 8 release on the &lt;a href="http://www.pwelverumandsun.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;P.W. Elverum &amp;amp; Sun&lt;/a&gt; label.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LsvQkuwMb0Y" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LsvQkuwMb0Y" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Mount Eerie with Julie Doiron - &amp;quot;Belief pt. 2&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Against The Pavement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-20-against-the-pavement/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-20-against-the-pavement/</id>
    <published>2019-10-19T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-23T09:42:26-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve joked in this newsletter that I can&amp;#39;t keep track of how many bands feature &lt;a href="http://robbiebrake.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Robbie Brake&lt;/a&gt;. Recording out of London, Ontario, Brake seems cursed to singlehandedly churn out more material than any single group could hope to contain. This year alone, he&amp;#39;s contributed to new tunes from the power-pop group &lt;a href="https://isolationparty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Isölation Party&lt;/a&gt;, the three-piece garage-punk act &lt;a href="https://mononegatives.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mononegatives&lt;/a&gt;, the similarly motivated two-piece &lt;a href="https://klazo.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Klazo&lt;/a&gt;, and a surf rock side-project dubbed &lt;a href="https://hookandthecreeps.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hook and the Creeps&lt;/a&gt;. On top of that, he remains an active member of the glam-punk act &lt;a href="https://dongvegan.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dong Vegan&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, and then there&amp;#39;s solo material on top of that. Quite frankly, I&amp;#39;m unclear on how one individual manages that level of creative plate spinning. Hell, I can barely get this newsletter out weekly, and 80% of that&amp;#39;s just copying and pasting links from Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I suppose I shouldn&amp;#39;t feed his addiction, but I happen to be absolutely &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; for the 70s-indebted punk sound that&amp;#39;s so broken the mind of Robbie Brake. I&amp;#39;m thus thrilled to debut the latest band in his legion: the spastic synth-punk act &lt;a href="https://isolationparty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telegenic Pleasure&lt;/a&gt;! The group&amp;#39;s a duo, bridging London, Ontario and its&amp;#39; namesake over in the United Kingdom. From that side of the pond, Telegenic Pleasure features the blown-out vocals of Marco Palumbo Rodriguez. You may know him from &lt;a href="https://wandarecords.bandcamp.com/album/gag-on-this-the-complete-singles" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Gaggers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://miscalculations.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Miscalculations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Brake tracked Telegenic Pleasure&amp;#39;s breakneck instrumentals in a converted pantyhose factory in London (Ontario). Rodriguez recorded his cyborg yelps on his end, with engineer Preston Lobzun mixing the results somewhere in between (let&amp;#39;s assume some third London, because why not). The results have roots in the Buzzcocks and Devo, finding common cause with the robot armies of The Spits, The Epoxies, Dutchess Says, and New Vogue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band&amp;#39;s 8-track debut is due for an official release in mid-November from &lt;a href="http://www.nofrontteeth.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Front Teeth Records&lt;/a&gt;. As Brake&amp;#39;s unable to take his foot off the gas, a second 12-song sophomore full length is expected to follow in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1279334412/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://telegenicpleasure.bandcamp.com/album/telegenic-pleasure"&gt;Telegenic Pleasure by Telegenic Pleasure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://telegenicpleasure.bandcamp.com/album/telegenic-pleasure" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Telegenic Pleasure - &amp;quot;Sealed Off&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Solem Vancouver indie-rock act &lt;a href="https://woolworm.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Woolworm&lt;/a&gt; recently shared the second new single from &lt;em&gt;Awe&lt;/em&gt;. Titled &amp;quot;Let Me Wear The Mask,&amp;quot; the song will appear on upcoming 12-song full-length, the band&amp;#39;s third LP. It arrives on November 8 from &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In a statement frontman Giles Roy commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;This song felt like it was about so many different things during the writing process, and it ended up being sort of abstract as a result. When we play it, I think of my own destructive tendencies, as well my attempts to curb them with what amounts to dishonesty. Sometimes I find genuine release in that escapism. That said, hopefully people will find their own meaning here. That&amp;#39;s really what I want for all of our music.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Woolworm recorded and mixed this record with their Mint labelmate &lt;a href="https://jayarner.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jay Arner&lt;/a&gt;. The new set follows the group&amp;#39;s 2017 LP &lt;em&gt;Deserve to Die&lt;/em&gt;, but strikes a decidedly different tone than that hardcore-influenced sophomore effort. A record release show has been scheduled for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2322877178022891/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;November 15&lt;/a&gt; at the Red Gate in Vancouver, with support from Juice, Outpatient, and Kamikaze Nurse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Woolworm features Giles Roy on guitars and vocals, guitarist Alex Pomeroy, bassist Heather Black, and drummer Nick Tolliday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3845227047/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2839694658/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://woolworm.bandcamp.com/album/awe"&gt;AWE by WOOLWORM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://woolworm.bandcamp.com/track/let-me-wear-the-mask" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Woolworm - &amp;quot;Let Me Wear The Mask&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Peter Johnson of the Toronto post-hardcore act &lt;a href="https://low--sun.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Low Sun&lt;/a&gt; is hitting the road this week in his &lt;a href="https://tanginternetpropaganda.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tang&lt;/a&gt; guise for a tour of the U.S. midwest. He&amp;#39;ll be playing alongside Milwaukee&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://cairnsmke.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cairns&lt;/a&gt;. This will be Johnson&amp;#39;s first solo tour as the pensive, low-fi Tang, promising a set filled with &amp;quot;scratchy 4 track loops&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;warm, droney experimentation[s] of songs&amp;quot; re-interpreted from the band&amp;#39;s studio recordings. The tour kicks off on the 23rd and runs through the 27th with shows in Wisconsin and Michigan. Check Tang&amp;#39;s website for the full routing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;To help promote the trek, Tang released a video featuring a new song, recorded live at The Be Droom (your guess is as good as mine for what or where that is, but it sounds suitably ominous). A full-band version of the song, titled &amp;quot;Blurred Landscape,&amp;quot; is due to appear on Tang&amp;#39;s next full-length. You can check out this version out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The upcoming Tang record is due in December from &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt;. It will follow up 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Super Happy&lt;/em&gt;, which I can assure you was anything but.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/12rcmC3RqVQ" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/12rcmC3RqVQ" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Tang - &amp;quot;Blurred Landscape&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Madeline Link&amp;#39;s low-fi project &lt;a href="https://madelink.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PAX&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for the song &amp;quot;Clingfilm,&amp;quot; a b-side from their recent EP &lt;em&gt;Eat Me&lt;/em&gt;. The clip, directed by Link&amp;#39;s sister Eva, features her band cavorting around in a park while dressed for a Renaissance fair that doesn&amp;#39;t appear to be happening. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While initially a bedroom recording project, PAX recently grew into a full band featuring Madeline backed by guitarist Dexter Nash, bassist Noah O&amp;#39;Neil, and drummer Shane Hooper. The group&amp;#39;s last physical release was the full-length &lt;em&gt;Ouch&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt;. The Link sisters just last week released &lt;em&gt;Big Time&lt;/em&gt;, their first full-length as the jangle-pop duo &lt;a href="https://triplesband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Triples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Baq1nEGZ-G8" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Baq1nEGZ-G8" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: PAX - &amp;quot;Clingfilm&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;We&amp;#39;ve got one more note from the Uncarved Block family before we move on this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Toronto low-fi post-punk trio &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/whatisfond/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fond&lt;/a&gt; recently premiered another track from their new EP &lt;em&gt;Vern&lt;/em&gt;. You can check out the song &amp;quot;Against The Pavement&amp;quot; below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Fond will launch the 5-song cassette release this week with a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/405890876735653/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;show&lt;/a&gt; at the Owls Club on October 24, supported by locals &lt;a href="https://dartsbud.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dart Mouth&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://nigelnigel.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nigel Nigel&lt;/a&gt;. The Meat Puppets-inspired group brings together Ryan Naray of Animal Faces and Soft Floors, Zach Van Horne of Creeper, and label-co-head Rob Johnson (also of Low Sun and Shahman).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/681290738&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/artoftheuncarvedblock/against-the-pavement" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Fond - &amp;quot;Against The Pavement&amp;quot; @ SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://kristeljax.com/bardont.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brigitte Bardon&amp;#39;t&lt;/a&gt;, the stage name of Toronto drone-pop artist Kristel Jax, has a new full-length on the way titled &lt;em&gt;Radio Songs&lt;/em&gt;. The twelve-track collection of sound collages is the result of a series of field recordings recorded over the past five years. Each track showcases a different town, with recordings made in Canada, the U.S., and Italy. &lt;a href="https://alreadydeadtapes.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Already Dead Tapes&lt;/a&gt; will release &lt;em&gt;Radio Songs&lt;/em&gt; as a cassette on November 1. The label commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Here, Bardon&amp;#39;t&amp;#39;s haunting vocals are absent — these twelve tracks feature only radio and field recordings, layered, collaged, sampled back, slowed, or recorded straight in one shot. Inspired by DJ Screw, Maria Chavez, Christian Marclay, and Nike7up, these noise and pop compositions dial into the radio as an emotional barometer of place and time.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can preview &amp;quot;I Wonder,&amp;quot; the track Jax crafted from the aural flotsam of Toronto, below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Along with Brigitte Bardon&amp;#39;t, Jax has worked on the multi-media project O / L, the radio series &lt;a href="http://kristeljax.com/poolside.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Infinite Poolside&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="http://kristeljax.com/therapy.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drone Therapy Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. In 2019 she released a 7&amp;quot; split single on &lt;a href="https://noexist4vr.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Exist&lt;/a&gt; with Turkey&amp;#39;s Okay Vivian. That record found Jax performing a cover of Chris Isaak&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Wicked Game&amp;quot; set to a series of shortwave radio recordings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c76xmzlqkb8" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/c76xmzlqkb8" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Brigitte Bardon&amp;#39;t - &amp;quot;I Wonder&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A new album from the experimental folk project &lt;a href="http://anamaimusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;ANAMAI&lt;/a&gt; has been announced. The duo will release &lt;em&gt;Dream Baby&lt;/em&gt; on October 25 on the &lt;a href="https://haloclinetrance.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Halocline Trance&lt;/a&gt; label. It&amp;#39;s a 9-song set that includes &amp;quot;The Holder&amp;quot; (we previewed that one in the summer) and the title track that you can hear below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A press release from the label attempts to encapsulate the low-key group&amp;#39;s sound, claiming:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;...soft sounds to dent skin and flesh. The music is naked and exquisitely personal, threatening banality, but mainly an embrace of the commune. Dramatic and confidential anthems of divine insignificance. Across three studio albums the project has explored the nature of intimacy with tiny confessions released into vast lakes of sound. Simple songs punctuated by clusters of detail. The project is built on contradictions: traditional yet modern; miniscule yet infinite; proud but deflated. Something for everyone and nothing to no one. A search for peace?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;ANAMAI&amp;#39;s atmospheric, minimalist folk music comes courtesy of Anna Mayberry (formerly of Toronto sludge punks &lt;a href="https://hsy666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;HSY&lt;/a&gt;) and David Psutka (of &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/egyptrixx" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Egyptrixx&lt;/a&gt; and ACT!). The group last released the full-length &lt;em&gt;What Mountain&lt;/em&gt; in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2367576224/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://anamaimusic.bandcamp.com/album/dream-baby-htra009"&gt;Dream Baby (HTRA009) by Anamai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://anamaimusic.bandcamp.com/album/dream-baby-htra009" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Anamai - &amp;quot;Dream Baby&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.simonerecords.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Simone Records&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a new single from the prolific singer-songwriter &lt;a href="https://danyplacard.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dany Placard&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Pulperie&amp;quot; finds the Montreal musician branching further from his folk-rock roots to land in trippy late-60s psychedelia. The song arrived alongside a video from director Ariel Poupart that really drives home the artist&amp;#39;s hallucinogenic new direction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new single is due for Placard&amp;#39;s upcoming full-length &lt;em&gt;J&amp;#39;connais rien à l&amp;#39;astronomie&lt;/em&gt;, which is due in early 2020. Dany Placard last released &lt;em&gt;Full Face&lt;/em&gt; in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5bfwgHRKl8Q" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/5bfwgHRKl8Q" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Dany Placard - &amp;quot;Pulperie&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s laid-back alt-pop quintet &lt;a href="https://nutrientsmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nutrients&lt;/a&gt; recently released a video for &amp;quot;Hide &amp;amp; Seek,&amp;quot; the second single from their upcoming self-titled debut. In a statement the band commented on the tune:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;[Hide &amp;amp; Seek] is all about recreating the excitement of your first taste of adolescent independence. The room was dark, and faint whispers made their way to your ears from mysterious directions. The time for silence was nigh, however. The game was about to start. We&amp;#39;re playing hide and seek, and that feeling of the neverending night ahead was like a rare, illicit elixir. Who knows what&amp;#39;s in store?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Like the earlier released &amp;quot;Such Slime,&amp;quot; this track features a retro-styled video from Issac Roberts. Nutrients started as a Montreal-based bedroom-pop project from vocalist Taylor Teeple. Since relocating to Toronto, Teepe&amp;#39;s built out a full band featuring guitarist Will Hunter, drummer Turner Wigginton, bassist Sean McKee, and keyboardist Iulia Ciobanu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lT1aELU3wVc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/lT1aELU3wVc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Nutrients - &amp;quot;Hide &amp;amp; Seek&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://casperskulls.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Casper Skulls&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; vocalist Melanie St-Pierre recently debuted a solo act with the name of &lt;a href="https://lloop.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;l&amp;#39;loop&lt;/a&gt;. She premiered the new bedroom recording project with the song &amp;quot;Valleys&amp;quot; and an accompanying music video. St-Pierre commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I started l&amp;#39;loop in the spring of 2019 while I was writing the rest of the new Casper Skulls record. I wanted to get more familiar with recording myself and exploring my love for ambient. While Casper may be bold, l&amp;#39;loop is tender and lo-fi. Exploring these two aspects is very exciting and keeping creative is so therapeutic to me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Valleys&amp;quot; features looping instrumentals and St-Pierre&amp;#39;s etherial folk-rock vocals, with percussion provided by Casper Skulls bassist Fraser McClean. Rivka Ravede of the Philadelphia band Spirit of the Beehive created the animated video for the track. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Casper Skulls last released the full-length &lt;em&gt;Mercy Works&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://buzzrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Buzz Records&lt;/a&gt;. The follow-up to that LP is currently in the works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yFoLYkHkqQc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/yFoLYkHkqQc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: L&amp;#39;loop - &amp;quot;Valleys&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Later this week Ben Cook will release &lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt;, his second full-length of the year as &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt;. A final preview of the album arrived last week in the form of &amp;quot;She&amp;#39;s a Fantasy,&amp;quot; the power-pop record&amp;#39;s lead track. You can check it out below, and good luck getting this one out of your head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt; will arrive from &lt;a href="http://www.runforcoverrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover Records&lt;/a&gt; on Friday. It follows the &lt;em&gt;GUV I&lt;/em&gt; installment from this past summer. Cook&amp;#39;s last release as Young Guv was 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;2 Sad 2 Funk&lt;/em&gt;. In the year since that album, he&amp;#39;s put out acclaimed work as part of the Toronto hardcore groups &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-O9b9q5PVik" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/-O9b9q5PVik" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Young Guv - &amp;quot;She&amp;#39;s A Fantasy&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;90s-era Vancouver glam-punk act &lt;a href="https://theblackhalos.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Black Halos&lt;/a&gt; are back in action. The newest incarnation of the memorable B.C. group brings together original vocalist Billy Hopeless, guitarist/vocalist Rich Jones and guitarist Jay Millette with a new rhythm section featuring bassist John Kern and drummer Danni Action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The group&amp;#39;s first new release together will be a limited edition colour 7&amp;quot; on London&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://yeahrightrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yeah Right Records&lt;/a&gt;. The set will feature the new songs &amp;quot;Geisterbahn II&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Tandem Down,&amp;quot; both of which were mixed by the legendary Seattle grunge producer Jack Endino. It drops Christmas Day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A new full-length from the group is due in 2020. The Black Halos first got together in 1993 as the Black Market Babies, with the band&amp;#39;s debut LP not arriving until &amp;#39;99. The group&amp;#39;s original run lasted until 2008, with the band first reforming for select live performances in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2947630927/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://yeahrightrecords.bandcamp.com/album/geisterbahn-ii-7"&gt;Geisterbahn II 7" by The Black Halos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://yeahrightrecords.bandcamp.com/track/tandem-drown" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Black Halos - &amp;quot;Tandem Down&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It took me a while to wrap my head around Hamilton dream-pop group &lt;a href="https://www.basementrevolver.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Basement Revolver&lt;/a&gt;, but the group&amp;#39;s new single (the second from their upcoming EP) finally clicked for me. &amp;quot;Have I Been Deceived&amp;quot; comes from the shoegaze-influenced group&amp;#39;s new &lt;a href="http://www.sonicunyon.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sonic Unyon&lt;/a&gt; release &lt;em&gt;Wax and Digital&lt;/em&gt;. The track (which boasts some serious Cranberries vibes) reflects upon the religious upbringing of guitarist/vocalist Chrisy Hurn. She commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Think about &amp;#39;Have I Been Deceived&amp;#39; as an open letter to God. This past year, I have been feeling like I was brainwashed. I was taught to think in a particular manner, taught to love in a specific way, taught to think about my body and sexuality in a specific (ahem oppressive) way, and quite honestly at the time, I ate that shit up. I was the girl in highschool trying to convert all my friends, telling everyone to stay abstinent, listening to every Christian band that sounded almost as good as the real thing. That was my entire identity. Throughout my twenties, this identity fell apart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve become increasingly uncomfortable with who I was, so much that being around any type of Christian culture, makes me feel nauseous, or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I want to let that go, I want to think clearly about faith, but I am afraid that I am not able to. I am afraid that I was gaslighted into loving something that is wrong or an ugly version of something that could be good. I don&amp;#39;t know who I am without my past. I don&amp;#39;t know who I am moving forward. I wish I had a more clear answer but I don&amp;#39;t; I am just here.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Basement Revolver recorded with producer Ian Gomes (Greys, Frigs, Odonis Odonis). The group features Chrisy Hurn on vocals and guitar, guitarist Jonathan Malström, bassist Nimal Agalawatte, and drummer Brandon Munro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p6zOQZSn7qA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/p6zOQZSn7qA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Basement Revolver - &amp;quot;Have I Been Deceived&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of 90s vibes, there&amp;#39;s a new single out from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://maybekindasorta.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Maybe Kinda Sorta&lt;/a&gt;, a preview of that project&amp;#39;s forthcoming EP. &amp;quot;Sit Around&amp;quot; will appear on the matter-of-factly titled &lt;em&gt;Another EP&lt;/em&gt;, which is due on Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Maybe Kinds Sorta is the songwriting project of Brent Fulop, the former drummer for the now-defunct Welland, Ontario punk group &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thesnipsmusic/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Snips&lt;/a&gt;. As with Fulop&amp;#39;s other recordings under this name, this track was produced by &lt;a href="https://marvelousmark.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mark Fosco&lt;/a&gt; (Marvelous Mark of the Marvelous Darlings) at the Fuzz Co studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3510768418/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://maybekindasorta.bandcamp.com/track/sit-around"&gt;Sit Around by Maybe Kinda Sorta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://maybekindasorta.bandcamp.com/track/sit-around" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Maybe Kinda Sorta - &amp;quot;Sit Around&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Page&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://expandafuzz.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Expanda Fuzz&lt;/a&gt; continues to tease his next solo LP through a series of interesting covers. This time out, the Ottawa-area artist shared a laid-back rendition of PJ Harvey&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Yuri-G.&amp;quot; It follows Page&amp;#39;s earlier take on the INXS single &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Change.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Expanda Fuzz last released &lt;em&gt;Cotton Candy Jet Engine&lt;/em&gt; in 2018. Page is perhaps best known for his time recording as part of &lt;a href="http://campradio.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Camp Radio&lt;/a&gt; and before that as a member of the 90s pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://thestandgt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Stand GT&lt;/a&gt;. This upcoming record will follow up his 2015 LP &lt;em&gt;Volume Vs. Voice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2521738698/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrispage.bandcamp.com/track/yuri-g-pj-harvey-cover"&gt;Yuri-G (PJ Harvey cover) by Chris Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/track/yuri-g-pj-harvey-cover" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chris Page - &amp;quot;Yuri-G&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver&amp;#39;s sea shanty-themed folk-punk act &lt;a href="http://thedreadnoughts.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dreadnoughts&lt;/a&gt; have a new record due on November 15, titled &lt;em&gt;Into The North&lt;/em&gt;. In a statement the group commented on the recording process:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Holed up for a week in a small wooden cabin with nothing but whiskey in our glasses, four microphones in front of us, and hordes of mosquitoes outside singing along, we belted these damn songs over and over until we had them just right, and the result is the album we&amp;#39;ve always wanted to make.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can hear the album&amp;#39;s first single, &amp;quot;Joli Rouge,&amp;quot; below. It&amp;#39;s a drinking song about an actual product, a cider produced by the soon-to-launch &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/cidrejolirouge/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Joli Rouge&lt;/a&gt; producer out of Chicoutimi, Quebec. &lt;em&gt;Into The North&lt;/em&gt; will arrive via &lt;a href="https://stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2516439092/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=333643471/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thedreadnoughts.bandcamp.com/album/into-the-north"&gt;Into The North by The Dreadnoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://thedreadnoughts.bandcamp.com/album/into-the-north" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Dreadnoughts - &amp;quot;Joli Rouge&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Punknews.org recently premiered a new single from the Brantford, Ontario pop-punk band &lt;a href="https://www.fortunecovemusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fortune Cove&lt;/a&gt;. Titled &amp;quot;Direction,&amp;quot; the track arrived alongside a video that you can see below. The song will appear on the band&amp;#39;s new full-length for &lt;a href="www.fourchordmusic.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Four Chord Music&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;Dear Happiness&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s due on November 22.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Formerly known as Harbour, Fortune Cove will be supporting the record with a fall tour of Ontario, Quebec, and the U.S. east coast, playing with bands like The Letdown and Rival Town on select dates. You can snag that itinerary over at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/71063/exclusivevideos-fortune-cove-direction" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bez8GFOQ9PE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/bez8GFOQ9PE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Fortune Cove - &amp;quot;Direction&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lying Signal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-13-lying-signal/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-13-lying-signal/</id>
    <published>2019-10-12T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T00:46:36-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve never noticed (and let&amp;#39;s be honest, you have better things to do, but humour me here), I always date these newsletters to the Sunday of the week they&amp;#39;re covering. That&amp;#39;s mostly because it reflects the content, but it also denotes which slice of my dwindling free time was given to compiling it. What it doesn&amp;#39;t reflect, at least not much these days, is the day I press send. That&amp;#39;s crept out to Mondays and Tuesdays, but as I&amp;#39;ve been trading off timeliness for proof-reading, I don&amp;#39;t mind the lie. You suffered quite enough of my frantic Sunday night typos in the first year anyway.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;All that said, as I wrap this edition, it&amp;#39;s nearly Friday. Friday! Sure, it was a long weekend, and yes, I irresponsibly gave up an extra evening to go see Ancient Shapes and Teenanger be amazing, but that&amp;#39;s just tragically, inexcusably late. My apologies for that, dear reader. I&amp;#39;ll try better to keep up. This edition, as a result, reserves a few newsworthy items from the current week for Sunday the 20th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anyways...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class='bg-black-30 mt4 mb4 maxread bn hr-1'/&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;We&amp;#39;re fast approaching the November 1 release of &lt;em&gt;Warrior Down&lt;/em&gt;, the new full-length from London&amp;#39;s sludgy grunge/folk five-piece &lt;a href="https://thenoisymountain.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WHOOP-Szo&lt;/a&gt;. Last week the band released &amp;quot;Gerry,&amp;quot; a fervent, heartbreaking ode to a fallen member of guitarist/vocalist Adam Sturgeon&amp;#39;s family. The song&amp;#39;s shockingly direct, shedding all pretense and symbolism with its very first verse. You don&amp;#39;t get more straightforward than &amp;quot;My cousin Gerry was shot by a cop.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Travis Welowszky and Sebastian Di Trolio&amp;#39;s accompanying video sets the lyrics against a collage of vintage home movies, the footage becoming more disjointed as the song reaches its crescendo. You can feel the tension rising as the cuts lock in step with Eric Lourenco&amp;#39;s increasingly frantic percussion. You can view the clip below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sturgeon released a statement that sheds some light on his family history:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;My cousin Gerry was shot by a cop. Murdered. In his own home. While the circumstances surrounding his death are unclear, there has only ever been one side to the story, that of the RCMP. No external investigations took place and our family is left without answers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I remember getting a call from Gerry shortly before he died. He was angry about a broken system, slurring his words through the distant telephone line from his home in Saskatchewan. He had taken to calling our house, connecting with my Mom for some much needed love and comfort, my Dad to address his issues with alcohol, and to converse with me about music and art... and to question my passions for my &amp;#39;Dad&amp;#39;s culture&amp;#39;. I&amp;#39;d change the subject, letting him know that the guitar he had given me, my first guitar in fact, was the passion and release that he had offered me and that I wouldn&amp;#39;t trade it for anything. I&amp;#39;d be late for work or some other engagement and have to let him know several times that I needed to hang up the phone. He&amp;#39;d get angry again and start ranting on and I&amp;#39;d have to remind him there were places to be. He called me a sell out and I&amp;#39;d tell him I loved him. I promised I&amp;#39;d visit on tour sometime. I&amp;#39;d tell him he could teach me some more chords.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve driven through the town he died in, but Gerry isn&amp;#39;t there. Where are our protectors when we need them? Why did an officer force his way into Gerry&amp;#39;s home? Why was Gerry shot 4 times and why have these circumstances been justified by a system that leaves the vulnerable under fire?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warrior Down&lt;/em&gt; arrives on November 1 from &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;. Kyle Ashbourne recorded and mixed the 10-song set at the Sugar Shack in London, ON, with additional drum tracking by Sturgeon and Nathan Lamb at the Out of Sound House. WHOOP-Szo features guitarist/vocalist Adam Sturgeon, Kirsten Kurvink Palm on guitar, synth, and vocals, bassist/keyboardist Joe Thorner, Andrew Lennox on 12-string guitar and synth, and drummer Eric Lourenco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new record follows 2016&amp;#39;s EP &lt;em&gt;Citizen&amp;#39;s Ban(ne)d Radio&lt;/em&gt;, a 2017 split with Halifax psych group &lt;a href="https://walrustheband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Walrus&lt;/a&gt;, and last year&amp;#39;s 7&amp;quot; single &lt;em&gt;The Dive&lt;/em&gt;. The band will &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/WHOOPszo/events/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;tour&lt;/a&gt; behind the record in November, playing shows along the way with &lt;a href="https://chastitysongs.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chastity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://motherhoodmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Motherhood&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://fetnat.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FET.NAT&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BzuKXBpTACA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/BzuKXBpTACA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: WHOOP-Szo - &amp;quot;Gerry&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One of the first bands I covered on Some Party, was a Saint John-based four-piece punk group with the rather unfortunate name of &lt;a href="https://rightshitty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Right Shitty&lt;/a&gt;. That band put out a satisfyingly gritty full-length in 2016 titled &lt;em&gt;Bachelor Of Arts&lt;/em&gt;, followed in 2017 by a split with the Ontario noise-duo &lt;a href="https://buysomedeathsticks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deathsticks&lt;/a&gt;. In a lot of ways, finding Right Shitty was incredibly validating when I started this project. Here was a great little punk band of the sort I spent more than a decade championing at Punknews.org, but one I only stumbled upon because of this publication&amp;#39;s stubborn focus on imaginary lines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Since 2017 there hasn&amp;#39;t been much to say about Right Shitty, though. The band&amp;#39;s activity dindled, and they never seemed to venture far outside of New Brunswick. That all changes this week with the surprise release of the band&amp;#39;s second album, &lt;em&gt;Worry Circle&lt;/em&gt;. At some point in the past year the group relocated to Montreal, shuffling a few members out along the way. The new nine-song record features guitarist/vocalist Stephen Ricketts, guitarist Peter Ellefsen, bassist Stuart Buckley, and drummer Pat Bonner. You can preview the blown-out &amp;quot;Lying Signal&amp;quot; and the darker &amp;quot;Tall Dark Shape&amp;quot; below, although given how late I am this week, the whole album should be up on Bandcamp any minute now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1767843962/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://rightshitty.bandcamp.com/album/worry-circle"&gt;Worry Circle by Right Shitty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://rightshitty.bandcamp.com/album/worry-circle" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Right Shitty - &amp;quot;Lying Signal&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Tall Dark Shape&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The highly anticipated new record from Montreal post-punk group &lt;a href="https://corridormtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Corridor&lt;/a&gt; also arrives this week. &lt;a href="https://www.thelineofbestfit.com/new-music/song-of-the-day/corridor-pow/amp" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Line of Best Fit&lt;/a&gt; recently shared the album&amp;#39;s final preview, the vibrant, driving &amp;quot;Pow.&amp;quot; While suitably percussive (given its title), the track memorably features heavily vocoded yodelling at few points. The song joins the previously previewed &amp;quot;Topographe,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Domino&amp;quot; among the ten tracks comprising &lt;em&gt;Junior&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The record&amp;#39;s arriving on &lt;a href="http://www.bonsound.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonsound&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and the legendary &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere, with Corridor holding the distinction of being the first francophone act to join the latter. Produced by Emmanuel Éthier, &lt;em&gt;Junoir&lt;/em&gt; is the band&amp;#39;s third album and follows up to 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Supermercado&lt;/em&gt;. Corridor features Jonathan Robert on vocals, guitar, and synths, with Dominic Berthiaume on vocals and bass, Julian Perreault on guitar, and Julien Bakvis drumming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3686736606/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/license_id=739/tracklist=false/track=2870579288/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://corridormtl.bandcamp.com/track/pow"&gt;Junior by Corridor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://corridormtl.bandcamp.com/track/pow" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Corridor - &amp;quot;Pow&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Friday, October 17 also marks the release of &lt;em&gt;Big Time&lt;/em&gt;, the debut full-length from Toronto jangle-pop duo &lt;a href="https://triplesband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Triples&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt; has the 10-song set streaming online now, with a cassette release to follow soon. The collection follows a few years of one-off digital singles, folding several of those tracks (like the infectious &amp;quot;Hillside&amp;quot;) into its run-time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Triples feature the sisters Eva and Madeline Link. Eva&amp;#39;s previously played bass in the Toronto pop-punk band &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ponyband/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PONY&lt;/a&gt;, while Madeline&amp;#39;s low-fi project &lt;a href="https://madelink.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PAX&lt;/a&gt; recently released a full-length titled &lt;em&gt;Ouch&lt;/em&gt;. Seamus Patterson recorded and produced the tracks comprising &lt;em&gt;Big Time&lt;/em&gt; in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=403180520/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://triplesband.bandcamp.com/album/big-time"&gt;Big Time by Triples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://triplesband.bandcamp.com/album/big-time" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Triples - &lt;em&gt;Big Time&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Raucous Ottawa punk group &lt;a href="https://liquidassets.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Liquid Assets&lt;/a&gt; will make their vinyl debut before the end of the year. The 7&amp;quot; release, which carries the lengthy title &lt;em&gt;SNC Lava Lamp EP: The Return of The Liquid Assets of Ottawa&lt;/em&gt;, will arrive in December from Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://schizophrenicrex.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Schizophrenic Records&lt;/a&gt;. The band will support it with a pair of release parties: a hometown gig at House of TARG on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2341846549365590/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;December 13&lt;/a&gt; and a trip to the Hammer&amp;#39;s Doors Pub on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/901023870274168/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;December 14&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The gig on the 13th will feature with &lt;a href="https://fazefazefaze.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Faze&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://cokejawduh.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Coke Jaw&lt;/a&gt;, and Spirit Cry, a new local supergroup featuring members of Omerta, The CHUDs, Dogma, and others. Coke Jaw comes along for the second show as well, a packed bill that includes &lt;a href="https://getoffthecop.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Get Off The Cop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://sickofshit.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sick of Shit&lt;/a&gt;, Violent Image, and &lt;a href="https://kilgoretheclown.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kilgore the Clown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;There&amp;#39;s no music to share from &lt;em&gt;SNC Lava Lamp&lt;/em&gt; just yet, but here&amp;#39;s a pair of tunes from Liquid Assets&amp;#39; 2018 demo to hold you over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1508277405/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://liquidassets.bandcamp.com/album/demo"&gt;DEMO by Liquid Assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://liquidassets.bandcamp.com/album/demo" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Liquid Assets - 2018 Demo @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a live video of Toronto art-punks &lt;a href="https://deliluh.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deliluh&lt;/a&gt;. The clip, shot by &lt;a href="https://www.colinmedley.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Colin Medley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/margiebrighton" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Margarita Brighton&lt;/a&gt;, features the band performing their new track &amp;quot;Hymn&amp;quot; at the Owls Club in Toronto. That venue&amp;#39;s become fully entwined in the band&amp;#39;s story, serving as their de facto studio and frequent performance space, as documented in the recent short &lt;em&gt;Somewhere Else&lt;/em&gt; by Medley and &lt;a href="https://mariatt.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Maria Todorov-Topouzov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Hymn&amp;quot; will appear on the band&amp;#39;s upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Beneath The Floors&lt;/em&gt;. That 10-song set, due November 15, is the band&amp;#39;s second release of the year following May&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Oath of Intent&lt;/em&gt; EP. Look for it on Telephone Explosion in North America and &lt;a href="https://www.tinangelrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tin Angel&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LZsNLbEl9vo" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LZsNLbEl9vo" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Deliluh - &amp;quot;Hymn&amp;quot; (Live Performance) @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of Telephone Explosion (and not for the last time this week), the label also recently shared a new video for the song &amp;quot;Froggy,&amp;quot; a track from &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/products/andre-ethier-croak-in-the-weeds" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;André Ethier&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s gorgeous new slow-burner &lt;em&gt;Croak in the Weeds&lt;/em&gt;. The above-mentioned Colin Medley also directed this one, with the titular amphibian animated by Seth Scriver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Croak in the Weeds&lt;/em&gt; is the second record in a planned trilogy from the wry &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Deadly_Snakes" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deadly Snakes&lt;/a&gt; frontman. It follows 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Under Grape Leaves&lt;/em&gt;, and like that album was produced in collaboration with producer &lt;a href="http://www.sandroperri.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sandro Perri&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ethier gave some background on the song&amp;#39;s imagery:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I was imagining a pond at the swamp. A pond gets murkier the deeper you dive. Frogs are amphibians. They&amp;#39;re in and out of the pond like it&amp;#39;s no big deal, but we stay mostly on the shore and only peer in. Then, when the weather is right, the pond rises in a mist and we can breathe it too. We can be in the pond but also on the shore.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P-nsvjxp3Ls" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/P-nsvjxp3Ls" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: André Ethier - &amp;quot;Froggy&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One final Telephone Explosion story and I&amp;#39;ll move on!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The label recently announced the next record from Maximilian&amp;#39;  Twig&amp;#39; Turnbull&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://badgeepoque.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Badge Époque Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;, the instrumental sextet&amp;#39;s second of the year following their self-titled album. This set, titled &lt;em&gt;Nature, Man &amp;amp; Woman&lt;/em&gt;, features just three tracks but divides up a near half-hour run-time between them. You can preview the record&amp;#39;s 14-minute b-side, a flute-driven funk number titled &amp;quot;Badge Theme,&amp;quot; at Bandcamp. The a-side opener &amp;quot;Zealous Child&amp;quot; features guest vocals from Toronto singer &lt;a href="https://dorotheapaas.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dorothea Paas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A celebrated multi-instrumentalist, Turnbull&amp;#39;s served as a songwriter and producer for both &lt;a href="http://yousgirls.blogspot.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Girls&lt;/a&gt; and the offshoot rock band &lt;a href="https://darleneshrugg.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Darlene Shrugg&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#39;s also a regular performer in the psych-jazz group &lt;a href="http://thecosmicrange.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Cosmic Range&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4060987747/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://telephoneexplosion.bandcamp.com/album/nature-man-and-woman"&gt;Nature, Man and Woman by Badge Époque Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://telephoneexplosion.bandcamp.com/album/nature-man-and-woman" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Badge Époque Ensemble - &amp;quot;Badge Theme&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Jim Di Gioia at &lt;a href="https://dominionated.ca/feat-instagram/no-gasoline-second-chance-charm/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Domionated&lt;/a&gt; recently turned me on to a scrappy Welland pop-punk group that I somehow overlooked. The four-piece &lt;a href="https://charmband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Charm&lt;/a&gt; released a two-song EP in early September, featuring the driving single &amp;quot;No Gasoline&amp;quot; and the b-side torch song &amp;quot;Second Chance.&amp;quot; Charm strikes a perfect balance between guitar-driven, classicly-minded punk rock and innocent, 60s-flavoured bubblegum pop. While that&amp;#39;s a classic play (hell, it was in some respects the Ramones&amp;#39; whole shtick), Martine&amp;#39;s vocal performance really sells the vintage pop angle. Charm features some heavy hitters from Niagara&amp;#39;s underground rock scene, including members of the frenetic power-pop group &lt;a href="https://bigschoolband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Big School&lt;/a&gt; and the Falls&amp;#39; reigning hardcore kings &lt;a href="https://wildsidehc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wild Side&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Mitch Courtois recorded and mixed these songs in Welland, ON, with Daniel Husayn mastering at the North London Bomb Factory. Courtois also crafted an animated video for the a-side, which you can find below. The new single follows the &amp;quot;U Don&amp;#39;t Talk&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;Lie to Me&amp;quot; pair from January of this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jVZZwW9ETfE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jVZZwW9ETfE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Charm - &amp;quot;No Gasoline&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of cool things I missed on the first round, &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; regulars &lt;a href="https://aquakultre.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Aquakultre&lt;/a&gt; have a new song out. The Halifax-based neo-soul act recently shared the powerful &amp;quot;I Doubt It.&amp;quot; Vocalist Lance Sampson commented on the track, revealing that &lt;a href="https://lidopimienta.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lido Pimienta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s performance at the 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.halifaxpopexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Halifax Pop Explosion&lt;/a&gt; (and the ensuing online controversy) were key inspirations:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wrote &amp;#39;I Doubt It&amp;#39; three days after Lido Pimienta came to Halifax and performed at the Halifax Pop Explosion. Aquakultre performed the next night the same stage at the festival as well. There was a lot of politics behind the Lido Pimienta show. She asks if POC women, brown women, people of different abilities, could come to the front of the stage. One individual didn&amp;#39;t want to move from a position directly at the front to accommodate those that had come forth and a national media storm occurred where a lot of racism and racial discussion was provoked, and... it was wild, it really sucked. It took a while to digest and when it finally did, a few lines in my head started to manifest. &amp;#39;Cause i&amp;#39;m proud/ just control the crowd and we got it.&amp;#39; This line was a testament to myself, because at the time performing terrified me, and to watch someone bless a stage so confidently, and control a crowd so seamlessly, it was inspiring for sure. Sometimes all it takes is a moment in time, or someone else&amp;#39;s&amp;#39; experience that sparks my writing, and once those two lines had come to mind, everything else just fit together like glue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As an artist and a songwriter who has been given an opportunity and platform, I always intend to share my truth. I like to give people a little piece of me with every song. &amp;#39;I Doubt It&amp;#39; is giving people an insight, an understanding of the other side of the game. My experiences come from living a life that I chose to live. Selling drugs, skipping school, hanging out with my homies until 3am, robbing, and stealing. You name it, I&amp;#39;ve done it. This song was sparked by Lido, but written through my experience. When I do present my art and music, it&amp;#39;s mostly to people who have never experienced what I have been through. This song is a representation of the oppressed perspective, so if you just don&amp;#39;t &amp;#39;know&amp;#39;, then I doubt you&amp;#39;ll ever understand where I&amp;#39;m coming from.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pimienta&amp;#39;s visual art serves as the single&amp;#39;s cover, as well. &amp;quot;I Doubt It&amp;quot; was recorded in a residency at the National Music Centre in Calgary (which the band had access to via their 2018 &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/music/events/searchlight" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CBC Searchlight&lt;/a&gt; win). The track features Nick Dourado on piano, keyboards, and saxophone, Jeremy Costello playing bass and mellotron, and percussion from drummer Nathan Doucet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=288533830/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://aquakultre.bandcamp.com/track/i-doubt-it"&gt;I Doubt It by Aquakultre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://aquakultre.bandcamp.com/track/i-doubt-it" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Aquakultre - &amp;quot;I Doubt It&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Early Ottawa punk pioneers &lt;a href="http://porcelainforehead.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Porcelain Forehead&lt;/a&gt; recently uploaded the brunt of their previously hard-to-find recordings to Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Porcelain Forehead came together in 1982 and ran for three years. The group featured vocalist Mike Hillis, guitarist Chris McLellan, bassist Bruce Stevenson, and drummer Ian Seabrook. Geordie Allen took over for Seabrook in &amp;#39;83 and played with the group until they split in &amp;#39;85. The group got back together in 2010 for a series of reunion performances, swapping in &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/426085-Unwarranted-Trust" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Unwarranted Trust&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Janine Frenken on bass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Porcelain Forehead released their debut EP, &lt;em&gt;Right Now! The World Needs a Clear Head&lt;/em&gt;, in 1982, followed by the &lt;em&gt;Frogboy Lives&lt;/em&gt; LP a year later. In their time, the band played with many notable early punk and hardcore groups, sharing the stage with Dead Kennedys, Butthole Surfers, and M.D.C., among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2332764803/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://porcelainforehead.bandcamp.com/album/right-now-the-world-needs-a-clear-head"&gt;Right Now, The World Needs a Clear Head+ by Porcelain Forehead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://porcelainforehead.bandcamp.com/album/right-now-the-world-needs-a-clear-head" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Porcelain Forehead - &lt;em&gt;Right Now, The World Needs a Clear Head&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hockey Dad</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-06-hockey-dad/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-10-06-hockey-dad/</id>
    <published>2019-10-05T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-07T21:22:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;If there are tiers to the Toronto punk world, the new single from &lt;a href="http://www.bikethiefsband.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bike Thiefs&lt;/a&gt; makes a strong case that the trio deserves a slot in a higher bracket. &amp;quot;Hockey Dad&amp;quot; is packed with tricks. It&amp;#39;s built around a driving post-punk instrumental paired with a few distinct vocal movements. The band&amp;#39;s clearly put some thought into how to best utilize Marko Woloshyn&amp;#39;s deadpan, half-spoken delivery, and he&amp;#39;s given a lot to do here with some clever turns of phrase and more than a few engaging shifts in tempo. The song&amp;#39;s greatest asset is that it&amp;#39;s funny, or at least absurdist, while still tackling some heavy topics (addition, namely). That&amp;#39;s a hard balance to strike, but the band never seems like they&amp;#39;re taking the subject too lightly. It&amp;#39;s clear that Bike Thiefs are mocking their narrator&amp;#39;s bluster, not his underlying ailment, and it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Woloshyn, the band&amp;#39;s vocalist and lead guitarist, commented on the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Hockey Dad&amp;#39; is about a friend dealing with drug addiction. It&amp;#39;s heartbreaking to see how polarizing, and frankly exhausting the experience for them (and the people that surround them) can be. They vacillate between feeling like they&amp;#39;re king shit of asshole mountain or a has-been hockey dad trying to hold on to any semblance of past success. You watch as the drugs at times gives them the confidence to spin plates and hold court in crowds of strangers. At other times you watch the crippling anxiety start to dig paranoid foxholes into the middle of their box-spring. It feels like a tired topic, but there&amp;#39;s an opioid crisis in North America, an inordinate amount of high functioning alcoholics and people being hand-fed pharmaceuticals as a band-aid solution to an incomprehensible depression. Maybe not a new idea, but maybe that&amp;#39;s why it&amp;#39;s still important.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Bike Thiefs features Woloshyn alongside bassist Kris Pandierada and drummer Andrew Fasken. &lt;a href="http://beliefsmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beliefs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Josh Korody (The Dirty Nil, Dilly Dally) produced the track. The grammatically-challenged trio are following up their 2017 EP &lt;em&gt;Lean Into It&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/BikeThiefs/events/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;on the road&lt;/a&gt; now. Look for them on tour throughout the U.S. for the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3490828300/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://bikethiefs.bandcamp.com/track/hockey-dad"&gt;Hockey Dad by Bike Thiefs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://bikethiefs.bandcamp.com/track/hockey-dad" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bike Thiefs - &amp;quot;Hockey Dad&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Early last week, Vancouver&amp;#39;s reunited &lt;a href="https://apolloghosts.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Apollo Ghosts&lt;/a&gt; released &lt;em&gt;Living Memory&lt;/em&gt;, and while it&amp;#39;s technically their first full-length in seven years (and the first since their reunion), it&amp;#39;s a far cry from the jangly, lyrically playful indie-rock the band&amp;#39;s been known for. The instrumental &lt;em&gt;Living Memory&lt;/em&gt; is an ambient, piano-driven work from frontman Adrian Teacher. In a statement (that you can read in full at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ApolloGhosts/posts/10156313969266174" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;), Teacher outlines the forces influencing the piece, drawing lines between his father&amp;#39;s collapse into Alzheimer&amp;#39;s, the death of BC&amp;#39;s cedar forests (a result of climate change), and broader struggles tied up in the legacy of colonialism. In short:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Even though cedar trees are not my kin, I still feel despair because they&amp;#39;re dying. I see them everywhere now, when I&amp;#39;m out hiking or just walking around my neighborhood. This album is my attempt to manipulate the grief and despair I feel about climate change. If I can give it a form, maybe I can understand it. Maybe I can feel that grief, listen to it, set it aside briefly, and then try to take action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Many of the songs are expressions of some of my most vivid memories of my father. If I can give those memories form, maybe I can relive them, engage with them, set them aside, and then appreciate the time with my father still left to me. Maybe, when my memory also fades, I can at least listen to the songs for a reminder of my memories of him.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Teacher recorded &lt;em&gt;Living Memory&lt;/em&gt; over the past year, with Dave Carsell mixing the results. All proceeds raised from the sale of the album are due for the &lt;a href="https://cpaws.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Canadian Parks and Wilderness Society&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://unistoten.camp/support-us/donate/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;UNIST&amp;#39;OT&amp;#39;TEN Legal Fund&lt;/a&gt;. A video for the track &amp;quot;Western Red Cedar,&amp;quot; showcasing the trees&amp;#39; decline, is also now online and linked up below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While Apollo Ghosts have technically been inactive since the release of &lt;em&gt;Landmark&lt;/em&gt; in 2012, Teacher&amp;#39;s continued to put out music under a variety of names in the years since. His post-Ghosts acts included &lt;a href="https://thenameofthisbandiscool.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;COOL TV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://adrianteacher.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Adrian Teacher and the Subs&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://arbutus.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arbutus&lt;/a&gt; (which is the closest in style to what you find on this record). In interviews addressing the band&amp;#39;s recent reunion, Teacher commented that, while initially hesitant, he&amp;#39;s since come around to embrace the Ghosts&amp;#39; name and legacy. That explains why an intensely personal work like this has arrived as part of the Apollo Ghosts discography (and from that perspective, our most recent touchpoint shouldn&amp;#39;t be &lt;em&gt;Landmark&lt;/em&gt; at all, but instead the 2018 Subs record &lt;em&gt;Anxious Love&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jd7uwUM-WlA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Jd7uwUM-WlA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Apollo Ghosts - &amp;quot;Western Red Cedar&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3386988840/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://apolloghosts.bandcamp.com/album/living-memory"&gt;Living Memory by Apollo Ghosts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://apolloghosts.bandcamp.com/album/living-memory" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Apollo Ghosts - &lt;em&gt;Living Memory&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week the Toronto electronica group &lt;a href="https://www.holyfuckmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Holy Fuck&lt;/a&gt; detailed their next full-length, a 9-song set titled &lt;em&gt;Deleter&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s due on January 16 from &lt;a href="https://lastgang.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Last Gang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The set includes the recently unveiled single &amp;quot;Luxe,&amp;quot; which we first got our hands on in September. You&amp;#39;ll recall it featured guest vocals from Alexis Taylor of the English synthpop group Hot Chip. Holy Fuck made the announcement alongside the release of a new animated video for &amp;quot;Luxe,&amp;quot; created by Cynthia Alfonso and Óscar Raña. The band commented on the visuals in a statement:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;synesthesia is a big part of the creative process for us; deciding where to pan instruments, how to treat them in the mix, as well as the overall song writing process – you naturally connect it to the visual. It&amp;#39;s then out of our hands the moment we ask someone else to handle artwork and videos. But that&amp;#39;s the most interesting part... &amp;#39;seeing&amp;#39; how someone else sees it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;For the video, Cynthia and Oscar were able to take this visual world of &lt;em&gt;Deleter&lt;/em&gt; to the next dimension, creating a world that feels a lot like the one we lived in when we were in the studio making the record. We love how they distort mundane, industrial, inanimate objects to create something emotional and organic... something so fundamentally human. In the process of bringing things to life, they make them either playful or dangerous. Everything&amp;#39; off-gases.&amp;#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Holy Fuck features Brian Borcherdt and Graham Walsh at the controls, backed by bassist Matt &amp;quot;Punchy&amp;quot; McQuaid and drummer Matt Schulz. They&amp;#39;re following up 2016&amp;#39;s full-length &lt;em&gt;Congrats&lt;/em&gt; and the 2017 &lt;em&gt;Bird Brains&lt;/em&gt; EP with this release. Along with Taylor, the new record features guest appearances from Angus Andrew of Brooklyn&amp;#39;s Liars and Nicholas Allbrook of the Australian psyche duo Allbrook/Avery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In a statement, Holy Fuck further commented on the album&amp;#39;s themes, which address the convergence of humanity and the machines we&amp;#39;ve built:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The robots are smarter than ever, and the algorithm knows more and more what we like as individuals, but we have to remind ourselves that there is music in the margins that can go missing and that that music is more important than ever.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I6gP4IijTCM" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/I6gP4IijTCM" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Holy Fuck - Luxe (ft. Alexis Taylor) @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last month I missed the new single from Toronto five-piece &lt;a href="https://nutrientsmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nutrients&lt;/a&gt;, but the unassuming yet groovy pop of &amp;quot;Such Slime&amp;quot; remains well-worth your attention. In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://northerntransmissions.com/nutrients-release-new-video-for-such-slime/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Northern Transmissions&lt;/a&gt;, vocalist Taylor Teeple commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wanted to write a song that could be someone&amp;#39;s favourite, go-to song to do at karaoke in an alternate universe. Or maybe an alien karaoke party on another planet. I think the ballad-like intro and the climactic bridge both lend themselves well to a drunk person singing this song at a half-empty, dimly lit karaoke night. The title also works great with this pathetic karaoke crooner, bemoaning their identity as someone who is slimy and unattractive, as they slowly descend into sadness.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The song arrived alongside a cool retro video from Isaac Roberts. Louise Short recorded &amp;quot;Such Slime&amp;quot; at Dining Room Sound last winter. The sax on the recording comes courtesy of &lt;a href="http://na-o-mi.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Naomi McCarroll-Butler&lt;/a&gt; (not that it&amp;#39;s her in the video, mind you, rather that&amp;#39;s actress Bea Santos).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Nutrients are the outgrowth of a bedroom-pop project stated by Teeple while living in Montreal. Now operating out of Toronto, his band features guitarist Will Hunter, drummer Turner Wigginton, bassist Sean McKee, and keyboardist Iulia Ciobanu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lz8eTCDY1d0" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Lz8eTCDY1d0" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Nutrients - &amp;quot;Such Slime&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m admittingly pretty ignorant of &lt;a href="https://louis-philippegingras.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Louis-Philippe Gingras&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; career to date, and the machine translations of &lt;a href="http://www.simonerecords.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Simone Records&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; French-language press material are providing me with little more than florid gibberish. So context or subtleties aside, I&amp;#39;m entirely on-board with &amp;quot;Barrés d&amp;#39;Toronto.&amp;quot; The joyous folk-rock tune&amp;#39;s the second single from singer-songwriter&amp;#39;s upcoming record &lt;em&gt;Tropicale Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt;, the third full-length from the Abitibi-bred, now Montreal-based musician. It follows the Caribbean-flavoured &amp;quot;Apocalypso,&amp;quot; which premiered in August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That the song details a road trip from &lt;a href="http://www.fmeat.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FME&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Rouyn-Noranda to my hometown of Niagara Falls is just icing on the cake. I&amp;#39;m a sucker for geography in my Cancon, local in particular. To top it off, the song features a delightfully silly steel drum bridge and a delightful children&amp;#39;s choir.  &lt;em&gt;Tropicale Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; is due in November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=159946637/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://louis-philippegingras.bandcamp.com/track/barr-s-dtoronto"&gt;Barrés d'Toronto by Louis-Philippe Gingras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://louis-philippegingras.bandcamp.com/track/barr-s-dtoronto" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Louis-Philippe Gingras - &amp;quot;Barrés d&amp;#39;Toronto&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Four-piece Vancouver post-punk group &lt;a href="https://championlawnmower.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Champion Lawnmower&lt;/a&gt; has returned with a new self-titled full-length. The eight-song set arrived on Bandcamp last week without a lot of fanfare, following up the group&amp;#39;s 2017 effort &lt;em&gt;Babies&lt;/em&gt;. Other than that, I&amp;#39;m not sure what to tell you! Champion Lawnmower&amp;#39;s quite impressively offline, at least at the moment, so my information is otherwise thin. I&amp;#39;m not even sure how I know about this one, to tell you the truth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Champion Lawnmower features members of the now-defunct Vancouver punk acts &lt;a href="https://crumbvancouver.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crumb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://otherjesus.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Other Jesus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=399960937/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://championlawnmower.bandcamp.com/album/champion-lawnmower"&gt;Champion Lawnmower by Champion Lawnmower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://championlawnmower.bandcamp.com/album/champion-lawnmower" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Champion Lawnmower - &lt;em&gt;Champion Lawnmower&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Etobicoke-based dub producer &lt;a href="https://kingpongdubsystem.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;King Pong&lt;/a&gt; recently unveiled his seventh release as the King Pong Dub System, a two-track set titled &lt;em&gt;1/2 Hour Dub Bomb&lt;/em&gt;. With two long-form 15-minute epics, the &lt;a href="https://arachnidiscs.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arachnidiscs&lt;/a&gt; release delivers pretty much exactly what it says on the tin. The new set arrives this Friday as a limited edition C30 cassette. The label boasts that the instrumental cuts thump along like &amp;quot;Adrian Sherwood and The Scientist and Mad Professor meet Public Image Ltd.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;King Pong is the stage name of Jakob Rehlinger. He&amp;#39;s taken part in works from Moonwood, Stargoon, Void Fill, and Tranzmit, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=315144785/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://arachnidiscs.bandcamp.com/album/1-2-hour-dub-bomb"&gt;1/2 Hour Dub Bomb by KING PONG DUB SYSTEM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://arachnidiscs.bandcamp.com/album/1-2-hour-dub-bomb" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: King Pong Dub System - &lt;em&gt;1/2 Hour Dub Bomb&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Calgarian rock duo &lt;a href="https://mieshathespanks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Miesha &amp;amp; The Spanks&lt;/a&gt; have an anthemic new single out titled &amp;quot;The Girls Are O.K..&amp;quot; It features the band&amp;#39;s core unit of Miesha Louie (lead vocals, guitar and bass) and Sean Hamilton (drums and percussion) backed by a chorus from the city&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.girlsrockcampcalgary.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Girls Rock Camp&lt;/a&gt;. In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://aestheticmagazinetoronto.com/2019/10/01/exclusive-premiere-stream-miesha-the-spanks-new-single-the-girls-are-o-k/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Aesthetic Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, Louie commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wrote our new single... while in my third trimester this summer, expecting twins — no idea what their gender would be. At the same time I was scheduling this year&amp;#39;s Girls Rock Camp in Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The whole thing got me thinking about these strong, weird, cool girls that I get to work with every year and watch grow, and how if I ended up with two baby girls, I wouldn&amp;#39;t be worried about or for them at all, because the girls from camp were already light years ahead of where I was at their age.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;They&amp;#39;re so brave and they already know they don&amp;#39;t have to take any bullshit — something I learned much later in life. They&amp;#39;re going to be more than okay – they&amp;#39;re going to be great.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new single follows the Miesha &amp;amp; The Spanks&amp;#39;s 2018 full-length &lt;em&gt;Girls Girls Girls&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/681029303&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/mandthespanks/the-girls-are-ok" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Miesha &amp;amp; The Spanks - &amp;quot;The Girls Are O.K.&amp;quot; @ SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Vancouver post-punk group &lt;a href="https://actors.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;ACTORS&lt;/a&gt; recently saw one of their singles remixed by the long-running BC synthwave artist &lt;a href="https://fmattack.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FM Attack&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Slaves&amp;quot; originally appeared on 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://artoffact.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Artoffact Records&lt;/a&gt; full length &lt;em&gt;It Will Come To You&lt;/em&gt;. You can find the new take on your digital platform of choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;ACTORS features guitarist/vocalist Jason Corbett backed by Shannon Hemmett on synth, bassist Jahmeel Russell (formerly of Winnipeg noise-rock act KEN mode), and drummer Adam Fink. Corbett recorded and produced the band&amp;#39;s material front-to-back at his Jacknife Sound studio. FM Attack is the stage name of producer Shawn Ward. His most recent record was &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt;, a 10 song full-length released this past June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/olSCqwZo14U" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/olSCqwZo14U" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: ACTORS - &amp;quot;Slaves&amp;quot; FM Attack Remix @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Earlier today, I premiered new music from the Montreal power-trio &lt;a href="https://thebambies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bambies&lt;/a&gt;. The group brings together musicians from Costa Rica, France, and Quebec to find common ground in snotty, 77&amp;#39; style punk. Imagine The Briefs playing classic Chuck Berry riffs. Something like that. The band&amp;#39;s high energy new single features the anthem &amp;quot;Red Guitar&amp;quot; backed by &amp;quot;Black Hands,&amp;quot; available for preorder now from the upstart &lt;a href="https://retarecords.bandcamp.com/album/red-guitar-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Reta Records&lt;/a&gt; on black or limited red wax. Reta&amp;#39;s a relatively new label run by Jamie Rae of Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;. You can stream both tracks at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/70984/stream-the-new-ep-from-montreal-trio-bambies" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Red Guitar&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Black Hands&amp;quot; was recorded in Montreal by Matt Damron, with Harris Newman mastering. Sami, Franki and Feli of Bambies recently travelled to Mexico, where the band recorded 13 new songs with Diego Mier of Mexico City psych group &lt;a href="https://buildavista.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Build a Vista&lt;/a&gt;. That material is bound to show up on some future release that&amp;#39;s yet to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/70984/stream-the-new-ep-from-montreal-trio-bambies" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bambies - &amp;quot;Red Guitar&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Black Hands&amp;quot; @ Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evolve</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-09-29-evolve/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-09-29-evolve/</id>
    <published>2019-09-28T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-28T18:43:43-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal aqua-punks &lt;a href="https://barnaclemtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Barnacle&lt;/a&gt; recently played an &lt;a href="http://www.outofearshotfestival.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Out Of Earshot&lt;/a&gt;-sponsored &lt;a href="https://popmontreal.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;POP Montreal&lt;/a&gt; showcase, promoting the event with a video for their song &amp;quot;Evolve.&amp;quot; The band commented &amp;quot;we built the biggest water slide in the world&amp;quot; and the clip does nothing to dispute that claim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had Barnacle&amp;#39;s February demo in near-constant rotation since I stumbled across them in this year&amp;#39;s SappyFest lineup. The band last released a 6-song live set in April (not to mention a super-limited Sappy-exclusive cassette that, no, I won&amp;#39;t sell you). With sea levels rising and us, as a species, pretty much incapable of unmaking our mess, I&amp;#39;m pretty sure Barnacle is the future. The smart money&amp;#39;s in snorkels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U6hP0sjvPKw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/U6hP0sjvPKw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Barnacle - &amp;quot;Evolve&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://hugeluge.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Luge&lt;/a&gt; toy with the familiar, what they create is anything but. The four-piece deconstructs rock songs. They peel apart tired and true structures, recombining them into something that&amp;#39;s just fascinatingly &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt;. 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Tall Is Just a Feeling&lt;/em&gt; jerked from moments of abrasive punk to angular no wave, flipping at random from fleeting moments of perfectly hooky pop to oblique, bass-driven art-funk. There&amp;#39;s a moment on that record where Luge serves up a riff that&amp;#39;s, bewildering, a little bit country. The second your recognition kicks in though, the band careens off in the opposite direction. The results were often &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt;, and intentionally so, but all that misdirection was incredibly compelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s been nearly a year since that LP, and the group&amp;#39;s now returned with &amp;quot;Up &amp;amp; Up,&amp;quot; a new single that picks up where &lt;em&gt;Tall&lt;/em&gt; left off. Some Party&amp;#39;s honoured to premiere the video for the track, a clip that takes its cue from your dusty old Nintendo. The setup should feel familiar, and indeed bands have been drawing from the well of millennial nostalgia with increased frequency. However, this being Luge, the rhythm you expect is never what you get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;When PUP played this card to &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/iVuB1ZASrGw" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;viral success&lt;/a&gt;, they went for the thrill of recognition, throwing as many clever references at the viewer as possible. New Cancon supergroup the Anyway Gang went saccharine with their &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/D7zDFHct-x4" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;recent take&lt;/a&gt;, the entire affair dripping with 90s-kid sentimentality. Luge lulls you in with the familiar but quickly goes askew. Staged like a classic fighting game, the &amp;quot;Up &amp;amp; Up&amp;quot; clip spends the brunt of its running time on the character selection screen. The viewer waits while the unseen player methodically wanders through characters and costumes. The action&amp;#39;s almost an afterthought. It&amp;#39;s the choosing that&amp;#39;s important. The mock gameplay only really commences in the video&amp;#39;s final third, and even that can&amp;#39;t be what you were expecting. The pacing almost hypnotically tosses your expectations, which is very fittingly Luge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band commented on the clip:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Up &amp;amp; Up&amp;#39; is our latest single that combines all the spices on the rack. It is a narrowing tunnel that fills with illness and textiles. The song manifested from the digital realm and, consequently, inspired the video. Our ambitious idea of an old school video game aesthetic was brought to fruition by our close collaborator Isaac Roberts. His visual prowess helped us make the best of a makeshift green screen and second rate actors.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Up &amp;amp; Up&amp;quot; was recorded by Stephen Pitman (&lt;a href="http://tallies.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tallies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chladny.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chladny&lt;/a&gt;) at Dining Room Studios. Jackson Willows mixed and mastered the track. You can pick a digital copy of the song up &lt;a href="https://hugeluge.bandcamp.com/track/up-up" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;. Luge is Cam Fraser, Kaiva Gotham, Tobias Hart, and Stu Mein.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U-ywV-hz6I0" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/premieres/luge-up-and-up/" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Luge - &amp;quot;Up &amp;amp; Up&amp;quot; @ SomeParty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto glam-pop sensation &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/thisisnyssa" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nyssa&lt;/a&gt; has a new single and video online, following the pattern set by her recent tracks &amp;quot;I Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Live On The Moon (Without U)&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Hey Jackie.&amp;quot; This one&amp;#39;s titled &amp;quot;#1Girl,&amp;quot; and like its siblings comes with a video by director Ron Hollywood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Nyssa&amp;#39;s string of new singles follows the artist&amp;#39;s 2018&amp;#39; EP &lt;em&gt;Champion of Love&lt;/em&gt;. This track&amp;#39;s a little closer to the electro-pop of that record than the 70s rock vibes explored on &amp;quot;Hey Jackie,&amp;quot; but Nyssa&amp;#39;s astonishing vocal range remains the star attraction regardless of genre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HFDDWJhQLV4" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/HFDDWJhQLV4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Nyssa - &amp;quot;#1Girl&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;There&amp;#39;s a quiet reverence in the Canadian indie rock universe for &lt;em&gt;Lost Wisdom&lt;/em&gt;, a 2008 collaboration between New Brunswick singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://juliedoiron.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Julie Doiron&lt;/a&gt;, Shotgun &amp;amp; Jaybird&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://fredericksquire.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fred Squire&lt;/a&gt;, and Phil Elverum&amp;#39;s Washinton-based &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PWElverum" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mount Eerie&lt;/a&gt;. Just over a decade later, Elverum and Doiron have again joined forces for &lt;em&gt;Lost Wisdom pt. 2&lt;/em&gt;, a full-length set for a November 8 release on the &lt;a href="http://www.pwelverumandsun.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;P.W. Elverum &amp;amp; Sun&lt;/a&gt; label. You can hear the first single, titled &amp;quot;Love Without Possession,&amp;quot; below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In a statement, Elverum reflects on how the new works address the personal tragedies he&amp;#39;s endured over the past few years. With the death of his wife, Quebec cartoonist Geneviève Castrée, profoundly affecting his last two records and his recent separation from actress Michelle Williams a more recent wound. Elverum commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I tried to make songs that did not rely at all on who I am or who I am singing about. Knowing that anyone with internet access might have questions about my specifics, I don&amp;#39;t want to say anything personal that isn&amp;#39;t already in the songs. My fingers are crossed that when I push them out to sea they will be met with calm humane understanding. That&amp;#39;s what they&amp;#39;re about after all.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can read his full statement at &lt;a href="https://pitchfork.com/news/mount-eerie-and-julie-doiron-announce-new-album-lost-wisdom-pt-2-share-song-listen/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pitchfork&lt;/a&gt;. While you&amp;#39;re there, you can find the dates for the short tour Mount Eerie and Julie Doiron have scheduled for December. That trek, which includes lone Canadian stops in Vancouver and Toronto, will &amp;quot;likely be the only performance of this album&amp;#39;s material for the foreseeable future.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2922869870/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=1120842117/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://pwelverumandsun.bandcamp.com/album/lost-wisdom-pt-2"&gt;Lost Wisdom pt. 2 by Mount Eerie with Julie Doiron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://pwelverumandsun.bandcamp.com/album/lost-wisdom-pt-2" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Mount Eerie with Julie Doiron - &amp;quot;Love Without Possession&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto low-fi post-punk trio &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/whatisfond/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fond&lt;/a&gt; premiered a hypnotic new track last week at &lt;a href="http://post-trash.com/news/2019/9/24/fond-smothered-post-trash-premiere" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Post-Trash&lt;/a&gt;. Titled &amp;quot;Smothered,&amp;quot; it&amp;#39;s slated to appear for the trio&amp;#39;s upcoming five-song EP &lt;em&gt;Vern&lt;/em&gt;, due October 24 from &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt;. It follows up on last year&amp;#39;s self-titled debut. The label references Pile and the Meat Puppets when describing this one, or more perhaps more generally: &amp;quot;another five tunes for future dirt-eating humanoids that survive the meteor.&amp;quot; Bands flippantly referencing the end of the world is something of a running theme in this edition of Some Party, as you&amp;#39;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The day of the release Fond will perform a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/405890876735653/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;release show&lt;/a&gt; at the Owls Club, supported by locals &lt;a href="https://dartsbud.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dart Mouth&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://nigelnigel.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nigel Nigel&lt;/a&gt;. The band features Ryan Naray (Animal Faces, Soft Floors), Zach Van Horne (Creeper), and Rob Johnson (Low Sun, Shahman).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="autoplay" scrolling="no" width="100%" data-embed="true" frameborder="no" height="300" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/681290333%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-V500I&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&amp;amp;wmode=opaque" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://post-trash.com/news/2019/9/24/fond-smothered-post-trash-premiere" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Fond - &amp;quot;Smothered&amp;quot; @ Post-Trash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto melodic-hardcore trio &lt;a href="https://schooldamage.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;School Damage&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for the song &amp;quot;I Don&amp;#39;t Like What I&amp;#39;ve Become,&amp;quot; a track from their 2018 full-length &lt;em&gt;Hello, Cruel World&lt;/em&gt;. The clip finds the band (and friends) loitering about in the back alleys of the Big Smoke, partaking in some now-legal substances and ignoring all manner of signage that&amp;#39;s meant to deter such activities. Jesse Marshall was behind the camera on this clip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band&amp;#39;s sophomore record, &lt;em&gt;Hello, Cruel World&lt;/em&gt; followed up on 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Battered Lives&lt;/em&gt;. The LP arrived last fall from &lt;a href="http://radgirlfriendrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Rad Girlfriend Records&lt;/a&gt; in the States, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ibuyrecordswebzine/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;I Buy Records&lt;/a&gt; in Europe, and Brain Candy at home. On &lt;em&gt;Cruel World&lt;/em&gt; School Damage featured guitarist/vocalist Brad Manners, bassist/vocalist Jon Cabatan, and drummer Curtis Tone. Tone&amp;#39;s since left the band (although he&amp;#39;s in this video), with Dennis Lee, formerly of Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://boids.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Boids&lt;/a&gt;, now behind the kit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;School Damage is in the midst of a mini-tour of Ontario and Quebec Italy&amp;#39;s Ratbones. They&amp;#39;ll play this Thursday at Montreal&amp;#39;s Escogriffe Bar Spectacle with NECK and Bambies supporting, then on Friday at the Dominion Tavern in Ottawa, again with NECK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/erusZ2b6u8A" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/erusZ2b6u8A" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: School Damage - &amp;quot;I Don&amp;#39;t Like What I&amp;#39;ve Become&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="https://necktunes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;NECK&lt;/a&gt;, the Ottawa &amp;quot;pop-punk gang&amp;quot; and their Italian tourmates recently released a four-song split 7&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="http://momsbasementrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Moms Basement Records&lt;/a&gt;. NECK contributes the songs &amp;quot;Ha Ha Hertz&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Morrisey&amp;#39;s a Creep&amp;quot; to the set, with the Genoa-based &lt;a href="https://ratbones.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ratbones&lt;/a&gt; providing a pair of their own. I&amp;#39;m going to assume that the latter song&amp;#39;s title is misspelt in the liner notes and we&amp;#39;re talking about Morrissey, who&amp;#39;s also a creep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;NECK last released the 10-song LP &lt;em&gt;You Don&amp;#39;t Think It&amp;#39;s Evil...&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/uncledrecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Uncle D Records&lt;/a&gt;. It followed up their 2015 LP &lt;em&gt;Hate To Read&lt;/em&gt; with a new slate of irreverent and snarky buzzsaw punk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1761200697/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://momsbasementrecords.bandcamp.com/album/neck-ratbones-split-ep"&gt;NECK/Ratbones Split ep by Moms Basement Records&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://momsbasementrecords.bandcamp.com/album/neck-ratbones-split-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: NECK - &amp;quot;Ha Ha Hertz&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Morrisey&amp;#39;s A Creep&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of splits, the Toronto-via-St. John&amp;#39;s hardcore act &lt;a href="http://brutalyouth.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brutal Youth&lt;/a&gt; is back with new material. The group&amp;#39;s following up their 2016 Stomp Records LP &lt;em&gt;Sanguine&lt;/em&gt; with a split 7&amp;quot; with Albany, New York&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.afterthefall518.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;After The Fall&lt;/a&gt;. The set arrives on October 8 from &lt;a href="http://www.paperandplastick.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paper + Plastick&lt;/a&gt;. You can preview the new track &amp;quot;Thick Skinned&amp;quot; below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/687364423&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/paperandplastick/brutal-youth-thin-skinned" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Brutal Youth - &amp;quot;Thin Skinned&amp;quot; @ SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://kiwijr.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kiwi Jr.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s another east coast act now slugging it out in Hogtown. The Charlottetown-bred indie rock group&amp;#39;s set to reissue their recent &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; full-length &lt;em&gt;Football Money&lt;/em&gt; worldwide on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/personanongratarecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Persona Non Grata Records&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;#39;s expected in January, but if you&amp;#39;re reading this newsletter you can probably go grab a copy in stores now. The band announced the new arrangement with a video for their jangle-pop anthem &amp;quot;Salary Man.&amp;quot; Director Ben Rayner commented on the clip, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;...putting together a perspective for this video, I wanted it to be fast paced, low budget, tongue-in-cheek, and highly personable.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 10-song &lt;em&gt;Football Money&lt;/em&gt; arrived this past March from Mint Records. Kiwi Jr. features vocalist Jeremy Gaudet, guitarist Brian Murphy, bassist Mike Walker, and drummer Brohan Moore. Aaron Goldstein (Daniel Romano, Bry Webb) engineered the record, with Holy Fuck&amp;#39;s Graham Walsh mixing. Alec O&amp;#39;Hanley (who plays with Murphy in Alvvays) is credited with additional instrumentation and production.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A7B2-2pYqfs" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/A7B2-2pYqfs" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Kiwi Jr. - &amp;quot;Salary Man&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;High octane Toronto garage-rock act &lt;a href="https://teenarcher.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teen Archer&lt;/a&gt; has a new single out titled &amp;quot;Demon Queen.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the first new track to arrive in a few years from the James McKeever-lead group and should slide in perfectly amongst their catalogue of muscular riff-rock. You could easily picture Teen Archer slotted in among the early 2000s Gearhead Records roster, somewhere between the Hellacopters and Lords of Altamont.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fWgWwujdbrw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/fWgWwujdbrw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Teen Archer - &amp;quot;Demon Queen&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;We&amp;#39;re not too far out from the release of &lt;em&gt;Big Blue&lt;/em&gt;, the new full-length from BC power-pop act &lt;a href="http://dead-soft.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dead Soft&lt;/a&gt;. In the lead-up to the October 18 &lt;a href="https://arts-crafts.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arts &amp;amp; Crafts&lt;/a&gt; drop the group&amp;#39;s unveiled a new video for the single &amp;quot;Step Out,&amp;quot; a clip that embraces a low-budget horror aesthetic. Speaking to &lt;a href="https://www.kerrang.com/the-news/dead-soft-are-super-bummed-about-being-murdered-in-their-new-video/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kerrang&lt;/a&gt;, vocalist/guitarist Nathaniel Epp commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;This song is about looking in on your life from the outside and the idea of stepping out of your day to day world into another one... It also makes reference to a reoccurring dream I had for a while where the earth got sucked into a black hole. It&amp;#39;s like that dream mixed with the fantasy of running away from home.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dead Soft features Epp with bassist/vocalist Keeley Rochon and drummer Alex Smith. With the release of their prior single, &amp;quot;I Believe You,&amp;quot; the band revealed that they&amp;#39;d recently relocated from Vancouver to take up residency on Gabriola Island near Nanaimo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AtkPyPO3Y9g" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/AtkPyPO3Y9g" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Dead Soft - &amp;quot;Step Out&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;With the October 25 release of &lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt; on the horizon, new media supporting &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s new LP seems to be arriving weekly. This time out we&amp;#39;ve got the single &amp;quot;Caught Lookin&amp;#39;,&amp;quot; featuring guest vocals from &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/roaratz/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Aurora Shields&lt;/a&gt;. It landed alongside a video by &lt;a href="https://www.danielleaphroditenemet.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Danielle Nemet&lt;/a&gt;. Speaking on the song, Ben Cook revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Although this one may sound like an accusatory duet between two lovers, it&amp;#39;s actually about how corporations control and own our attention through the mining of our data via smart phones.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt; is the second installment in a series of power-pop records, with the first salvo (&lt;em&gt;GUV I&lt;/em&gt;) arriving in August from &lt;a href="http://www.runforcoverrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover&lt;/a&gt;. This bright new material follows 2018&amp;#39;s eclectic &lt;em&gt;2 Sad 2 Funk&lt;/em&gt;, not to mention some decidedly louder recent work from Cook as a member of the Toronto hardcore groups &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/podc9B0f04Q" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/podc9B0f04Q" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Young Guv - &amp;quot;Caught Lookin&amp;#39;&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Page&lt;/a&gt; has been teasing a new collection of music, the follow-up to his 2015 LP &lt;em&gt;Volume Vs. Voice&lt;/em&gt;. During the sessions for this currently undisclosed new record, he tracked a few covers, of which the first is now online. You can check out Page&amp;#39;s cover of the 1982 INXS single &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Change&amp;quot; below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Ottawa-area artist has played in recent years as half of the duo &lt;a href="https://expandafuzz.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Expanda Fuzz&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#39;s known for his time recording as part of &lt;a href="http://campradio.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Camp Radio&lt;/a&gt; and before that in the 90s pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://thestandgt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Stand GT&lt;/a&gt;. Over the last year Page has been revisiting his early solo record &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay And Swim&lt;/em&gt; with a series of acoustic re-recordings under the name &lt;em&gt;Decide to Stay and Swim Again&lt;/em&gt;. Expanda Fuzz last released &lt;em&gt;Cotton Candy Jet Engine&lt;/em&gt; in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=167529821/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrispage.bandcamp.com/track/dont-change"&gt;Don't Change by Chris Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrispage.bandcamp.com/track/dont-change" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chris Page - &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Change&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The acerbic Kitchener punk act &lt;a href="http://badegg.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bad Egg&lt;/a&gt; has a new EP available. Titled &lt;em&gt;Serotonin Flush #10301985&lt;/em&gt;, the set features six original songs along with a cover of Black Flag&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Depression.&amp;quot; The full run, which can&amp;#39;t be more than 8 minutes long, follows a similarly brisk 10-song demo from this past February.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1259047321/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://badegg.bandcamp.com/album/serotonin-flush-10301985"&gt;Serotonin Flush #10301985 by Bad Egg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://badegg.bandcamp.com/album/serotonin-flush-10301985" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bad Egg - &lt;em&gt;Serotonin Flush #10301985&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The polished Hamilton, Ontario psych-rock group &lt;a href="https://thecrowleys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Crowleys&lt;/a&gt; have a new single out titled &amp;quot;Clarice.&amp;quot; In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://www.liveinlimbo.com/2019/09/27/world-premiere/song-premiere-clarice-by-the-crowleys.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Live In Limbo&lt;/a&gt; the band commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Clarice is about an uncertainty within yourself when struggling with mental health issues, as well as the lingering feelings of loneliness and sorrow that come with those experiences. Though the song is not about a specific person or event, it pulls from real emotions and a motivation to delve deeper into oneself.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Michael Keire and Cohen Wylie produced the new track at the Threshold Recording Studio. The Crowleys, who have roots as high school band, feature Cohen Wylie (guitar/vocals), Stuart Downie (drums/vocals), and Giulianna Frontini (vocals), with the brothers Justyn and Collin Horlick  (synth/guitar and bass). &amp;quot;Clarice&amp;quot; follows up the group&amp;#39;s 2018 EP &lt;em&gt;Colours Change Their Tone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3489897543/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thecrowleys.bandcamp.com/track/clarice"&gt;Clarice by The Crowleys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://thecrowleys.bandcamp.com/track/clarice" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Crowleys - &amp;quot;Clarice&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto garage-rock act &lt;a href="https://heybrenda.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brenda&lt;/a&gt; has a new 5-song EP out titled &lt;em&gt;Megalith&lt;/em&gt;. The heavy collection, which pulls influence from psych rock and stoner metal, follows the band&amp;#39;s 2017 EP &lt;em&gt;Creeper&lt;/em&gt;. The group previously commented that the riffy EP &amp;quot;focuses on the impending failure of mankind and the uncertainty of what comes after&amp;quot; (so, you know, prog stuff). Dylan Frankland of &lt;a href="http://tallies.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tallies&lt;/a&gt; produced the EP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Brenda will support the &lt;em&gt;Megalith&lt;/em&gt; with an upcoming gig on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2353065344966317/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;November 2&lt;/a&gt; at Toronto&amp;#39;s Handlebar, supporting LA&amp;#39;s Frankie &amp;amp; The Witch Fingers. Members of Brenda recently appeared as part of the darkwave group &lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Gloin&lt;/a&gt;. That band released their &lt;em&gt;Soft Monster&lt;/em&gt; EP this past summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1669625824/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://heybrenda.bandcamp.com/album/megalith"&gt;MEGALITH by Brenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://heybrenda.bandcamp.com/album/megalith" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Brenda - &lt;em&gt;Megalith&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The amiable Guelph pop-rock outfit &lt;a href="http://drunkatthelibrary.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drunk at the Library&lt;/a&gt; has a new 6-song EP out. It carries the unwieldy title you can see linked below, but the group&amp;#39;s mercifully shortening it to &lt;em&gt;60YRS&lt;/em&gt; in conversation. Dan Loughrin produced, mixed, and mastered the new set Big Rig Studios, and tapes are available from the band at upcoming shows. Drunk at the Library features Will Wellington, Caitlin Digby, Laura Rutty, Sarah Becker, and Trevor Cooke.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1309481261/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://drunkatthelibrary.bandcamp.com/album/where-do-you-see-yourself-in-60-years-do-you-see-yourself-helping-me-out-of-the-bath"&gt;where do you see yourself in 60 years, do you see yourself helping me out of the bath? by Drunk at the Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://drunkatthelibrary.bandcamp.com/album/where-do-you-see-yourself-in-60-years-do-you-see-yourself-helping-me-out-of-the-bath" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Drunk at the Library - &lt;em&gt;where do you see yourself in 60 years, do you see yourself helping me out of the bath?&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hold the Bow</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-09-22-hold-the-bow/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2019-09-22-hold-the-bow/</id>
    <published>2019-09-21T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-24T12:00:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver indie rock act &lt;a href="https://woolworm.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Woolworm&lt;/a&gt; recently announced &lt;em&gt;Awe&lt;/em&gt;, a new 12-song full-length due November 8 from &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt;. Recorded and mixed by their labelmate &lt;a href="https://jayarner.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jay Arner&lt;/a&gt;, the set follow&amp;#39;s the band&amp;#39;s 2017 sophomore record &lt;em&gt;Deserve to Die&lt;/em&gt;. It also strikes a decidedly different tone, as guitarist Giles Roy noted in the press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Even though some of these songs date back to before &lt;em&gt;Deserve To Die&lt;/em&gt;, we allowed ourselves to be spontaneous and open-minded here and took a collage approach to the overall record. We let it be scrappier and more diverse and less symmetrical... &lt;em&gt;Deserve To Die&lt;/em&gt; was a sort of exorcism, and this one&amp;#39;s more of a meditation. That one took so long to write and record that finally releasing it had a cathartic effect. But now we&amp;#39;re done with death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;For the foreseeable future, at least. This is more of a life record.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can preview for yourself with the gothy vibes of &amp;quot;Hold the Bow.&amp;quot;  In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://indie88.com/indie88-premiere-woolworm-releases-new-track-hold-the-bow/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Indie 88&lt;/a&gt; the band reveals how they took inspiration from &lt;a href="https://publicdelivery.org/marina-abramovic-rest-energy/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rest Energy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a harrowing 1980 performance art piece by Serbian artist Marina Abramović. Roy continued to muse on the album&amp;#39;s themes in the press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Ultimately, I think the album is about other people — trying to relate to someone, sometimes succeeding brilliantly, sometimes failing horrifically. Just the process of connecting with anyone is such a trip... It&amp;#39;s so fucked up to have a real person in front of you and know that you&amp;#39;re each just hiding in your own mind. You can wind up knowing them pretty well but you will never know what it&amp;#39;s like to actually be them. So we&amp;#39;re all alone in our own realities, but then we&amp;#39;re all constantly trusting each other in so many ways. That can go horribly
wrong, but when it goes right, that&amp;#39;s the most beautiful thing I can think of.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Woolworm features Giles Roy on guitars and vocals, guitarist Alex Pomeroy, bassist Heather Black, and drummer Nick Tolliday. The band&amp;#39;s playing Pop Montreal this Thursday, then a pair of Ontario dates with labelmates &lt;a href="http://neckingband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Necking&lt;/a&gt; to round out the week. Look for them on September 27 at Ottawa&amp;#39;s newly opened art space &lt;a href="https://www.cinqhole.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cinqhole&lt;/a&gt;, then on Saturday the 28th in the basement of Toronto comic shop &lt;a href="http://www.beguilingbooksandart.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Beguiling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3845227047/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=3607980927/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://woolworm.bandcamp.com/album/awe"&gt;AWE by WOOLWORM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://woolworm.bandcamp.com/track/hold-the-bow" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Woolworm - &amp;quot;Hold the Bow&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I attended the Polaris gala last week. It was a fine-tuned event with a well-deserved outcome for the ultimate winner &lt;a href="https://haviahmighty.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Haviah Mighty&lt;/a&gt;. As always, I did my best to stay out of the way. As a random shlub with an unremarkable newsletter, I try not to draw too much attention from Toronto&amp;#39;s cultural elite, particularly while I&amp;#39;m trying to sneak their hors d&amp;#39;oeuvres. While every nominees&amp;#39; performance was enjoyable, I&amp;#39;m not sure I found any as singularly thrilling as last year&amp;#39;s gleefully anarchic blowout from &lt;a href="https://hubertlenoir.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hubert Lenoir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Quebec glam rock upstart returned last week with a new single, a collaboration with Australia&amp;#39;s androgynous alt-pop icon &lt;a href="kirinjcallinan.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kirin J. Callinan&lt;/a&gt;. Titled (in lower case) &amp;quot;hunny bunny,&amp;quot; the track came paired with a 16mm video chronicling the love lives of vampire skateboarders. Gabriel Lapointe and Noémie D. Leclerc directed the clip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking to &lt;a href="https://www.thefader.com/2019/09/19/hubert-lenoir-kirin-j-callinan-hunny-bunny-music-video" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Fader&lt;/a&gt;, Lenoir commented on the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Kirin and I met up in a studio in Amsterdam, and I was excited and terrified to show my ideas to him. I have so much respect and love for his work so it was surreal to have him with me. We recorded for two days, and tried every idea we came up with, crazy ideas and stupid ideas. Kirin is such a lovely person to be around and work with. He&amp;#39;s full of positivity, energy and joy, plus he&amp;#39;s lot older than me so he&amp;#39;s kind of a big brother/football coach. He told me, &amp;#39;trust yourself, Hubert!&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I was surrounded by English speaking persons (Kirin and the engineer Thomas) so it felt natural for me to write in English which I haven&amp;#39;t done in a long time. That was a big thing for me, but I couldn&amp;#39;t help putting two lines of French in, and Kirin tried to sing in French too. When we were recording the track I was always repeating the same words: it needs to be low key, low key pop. I didn&amp;#39;t see the hook as something that should come at you like a tiger but more like a snake, it attacks from the back and bites you without you knowing it. After those two days, we went back to finish our respective European tours and when I got back home I managed to mix the track with a few friends and worked with Kirin via FaceTime. Kirin had planned to add more guitars to the song but he broke both his arms few days after he finished his tour, lol.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I enjoy how casually Lenoir laughs off Callinan breaking &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; of his arms. Lenoir last released the Polaris shortlisted &lt;em&gt;Darlène&lt;/em&gt; in 2018. His early quartet &lt;a href="https://theseasonsmusic.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Seasons&lt;/a&gt; released their 2017-era &lt;em&gt;Midnight, Let&amp;#39;s Get a Hot Dog&lt;/em&gt; later that same year in the wake of &lt;em&gt;Darlène&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s success. Both albums arrived via &lt;a href="http://www.simonerecords.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Simone Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Idlqe_wIjvg" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Idlqe_wIjvg" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Hubert Lenoir and Kirin J. Callinan - &amp;quot;hunny bunny&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The low-fi art-punk group &lt;a href="https://deliluh.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deliluh&lt;/a&gt; recently announced &lt;em&gt;Beneath The Floors&lt;/em&gt;, a new LP due November 15. The 10-song set marks the band&amp;#39;s second major release of the year, following May&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Oath of Intent&lt;/em&gt; EP. As with that record, this one arrives on &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; in North America and &lt;a href="https://www.tinangelrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tin Angel&lt;/a&gt; everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Like &lt;em&gt;Oath of Intent&lt;/em&gt; before it, &lt;em&gt;Beneath The Floors&lt;/em&gt; was recorded live off the floor of Toronto veteran hall the Owls Club (although five months prior to the sessions for that record). The group shared the single &amp;quot;Lickspittle (A Nut in the Paste)&amp;quot; along with the announcement, a track that features an appearance from Patrick Flegel of &lt;a href="https://womenband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Women&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://cindylee-w25th.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cindy Lee&lt;/a&gt;. Band leader Kyle Knapp commented on the song, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;[Lickspittle] characterizes a naive outcast struggling to swing with an elitist crowd. The subject is a metaphor for the rampant trend of nouveau-bougie horse chocolate popping up all over Toronto: a &amp;#39;craft&amp;#39; class of try-hards, pining for status.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Deliluh&amp;#39;s relationship with the Owls Club was captured earlier this summer in the documentary short &lt;em&gt;Somewhere Else&lt;/em&gt;. That piece, from directors &lt;a href="https://www.colinmedley.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Colin Medley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://mariatt.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Maria Todorov-Topouzov&lt;/a&gt;, follows a community of Toronto bands utilizing non-traditional venues in the wake of the city&amp;#39;s ongoing spate of club closures. You can find it over at &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/332967020" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3435752802/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2480824732/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://telephoneexplosion.bandcamp.com/album/beneath-the-floors"&gt;Beneath The Floors by Deliluh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://telephoneexplosion.bandcamp.com/album/beneath-the-floors" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Deliluh - &amp;quot;Lickspittle (A Nut in the Paste)&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal post-punk group &lt;a href="https://corridormtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Corridor&lt;/a&gt; has another new single online, previewing their upcoming full-length &lt;em&gt;Junior&lt;/em&gt;. You can check out the rollicking No Wave guitar pop of &amp;quot;Domino&amp;quot; through a premiere at &lt;a href="https://www.clashmusic.com/news/corridors-domino-is-a-mighty-guitar-pop-epic" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Clash Music&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking to the publication, the band&amp;#39;s Jonathan Robert commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;People are often glorifying what being an Artist or a musician can mean. Art doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily make you a better person. There can be angst, stress and so on. It can have a negative, direct impact on the people closest to you. &amp;#39;Domino&amp;#39; is about navigating just that. It is the first song out of &amp;#39;Junior&amp;#39; that we&amp;#39;ve composed and we&amp;#39;ve played it live quite a few times already.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 10-song &lt;em&gt;Junior&lt;/em&gt; arrives on October 18 from &lt;a href="http://www.bonsound.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonsound&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere. Produced by Emmanuel Éthier, it&amp;#39;s the band&amp;#39;s third album and follow up to 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Supermercado&lt;/em&gt;. Corridor features Jonathan Robert on vocals, guitar, and synths, with Dominic Berthiaume on vocals and bass, Julian Perreault on guitar, and Julien Bakvis drumming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/48YbjRXfegA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/48YbjRXfegA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Corridor - &amp;quot;Domino&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Former &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Deadly_Snakes" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deadly Snakes&lt;/a&gt; frontman &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/products/andre-ethier-croak-in-the-weeds" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;André Ethier&lt;/a&gt; recently shared another new track from his upcoming solo record. You can preview the enigmatic singer/songwriter&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Jenny The Blues&amp;quot; below. Ethier commented in a brief statement (and with characteristic wryness):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Here&amp;#39;s a funky little song about feeling sorry for yourself. And remember, you can&amp;#39;t wash the blues off a cop.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The nine-track &lt;em&gt;Croak in the Weeds&lt;/em&gt; is due October 11 from &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;, the second in a planned trilogy that started with 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Under Grape Leaves&lt;/em&gt;. Ethier recorded the new album in his Toronto studio with the celebrated ambient and post-rock producer &lt;a href="http://www.sandroperri.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sandro Perri&lt;/a&gt;. The pair previously worked together on &lt;em&gt;Grape Leaves&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I wrote about &lt;em&gt;Croak in the Weeds&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39; lead single, &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-09-01-dream-on-pigs/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dream On Pigs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; earlier in the month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1655189244/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=3702181850/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://telephoneexplosion.bandcamp.com/album/croak-in-the-weeds"&gt;Croak In The Weeds by Andre Ethier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://telephoneexplosion.bandcamp.com/track/jenny-the-blues" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: André Ethier - &amp;quot;Jenny The Blues&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Toronto psych-rock act &lt;a href="https://mimico.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mimico&lt;/a&gt; premiered a new video last week for the track &amp;quot;Common Tar.&amp;quot; The band&amp;#39;s Ben Oginz commented that the song was &amp;quot;a play on montage-style scoring,&amp;quot; adding:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The song imagines a post-human character living outside a walled city in a plastic tent village. This character is trying to download the knowledge of humanity before the last of the biological humans die out and has to steal the data from inside the walled city.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That grim quest is captured in a sci-fi clip from director &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/misskateyoung" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kate Young&lt;/a&gt; that stars Toronto photojournalist &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/galit_r/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Galit Yael Rodan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Common Tar&amp;quot; will appear on the &amp;#39;space-motorik&amp;#39; trio&amp;#39;s upcoming full-length, &lt;em&gt;Hi-Action&lt;/em&gt;, which is due for a fall release on &lt;a href="http://handdrawndracula.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hand Drawn Dracula&lt;/a&gt;. The band recorded with producer Justin Small (of &lt;a href="http://domakesaythink.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Do Make Say Think&lt;/a&gt;) in sessions at both the storied Bathhouse Studio (The Tragically Hip, The Sadies) and Toronto&amp;#39;s Palace Sound (Absolutely Free). The album features contributions from violinist Laura C. Bates (Volür) and guest-vocals from Ida Maidstone (Hush Pup). Mimico features Ben Oginz, Jeremiah Knight, and Nick Kervin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GTFJiQduh9c" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/GTFJiQduh9c" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Mimico - &amp;quot;Common Tar&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;After a few years performing as a live band, Ottawa trio &lt;a href="https://warplines.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warp Lines&lt;/a&gt; are finally set to deliver a proper studio album. The bands&amp;#39; first full-length finds them mashing up influences from their lengthy garage-punk resumes (Million Dollar Marxists, the Steve Adamk Band, etc.) with pop hooks and vocal harmonies from 90s Canadian alt-rock (Sloan, Thrush Hermit). The band&amp;#39;s first full-length will be titled &lt;em&gt;Human Fresh&lt;/em&gt; and is due this Friday from Portland&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://dirtcultrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dirt Cult Records&lt;/a&gt;. The band premiered a few new songs this month through various outlets, with &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/70732/ottawas-warp-lines-debut-hell-is-great-from-their-new-lp-human-fresh" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews&lt;/a&gt; debuting &amp;quot;Hell is Great&amp;quot; a few weeks ago and &lt;a href="https://thebadcopy.com/news/stream/warp-lines-premieres-new-song-measured/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Bad Copy&lt;/a&gt; recently showcasing &amp;quot;Measured.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Warp Lines features the entirety of the now-defunct bass-and-drum duo Big Dick, pairing long-time collaborators Johnny O (guitar) and Dave Secretary (drums) with bassist Kurt Rafuse (formerly of The Yips). The trio has extensive connections in the capital&amp;#39;s busy punk scene, with members having played at one time or another in groups like Van Johnson, Uranium Comeback, and The New Calling, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Warp Lines will launch the new record with a release show at Ottawa&amp;#39;s House of TARG on September 28, supported by locals &lt;a href="https://mushygushy.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mushy Gushy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://organeyes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Organ Eyes&lt;/a&gt;. Dave Williams of &lt;a href="https://crusades666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crusades&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://surrendersounds.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Surrender&lt;/a&gt; will be on site to DJ some synth-pop gems as well. A slate of shows in Ontario and Eastern Canada is scheduled for early 2020, with dates to be announced soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/655866401%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-1ygVl&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/70732/ottawas-warp-lines-debut-hell-is-great-from-their-new-lp-human-fresh" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Warp Lines - &amp;quot;Hell is Great&amp;quot; @ Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/655866686%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-9TrrH&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://thebadcopy.com/news/stream/warp-lines-premieres-new-song-measured/" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Warp Lines - &amp;quot;Measured&amp;quot; @ The Bad Copy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://ivanrivers.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ivan Rivers&lt;/a&gt; is the absurdist folk guise of Ivan Raczycki from the melodic Toronto punk quartet &lt;a href="https://stuckouthere.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stuck Out Here&lt;/a&gt;. November 22 will see the self-described &amp;quot;celebrated folk icon&amp;quot; release their debut full-length, &lt;em&gt;The Fallen Ivan Rivers&lt;/em&gt;. In a press release Rivers remarks on the album:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The record centers around their 2016-2017 psychospiritual manic spell that centers around a fantastical relationship with a woman they believed to be the reincarnated Mary Magdalene, detailing their dances with divinity, surreality, and eventual tragedy, as less than a year after their dalliance, she was murdered in The Village in Toronto.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;There&amp;#39;s a pair of songs from the record online for you to preview now. First is &amp;quot;On Pharmacy,&amp;quot; available as a video shot by Joe Elliott. The clip features Rivers portraying a &amp;quot;confused prophet sacrificing and executing several manifestations of self along the coast of Lake Ontario.&amp;quot; The track features &lt;a href="https://espanola.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Espanola&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Aaron Goldstein on pedal steel. You can also now stream a song titled &amp;quot;9 Black Crosses,&amp;quot; at your streaming service of choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Stuck Out Here recently released their third LP &lt;em&gt;Until We&amp;#39;re Each Someone Else&lt;/em&gt;, on &lt;a href="https://getparty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Get Party!&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://mustbenicerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Must Be Nice Records&lt;/a&gt;. Raczycki&amp;#39;s mental health challenges in the lead-up to that record &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2019-03-10-these-things-happen/#stuckouthere" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;factored heavily&lt;/a&gt; into the resulting songs. Ivan Rivers last released a pair of EPs in 2017, &lt;em&gt;Mystic Keg&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Confidante&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_98Uumdppck" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_98Uumdppck" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Ivan Rivers - &amp;quot;On Pharmacy&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal psych-rock trio &lt;a href="https://www.elephantstone.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Elephant Stone&lt;/a&gt; recently premiered a new single titled &amp;quot;Land of Dead&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="http://www.brooklynvegan.com/elephant-stone-get-heavy-on-new-single-listen-touring-around-levitation-fest/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brooklyn Vegan&lt;/a&gt;. Frontman Rishi Dir commented to the publication:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Land of Dead&amp;#39; began with stoner-rock riff on the sitar; it was pretty quick to write... Lyrically, I knew it would be the dark centrepiece of a song suite. Working with my friend, and &lt;a href="https://mien.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;MIEN&lt;/a&gt; bandmate, John Mark Lapham, we came up with the lyrics telling of a world devoid of empathy and burning skies. It&amp;#39;s tragic how life imitates art.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Elephant Stone last released &lt;em&gt;Ship of Fools&lt;/em&gt; in 2016, with the follow-up due sometime in 2020. The band&amp;#39;s set to play the &lt;a href="https://levitation-austin.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Levitation&lt;/a&gt; festival in Austin, Texas this November, with a U.S. tour built around their appearance. You can find all those details at Brooklyn Vegan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ApVOFmqpnNM" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ApVOFmqpnNM" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Elephant Stone - &amp;quot;Land of Dead&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dundas, Ontario power-trio &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thedirtynil/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; recently announced their &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.com/shows" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;fall tour&lt;/a&gt;, pairing the reveal with a new single titled &amp;quot;Idiot Victory.&amp;quot; Like their summer-released &amp;quot;Astro Ever After,&amp;quot; the track comes from the sessions for 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Master Volume&lt;/em&gt;, with both tracks appearing as part of an expanded edition of that record (at least on streaming services, the yellow cover variant available through Dine Alone instead comes with a second platter of demos).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Frontman Luke Bentham commented on the new track in a press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;To be honest, the song is about smashing your partner&amp;#39;s cell phone in a desperate bid for attention. I certainly participate in the modern landscape of social media but like many, I&amp;#39;m concerned about it&amp;#39;s obstruction of true, real-life connection. The title, to me is something separate. I like the ambiguity of it. It can be contextualized depending on its association. To me, Idiot Victory is the triumph of the underdog and a celebration of all things strange. Please play loud. Let your freak flag fly brothers and sisters.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Mitch Barnes and Victor Malang directed the &amp;quot;Idiot Victory&amp;quot; video. The Dirty Nil will play with London punks &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt; and Brampton hip hop/hardcore act &lt;a href="https://deardashgod.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dear-God&lt;/a&gt; on the tour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master Volume&lt;/em&gt; was the band&amp;#39;s second LP of new material for &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt; following 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Higher Power&lt;/em&gt;. Throughout the summer the band released pairs of cover songs as part of a four-volume set titled &lt;em&gt;You&amp;#39;re Welcome&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KDOKeVT6jAU" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/KDOKeVT6jAU" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Dirty Nil - &amp;quot;Idiot Victory&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week the prolific Toronto songwriter Ben Cook shared a video for his new single &amp;quot;Try Not To Hang On So Hard.&amp;quot; Shot by Tristan C-M and Kevin Fitz-Henry, the clip shows Cook and his bandmates in a home recording session and out roaming the streets of Brooklyn. Cook wrote the material for both the upcoming &lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt; and the summer-released &lt;em&gt;GUV I&lt;/em&gt; while living in New York City last May.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt; is the second chapter in a series of power-pop records slated for this year under Cook&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt; persona. &lt;em&gt;GUV I&lt;/em&gt; arrived in August from &lt;a href="http://www.runforcoverrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover Records&lt;/a&gt;, with this second chapter due from the label on October 25.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ben Cook&amp;#39;s, of course, no stranger to this newsletter, as he&amp;#39;s both the frontman of the Toronto hardcore group &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt; and a member of the acclaimed &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;. This pair of new Young Guv albums follow 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;2 Sad 2 Funk&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/01cu95qnHfs" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/01cu95qnHfs" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Young Guv - &amp;quot;Try Not To Hang On So Hard&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; has shared a new video for &amp;quot;Fountain,&amp;quot; a track from &lt;a href="https://shotgunjimmie.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shotgun Jimmie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s recently released &lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt;. The clip, shot by Colin Medley, features Jimmy and the band cavorting around the Sackville, New Brunswick waterfowl park before their set at this summer&amp;#39;s SappyFest. Among his party, you&amp;#39;ll find Ryan Peters of &lt;a href="https://ladyhawk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ladyhawk&lt;/a&gt;, Jay Baird of &lt;a href="http://domakesaythink.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Do Make Say Think&lt;/a&gt;, and José Miguel Contreras of &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transistor Sister 2&lt;/em&gt; is Shotgun Jimmie&amp;#39;s first new full-length since 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Field of Trampolines&lt;/em&gt;. He&amp;#39;ll support it on the road this fall with two separate tours, one in October as a solo act supporting the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thrush_Hermit" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Thrush Hermit&lt;/a&gt; reunion, then again in November for a week of full-band shows in Ontario. You can find the details &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/youvechangedrecords/posts/2201142463330659" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SmfhThS5sco" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SmfhThS5sco" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Shotgun Jimmie - &amp;quot;Fountain&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Newfoundland-by-way-of-Montreal indie-pop act &lt;a href="https://bbqtband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BBQT&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for their single &amp;quot;Flinch.&amp;quot; The video was compiled from old family home movies by director &lt;a href="https://www.raphaelsandler.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Raphael Sandler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Flinch&amp;quot; appears on the band&amp;#39;s recent EP &lt;em&gt;Nice View&lt;/em&gt;. That 5-song set followed the band&amp;#39;s 2018 release &lt;em&gt;All For Show&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href="https://braingumrecords.bigcartel.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brain Gum Records&lt;/a&gt; recently collected both on a new tape, with an LP in the works. BBQT features guitarist/vocalist Amery Sandford, guitarist Jack Bielli, bassist Mikey Melikey, and drummer Allison Graves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eQeu5TrrmDY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/eQeu5TrrmDY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: BBQT - &amp;quot;Flinch&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/raiseghosts/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Raise Ghosts&lt;/a&gt; is the new band that emerged from the now-defunct Mississauga emo/punk group &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/peacebestillca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Peace Be Still&lt;/a&gt;. The group recently premiered their debut release &lt;em&gt;Only in Darkness Can We Find True Light&lt;/em&gt;, over at &lt;a href="https://exclaim.ca/music/article/hear_raise_ghosts_new_album_only_in_darkness_we_can_find_true_light" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;. Jesse Gander (Needles//Pins, Japandroids, White Lung) recorded, mixed and mastered the set with some additional recording from &lt;a href="https://somersaulter.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Somersaulter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Taylor Barrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In a statement the band commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Only in Darkness Can We Find True Light&lt;/em&gt; has been a two-year journey, which began with the unceremonious end of Peace Be Still. The album closes the chapter on playing in that band for ten years and deals with loss, impermanence, and feeling alone. Raise Ghosts attempts to dovetail these issues and subject matter with music that is as heavy and challenging.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://mustbenicerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Must Be Nice Records&lt;/a&gt; is helping get this one out there. You can preview the track &amp;quot;Bonus&amp;quot; at their Bandcamp page or stream the entire 12-song set at Exclaim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2970923281/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mustbenicerecords.bandcamp.com/album/only-in-darkness-can-we-find-true-light-mbn019"&gt;Only in Darkness Can We Find True Light (MBN019) by Raise Ghosts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://mustbenicerecords.bandcamp.com/album/only-in-darkness-can-we-find-true-light-mbn019" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Raise Ghosts - &amp;quot;Bogus&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Roberval, Quebec&amp;#39;s hockey-themed alt-rock titans &lt;a href="https://lesdaleshawerchuk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Les Dales Hawerchuk&lt;/a&gt; have an incredibly on-brand new track available. The band&amp;#39;s composed a theme song for the &lt;a href="https://sagueneens.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chicoutimi Saguenéens&lt;/a&gt;, a team that plays as part of the Quebec Major Junior Hockey League. You can check their anthem, titled &amp;quot;Direct dans l &amp;#39;mille&amp;quot; over at Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band will appear at the opening game of the Sags&amp;#39; upcoming season on October 4. Les Dales Hawerchuk features the brothers Sylvain and Sébastien Séguin on vocals and guitars, with bassist Charles Perron and drummer Pierre Fortin. The group&amp;#39;s last full-length was 2016&amp;#39;s similarly hockey-referencing &lt;em&gt;Désavantage numérique&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve never heard Les Dales&amp;#39; namesake 2005 &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hbZqFTVozzs" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;single&lt;/a&gt;, it serves as a great example of how certain cultural artifacts never manage to escape Quebec&amp;#39;s linguistic orbit regardless of how much of an impact they have within the province. It also remains absolutely bonkers, regardless of language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3856733572/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://lesdaleshawerchuk.bandcamp.com/album/direct-dans-lmille"&gt;Direct dans l'mille by Les Dales Hawerchuk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://lesdaleshawerchuk.bandcamp.com/album/direct-dans-lmille" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Les Dales Hawerchuk - &amp;quot;Direct dans l&amp;#39;mille&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
