<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter on independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated every Sunday evening by Adam White of Punknews.org. A sober second thought on new music, cool records, and the people making their own culture.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-07-01T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Talk To Your Friends</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-02-talk-to-your-friends/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-02-talk-to-your-friends/</id>
    <published>2017-07-01T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T09:48:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This may be difficult to explain, but I don&amp;#39;t ascribe any special virtues to Canadian bands. Perhaps that&amp;#39;s an odd thing for me to say, given that I&amp;#39;m the author of a publication that focuses on them exclusively. If you subscribe to the old punk rock axiom that anyone can play rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll and it&amp;#39;s just a matter of having the will to do it, then the logical conclusion of that notion is that there should be an abundance of rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll bands. I believe there is, and there&amp;#39;s nothing in isolation that makes Halifax and Hamilton any better or worse than Portland and Denton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The border matters though. The financial and regulatory implications of crossing it for a band are real and prohibitive. Cultural currents also exist. If there are truly cool rock and roll bands everywhere, then that same border means it&amp;#39;s always going to be a little bit easier for a publication based in New York, LA, or Chicago to promote an American act than engage at length with an artist from, say, Saskatoon. We may be closer than ever online, but the Internet can&amp;#39;t fully solve for geography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The global village has another problem: with everyone at the party the noise has increased. It&amp;#39;s impossible to equally sample and judge the best of everything, and there&amp;#39;s so much &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; music out there that to pursue only the collectively accepted &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; just lands you in another silo. If you&amp;#39;re like me, you need to draw a line somewhere, even if its arbitrary. You need to pick a hill to stand on from where you can see the lay of the land. For me that hill is Canada. It&amp;#39;s Canada for no other reason than that&amp;#39;s where the accident of birth has found me. It remains Canada because I subscribe to that idea that anyone can play cool rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll, and I&amp;#39;m never left wanting when I narrow my focus to this nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m not touching #Canada150 on this newsletter, but the event has given me pause. I don&amp;#39;t think that I, or any of the similar labels or zines that focus on the cultural output of Canada, are doing so out of nationalism or patriotism or any other problematic -ism. It&amp;#39;s simply where we are, and all things being equal that&amp;#39;s a fine place to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Compatriots&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pentagon Black is a label owned an operated by Montreal duo &lt;a href="https://thefamines.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Famines&lt;/a&gt;. That band self-describes as a &amp;quot;noise-garage art cult&amp;quot; and their publishing wing is similarly high concept. Pentagon Black&amp;#39;s released three editions of a compilation series to date, the latest arriving this past June at the &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion&lt;/a&gt;. Each comp features a collection of underground Canadian bands and each was released exclusively on paper (which is to say, some objet d&amp;#39;art with a download code). The first two were 20x30&amp;quot; newsprint posters, the latest is a postcard about size of a 7&amp;quot; record. It&amp;#39;s an aggressive expression of how cost-effective it can be to create something of meaning, and it thumbs its nose at the trendy middle ground where a lot of garage bands find themselves when priced out of vinyl (namely, cassettes). It&amp;#39;s also a bold rejection of much of the superstructure built around independent music: the project forgoes the expected PR campaign, avoids online streaming sites, and leaves record collectors without the usual fetish item.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The third Pentagon Black collection features 16 bands, each of which recorded a live take of a new song to a cell phone. The Famines are present of course, as are the related Montreal punk band &lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt; (Famines drummer Drew Demers with members of &lt;a href="https://sonicavenues.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sonic Avenues&lt;/a&gt;). Quebec is further represented by Montreal&amp;#39;s surrealist guitar pop duo &lt;a href="https://couleurdessin.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Couleur Dessin&lt;/a&gt;, noise-punks &lt;a href="https://nushu.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nüshu&lt;/a&gt;, and &amp;quot;soft prog&amp;quot; group &lt;a href="https://lapslapslap.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;LAPS&lt;/a&gt;, along with Quebec City dance/punk/comedy duo &lt;a href="https://oromoctodiamond.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oromocto Diamond&lt;/a&gt;. From the east coast the comp features raw takes from Fredericton&amp;#39;s difficult-to-describe art rock trio &lt;a href="https://motherhoodmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Motherhood&lt;/a&gt; and experimental Saint John act &lt;a href="https://usse.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Usse&lt;/a&gt;. Toronto post-punks &lt;a href="https://centurypalm.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Century Palm&lt;/a&gt; and low-fi punk act &lt;a href="https://protruders.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Protruders&lt;/a&gt; appear along with a number of bands outside the GTA, including Ottawa noise duo &lt;a href="https://buysomedeathsticks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deathsticks&lt;/a&gt; and a trio of Peterborough bands (art-punks &lt;a href="https://thelonelyparade.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lonely Parade&lt;/a&gt;,  &amp;quot;doom rap / industrial soul&amp;quot; project &lt;a href="https://garbageface.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;garbageface&lt;/a&gt;, and garage-punk group &lt;a href="https://beefboys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beef Boys&lt;/a&gt;). Heading west the comp showcases Edmonton&amp;#39;s Smokey &amp;amp; Cole Kush (of &lt;a href="https://smokeysings.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Smokey &amp;amp; the Feeelings&lt;/a&gt;) and Winnipeg noise-pop act &lt;a href="https://microdotwpg.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Microdot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The beauty of a project like this is how quick the turnaround can be when free of the need to press physical media. The second Pentagon Black compilation was only released this past April, with many of the same bands participating. The interview Famines guitarist / singer Raymond Biesinger did with &lt;a href="http://www.chartattack.com/features/2016/03/10/pentagon-black-compilation-paper/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chart Attack&lt;/a&gt; for the first comp last year is still completely relevant and pretty much essential reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3029757273/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thefamines.bandcamp.com/album/talk-to-your-friends"&gt;Talk to Your Friends by the Famines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can acquire any of the Pentagon Black paper LPs what still exist from &lt;a href="https://thefamines.bandcamp.com/merch" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt; or at shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This week also say the release of the fourth &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/compilations/dominionated-iv/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dominionated&lt;/a&gt; compilation, a digital collection of classic Canadian songs covered and reinterpreted by modern Canadian bands. The labour of love was started back on the &lt;a href="http://www.quickbeforeitmelts.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Quick Before It Melts&lt;/a&gt; blog and has continued to the successor publication which shares its name. Part of the treat is the choice of songs, as &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily imply &amp;quot;well-known&amp;quot; here and there&amp;#39;s as much to explore in the source material as there are the performers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This year&amp;#39;s model features Saskatoon&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://thegarrys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Garrys&lt;/a&gt; covering “Dusty Boy” by defunct Montreal band &lt;a href="https://thepeelies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Peelies&lt;/a&gt;. Regina&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://oiseauxoiseaux.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oiseaux&lt;/a&gt; puts forth an aggressive and chaotic take on  Attack In Black&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Hunger of the Young.&amp;quot; That&amp;#39;s just two of nine, each of which is linked through to a wealth of worthwhile conversations on the Dominionated blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can download &lt;em&gt;DOMINIONATED IV&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="(http://dominionated.ca/compilations/dominionated-iv/)" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In this weekend of brash, shallow celebrations, there&amp;#39;s something eminently sane and dignified about how both &lt;em&gt;DOMINIONATED IV&lt;/em&gt; and the recent Pentagon Black compilations treat the subject of Canada. Each accomplishes the goal of sharing and celebrating the creative culture of this country, and neither feel like they&amp;#39;ll need be put away when you go back to work on July 4th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A full album preview of the debut &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/cheapwhine/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cheap Whine&lt;/a&gt; LP is now available to preview at &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/members_of_steve_adamyk_band_crusades_feral_trash_share_debut_album_as_cheap_whine" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;, courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.drunkensailorrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drunken Sailor Records&lt;/a&gt;. The Ottawa-based three-piece features a Canuck power-pop pedigree that includes &lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Adamyk&lt;/a&gt; of his titular band and the Sedatives, Jordy Bell of &lt;a href="https://crusades666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crusades&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/capitalcitycreeps" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Creeps&lt;/a&gt;, and Eric French from &lt;a href="https://feraltrash.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feral Trash&lt;/a&gt; and the Varsity Weirdos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 13 song album was recorded by Bell, with drums tracked to analog tape by David Dudley. It arrives on July 14th via the UK label.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/331046174&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt; continue to preview new music from their upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Teenager&lt;/em&gt;, this week sharing the bouncy &amp;quot;Just Drop It.&amp;quot; The band are set to tour their way to August&amp;#39;s SappyFest alongside Sweet Dave &amp;amp; The Shallow Graves (who are alums of the second Pentagon Black comp). You can find the dates over at &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/teenanger_share_just_drop_it_announce_east_coast_tour" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/329531479&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The organizers of Toronto&amp;#39;s annual fall punk and hardcore festival &lt;a href="http://notdeadyettoronto.tumblr.com/NDY2017" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Not Dead Yet&lt;/a&gt; have announced their 2017 lineup. From October 12th to the 15th an international set of artists will descent on the Big Smoke including Trapped Under Ice, founding Cro-Mags member Harley Flanagan, the first Toronto appearance from Portland&amp;#39;s Lebenden Toten, Cleveland acts Inmates and Vanilla Poppers, Halifax&amp;#39;s Booji Boys, Mexican acts Anti-Sex and Rina and more including 1-900s, Acrylics, Burden, C.H.E.W., Collagen, Druj, Fried Egg, Incendiary, Kohti Tuhoa, Krimewatch, Kombat, L.O.T.I.O.N., Marbled Eye, Mommy, Nosferatu, Patsy, Public Eye, Rashomon, Rik &amp;amp; the Pigs, and Witchtrial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;St. Catharines fuzz pop act &lt;a href="https://strangeshakes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Strange Shakes&lt;/a&gt; have released their new single &amp;quot;Pick Up The Phone.&amp;quot; The band will be supporting New Swears on their upcoming tour date in the Garden City on Friday, July 14th at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2530658449/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://strangeshakes.bandcamp.com/album/pick-up-the-phone"&gt;Pick up the Phone by Strange Shakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of which, I&amp;#39;d like to welcome &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; as the July sponsor of Some Party. Recently opened in St. Catharines, Ontario at 11 Geneva Street, the downtown venue has quickly become the go-to event space in Niagara for live music. Run by Eric Dickson of the &lt;a href="indoorshoesmusic.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;IndoorShoes&lt;/a&gt; promotion team, Warehouse has upcoming shows this summer from Daniel Romano, Protest The Hero, Hundred Suns and more. Visit them on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and check out the ever-growing list of upcoming shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A pair of Canadian acts will be separately traversing Europe this July to meet up at the &lt;a href="http://www.punkrockraduno.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punk Rock Raduno&lt;/a&gt; festival in Bergamo, Italy. Toronto&amp;#39;s three-piece punk rock act &lt;a href="https://schooldamage.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;School Damage&lt;/a&gt; will be &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64163/tours-school-damage-touring-with-ratbones-en-route-to-punk-rock-raduno" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;touring&lt;/a&gt; with Genoa, Italy&amp;#39;s Ratbones as they make their way to the event. At the same time Montreal pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt; have their own &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64078/tours-pale-lips-eu" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;shows scheduled&lt;/a&gt; en route.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pale Lips, also a Pentagon Black alumn come to think of it, are set to release a new 7&amp;quot; single this week. &lt;em&gt;Should&amp;#39;ve Known Better!&lt;/em&gt; will be available on July 4th via Italian label Surfin’ Ki and Resurrection Records in the US. Check out the title track below. It&amp;#39;s perfect summer listening:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3850798684/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://resurrectionrecords.bandcamp.com/album/shouldve-known-better"&gt;Should've Known Better! by Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.punkanormalactivity.com/2017/06/26/heading-west-winnipegs-uglies-stickaround-tour/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PunKanormal Activity&lt;/a&gt; shared the tour dates for an August western Canadian tour featuring Winnipeg punk bands &lt;a href="https://the-uglies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Uglies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://stickaroundca.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stickaround&lt;/a&gt;. The tour kicks off on August 18th at The Handsome Daughter and will find the bands supporting their respective 2016 full lengths with shows in major cities across the prairies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The September release of &lt;a href="https://partnerband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s full length &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt; is going to be huge, with the Windsor-via-Sackville band charming their way into everyone&amp;#39;s hearts this summer huge infectious pop songs about questionable behavior. The newest preview is &amp;quot;Sex Object,&amp;quot; which you can hear below. The new LP is out on the 8th of September on &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/330284444&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Glory Days</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-25-glory-days/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-25-glory-days/</id>
    <published>2017-06-24T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-25T23:34:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You knew it was happening from the teasers. Los Angeles punk label &lt;a href="https://sideonedummy.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SideOneDummy Records&lt;/a&gt; tweeted out an animated GIF of Ralph Wiggum sporting the Red Serge and playing the role of Canada at a Simpsons model UN. They had something Canadian to announce. Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt;, who&amp;#39;d broken into the the US punk scene on the label a few years ago, dropped hints as well. &lt;a href="https://www.pkewx3.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pkew Pkew Pkew&lt;/a&gt;, the Toronto party-punk act whose repertoire largely (and proudly) consists of songs about beer and pizza, was getting the call up to the punk rock big leagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s fascinating to look at this transition from this side of the border and compare it to the PR push. You&amp;#39;re of course elated that someone from the home team is getting a shot at making their band their day job. Of course a goofy punk act with a bizarre name like Pkew Pkew Pkew&amp;#39;s never going to sell out arenas, but this type of arrangement could absolutely keep them with a full tour calendar for the near future. You&amp;#39;ve also got that tinge of jealous regret that you&amp;#39;re probably never going to see the band play to 20 people on the floor of Patrick Sheehan&amp;#39;s Irish Pub ever again. Those days are numbered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;My main reaction to these signings, be it Pkew or PUP or The Dirty Nil, is it makes me feel for how damn exhausting the journey must have been. When I first saw Pkew Pkew Pkew it was as part of the now-defunct S.C.E.N.E. Music Festival, playing that graveyard shift of a noon set at an all day event. The infectious pop-punk songs they were belting out in 2011 (&amp;quot;Asshole Pandemic,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Stop Calling Us Chief&amp;quot;, et al) would later appear on a 7&amp;quot; here or there, eventually on the 2013 &lt;em&gt;Glory Days&lt;/em&gt; album (which was I think retroactively downgraded to an EP), and later on their proper debut for &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain&lt;/a&gt;. Now those songs are again getting a reprieve on this SideOne debut. This band has had to, likely many times in the years between now and then, make a choice to not settle for whatever level of exposure these dumb little drinking songs had achieved. For a group that seems so irreverent and carefree, there&amp;#39;s been a long slog behind the scenes to get from there to here. I&amp;#39;m so happy for them, but to consider the years it took and how much songwriting may have been on hold for the sake of &lt;em&gt;these&lt;/em&gt; songs... it just leaves me exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;If SideOne can be guaranteed of anything, it&amp;#39;s that Pkew Pkew Pkew are no strangers to hard work or taking the long view (so long as they can drink on the job, I guess).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WYzGVz0sX60?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Steel City&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hamilton three-piece garage-punk act &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fleshrag/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flesh Rag&lt;/a&gt; (members of Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teeveefreakzz/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt; and Welland&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Rocket-Reducers-50250806853/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Rocket Reducers&lt;/a&gt;) is touring this summer, heading to the Maritimes and back in the first few weeks of July, including an appearance at Moncton&amp;#39;s three day &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/210827159409117/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;NO Funswick Fest&lt;/a&gt; on the 7th. At the time of writing more than few of the venues are unconfirmed, so if you&amp;#39;re on that coast check your local show listings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band will be taking a summer tour tape along with them, released on their own Loose Lips Records. It features 3 new songs recorded in the spring of 2016 at Downtown Sound Studios By Mario Pietrangeli (one of them, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m Sick&amp;quot; is set for inclusion on the upcoming rust belt-themed &lt;em&gt;Killed By Meth 2&lt;/em&gt; compilation on London&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://itstrashrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;It&amp;#39;s Trash&lt;/a&gt;). Four live tracks are also included, recorded on Chris Forrest&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/incorrectthoughts/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Incorrect Thoughts&lt;/a&gt; radio show on &lt;a href="https://chrwradio.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CHRW&lt;/a&gt; this past winter (including an apt cover of the Stooges&amp;#39; &amp;quot;T.V. Eye&amp;quot;). The b-side will include the band&amp;#39;s entire out of print 2015 self-titled 12&amp;quot;. You can stream the new stuff over at BandCamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2723463631/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://fleshrag.bandcamp.com/album/tour-tape-summer-of-bummer-ii"&gt;Tour Tape (Summer of Bummer II) by Flesh Rag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Calgary&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.sledisland.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sled Island&lt;/a&gt; just wrapped up, and an appearance by 70s Hamilton psych / proto-punk act &lt;a href="https://www.simplysaucer.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Simply Saucer&lt;/a&gt; has drummed up a batch of interesting media. The band appeared on Dawn Loucks and Mike Bell&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://cjsw.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CJSW&lt;/a&gt; show &lt;a href="http://cjsw.com/program/saved-by-the-bell/episode/20170621/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Saved By the Bell&lt;/a&gt;, performing four songs live in the studio. The hosts also speak to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wipeoutbeat" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jesse Locke&lt;/a&gt; about his book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.eternalcavalierpress.com/2017/06/14/release-heavy-metalloid-music-second-edition/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Heavy Metalloid Music: The Story of Simply Saucer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the second edition of which was released this summer to coincide with the band&amp;#39;s summer festival appearances. Jesse&amp;#39;s of course a member of both Toronto&amp;#39;s Tough Age and Century Palm and is drumming for Simply Saucer. The band were also treated to a feature by veteran Calgary&amp;#39;s music writer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mrbell_23" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mike Bell&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href="http://www.theyyscene.ca/music/long-strange-trip-of-hamilton-psych-legends-simply-saucer-co/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;theYYSCENE.ca&lt;/a&gt;. Bell speaks at length with Saucer frontman Edgar Breau for the piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thanks to the good people of &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring the launch month of Some Party. Check out their selection online at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.ca&lt;/a&gt;, which ships out from Canada. If you&amp;#39;re looking for a deal their unfortunately soon-to-close physical store at 5904 Main St in Niagara Falls is discounting their stock until the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;UK label &lt;a href="http://www.drunkensailorrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drunken Sailor Records&lt;/a&gt; has confirmed that July will see the debut LP from Ottawa&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/cheapwhine/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cheap Whine&lt;/a&gt;, a three-piece featuring &lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Adamyk&lt;/a&gt;, Jordy of &lt;a href="https://crusades666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crusades&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/capitalcitycreeps" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Creeps&lt;/a&gt;, and Eric from Moncton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://feraltrash.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feral Trash&lt;/a&gt;. What do I get from the Tourism Moncton if I mention the city a third time in this week&amp;#39;s letter? The label boldly states that Cheap Wine &amp;quot;sound like classic 70s punk always sounds in your head, but somehow never quite lives up to&amp;quot; and while I&amp;#39;m not sure what that means, I&amp;#39;m down. You can check out the cover art and some pressing info at the label. There&amp;#39;s no music available to share yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; new, Wade MacNeil produced LP &lt;em&gt;Our Pleasure&lt;/em&gt; was released last week. It&amp;#39;s snide, self-depreciating, and is, from what I can see, being pretty well received. In support of the record there&amp;#39;s an overseas tour lined up for the fall that will see the band playing shows in the UK and mainland Europe. You can find the tour dates over at &lt;a href="http://www.upsetmagazine.com/news/single-mothers-announce-november-headline-tour/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Upset&lt;/a&gt;. A video for the song &amp;quot;People are Pets&amp;quot; also arrived this week. I&amp;#39;ll share it here, although I&amp;#39;m strongly considering a Some Party lyric video boycott, just on principle. This one&amp;#39;s not too bad though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TUMh5lgygGQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Extremely low-fi Toronto punk act &lt;a href="https://protruders.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Protruders&lt;/a&gt; released a new cassette last week to coincide with their Ottawa Explosion appearance. You can check out &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://protruders.bandcamp.com/album/steaming-pile-dance-dancing-ape" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steaming Pile/Dance Dancing Ape&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; over at BandCamp. Seriously though, I played a Protruders song on a Punknews podcast a few weeks ago and I&amp;#39;m pretty sure it made our producer mad at me. Something about clipping? I&amp;#39;m not an engineer, dude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1840099297/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://protruders.bandcamp.com/album/steaming-pile-dance-dancing-ape"&gt;STEAMING PILE/DANCE DANCING APE by protruders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dartmouth, Nova Scotia&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://designosaur.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Designosaur&lt;/a&gt; has the worst band name ever, and we just mentioned Pkew Pkew Pkew a few paragraphs up. The three-piece plays 90s style alt rock with a bit of a Sloan vibe. Their new full length &lt;em&gt;Seattle of the North&lt;/em&gt; was recently released and you can check it out at &lt;a href="https://designosaur.bandcamp.com/album/seattle-of-the-north" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;#39;re also playing No Funsiwck in Moncton (ding!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=719271834/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://designosaur.bandcamp.com/album/seattle-of-the-north"&gt;Seattle of the North by Designosaur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://newnoisemagazine.com/video-premiere-new-swears-777/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Noise&lt;/a&gt; premiered a video for &lt;a href="https://newswears.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; song &amp;quot;777&amp;quot; from their newly released &lt;em&gt;and the Magic of Horses&lt;/em&gt; full length. It was shot by Jordan Wiens, who was behind the camera on the band&amp;#39;s 2015 &amp;quot;Stay Gold&amp;quot; video, and revisits the raucous street scene from that outing (although a bit more relaxed this time).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w0rW0iwD7hc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Mathias Kom and Ariel Sharratt of &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; are heading back overseas this September to play a tour of Scotland alongside New York singer / songwriter Jeffrey Lewis. Before that they&amp;#39;ll also appear at the End Of The Road festival in Dorset (with a handful of Canuck acts including Daniel Romano, Japandroids, Nap Eyes, and Alvvays). Look for dates over at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/theburninghell/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;#39;s no word yet on the band&amp;#39;s follow up to &lt;em&gt;Public Library&lt;/em&gt; but it&amp;#39;s apparently coming this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Mint has announced details on the new full length from moody Vancouver indie rock act &lt;a href="https://woolworm.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Woolworm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Deserve to Die&lt;/em&gt; will arrive on August 25 and run 10 tracks, one of which is &amp;quot;Catbird&amp;quot; which can be streamed below. The band recorded at Rain City Recorders with Jesse Gander (Japandroids, White Lung) for this one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/326432964&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally, Ian Blurton is a busy dude. &lt;a href="https://publicanimal.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Public Animal&lt;/a&gt; is in the studio recording their third LP. Ian says they&amp;#39;ve been &amp;quot;getting our Zep 3 on&amp;quot; so fans of their classic rock referencing style should expect that to continue unabated. Exclaim also announced an &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/change_of_heart_expand_smile_reissue_tour" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;expansion&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href="https://nmc.ca/canadian-bands-you-should-know-change-of-heart/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Change of Heart&lt;/a&gt; reunion tour that&amp;#39;s celebrating the 25th anniversary of their &lt;em&gt;Smile&lt;/em&gt; record. The band&amp;#39;s touring lineup feature Blurton and founding bassist/lyricist Rob Taylor along with Bernard Maiezza on keboards and and Blue Rodeo&amp;#39;s Glenn Milchem on drums.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dream of Booji</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-18-dream-of-booji/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-18-dream-of-booji/</id>
    <published>2017-06-17T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-18T21:31:56-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s 2014 and I&amp;#39;ve just finished watching the Constantines reaffirm my obsession as the headliners of the &lt;a href="https://www.arboretumfestival.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arboretum&lt;/a&gt; festival. Once their set wrapped, my head still swimming in &lt;em&gt;Shine a Light&lt;/em&gt;, I began trekking across town vaguely in the direction of &lt;a href="http://www.gabbaheyshop.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Gabba Hey&lt;/a&gt;, a local Ottawa music shop and scene hub tucked away in an industrial park with zero useful signage. This was clearly not somewhere that I, a tourist who could barely point you towards Parliament, was meant to find. One shameful cab ride later and I&amp;#39;m in line to see WTCHS, the Dirty Nil, and Greys open a record-release show for Ottawa&amp;#39;s hedonistic dirtbag punk act &lt;a href="https://newswears.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The party that officially unveiled &lt;em&gt;Junkfood Forever, Bedtime Whatever&lt;/em&gt; is never far from my mind. It not only introduced me to my favourite record of that year, but it also reaffirmed for me how unpredictable and raucous (and messy with silly string) a punk show could be. That festival and the Gabba Hey gig in particular probably also kicked off a bit of an Ottawa fixation that came to a head this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s three years later and today I find myself on a train back to Niagara, having just attended the 2017 &lt;a href="http://www.ottawaexplosion.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion Weekend&lt;/a&gt;. While New Swears were absent this year, they are on the verge of releasing their follow-up and &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; debut, &lt;em&gt;New Swears and The Magic Of Horses&lt;/em&gt;. So here I sit, with hours to kill, eager to dig into this (perhaps) more mature modern day version of the band... and CBC Music is blocked on VIA Rail&amp;#39;s WiFi. I, as a tax payer, expect far more synergy between my Crown corporations, particularly when it comes to matters of rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll. If you&amp;#39;re not in a train, &lt;a href="http://www.cbcmusic.ca/first-plays/379/first-play-new-swears-and-the-magic-of-horses" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;have at it&lt;/a&gt; until the 23rd of June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='tc center'&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/via_blocked.jpg" alt="Festival Express this is not" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Ottawa Explosion Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;So I&amp;#39;ve attended and survived the 2017 Ottawa Explosion (most of it, we&amp;#39;re missing the Sunday afternoon sets so we can rescue my parents from our children). The venture, from Some Party&amp;#39;s standpoint, was wildly successful and there&amp;#39;ll be plenty to parse here in the coming weeks. In particular, I&amp;#39;ll revisit the release show for &lt;a href="https://thefamines.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Famines&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; new &lt;em&gt;Pentagon Black&lt;/em&gt; paper compilation in a future week (in the meantime though, you should read &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/albums/various-artists-pentagon-black-compilations/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dominionated&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s take on the project).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Above all I feel remarkably lucky to have had the chance to watch the Halifax band &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt; perform twice in one weekend (once in the doorway of Vertigo Records, then a day later in the Galerie Saw basement). The band may take both their name and general sense of weirdness from Devo, but there&amp;#39;s a hell of a lot of that frantic, treble-heavy Marked Men vibe in their sound. I&amp;#39;m happy to report that everything thrilling about their &lt;a href="http://www.drunkensailorrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drunken Sailor&lt;/a&gt;-released self-titled LP is fully reproduced live. Cody Googoo&amp;#39;s wild-eyed, lurching on-stage persona gives their performances a bit of theatre, a sense of showmanship that so many punk bands forgo these days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3227033875/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/album/s-t-lp"&gt;S/T LP by Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m not the first to say it, but Booji Boys are probably the best punk band in Canada in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The members of &lt;a href="https://tough-age.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tough Age&lt;/a&gt; continue to tap into something special. Their outdoor afternoon outdoor performance as part of the &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt; showcase was a great deal of fun, as was the midnight showing by their cousins &lt;a href="https://centurypalm.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Century Palm&lt;/a&gt; (which shares 2/3rds of the roster).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Having relocated from Vancouver to Toronto and paired down to a trio, this year&amp;#39;s model Tough Age is a different animal than you find on the affable garage-pop of 2015&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;I Get The Feeling Central&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;#39;s quite evident on &lt;em&gt;Unclean&lt;/em&gt;, the new 7&amp;quot; the band unveiled just in time for the festival. Once you&amp;#39;re past the frenetic &amp;quot;Guess Not,&amp;quot; the new material is rhythmic, low-fi indie-pop that fans of &lt;a href="https://thecourtneys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Courtneys&lt;/a&gt; and the classic &lt;a href="http://flyingnun.co.nz/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flying Nun&lt;/a&gt; roster should enjoy. You can stream the Mint-released single below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/324411325&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Tough Age should be playing all over the country in the next little while. If you&amp;#39;re at &lt;a href="https://www.sledisland.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sled Island&lt;/a&gt; in Calgary next week, go see them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I watched Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.needlesxpins.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Needles//Pins&lt;/a&gt; from the hill above the Galerie SAW courtyard and it was amazing to see the crowd shouting along with the every big chorus of the band&amp;#39;s gruff-yet-friendly anthems. You can often divide up punk bands up into two camps, one looking to confront and challenge the listener with the other trying to build camaraderie amongst misfits, and Needles//Pins are confidently in the latter. The songs on &lt;em&gt;Feel Good Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; are certainly on track to continue fostering that. The new video for &amp;quot;Miracle&amp;quot;  that &lt;a href="http://clrvynt.com/needle-pins-miracle/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;premiered&lt;/a&gt; at CLRVYNT this week is a strong nod to the band as a unifying force (weird fluorescent eyeballs aside... you&amp;#39;ll see...).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XEtP7nKwqgw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally the &lt;a href="http://thesmugglers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Smugglers&lt;/a&gt; played what &lt;a href="http://grantlawrence.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Grant Lawrence&lt;/a&gt; referred to as their &amp;quot;last show ever... unless a good offer comes along,&amp;quot; marking their final planned performance as part of the &lt;em&gt;Dirty Windshields&lt;/em&gt; book launch that reunited the band. Their set was as rife with nostalgia as one could hope for, from the shout-outs to past Ottawa bands, to the gallery of reproduction tour posters on the walls. I don&amp;#39;t envy the Smugglers having to perform in suits in that humidity (everyone was swimming by the end of it), but there was never a sense that age or inactivity had dulled their enthusiasm, and the crowd responded in kind. There&amp;#39;s a ton of press regarding the new book to tear into, and the recent Globe and Mail &lt;a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/arts/books-and-media/book-reviews/review-grant-lawrences-dirty-windshields-charts-rock-n-roll-fantasies/article35260438/?utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=Referrer:+Social+Network+/+Media&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Shared+Web+Article+Links" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to start as any.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I featured St. John&amp;#39;s based &lt;a href="https://bbqtband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BBQT&lt;/a&gt; on last week&amp;#39;s newsletter at the recommendation of &lt;a href="https://crossedwireshfx.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crossed Wires&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Heather Grant. As she hinted, the band&amp;#39;s released a new set of songs to coincide with their appearance at OWX. You can pick up &amp;quot;All Dressed&amp;quot; over at BandCamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=895846077/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://bbqtband.bandcamp.com/album/all-dressed"&gt;ALL DRESSED by BBQT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Dine Alone tour I mentioned a few weeks ago wrapped up in Toronto last night, and it feels like &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey and the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt; may be riding out of it on a huge wave of goodwill. At least that&amp;#39;s my unscientific survey of t-shirt sightings in Ottawa this weekend. The video for their Clash-meets-Stones single &amp;quot;Talk 2 Her&amp;quot; just premiered at &lt;a href="http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/ffca9f8771/sam-coffey-the-iron-lungs-talk-2-her-official-music-video" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Funny or Die&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s award season. The &lt;a href="http://polarismusicprize.ca/2017-long-list/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;long list&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href="http://polarismusicprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Polaris Music Prize&lt;/a&gt; was announced this past week. Jurors will now whittle down a list of 10 from these 40 Canadian records, including recent LPs from The Sadies, Fiver, The New Pornographers, Daniel Romano, John K. Samson, and more. If I&amp;#39;ve got to make a prediction, &lt;a href="http://atribecalledred.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;A Tribe Called Red&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;We Are the Halluci Nation&lt;/em&gt; feels like the record to beat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last year&amp;#39;s Polaris winner Kaytranada now finds himself contenting for another honour, this time the fan-voted &lt;a href="http://www.socansongwritingprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SOCAN Songwriting Prize&lt;/a&gt;. The nominees were announced this past week. Among them are two personal favourites of mine, &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;DVP&amp;quot; (part of the 1-2 punch that opens &lt;em&gt;The Dream Is Over&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://weavesband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Weaves&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; grungy anthem &amp;quot;Shithole.&amp;quot; You can vote, if you&amp;#39;re so inclined, at the link.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The latest from &lt;a href="http://vishkhanna.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Vish Khanna&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s always thoughtful &lt;a href="http://vishkhanna.com/2017/06/14/ep-324-daniel-romano/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kreative Kontrol&lt;/a&gt; podcast features a chat with &lt;a href="http://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt; on the inspirations and creative processes behind the now-Polaris nominated &lt;em&gt;Modern Pressure&lt;/em&gt;. Yes, I&amp;#39;m aware I write about this artist a lot. Never far from the pulse of things, Vish also featured Jasmyn Burke of the aforementioned Weaves on the new episode of his TV show Long Night. She&amp;#39;s part of a panel tasked with the question &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://vishkhanna.com/2017/06/16/ep-325-is-rock-music-dead-long-night-with-carl-wilson-shad-and-weaves-jasmyn-burke/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Is Rock Music Dead?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto three-piece &lt;a href="http://www.bikethiefsband.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bike Thiefs&lt;/a&gt; have an infuriating name but a cool sound, with sing-spoken vocals over busy, angular post-punk. They&amp;#39;ve announced a new EP titled &lt;em&gt;Lean Into It.&lt;/em&gt; The video for the first single, &amp;quot;Destination Wedding,&amp;quot; was premiered this past week at &lt;a href="http://www.imposemagazine.com/tv/bike-thiefs-destination-wedding" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Impose&lt;/a&gt; along with a number of tour dates in both the US and the Maritimes. Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bwMScpZbScg?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Earlier today &lt;a href="https://www.theonlybandever.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Alexisonfire&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s announced the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/AOFofficial/posts/10158916556895215" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;postponement&lt;/a&gt; of four sold out reunion shows that were set to kick off this week at Toronto&amp;#39;s Danforth Music Hall. The reasoning is medical, but not much else is known at this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One band that was slated to play those shows is Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;. The tightly wound garage-hardcore act has announced that, outside of the Alexis gig and a to-be-announced all-ages hometown show, they&amp;#39;re going to hunker down and write and record a new LP. The follow up to 2015&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://derangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deranged&lt;/a&gt;-released &lt;em&gt;Bad Luck Charms&lt;/em&gt; will be the band&amp;#39;s forth and first since frontman Dave O&amp;#39;Connor launched his Sweet Dave &amp;amp; The Shallow Graves side project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thanks to the good people of &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring the launch of Some Party. Check out their selection online at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.ca&lt;/a&gt;, which ships out from Canada. If you&amp;#39;re looking for a deal their unfortunately soon-to-close physical store at 5904 Main St in Niagara Falls is discounting their stock until they close up at the end of June.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bytown bound</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-11-bytown-bound/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-11-bytown-bound/</id>
    <published>2017-06-10T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-11T23:15:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This is the last newsletter before this year&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion&lt;/a&gt; kicks off. I don&amp;#39;t manage to get out to many festivals, but there&amp;#39;s something about this one in particular that feels very close to what I&amp;#39;m shooting for here on Some Party. In years past I&amp;#39;ve looked at the OXW lineups in complete awe, not because of the bands listed but because I&amp;#39;d recognize embarrassingly few of them. Those lineups were a wake up call that despite however many years I&amp;#39;ve spent talking about punk music (and Canadian punk music in particular), I wasn&amp;#39;t scratching the surface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;So I&amp;#39;ll absolutely be at the Ottawa Explosion this year, but as I&amp;#39;m very much still a tourist, let&amp;#39;s pull in an expert. To help spotlight one of the many cool bands I&amp;#39;ll be discovering this year, I reached out to Heather Grant. Based out of Halifax, Heather&amp;#39;s performing (at least) three sets at the festival this year. More on those in a minute, but here&amp;#39;s her recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;One band you should definitely catch at OXW is &lt;a href="https://bbqtband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BBQT&lt;/a&gt;. From St. John&amp;#39;s NL, this doo-wopp-y power pop band has such catchy songs that sometimes I&amp;#39;m kind of afraid to listen to them because I know for a fact that they&amp;#39;re going to be stuck in my head for the rest of the day. If you like bands like Peach Kelli Pop, the White Wires or early era Donnas, you&amp;#39;ll definitely be into BBQT. Word has it that they&amp;#39;re also releasing some new songs in the next few days leading up to OXW so folks should keep an eye out for that!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=846412531/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://bbqtband.bandcamp.com/album/bbqt"&gt;BBQT by BBQT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Heather&amp;#39;s got a pair of pop-punk / garage rock bands playing OXW. She&amp;#39;ll appear as part of the trio &lt;a href="https://crossedwireshfx.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crossed Wires&lt;/a&gt; on Friday at Club Saw, returning there the next day to perform with the four-piece &lt;a href="https://futuregirls.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Future Girls&lt;/a&gt;. Friday will also see her perform solo at St Alban&amp;#39;s along with a number of singer/songwriters (hometown troubadours &lt;a href="http://www.joncreeden.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jon Creeden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/cory-levesque" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cory Levesque&lt;/a&gt;, Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://jesselebourdais.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jesse Lebourdais&lt;/a&gt;, and Heather&amp;#39;s Future Girls bandmate Matty Grace).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yzjBK5vsXBg?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In the lead up to the Explosion a handful of interesting write-ups on the performing bands have bubbled up online. Eric Scharf of &lt;a href="http://www.ottawashowbox.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Showbox&lt;/a&gt; ran an &lt;a href="http://www.ottawashowbox.com/2017/06/famines-discuss-diy-minded-label-pentagon-black/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Drew Demers of Montreal art/noise duo &lt;a href="http://www.thefamines.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Famines&lt;/a&gt;. Demers discusses the band&amp;#39;s experimental record label Pentagon Black, which just released the third in their &amp;quot;paper compilation&amp;quot; series. Calgary punk act &lt;a href="https://leatherjacuzzi.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Leather Jacuzzi&lt;/a&gt; premiered the song &amp;quot;Gloved Hand Holding Caviar&amp;quot; from their upcoming sophomore cassette &lt;em&gt;Slander, Lies &amp;amp; Soda&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/leather_jacuzzi-gloved_hand_holding_caviar" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile over at &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dominionated&lt;/a&gt;, Jim Di Giota reviewed &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/albums/bonnie-doon-dooner-nooner/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dooner Nooner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the debut full length from &lt;a href="https://bonniedoon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonnie Doon&lt;/a&gt;, an incredibly eclectic mix of low-fi surf, sludgy post-punk, and high energy tracks with a bit of an X-Ray Spex vibe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1502602117/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2348226238/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://bonniedoon.bandcamp.com/album/dooner-nooner"&gt;Dooner Nooner by Bonnie Doon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 40 acts voted to the 2017 &lt;a href="http://polarismusicprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Polaris Music Prize&lt;/a&gt; long list will be unveiled next Tuesday, June 13. The announcement will be streamed live on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/polarismusicprize" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; at 2 PM EST / 11 PST. A live version of the Polaris podcast be recorded that evening at the &lt;a href="https://nac-cna.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;National Arts Centre&lt;/a&gt; with a number of jurors and special guests on hand to discuss the albums selected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://nardwuar.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nardwuar the Human Serviette&lt;/a&gt; appeared on &lt;a href="http://www.northerntransmissions.com/news/nardwuar-guests-records-life/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Northern Transmissions&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; &amp;quot;Records In My Life&amp;quot; video series. The chat was filmed during the Evaporators&amp;#39; Record Store Day appearance at Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://neptoon.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Neptoon Records&lt;/a&gt;. He discusses the band&amp;#39;s latest full length &lt;em&gt;Ogopogo Punk&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt;), which came out on 8-track (why not), along with stories about records from Slow, The Pointed Sticks and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://sheshredsmag.com/video-premiere-diy-pony/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;She Shreds Magazine&lt;/a&gt; premiered a video from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ponyband/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PONY&lt;/a&gt; for the song &amp;quot;DIY.&amp;quot; The track appears on the power-pop act&amp;#39;s upcoming EP for &lt;a href="http://buzzrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Buzz Records&lt;/a&gt; and was directed by Sudbury&amp;#39;s Shawn Kosmo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xnB8Z4Fbt0Y?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.katiemariejensen.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Katie Jensen&lt;/a&gt; recently made a deputation to the Toronto Music Advisory Council regarding the need to protect the city&amp;#39;s disappearing live music venues. The text of which, and a live-tweeting of the council&amp;#39;s recent meeting, can be found over at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/katiejensen/status/871813234638168066" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto punk act &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt; are going all in on their frequently misspelled name by calling their new full length &lt;em&gt;Teenager&lt;/em&gt;. The album, the band&amp;#39;s fifth, will be a 13 song set to be released by &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/products/teenanger-teenager-lp-pre-order" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; in July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/326570581&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Teenanger will be among the bands playing &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest&lt;/a&gt; in Sackville, NB this year. The event&amp;#39;s final lineup has now been announced, with &lt;a href="https://thecourtneys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Courtneys&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.fiverfiverfiver.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fiver&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://jonmckiel.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jon McKiel&lt;/a&gt; among the acts confirmed. SappyFest runs from August 4th to the 6th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; is recording a new LP. I don&amp;#39;t know much outside the fact that there are saxophones involved. It&amp;#39;s probably not a ska record, but you never know. The band&amp;#39;s Ben Cook recently put out a new power-pop single as &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt; titled &lt;em&gt;Traumatic&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s available on &lt;a href="http://www.slumberlandrecords.com/catalog/show/311" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slumberland&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/318104404&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A big thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring this first month of Some Party. I recently saw the sad news their physical location in Niagara is closing at the end of the month. While it&amp;#39;s a huge bummer, there are certainly deals to be had at 5904 Main St in Niagara Falls as they clear out the inventory, so check it out while you can. Their online record store at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.ca&lt;/a&gt; is still going strong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally, I&amp;#39;ve always found &lt;a href="http://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s relationship with punk rock to be fascinating, given his past and how aggressively he&amp;#39;s moved from the confines of the genre (Ancient Shapes notwithstanding). So how cool was it to run into a song like &amp;quot;The Pride of Queens&amp;quot; on his latest record &lt;em&gt;Modern Pressure&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;#39;ve heard far more Ramones tributes than I care to acknowledge, but there are very few as effective at this one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jZtmv-KLUfE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Best Buzz</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-04-best-buzz/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-04-best-buzz/</id>
    <published>2017-06-03T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T07:52:20-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m amazed that despite the incessant pace of online chatter I can often still recall the singular source where I first heard a band. Music rarely finds me through that nebulous sense of ambient awareness that social media&amp;#39;s supposed to provide. Whenever it seems like everyone&amp;#39;s talking about a new band, chances are it&amp;#39;s not for me. There&amp;#39;s a great deal I stumble upon through looking up the openers of shows or digging through the archives of some blog I trust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='tc center'&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/right_shitty.jpg" alt="Right Shitty" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;So to give credit where it&amp;#39;s due, I first ran into Saint John, New Brunswick&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://rightshitty.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Right Shitty&lt;/a&gt; while tearing through the archives of the venerable &lt;a href="https://weirdcanada.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Weird Canada&lt;/a&gt;. Somewhere among that day&amp;#39;s sea of obscure tape drones and flowery bilingual prose I ran into a gritty little punk rock band that sounds both familiar yet vital. 2016&amp;#39;s full length &lt;em&gt;Bachelor Of Arts&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href="http://monopolizedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Monopolized&lt;/a&gt;) makes the case that there&amp;#39;s plenty of gas left in the tank for gruff hardcore of the No Idea Records stripe. Yet unlike the acts that typify that Gainesville label, Right Shitty balances their louder moments not with melodic pop-punk but instead with low-fi grunge. Pavement&amp;#39;s the lazy comparison. I was instantly taken with &amp;quot;Best Buzz,&amp;quot; which gallops towards a first-in-the-air chorus that&amp;#39;s pretty much cynic proof.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=427801072/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=208060129/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://rightshitty.bandcamp.com/album/bachelor-of-arts-2"&gt;Bachelor of Arts by Right Shitty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It looks like the fine people of Saint John feel the same. &amp;quot;Best Buzz&amp;quot; and &lt;em&gt;Bachelor of Arts&lt;/em&gt; recently took home the top honours for Song and Album at the Best of Saint John Music Awards, thrown by the campus and community radio station &lt;a href="http://localfm.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Local 107.3FM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A week prior, I had the opportunity to help the band launch a few new songs at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/63924/media-right-shitty-henry-lee-lucas-crackd-out-punknews-exclusive" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Henry Lee Lucas&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Crack’d Out&amp;quot; land on the heavier end of the spectrum. They&amp;#39;re mixed and mastered by Monopolized&amp;#39;s Corey Bonnevie and appear in a video by Saint John filmmakers Mike Roy and Nick LeBlanc (the pair recently completed a local music scene documentary titled &lt;a href="http://www.gridcitymagazine.com/out-of-the-fog-quality-block-party/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;In the Brick: A Quality Block Party&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ddia8o8Rp9A?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I keep thinking about where I found Right Shitty, if for no other reason the band explicitly asked me, and I found that funny at the time. I listed &lt;em&gt;Bachelor of Arts&lt;/em&gt; in my year end write-up on Punknews and word somehow got to the group. I absolutely got the sense that, while they were happy for the recognition, they were somewhat surprised I had run into them at all. Credit goes to Weird of course, but I keep thinking about publications like theirs and the service that it provides artists. I&amp;#39;ve been in the PR-driven news cycle for so long that these more esoteric channels of discovery feel downright magical at times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Safe Harbour&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;University of Ottawa law professor Michael Geist provided some &lt;a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/2017/05/music-industrys-canadian-copyright-reform-goal-end-tech-companies-safe-harbours/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;commentary&lt;/a&gt; this week on a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MusicCanada/videos/vb.140246729361512/1473078872744951/?type=2&amp;amp;theater" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt; by Miranda Mulholland of &lt;a href="http://www.greatlakeswimmers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Great Lake Swimmers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.roaringgirlrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Roaring Girl Records&lt;/a&gt; to the Economic Club of Canada. While praising Mulholland&amp;#39;s passionate, personal talk Dr. Geist takes some time to unpack the concept of &amp;quot;safe harbours&amp;quot; in the Canadian context. Mulholland and the wider industry (her speech was broadcast by of the trade organization Music Canada) have been making the case that the government should legislate an end to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In the States the safe harbor provisions have allowed a user-generated content platform like YouTube to avoid legal responsibility for the uploading of unlicensed content. The service has to either remove infringing content upon request, or provide some form of compensation to the rightsholders, and this keeps matters out of the courts. The industry believes that by forcing Google (and everyone else) to be liable for infringement, ultimately more money for licensing will flow to the artists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dr. Geist&amp;#39;s angle is interesting in that he attempts to untangle the assumptions on how much of the US safe harbour provisions are actually mirrored in Canadian law. The big surprise for me was that there&amp;#39;s no legislated notice-and-takedown style  system in Canada at all. Both Dr. Geist&amp;#39;s break down of the legal specificities and Mulholland&amp;#39;s perspective are absolutely worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://warrenkinsella.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warren Kinsella&lt;/a&gt; has previewed a rough cut of a new song titled &amp;quot;GPS&amp;quot; from his self-described &amp;quot;geriatric punk rock group&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/sfhpunks/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shit From Hell&lt;/a&gt;. The Toronto-based lawyer and political consultant also has a new novel on the way titled &lt;em&gt;Recipe For Hate&lt;/em&gt; in which a band fights a gang of neo-Nazis. I&amp;#39;ll have more on that in a future week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tss9DtrWGhk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ottawa&amp;#39;s debaucherous garage rock act &lt;a href="https://newswears.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears&lt;/a&gt; continue to tease music from their third LP (and first for Dine Alone), &lt;em&gt;The Magic of Horses&lt;/em&gt;. The song &amp;quot;Halos in Hell&amp;quot; premiered over at &lt;a href="http://earmilk.com/2017/06/01/new-swears-call-for-a-shouty-singalong-with-halos-in-hell-premiere/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ear Milk&lt;/a&gt; along with a batch of tour dates supporting the June 23rd release of the record (including a pair of release shows at their hometown pierogi &amp;amp; pinball venue &lt;a href="http://www.houseoftarg.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;House of TARG&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;#39;ll admit I have a slight obsession with).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://grantlawrence.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Grant Lawrence&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://thesmugglers.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Smugglers&lt;/a&gt; will launch &lt;em&gt;Dirty Windows&lt;/em&gt;, his new book of tour diaries, with a show at Toronto&amp;#39;s legendary &lt;a href="http://www.horseshoetavern.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Horseshow Tavern&lt;/a&gt; (I can&amp;#39;t write that name without prefixing &amp;quot;legendary,&amp;quot; as it&amp;#39;s been drilled into me for years). The June 16th show will feature &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt; acts &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/duotangband/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Duotang&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.needlesxpins.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Needles//Pins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This first month of the Some Party newsletter is sponsored by the folks at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt;. You can purchased records online from them at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.ca&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.com&lt;/a&gt;, or in person at 5904 Main St in Niagara Falls and 1695 Queen St West in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/arts/music/partners-technical-prowess-meets-slacker-predispositions/article35156941/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Globe and Mail&lt;/a&gt; did a big feature on the Windsor, Ontario based &lt;a href="http://partnerband.tumblr.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt;, announcing that the five-piece will release &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt; on September 8th via &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You’ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;. This all comes with the unveiling of the HUGE pop single &amp;quot;Everybody Knows,&amp;quot; which I&amp;#39;ll venture is among the hookiest damn songs about weed ever written.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/325252266&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of which, the &lt;a href="http://www.thehip.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tragically Hip&lt;/a&gt; are getting into the medical cannabis business, announcing a &lt;a href="http://www.thehip.com/cannabis/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;partnership&lt;/a&gt; with the Brantford based company &lt;a href="http://newstrike.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Newstrike&lt;/a&gt; this week. The CBC is also set to rebroadcast the now-famous Kingston &lt;em&gt;Man Machine Poem&lt;/em&gt; show, in its entirety, on June 24 (just in case you wanted to cry again).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://peeling.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Peeling&lt;/a&gt; recently released the EP &lt;em&gt;7 Years of Blood&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://buzzrecords.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Buzz Records&lt;/a&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s fronted by Mexican Slang&amp;#39;s Annabelle Lee and features &lt;a href="https://dillydally.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dilly Dally&lt;/a&gt; bassist Jimmy Tony Rowlinson, &lt;a href="http://www.odonisodonis.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Odonis Odonis&lt;/a&gt; drummer Denholm Whale, and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thegoldendogs/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Golden Dogs&lt;/a&gt; guitarist Alejandro Cairncross. A video for the song &amp;quot;Wandering Womb,&amp;quot; directed by Lee and shot by Mike Wallace of Preoccupations, was recently premiered over at &lt;a href="https://noisey.vice.com/en_ca/article/peelings-new-video-smears-menstrual-blood-on-wandering-womb-myth" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Noisey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O2dyoPPZsLo?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally this week, Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.bajohnston.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;B.A. Johnston&lt;/a&gt;, in a remarkably obvious move that I can&amp;#39;t believe hadn&amp;#39;t happened sooner, announced the production of Olde B.A. Johnston’s Finest Malt Liquor. The iconoclastic singer-songwriter has paired up with Gravenhurst, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.sawdustcitybrewing.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sawdust City&lt;/a&gt; for the brewing expertise. It should be available on June 15th in the Sawdust City taproom and on tap at various bars across Ontario. B.A. will most likely drink it in the alley next to said bars, given that Dude Beer is no longer a thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BUzVkIfAq4K/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank"&gt;Get ready for a HAMMER to your liver. BA Johnston Malt Liquor out in mid June, from the good people at Sawdust City Brewery. Bug your local dives to stock. #maltliqour #crunked #shreddable #credible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A post shared by ba johnston (@oldbajohnston) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-06-01T15:33:50+00:00"&gt;Jun 1, 2017 at 8:33am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pleasure Overdose</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-05-28-pleasure-overdose/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-05-28-pleasure-overdose/</id>
    <published>2017-05-27T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-28T23:25:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Part of my motivation in starting Some Party as a weekly newsletter was to force myself to operate outside the daily news cycle that Punknews and the rest of the Internet music apparatus thrives on. There&amp;#39;s a formula to how a new music is disseminated and it should sound familiar. A band will make mention of their next album, perhaps by sharing a title or who&amp;#39;s producing it, sometimes just their &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; to record, that will kick off a round of press coverage. In the lead-up to the release you&amp;#39;ll see the usual collection of stories, dribbled out over time. Studio photos show up on Instagram. Perhaps there&amp;#39;s a studio clip of the guitarist noodling out the hook from a new song on Facebook. Eventually a single shows up on SoundCloud or BandCamp, and it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;exclusively&amp;quot; announced on one news outlet or another. That repeats a few times and eventually the record&amp;#39;s released. The band, the label, a PR person if that&amp;#39;s in the budget, and the press kick that ball back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;What you&amp;#39;ll rarely see is news that an album &lt;em&gt;has been&lt;/em&gt; released. That crosses the incredibly nebulous line between reporting and promotion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While it&amp;#39;s become more common these days to see bands big and small forgo the lead-up and surprise fans with a new record, it&amp;#39;s remains awkward to report on. &amp;quot;Product exists for purchase&amp;quot; isn&amp;#39;t a great story. The exception of course is if the artist is of global name recognition, then the story shifts to how utterly awed we all are that they dared buck the system for the sake of their art, or some nonsense like that. Small bands don&amp;#39;t get to play that card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I was elated that this week saw the sudden and unheralded release of a new album from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://soupcans.info/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Soupcans&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pleasure Overdose&lt;/em&gt; is 9 songs in 18 minutes of erratic, gloriously bonkers punk rock from one of the city&amp;#39;s shining examples of how the genre can remain dangerous and unpredictable in 2017. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; was not only a release worth celebrating ,but it&amp;#39;s precisely the kind of thing I want to talk about on this newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3568221848/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thesoupcans.bandcamp.com/album/pleasure-overdose"&gt;Pleasure Overdose by Soupcans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Furthermore if you follow the band online one gets the distinct impression that they had broken up following  their late-2015 &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; album &lt;em&gt;Soft Party&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than simply accept and celebrate this new record, my instinct was to put on my reporter hat and dig a bit. I reached out to the group and got in touch with bassist Nick (lastname withheld) who graciously agreed to talk to me. I proceeded to ignore the circumstances of the release and throw him a bunch of rote online music news questions (which in retrospect amounted to &amp;quot;please write me a press release&amp;quot;), followed by a postscript that read&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;If you&amp;#39;re shooting for a level of weird mystique with the whole thing then by all means don&amp;#39;t break that veil by telling me anything.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I did get answers, because Nick is great. I also got the distinct impression a veil of weird mystique is the preferred mode of operation for the band. If I was reporting for a news website I&amp;#39;d be more inclined to share the boring details I extracted, but that&amp;#39;s not the goal &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You should go listen to &lt;em&gt;Pleasure Overdose&lt;/em&gt; because it&amp;#39;s cool. It picks up on the speed and moments of pure sludge that made &lt;em&gt;Soft Party&lt;/em&gt; so vital, and tosses in a mix of free-flowing new ideas and deviations. Enjoy it for what it is. You can pay what you want for it at &lt;a href="https://thesoupcans.bandcamp.com/album/pleasure-overdose" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Human Party Trick&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I caught the first night of the &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; package tour in Hamilton on Thursday. While I&amp;#39;ve seen both the Dirty Nil and the Flatliners more times than I can recall, it was my first live experience with the Toronto-via-Waterloo group &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey and the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt;, who opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While I enjoyed the band&amp;#39;s last record, the material they&amp;#39;ve assembled for their upcoming self-titled &lt;a href="http://burgerrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Burger&lt;/a&gt; / Dine Alone co-release is something else. The six-piece, in matching denim, put on one of the strongest and most engaging sets I&amp;#39;ve seen in a while. The new songs feel like big, muscular covers of 80s pop-rock hits and I mean that with as much affection as possible. This band&amp;#39;s been all over the place stylistically in the past, but the place they&amp;#39;ve landed is really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/318509292&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The rest of the bill had me playing anthropologist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;My love affair with Dundas, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thedirtynil/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; is pretty well known, but I couldn&amp;#39;t help but be a little worried about the band. After countless small bar shows the last time I saw them was opening for Flag, and they had the unforgiving task of opening a sparsely filled Lee&amp;#39;s Palace, which felt cavernous and foreign. This would also be the first time I&amp;#39;ve seen them perform since losing bassist Dave Nardi. I had no doubts that Ross Miller, his replacement, would be able to carry the songs. Ross has been a fixture in the Niagara music scene for years and he&amp;#39;s proven to be everyone&amp;#39;s go-to &lt;a href="https://sidemanhc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;sideman&lt;/a&gt;. Dave&amp;#39;s absence is notable because his stoic stage presence and aggressive, serious performance always felt like a perfect counterpoint to frontman Luke Bentham&amp;#39;s playful, showy charisma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Nil sounded great though. Ross isn&amp;#39;t Dave, but he wasn&amp;#39;t trying to dial back his own strong personality to fit someone&amp;#39;s mould. It&amp;#39;s a new dynamic, but it worked. The more intimate venue (&lt;a href="http://www.clubabsinthe.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Club Absinthe&lt;/a&gt;) and the hometown crowd shook off any sense of fatigue I sensed back at that Flag gig. It&amp;#39;ll remain to be seen what kind of material the band writes without Nardi&amp;#39;s tastes in the mix, but so far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theflatliners.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Flatliners&lt;/a&gt; have been through their current trials before. The band had been easing away from their 3rd wave ska trappings for years but with 2010&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Cavalcade&lt;/em&gt; made that transition complete. There were shows back then where you could feel the crowd&amp;#39;s trepidation with the new material. A room that was bouncing one minute locked still the next until something familiar returned. The big punk anthems the band was writing though turned out to be so damn likable that it didn&amp;#39;t take long for those to become the new standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The songs of &lt;em&gt;Inviting Light&lt;/em&gt;, the new record, step away from the roaring anthems and fist-pumping crowd-pleasers. What you&amp;#39;re left with is a rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll band with few genre conventions to hide under. I&amp;#39;m not sure the crowd was quite into it yet, but what struck me seeing them live is that these new songs have incredibly strong bones. It may not be what a lot of the old guard fans want, but the songwriting&amp;#39;s there and the band&amp;#39;s confident in it. There&amp;#39;s a pretty dynamic set list to be built between these and the &lt;em&gt;Cavalcade&lt;/em&gt; era anthems as well. I&amp;#39;m feeling a lot better about this record than I was initially.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ff8KCvbxkZA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That said, after the requisite encore of the decade-old ska-punk favourite &amp;quot;Fred&amp;#39;s Got Slacks,&amp;quot; someone turned to me and said ecstatically &amp;quot;Dude! It&amp;#39;s like high school!&amp;quot; so I&amp;#39;m not sure what people really want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://ottawabeat.com/2017/05/18/brief-history-ottawa-explosion-weekend/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Beat&lt;/a&gt; has written up a brief history of the &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion Weekend&lt;/a&gt; that delves into the shows and scenes that preceded, and gave raise to the now-annual garage-punk festival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One band playing this year&amp;#39;s Explosion is Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://sweetdaveandtheshallowgraves.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sweet Dave and the Shallow Graves&lt;/a&gt;, the gothic, esoteric project of &lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; David O&amp;#39;Connor. His touring band, which in fact includes the aforementioned Dave Nardi, will hit the road following this Summer in an eastward trek to land them at &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sappyfest&lt;/a&gt; in Sackville, New Brunswick in early August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;div class='dib tl w-100 maxread'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media dib tl" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BUhWjMvDm4W/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank"&gt;SWEET DAVE &amp;amp; THE SHALLOW GRAVES SUMMER 2017 TOUR DATES: Friday, June 16. Ottawa - OXW - Avante Garde Bar Thursday, June 22. Hamilton - Doors Pub w/Dead Soft Thursday, June 29. Toronto - Baby G w/Fotocrime  Friday, July 14. Paris, ON - Strangewaves w/The Urinals  Friday, July 28. Hamilton - Boxcar w/Teenanger &amp;amp; Big School Saturday, July 29. Ottawa - House of Targ w/Teenanger Sunday, July 30. Montreal - TBA w/Teenanger Tuesday, August 1. Quebec City - L'Anti Bar w/Teenanger Wednesday, August 2. Fredericton - TBA w/Teenanger  Thursday, August 3. Halifax - The Seahorse w/Teenanger &amp;amp; Booji Boys Friday, August 4 - Sappyfest Saturday, August 5 - Sappyfest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A post shared by David O'Connor (@sweeetdave) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-05-25T15:56:07+00:00"&gt;May 25, 2017 at 8:56am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;div class='dib tl w-100 maxread'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"&gt;
&lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/head&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Keeping with the theme of referencing musicians from earlier in this very newsletter, new Dirty Nil bassist Ross Miller also plays with London, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt;. That band&amp;#39;s new record &lt;em&gt;Our Pleasure&lt;/em&gt; arrives on June 16th via Dine Alone. They previewed the new song &amp;quot;Leash&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="http://www.brooklynvegan.com/stream-single-mothers-leash-off-upcoming-lp/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brooklyn Vegan&lt;/a&gt; this week and have &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/singlemothersparty/events/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;three release shows&lt;/a&gt; announced in Ontario this June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/324337394&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ll leave you with a feel-good story about the teenage Peel band Vinyl Ambush. The group was playing a house party that was hit with a noise complaint, and the police officer who arrived at the scene ended up playing with them. You can find the full account at &lt;a href="http://www.citynews.ca/2017/05/21/peel-police-officer-rocks-local-band-vinyl-ambush/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;City News&lt;/a&gt; and see the evidence below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iV788SBdjyw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A huge thanks to the folks at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring this first month of the Some Party newsletter. Check out the great selection at their online record stores at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.ca&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.com&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;#39;re south of the border. They&amp;#39;ve got friendly physical locations at both 5904 Main St in Niagara Falls and 1695 Queen St West in Toronto for you to check out too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
