<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter sharing the latest in independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated every Sunday evening by Adam White. Some Party features punk, garage, psych, and otherwise uncategorizable indie rock, drawing lines from proto to post and every weird diversion along the way.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2020-09-19T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Big Gay Hands</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-09-20-big-gay-hands/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2020-09-20-big-gay-hands/</id>
    <published>2020-09-19T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-22T16:52:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sackville-bred slack-rock heroes &lt;a href="https://www.partnerband.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt; recently shared the fourth preview of their upcoming sophomore full-length. &amp;quot;Big Gay Hands&amp;quot; is a song that&amp;#39;s become a live staple over the past few years (so much so that it was part of the group&amp;#39;s high profile Polaris Gala performance when &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt; was in contention). The long-awaited studio version of the track doesn&amp;#39;t disappoint, lyrically flipping a hard-rock trope on its head while at the same time paying unabashed homage to the guitar heroism of its classic rock forebearers. The band commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Big Gay Hands&amp;#39; has been a live favourite for 3 years now, and we&amp;#39;re so excited to release it on our upcoming album, &lt;em&gt;Never Give Up&lt;/em&gt;. We wrote &amp;#39;Big Gay Hands&amp;#39; after listening to a lot of AC/DC and other hard rock acts singing about women&amp;#39;s bodies and sexualizing them. We didn&amp;#39;t think there was enough songs out there (or even A song?) about women&amp;#39;s big gay hands. So we fixed that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This song is about a wild night on the town filled with queer desire. It is an important song to us because it expresses a feeling we know is shared by many. There are a lot of songs out there about women&amp;#39;s bodies but this is the only song we know about big gay hands. This song is dedicated to the hotties and to those who love them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Partner worked with &lt;a href="https://bonniedoon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonnie Doon&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Lesley Marshall on the accompanying video (which is absolutely adorable, by the way).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 10-song &lt;em&gt;Never Give Up&lt;/em&gt; arrives from &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; on November 20, following up 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt; and 2019&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Saturday the 14th&lt;/em&gt; EP. This record finds vocalist/guitarist Josée Caron and vocalist/bassist Lucy Niles backed by drummer Simone TB (Darlene Shrugg, Fake Palms). Partner recorded this material in July of 2019 at Palace Sounds, with Steve Chahley (Ice Cream, US Girls) engineering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3hxWLlmQYVY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3hxWLlmQYVY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Partner - &amp;quot;Big Gay Hands&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto punk trio &lt;a href="http://theobgms.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The OBGMs&lt;/a&gt; have a frantic new video online featuring &amp;quot;Outsah,&amp;quot; the album-opening cut from their upcoming full-length &lt;em&gt;The Ends&lt;/em&gt;. The group co-directed the aggressive clip with Toronto rapper &lt;a href="https://www.ctsecond.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Clairmont The Second&lt;/a&gt; and their frequent visual collaborator Beee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vocalist/guitarist Densil McFarlane commented on the video and the song&amp;#39;s role as a forceful declaration of intent:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We make movies over here. &amp;#39;Outsah&amp;#39; is a joint collaboration with Clairmont The Second and Beee and we really wanted to do something gritty. I wanted to tell a story in a cinematic continuous shot and really make a statement. This song, and this video, speak to what we are willing to do. We are going to run up in your house, give us what we want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This is one of those songs where we&amp;#39;re doing stuff other people aren&amp;#39;t doing. We threw bongos on the motherfucker. That song is a statement and that statement is, &amp;#39;We&amp;#39;re not afraid of you, and we&amp;#39;de willing to confront you. Come see me if you have a problem with it. We&amp;#39;re already outside.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ends&lt;/em&gt; arrives on October 30 from &lt;a href="https://weareblackbox.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Box&lt;/a&gt;. These days the OBGMs play as a trio comprised of McFarlane, bassist Joseph Brosnan, and drummer Colanthony Humphrey. They recorded this new material with Grammy and JUNO Award-winning producer Dave Schiffman (PUP, The Bronx, Anti-Flag).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HmdWcsm6vUY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/HmdWcsm6vUY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The OBGMs - &amp;quot;Outsah&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;New York City post-punk artist Chandra, and her Toronto-based backing band, recently unveiled a remote-recorded version of &amp;quot;Shut In / Shut Out.&amp;quot; The song (accompanied by a Zoom-style performance video) gives new life to a demo Chandra Oppenheim wrote in 1983 at the age of 14. Oppenheim, who had been active in the New York No Wave scene (rather astonishingly) at the age of 10, tracked her initial demo of this song with Eugenie Diserio and Steven Alexander of The Dance. This period followed the break-up of The Chandra Dimension, but just before Oppenheim left the recorded music world to pursue her education. The vocalist commented on the track&amp;#39;s history in a press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I don&amp;#39;t have a clear memory of what inspired it. My guess is that it was meant to be a message to people who felt they were on the periphery. I was giving advice based on my experiences at middle school of feeling excluded and rejected.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;CChandra&amp;#39;s band features several Toronto-based musicians with whom readers of this newsletter should be well acquainted. Among the group, you&amp;#39;ll find Victoria Cheong (&lt;a href="https://www.newchance.biz/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Chance&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href="https://bilesister.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bile Sister&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Julie Reich on vocals, Kristina Koski on keyboards, &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Jon Schouten on guitar, Nyles Miszczyk on bass, and Jesse Locke of &lt;a href="https://tough-age.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tough Age&lt;/a&gt; on drums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The track&amp;#39;s digital release includeS a dub remix of the single by Saturday Looks Good To Me legend Fred Thomas. All proceeds raised are due for the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/esn_to" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Encampment Support Network&lt;/a&gt; and the shelter organization &lt;a href="https://www.throughthesedoors.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Through These Doors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In 2018 the &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; label collected and reissued Chandra&amp;#39;s early work as the &lt;em&gt;Transportation EPs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y-zURxDkGfo" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Y-zURxDkGfo" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Chandra - &amp;quot;Shut In / Shut Out&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Acclaimed Ontario singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://jennifercastle.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jennifer Castle&lt;/a&gt; returns this fall with a new full length. &lt;em&gt;Monarch Season&lt;/em&gt; follows up on 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Angels Of Death&lt;/em&gt;, with the artist working entirely solo from her Port Stanley home. Without the accompaniment of other musicians, Castle&amp;#39;s crafted a far more vulnerable and intimate sound this time out. That sense of space allowed Castle the room to incorporate field recordings of insects, waterfowl, and the waves on Lake Erie into the mix (physical versions of the release include expanded segments of these as ambient interludes).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Castle worked with longtime co-producer Jeff McMurrich on the album. Early editions of the LP, due from &lt;a href="http://ideefixerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Idée Fixe Records&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.paradiseofbachelors.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paradise of Bachelors&lt;/a&gt;, include a songbook with photographs from the recording sessions and sheet music for each song. The record arrives on October 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Castle premiered &lt;em&gt;Monarch Season&lt;/em&gt; with the delicate and airy new single, &amp;quot;Justice.&amp;quot; It arrived alongside a hand-drawn animated video from Toronto visual artist &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/yogawithjesi/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jesi Jordan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://www.thefader.com/2020/09/16/jennifer-castle-shares-justice-and-announces-new-album-monarch-season" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Fader&lt;/a&gt;, Castle commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The duality of being heartbroken and hopeful at once unfolds from my heart into a continuum. Even in the broken place where I have only questions and fists, there is another, more powerful place, where I have hope and courage. Thrust upon many mothers is the assumption we can find hope at all costs, in any condition, even when great injustices have occurred. The world looks to mothers as a symbol of hope and strength. This song is by them, for them. And for all the people, young or old, who might need it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbGgBj2ABnI" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rbGgBj2ABnI" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Jennifer Castle - &amp;quot;Justice&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto punk favourites &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt; have collected some of their isolation-era work as a new EP, a piece that carries the rather brash (but not at all inaccurate) title of &lt;em&gt;This Place Sucks Ass&lt;/em&gt;. Arriving October 23, the six-song set includes the recent &amp;quot;Anaphylaxis&amp;quot; single along with their previously shared cover of Grandaddy&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;A.M. 180.&amp;quot; The announcement came alongside the release of the acerbic new single &amp;quot;Rot.&amp;quot; Three additional songs, &amp;quot;Nothing Changes,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Floodgates,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Edmonton,&amp;quot; all originated from the &lt;em&gt;Morbid Stuff&lt;/em&gt; sessions (cut for being &amp;quot;too frenetic or too unhinged,&amp;quot; which sound like positive qualities to me).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Frontman Stefan Babcock commented on the EP&amp;#39;s title in a statement to &lt;a href="https://exclaim.ca/music/article/pup_declare_this_place_sucks_ass_on_new_ep" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;It was a thing we used to say as a joke a million times on tour. Literally any city, whether it was Lethbridge, AB, or New York City, we&amp;#39;d be like, &amp;#39;This place sucks ass.&amp;#39; We have so much negativity, and sometimes it becomes so extreme and ridiculous that we start to find it funny. But at this moment in time, it feels so fucking real. Wherever you are, it sucks ass right now. So, wherever you live, whatever your circumstances, this is an EP about the place you&amp;#39;re from, and the place you&amp;#39;re at now.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The EP arrives in Canada on the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.littledipperart.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Little Dipper&lt;/a&gt; imprint, with Rise Records issuing the US version. The band intends to celebrate the release with a live stream performance from the Toronto institution Sneaky Dee&amp;#39;s on October 23. You can find tickets for that event and other merchandise (all sporting some appropriately hellish comic art from Toronto illustrator &lt;a href="https://www.brandonlepine.art/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brandon Lepine&lt;/a&gt;) at the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://thisstoresucksass.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;PUP last released &lt;em&gt;Morbid Stuff&lt;/em&gt; in 2019. That album, the group&amp;#39;s third, landed them land on the Polaris Music Prize shortlist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=442941848/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://puptheband.bandcamp.com/album/this-place-sucks-ass"&gt;This Place Sucks Ass by PUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://puptheband.bandcamp.com/album/this-place-sucks-ass" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: PUP - &amp;quot;Rot&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Moncton&amp;#39;s high energy rock unit &lt;a href="https://nervebutton.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nerve Button&lt;/a&gt; has a new record out. &lt;em&gt;Volume 2&lt;/em&gt; arrived recently from Germany&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://wandarecords.bandcamp.com/album/volume-2" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wanza Records&lt;/a&gt;, following up on the band&amp;#39;s 2016 debut and their 2018 split with Hamilton street punks &lt;a href="https://barbedwirebraces.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Barbed Wire Braces&lt;/a&gt;. The record features 12 new songs, recorded with engineer Nick Mcnally behind the boards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Nerve Button features Mike Melanson (aka Batman), Ray Auffrey, and Claude Doiron, all veterans of the late-80s Moncton punk group &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/932247-Bad-Luck-13" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bad Luck #13&lt;/a&gt;. The group&amp;#39;s rounded out by prolific drummer Marc Doucet (Thee Suddens, Burnt Offerings, The Robins, and many others), and Tyler Boutilier of &lt;a href="https://phonejerks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Phone Jerks&lt;/a&gt; (and the solo moniker &lt;a href="https://tjcabot.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TJ Cabot&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4149183597/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://wandarecords.bandcamp.com/album/volume-2"&gt;Volume 2 by Nerve Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://wandarecords.bandcamp.com/album/volume-2" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Nerve Button - &lt;em&gt;Volume 2&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This October brings the debut release from the whip-fast Halifax hardcore group &lt;a href="https://misanthropicmutantmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Misanthropic Minds&lt;/a&gt;. Titled &lt;em&gt;Welcome To The Homeland, Greetings From The Wasteland&lt;/em&gt;, the five-song EP arrives October 20 via &lt;a href="http://sewerciderecords.blogspot.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sewercide Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Misanthropic Minds features Cody Googoo of the &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href="https://alienation902.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Alienation&lt;/a&gt; bandmate Dave Brown. If you recall Alienation&amp;#39;s absolutely killer &lt;em&gt;Bitter Reality&lt;/em&gt; EP from 2018, this is very much in a similar vein of buzzsaw guitars and raw-throated vocals. Not to be played near any painted, as that paint will most assuredly peel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3408925348/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://misanthropicmutantmusic.bandcamp.com/album/welcome-to-the-homeland-greetings-from-the-wasteland-ep"&gt;Welcome To The Homeland, Greetings From The Wasteland EP by Misanthropic Minds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://misanthropicmutantmusic.bandcamp.com/album/welcome-to-the-homeland-greetings-from-the-wasteland-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Misanthropic Minds - &lt;em&gt;Welcome To The Homeland, Greetings From The Wasteland EP&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ottawa peace-punk four-piece &lt;a href="https://dogmapeacepunk.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dogma&lt;/a&gt; recently detailed their debut full-length, a self-titled ten-song set due on October 31. The Crass-inspired group signed with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Growyourownrecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Grow Your Own Records&lt;/a&gt; for the project, which looks to feature the definitive versions of several songs released online by the group over the past year.s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;With the announcement, the band shared the album-opening track &amp;quot;Austerity.&amp;quot; You can stream it from Bandcamp now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dogma recorded with &lt;a href="http://www.houseoftarg.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;House of TARG&lt;/a&gt; co-founder Paul &amp;quot;Yogi&amp;quot; Granger at Meatlocker Studios in March of this year. Will Killingsworth of Orchid and Bucket Full of Teeth mastered the set at Dead Air Studios. Eschewing last names, the band features vocalist Steph, guitarist/vocalist Rusty, bassist Jeff, and drummer James.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2167730049/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dogmapeacepunk.bandcamp.com/album/dogma-2"&gt;Dogma by Dogma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://dogmapeacepunk.bandcamp.com/album/dogma-2" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Dogma - &amp;quot;Austerity&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s set a December 4 release date for &lt;em&gt;The Fink&lt;/em&gt;, the latest record from Dan Lee&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;cyborg-funk&amp;quot; post-punk outfit &lt;a href="https://leeparadisemusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lee Paradise&lt;/a&gt;. You can preview the record now through the single &amp;quot;Message to the Past.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The label elaborated on Lee&amp;#39;s songwriting process, highlighting how the live incarnation of the project helped shape these new tunes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Beginning with a bedrock of programmed drums — the same kick, snare, and cymbal samples he first used 10 years ago — Lee attempted to channel the hard-hitting sound quality of old hip-hop. From here, he stacked up layers of eerie vocals, chaotic extraterrestrial synths, and the massive bass lines that provide Lee Paradise&amp;#39;s signature sonic element. This sound continued to develop through live performances with a trio version of the band, as drummer Jonathan Pappo&amp;#39;s nimble rhythms and Michael Butler&amp;#39;s Yamaha CS-5 fleshed out the songs even further. It was this process that forced Lee to write lyrics, shaping his musical sketches into contained forms.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dan Lee plays in the Toronto art-rock group &lt;a href="https://hoodedfang.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hooded Fang&lt;/a&gt; as well as the electronic psych-pop group &lt;a href="https://phedre.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Phèdre&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s been six years since the release of Lee Paradise&amp;#39;s debut, &lt;em&gt;Water Palace Kingdom&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=133649419/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://leeparadise2.bandcamp.com/album/the-fink"&gt;The Fink by Lee Paradise &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://leeparadise2.bandcamp.com/album/the-fink" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Lee Paradise - &amp;quot;Message To The Past&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto noise-punks &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt; have a third video online previewing the upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Atlas Vending&lt;/em&gt;. This week the trio shared the single &amp;quot;Blind Youth Industrial Park,&amp;quot; as showcased in a dystopian video by director Dylan Pharazyn. Pharazyn commented on the New Zealand-shot short and its dark sci-fi undertones:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I started thinking of the feeling of war or samurai films, beautiful but dark and violent... but then I had this idea to work up a more unique world... I started to think of a more futuristic setting — more unusual and dream-like with the story set on a distant planet where there is future technology and some kind of alien magic... like a futuristic fable. I loved the idea of the hero Ayeth on this nomadic walk through an epic landscape... I loved the strength in her and the pairing of her with a wounded companion, something really human and vulnerable… I wanted that emotive warmth countering the cold military images.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;SSimilar to PUP&amp;#39;s plans, METZ also announced that a live stream performace to coincide with the release. The ticketed event will see the group playing the record in its entirety on October 15, with the trio taking the stage at Toronto&amp;#39;s Opera House. An October 17 performance will also air, targeting audiences overseas. Tickets and details on the streams are online at the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://dice.fm/artist/metz-jvl4" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Frontman Alex Edkins commented on the importance of the live show and reflected on its glaring absence this album cycle:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Something that is intrinsic to who we are as people has been taken away. We want, so badly, to find that feeling again, to forget the world for a moment, and share a brand new album that we love very much (plus some oldies) with you. To all the people of the world who have come to our shows to dance, sweat, and scream, we hope you can join us once again with this show.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atlas Vending&lt;/em&gt; arrives on October 9 from &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain Records&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt;. Ben Greenberg (Uniform) co-produced the album with the band, with Seth Manchester (Daughters, Lingua Ignota, The Body) engineering and mixing at Pawtucket&amp;#39;s Machines with Magnets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uaM6pwskDh0" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/uaM6pwskDh0" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: METZ - &amp;quot;Blind Youth Industrial Park&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hamilton-based shoegaze project &lt;a href="http://www.zoongideewin.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Zoon&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for &amp;quot;Brokenhead,&amp;quot; a song from the recent &lt;a href="http://paperbagrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paper Bag Records&lt;/a&gt; release &lt;em&gt;Bleached Wavves&lt;/em&gt;. In the premiere at &lt;a href="https://www.pastemagazine.com/music/zoon/zoon-brokenhead-premiere/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paste Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, Zoon principal Daniel Monkman commented on the track&amp;#39;s emotional connection to his family&amp;#39;s experience with Canada&amp;#39;s residential school system:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The song &amp;#39;Brokenhead&amp;#39; was written/composed from a feeling I had when I left the reservation as a young teen. It was the first time I had built a strong relationship with my dad since becoming a young adult. He wanted a better life for me - to get me off the reserve and explore Canada. To do this he helped me buy a truck. My dad had been recently compensated by the Canadian government for being forced to attend residential schools from childhood to early teens. Although his ability to help me came at a great cost and I wouldn&amp;#39;t fully understand until years later, the realization heavily influenced the conception of &amp;#39;Brokenhead.&amp;#39; I remember that very first solo drive away from his place after months of teaching me to drive. He and my uncle followed me a short distance down the highway and then stopped. I could see he and my uncle in the review mirror waving goodbye as distance between us grew further and further away. I felt a kind of triumph and yet a rush of sadness/happiness. When I was recording the guitars, I kept focusing on that feeling.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Monkman worked with director (and all-around Some Party pal) &lt;a href="https://www.immvproductions.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Justis Krar&lt;/a&gt; of IMMV Productions on the video. You can find it below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUFwCtYxpzw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rUFwCtYxpzw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Zoon - &amp;quot;Brokenhead&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Saint John rock group &lt;a href="http://papalvisit.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Papal Visit&lt;/a&gt; have their final new single of the summer online, featuring &amp;quot;Inaudible&amp;quot; backed by &amp;quot;Pledge Allegiance To The Stain.&amp;quot; The A-side track features backing vocals by New Brunswick musician &lt;a href="https://therealslimsadie.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sadie&lt;/a&gt;. You can stream both at Bandcamp now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Papal Visit&amp;#39;s released a series of singles throughout the year, part of an effort to pair down the 30-odd candidate songs for the band&amp;#39;s upcoming LP. (Look for the A-sides to be included in that set when it arrives in the fall on &lt;a href="https://monopolizedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Monopolized Records&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vocalist Adam Mowery formed Papal Visit after moving to Halifax as a way to stay connected with the Saint John music scene he came up in. Working remotely with Pierre Cormier and a revolving group of New Brunswick musicians, he&amp;#39;s put out a wealth of material over the past few years, most recently the 2019 live album &lt;em&gt;Prepare For Your Reversal&lt;/em&gt;. Their new record will be the band&amp;#39;s first proper LP since 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Garden Grove&lt;/em&gt;. Papal Visit&amp;#39;s current lineup features Mowery on vocals and Cormier on bass, Jason Ogden and Chris Braydon on guitars, and drummer Geoffrey Smith.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In case you missed it, &lt;a href="https://itsadammowery.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Mowery&lt;/a&gt; also released a solo LP earlier in the summer titled &lt;em&gt;Horseshoe Canyon&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3305715811/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://papalvisit.bandcamp.com/album/inaudible"&gt;Inaudible by PAPAL VISIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://papalvisit.bandcamp.com/album/inaudible" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Papal Visit - &amp;quot;Inaudible&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal art-rock group &lt;a href="https://suuns.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Suuns&lt;/a&gt; have a new EP due for an October 30 release on &lt;a href="https://www.secretcityrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Secret City&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.joyfulnoiserecordings.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Joyful Noise&lt;/a&gt;. The set, titled &lt;em&gt;Fiction&lt;/em&gt;, follows 2018&amp;#39;s full-length &lt;em&gt;Felt&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;With the announcement the band shared the audio for the song  &amp;quot;Pray.&amp;quot; Drummer Liam O&amp;#39;Neill commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We recorded &lt;em&gt;PRAY&lt;/em&gt; in the heat of the Dallas summer in 2015 with our mate John Congleton. We loved it. It was the best song we recorded for our 2016 album &lt;em&gt;Hold/Still&lt;/em&gt;, but it didn&amp;#39;t make the cut, probably because we loved it so much and thought we had an even better version of it in us. We subsequently tried to record multiple versions of this song, none of which captured the unhinged energy of this live-off-the-floor performance. Discovering this lost jam and its power felt like a reminder to keep in the moment and to trust ourselves - you just have to keep moving forward.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The record includes guest appearances from &lt;a href="http://www.blackmountainarmy.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Mountain&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Amber Webber and Montreal artist &lt;a href="https://www.jerusaleminmyheart.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jerusalem In My Heart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pY56vaNYCVE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/pY56vaNYCVE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Suuns - &amp;quot;Pray&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hamilton skid-troubadour &lt;a href="http://www.bajohnston.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;B.A. Johnston&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a home recording of a new song dubbed &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Work for a Living (Wish I was born an Irving).&amp;quot; The tune arrived in the wake of the recent New Brunswick election, which saw former Irving Oil executive Blaine Higgs re-elected with a majority government. You can find it streaming on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BAJohnston/status/1305872136591020033?s=20" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Johnston last issued &lt;em&gt;The Skid Is Hot Tonight&lt;/em&gt; in 2019 through &lt;a href="http://www.transistor66.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Transistor 66&lt;/a&gt;, with the follow-up, supposedly titled &lt;em&gt;Werewolves of London, Ontario&lt;/em&gt;, currently in the works. In recent months of the pandemic, the artist&amp;#39;s performed a series of private, social-distanced driveway shows in various pockets of the country. Johnston also recently took part in a split 7&amp;quot; with &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;, contributing his new isolation ode &amp;quot;Supreme Self-Quarantine&amp;quot; and the classic &amp;quot;I Want to Drink in a Bar Filled with Aliens.&amp;quot; The set raised funds for support shuttered grassroots music venues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Work for a Living (Wish I was born an Irving)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Miss you NB &lt;a href="https://t.co/cUr6LfwTGP"&gt;pic.twitter.com/cUr6LfwTGP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; BA Johnston (@BAJohnston) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BAJohnston/status/1305872136591020033?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 15, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BAJohnston/status/1305872136591020033" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: B.A. Johnston - &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Work for a Living (Wish I was born an Irving)&amp;quot; @ Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Colourful</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-09-13-colourful/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2020-09-13-colourful/</id>
    <published>2020-09-12T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-17T00:11:30-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It&amp;#39;s been one of those weeks, folks... one of those weeks where I again prove that the world doesn&amp;#39;t pause to accomodate my lackadasical efforts. I stretched my already nebulous concept of &amp;quot;Sunday&amp;quot; out longer than I should have and came crashing right into the next week&amp;#39;s new music slate. How dare the nation&amp;#39;s PR engines not play to the sorry beat of my lethargic drum?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As of now, there&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;essential&lt;/em&gt; new stuff out in the wild from Jennifer Castle, the Chandra band, Partner, the OBGMs, and a host of other notables. I&amp;#39;ll catch up with all of that in the next edition, but you&amp;#39;re encouraged to seek it out in the meantime. &amp;quot;React to it at your leisure&amp;quot; has been the unofficial slogan of this newsletter since the get-go, and this week I&amp;#39;m leaning just a little too far into it for comfort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class='bg-black-30 mt4 mb4 maxread bn hr-1'/&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Occasionally (which is to say, with a frequency that should be unsurprising given the above), I come across a blind spot in this newsletter&amp;#39;s coverage that makes very little sense given my personal history. Somehow this year, I&amp;#39;ve missed every single update from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/figurewalking/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Figure Walking&lt;/a&gt;, the Winnipeg duo featuring singer/songwriter &lt;a href="http://gregmacpherson.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Greg MacPherson&lt;/a&gt; and drummer Rob Gardiner (Conduct, Pip Skid). My oversights usually don&amp;#39;t trouble me, I&amp;#39;m more aware than anyone of the precipitous sliver of free time on which Some Party operates, but I&amp;#39;ve got history with MacPherson! I interviewed Greg as a university student in the early Punknews days, just before or after &lt;em&gt;Night Flares&lt;/em&gt; came out on the G7 Welcoming Committee. I was deeply enamoured with the song &amp;quot;Company Store&amp;quot; and how that tense little protest tune mirrored my great grandfather&amp;#39;s history in the Sydney mines. Furthermore, it was an early attempt at leveraging whatever clout Punknews had at the time to force the spotlight on something cool and Canadian. You could say the whole misguided quest of this newsletter had its roots in G7 fandom!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;So with all that said, I have no idea how I lost track of Greg MacPherson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Figure Walking&amp;#39;s new record &lt;em&gt;Vertical/Horizontal&lt;/em&gt; arrived last Friday from &lt;a href="https://disintegrationrecords.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Disintegration Records&lt;/a&gt;. The 10-song set is the duo&amp;#39;s sophomore release under the name, showcasing MacPherson&amp;#39;s impassioned personal/political storytelling backed by Gardiner&amp;#39;s post-rock inspired percussion. The release came alongside a video for the album track &amp;quot;Colourful,&amp;quot; shot and edited by MacPherson on a cell phone this past September. The artist commented on the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;[Colourful] is a kind of weather report; projecting a bitter cold front ahead of vicious winds, heavy ice and freezing rains. There&amp;#39;s a violent storm overhead, some of us are hiding under our houses or huddled near a load bearing wall but there are many who seem convinced against evidence that all will be well.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;MacPherson further explained the narrative presented in the &amp;quot;Colourful&amp;quot; video:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Three true believers navigate modernity and late stage capitalism, preparing themselves for a new world; one is a believer in science, the next religion, the third commerce. They grapple with over a hundred years of Winnipeg urban design and then square off with one another in a bizarre post-cultural dance-a-thon.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Figure Walking recorded &lt;em&gt;Vertical/Horizontal&lt;/em&gt; in Montreal (at The Pines with Steve Bates) and Winnipeg (at Argyle Studios with Cam Loeppky). The record serves as Greg&amp;#39;s 10th studio album as a principal songwriter and his fourth collaborating with Gardiner. Videos for the tracks &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/VzbOjDeQ70k" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mr. X&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/by-ErPE64Yc" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Last Dollar (Green July)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; were shared in the run-up to the release (not that I shared anything about it). Figure Walking last released the Polaris long-listed &lt;em&gt;The Big Other&lt;/em&gt; in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pM55Yt74p7k" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/pM55Yt74p7k" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Figure Walking - &amp;quot;Colourful&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s genre-elusive garage-punks &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt; have the third preview of their upcoming &lt;em&gt;Good Time&lt;/em&gt; LP online. The single &amp;quot;Romance for Rent&amp;quot; comes alongside a hilarious Jack Blair-directed video that finds drummer Steve Sidoli in a fraught and utterly unhealthy relationship with a pair of novelty pillows. There are few visual art pieces that so deftly capture the absurdities of isolation, particularly isolation with easy access to online mailorder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vocalist Chris Swimmings commented on the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The lyrics were inspired by a friend of mine who had come out of a long-term relationship and was exploring the world of online dating. I&amp;#39;ve been a serial monogamist for the last 12 years so it was a vicarious exploration into his life at the time.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Director Jack Blair echoed that sentiment:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The &amp;#39;Romance for Rent&amp;#39; video takes the idea of loneliness and buying love and puts it in a blender with internet culture. It follows a lonely man who, rather than learning how to connect with others, connects with a meme pillow, and finds some short-lived solace with it; he is trying to solve his loneliness with an internet search, and kinda clings to the first thing he finds - a celebrity pillow. When that fails to get him the attention or connection that he was looking for, he goes back online. Rather than changing anything about himself or what he&amp;#39;s looking for, he just repeats the same cycle.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I suspect the video&amp;#39;s a better overall experience if you come into it cold, so I&amp;#39;m not naming the celebrities involved. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Teenanger&amp;#39;s sixth full-length, &lt;em&gt;Good Time&lt;/em&gt; arrives October 2 via the band&amp;#39;s longtime label &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;. The group recorded at Studio Z in Toronto with the celebrated post-rock artist &lt;a href="http://www.sandroperri.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sandro Perri&lt;/a&gt; producing. Together for more than a decade, Teenanger still boasts their original lineup of drummer Steve Sidoli, bassist Melissa Bell, guitarist Jon Schouten, and vocalist Chris Swimmings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MUVa-zKWSX8" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/MUVa-zKWSX8" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Teenanger - &amp;quot;Romance For Rent&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal weird-pop group &lt;a href="https://nightlunch.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Night Lunch&lt;/a&gt; has a video online for their haunting new single &amp;quot;Motorhome.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the retro-futurist band&amp;#39;s first preview of their upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Wall of Love&lt;/em&gt;, due October 9 from Joe Chamandy&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://celluloidlunch.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Celluloid Lunch Records&lt;/a&gt;. Bassist Marlee Kay handles vocals on the track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Night Lunch features members of Quebec groups &lt;a href="https://bakedgoods.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Baked Goods&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://themarlees.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Marlees&lt;/a&gt;, with Baked Goods&amp;#39; 2012 track &amp;quot;Your Body&amp;quot; revisited for this release. The band worked primarily at The Bottle Garden with Peter Woodford (Tough Age, Deliluh, Bleu Nuit) on this release, with a few additional songs tracked by Peter Bowering at MOD Studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Night Lunch features guitarist/vocalist Lukie Lovechild, bassist/vocalist Marlee Kay, keyboardist Wesley Dunphy, and drummer Sailor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JkKw6GMAbyA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/JkKw6GMAbyA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Night Lunch - &amp;quot;Motorhome&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This week sees the self-titled debut release from Calgary power-pop group &lt;a href="https://selfcutbangs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Self-Cut Bangs&lt;/a&gt;. The high-energy duo features Carley O&amp;#39;Neill of the synth-pop group &lt;a href="https://darktimemusic.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dark Time&lt;/a&gt; paired with Shawn Petsche of the high-octane &lt;a href="https://napalmpom.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Napalmpom&lt;/a&gt;. The project materialized as a means to widdle away the quarantine hours, with the full record conceived, written, and recorded over the summer. From the press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Initially started as a means to kill time without killing their wallets in the very early days of 2020 quarantine, Cayley O&amp;#39;Neill and Shawn Petsche spent a short Saturday afternoon writing a rock song that looked forward to time outside of their small Calgary apartment. As quarantine was extended, so too was the tradition of waking up Saturday morning and writing and recording a song before the sun went down, by themselves, for no one else but themselves. Before they knew it, they had an album&amp;#39;s worth of material that they slowly admitted to themselves was &amp;#39;actually pretty good. Maybe even really good?&amp;#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A video for the song &amp;quot;Pillow Talk&amp;quot; is online now, featuring animated wrestling footage entirely assembled within the &lt;em&gt;WWE 2K16&lt;/em&gt; video game. You can also preview three of the record&amp;#39;s nine songs at Bandcamp now (with the rest coming this Friday).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qmzDpmKRs8Y" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/qmzDpmKRs8Y" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Self-Cut Bangs - &amp;quot;Pillow Talk&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://bardont.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brigitte Bardon&amp;#39;t&lt;/a&gt;, the drone-pop guise of Toronto musician and artist Kristel Jax, recently unveiled &lt;em&gt;Pink&lt;/em&gt;. The 8-song cassette release on the &lt;a href="https://industrialcoast.bigcartel.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Industrial Coast&lt;/a&gt; label features music entirely composed on (and cleverly manipulated from) a Barbie-branded &lt;em&gt;Jam With Me&lt;/em&gt; toy keyboard found broken and abandoned on the road in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Jax commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Every track on Pink was recorded with the Barbie keyboard I found in the trash. The plan was to make one song, then circuit bend the shit out of the hardware, but once I started to really listen to the instrument I realized there had to be a larger collection of songs and sounds.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The full write-up at Bandcamp details how Jax extracted some unintended sounds from the toy, describing &amp;quot;static generated by wiggling the star-embedded volume knobs just right&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;feedback made by pointing the bendy green microphone at the speaker.&amp;quot; The process is fascinating, with the resulting compositions often hypnotic and haunting (I completely lost track of writing this week&amp;#39;s edition while listening to the closer &amp;quot;Lavender&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Jax recorded &lt;em&gt;Pink&lt;/em&gt; front to back during Toronto&amp;#39;s COVID-19 lockdown. Davide Eseni engineered the track in Bergamo, Italy (coincidentally an early epicentre of the pandemic). &lt;a href="https://www.tasmanrichardson.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tasman Richardson&lt;/a&gt; provides art for the release and takes part in the composition of the track &amp;quot;Orchid.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Brigitte Bardon&amp;#39;t last released the field recording collage set &lt;em&gt;Radio Songs&lt;/em&gt; in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2013820131/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bardont.bandcamp.com/album/pink"&gt;Pink by Brigitte Bardon't&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://bardont.bandcamp.com/album/pink" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Brigitte Bardon&amp;#39;t - &lt;em&gt;Pink&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s scrappy indie-rock quartet &lt;a href="https://roachband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Roach&lt;/a&gt; has a new single online, pairing the infectious emo-pop tune (and ode to a dead pet) &amp;quot;R.I.P. Soft Serve&amp;quot; with the b-side &amp;quot;Manspreading.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Roach features vocalist/guitarist Violet DeRege Braga, drummer Carly Harris, guitarist Jackson Seaward, and bassist Tyler Twigger. The group released its debut EP, &lt;em&gt;Taste Test&lt;/em&gt;, in the spring of 2019. They also recently appeared as part of the &lt;em&gt;Black And Loud&lt;/em&gt; compilation from the &lt;a href="http://ontarioartistsagainstinjustice.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ontario Artists Against Injustice&lt;/a&gt; group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3374680524/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://roachband.bandcamp.com/album/r-i-p-soft-serve"&gt;R.I.P. Soft Serve by Roach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://roachband.bandcamp.com/album/r-i-p-soft-serve" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Roach - &amp;quot;R.I.P. Soft Serve&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week &lt;a href="https://www.spencerburtonmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Spencer Burton&lt;/a&gt; unveiled &amp;quot;Further,&amp;quot; his first single as a part of Dallas Green&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; imprint &lt;a href="http://stillrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Still Records&lt;/a&gt;. The lushly orchestrated track certainly feels like a step up in production value from the Niagara-area folk artist. Burton commented on the song:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Further&amp;#39; was written with the world&amp;#39;s downward spiral in mind. We&amp;#39;ve lost focus. Forgotten what matters. We are the world? But the world isn&amp;#39;t us. I think we need to find out how to become equal parts earth and humanity without causing damage to one another. There&amp;#39;s a balance in there somewhere.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The single premiered alongside a video from director &lt;a href="https://www.immvproductions.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Justis Krar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new material follows &lt;em&gt;The Mountain Man&lt;/em&gt;, an album of children&amp;#39;s songs the rural-minded Burton issued last year. The track serves as the proper follow-up to his 2017 full-length &lt;em&gt;Songs Of&lt;/em&gt;. While he&amp;#39;s several albums into a solo career writing rustic country and clever folk tunes, Burton&amp;#39;s roots were in the much-loved Welland pop-punk band &lt;a href="https://attackinblack.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Attack In Black&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ICCwRQ2MIKY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ICCwRQ2MIKY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Spencer Burton - &amp;quot;Further&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The &lt;a href="https://abattoir-label.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Abattoir&lt;/a&gt; label has collected the recent work of stark Haligonian coldwave group &lt;a href="https://labise.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;La Bise&lt;/a&gt;. The cassette label&amp;#39;s paired the band&amp;#39;s first EP (2019&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;So Long&lt;/em&gt;) with this year&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Stagnant Motion&lt;/em&gt; project for a limited physical run (Abattoir&amp;#39;s releases are always rather striking, visually, and this is no different). The b-side audio is a compilation of two unreleased songs the band assembled on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/v1bip38Vpv4" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; as part of the pandemic edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.everyseeker.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Everseeker&lt;/a&gt; festival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;La Bise features vocalist Kelsey Crewson, bassist Kirsten Todd, guitarists Arianna Lehr and Scott Randles, and drummer Lucas Goudie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=580838072/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://abattoir-label.bandcamp.com/album/so-long-stagnant-motion"&gt;So Long + Stagnant Motion by La Bise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://abattoir-label.bandcamp.com/album/so-long-stagnant-motion" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: La Bise - &amp;quot;So Long&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Stagnant Motion&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal emo-revivalists &lt;a href="https://gulfer.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Gulfer&lt;/a&gt; have a second preview online from their upcoming self-titled LP. You can check out &amp;quot;Heat Wave&amp;quot; below. Vocalist/guitarist Joseph Therriault commented on the track, one of 13 slated for the new record:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Heat Wave&amp;#39; is about how conversation and interpersonal interactions can be so performative. It&amp;#39;s about how people present an idealized version of themselves in many situations (myself included). This is something I&amp;#39;ve been noticing more and more as I get older and lose touch with old friends. In a way, the flip side of that coin is to draw attention to how important real friendships are.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Gulfer&amp;#39;s self-titled record, their third full-length outing, arrives October 16 from &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.topshelfrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Topshelf Records&lt;/a&gt;. The new album follows their 2018 LP &lt;em&gt;Dog Bless&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Gulfer features guitarist/vocalists Vincent Ford and Joe Therriault, bassist David Mitchell, and drummer Julien Daoust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2534282644/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=4228147849/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gulfer.bandcamp.com/album/gulfer"&gt;Gulfer by Gulfer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://gulfer.bandcamp.com/track/heat-wave" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Gulfer - &amp;quot;Heat Wave&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This month will see Montreal sombre punk outfit &lt;a href="https://oakheartsmtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oakhearts&lt;/a&gt; issue &lt;em&gt;Triangles and Squares&lt;/em&gt;, a four-song EP for &lt;a href="https://littlerocketrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Little Rocket Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Guitarist/vocalist Daniel Aubut spoke to Punknews about the title track, commenting:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Triangles and Squares&amp;#39; tell a story about drowning in self inquisition about life. Deciding to bring changes to your own life without knowing where you&amp;#39;re going but in a simple quest of self-well-being. This was inspired by a time when I arrived to a crossroad in my career and personal life needing changes to be made.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;An accompanying video features the band performing the track at Montreal&amp;#39;s Breakglass Studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Oakhearts features Daniel Aubut (Young &amp;amp; Lost, Les Midnights), alongside guitarist Daniel B. Cesare (The Sober Dawn, Powernap), bassist Mathieu Caumartin, and drummer Emilien Catalano (The Nils, The Sangomas, Moving Targets). The group recorded these tracks back in February with producer Ryan Battistuzzi (Pale Lips, Malajube, Les Breastfeeders).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3qYuPmXVAMs" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3qYuPmXVAMs" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Oakhearts - &amp;quot;Triangle and Squares&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This past June, melodic Montreal punk quartet &lt;a href="http://lesmainssalesmontreal.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Les Mains Sales&lt;/a&gt; took to Studio La Traque to capture live versions of five songs from their recent LP, &lt;em&gt;Fêlures&lt;/em&gt;. Last week the band unveiled the second clip from the set, showcasing the track &amp;quot;Décatie.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Les Mains Sales feature Fred Jacques of &lt;a href="https://thesaintecatherines.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Sainte Catherines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://yesterdaysringmtl.bandcamp.com/releases" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Ring&lt;/a&gt; on lead vocals and guitar, backed by several players from that scene. He&amp;#39;s joined here by the above-mentioned Ryan Battistuzzi (Colin Moore, Fontarabie, Yesterday&amp;#39;s Ring, Miracles, The Bottle) on guitar and Oakhearts&amp;#39; Dan Cesare on bass, along with drummer Rich Bouthillier (The Sainte Catherines, Yesterday&amp;#39;s Ring, Rudy Caya).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fêlures&lt;/em&gt; arrived via &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt; in May.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rRov36OO2GI" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rRov36OO2GI" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Les Mains Sales - &amp;quot;Décatie&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;-adjacent found-art project &lt;a href="https://leisurepalace.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Leisure Palace&lt;/a&gt; has another new video online from their &lt;em&gt;Special Problems&lt;/em&gt; release. This time out, José Miguel Contrera and Amy I. Nicoll showcase the track &amp;quot;Problems Of The Professional.&amp;quot; You can find it below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The pair recorded these songs in their bedroom back in February of 2016 as part of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RPM_Challenge" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;RPM Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, pulling together a heady mix of tape loops and vocals with a slate of unconventional instrumentation. The duo unearthed the recordings and mixed the resulting record during the summer quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;José Contreras last released &lt;em&gt;At The Slaughterhouse&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://headlessowl.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Headless Owl&lt;/a&gt;. All three members of By Divine Right also recently appeared with &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/Another-Blue-Door-Haulers/release/3524074" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Another Blue Door&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Dave Schoonderbeek on the &lt;a href="http://schoonderbeekwithbdr.bandcamp.com/album/let-it-beek" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let It Beek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; LP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1S4syKfZUjk" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1S4syKfZUjk" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Leisure Palace - &amp;quot;Problems of the Professional&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As part of last Saturday&amp;#39;s online &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/mtl.vs.r/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;MTL vs. Racisme&lt;/a&gt; festival, the early third wave ska group &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/memomandmorgentaler/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Me Mom and Morgentaler&lt;/a&gt; reunited for a cover of The Specials&amp;#39; &amp;quot;Racist Friend.&amp;quot; While the Montreal group disbanded back in 1995, the pandemic era tools gave them the means to reconvene and record remotely. Members of the band recorded their parts abroad from Brooklyn, Paris, Barcelona, and where it all started in Quebec.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A video featuring the cover, co-created by drummer Sid Santiago and longtime friend Rosella Tursi, screened as part of the online event and fundraiser. You can check it out now on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Me Mom and Morgentaler came together in 1988, releasing their first EP, &lt;em&gt;Clown Heaven and Hell&lt;/em&gt;, in 1991. Their lone studio album, &lt;em&gt;Shiva Space Machine&lt;/em&gt;, arrived two years later, followed by the live record &lt;em&gt;We Are Revolting&lt;/em&gt; in 1994. The group last reunited on stage in 2007. Players on this song include vocalist/guitarist Gus Van Go, vocalists
Kim Bingham and Noah Green, Adam Bix Berger on vocals and trumpet, John Jordan on vocals and saxophone, Kasia Hering on the accordion, Matt Lipscombe on bass, John JB Britton on percussion, and drummer Sid Zanforlin. Van Go collected the disparate recordings to produce, mix, and master the result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IVygczRFfEc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/IVygczRFfEc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Me Mom &amp;amp; Morgentaler - &amp;quot;Racist Friend&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dartmouth singer/songwriter &lt;a href="http://mokenney.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mo Kenney&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a gorgeous cover of the Guided By Voices classic &amp;quot;Game of Pricks.&amp;quot; The track finds Kenney slowing the indie-rock staple down to its raw, emotional core, with &lt;a href="http://joelplaskett.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Joel Plaskett&lt;/a&gt; accompanying on piano.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can check the song out now in the Matt Williams-directed video linked below. The GBV cover&amp;#39;s been a part of Kenney&amp;#39;s live set for a few years now, with the studio recording due for an upcoming covers record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zsIKo-Yra7U" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/zsIKo-Yra7U" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Mo Kenney - &amp;quot;Game of Pricks&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>God Bless The Ego</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-09-06-god-bless-the-ego/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2020-09-06-god-bless-the-ego/</id>
    <published>2020-09-05T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-10T12:23:11-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In a recent letter to fans, &lt;a href="https://protruders.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Protruders&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Joe Chamandy confirmed that his Toronto&amp;#39;s proto-punk outfit is &amp;quot;more or less defunct.&amp;quot; With the band&amp;#39;s members splintered across the country, and the ongoing pandemic likely to keep them that way, it was time to call it. Based now in Montreal, Joe announced the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/celluloidlunchrecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Celluloid Lunch Records&lt;/a&gt;, an extension of his year-old fanzine of the same name. As the label&amp;#39;s first release, Joe&amp;#39;s debuted a new musical project dubbed &lt;a href="https://itchyself.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Itchy Self&lt;/a&gt;, with an EP titled &lt;em&gt;Here&amp;#39;s The Rub&lt;/em&gt; due on October 2. Citing The Saints, the Rats, and Neon Boys as inspiration, the fledgling label commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Drawing influence from the looser end of the Ork records catalogue, the sensitive side of Ohio&amp;#39;s proto-punk scene and the grittiest and most sluggish tangent of 70&amp;#39;s power pop, Itchy Self&amp;#39;s debut 12&amp;quot; is an exploration of fully formed songs treated with spontaneous delivery. The group got together in early 2020 for 3 practices and a recording session and here are the results, laid out in their raw form. This is cross-generational racket n roll music that wears its heart on its loosey goosey sleeve.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The group features Chamandy on guitar and vocals, Scott Brown on bass, Chris Burns on guitar, and Zak Slax on drums. Moss Lime&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://helenebarbier.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hélène Barbier&lt;/a&gt; sings backup, along with Kay Moon (Dead Beat Poet Society) and &lt;a href="http://preoccupationsband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Preoccupations&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Scott Munro. Munro recorded the five-song set, with mastering performed by Mikey Young of the Eddy Current Suppression Ring and Total Control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The single &amp;quot;God Bless The Ego&amp;quot; is streaming now at Bandcamp, with a video directed by &lt;a href="https://equivoc.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Équivoc&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Olivia Faye Lathuillière now playing at &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/IIZkgB_OgGw" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Protruders last released &lt;em&gt;Poison Future&lt;/em&gt; in 2019 on &lt;a href="https://feelitrecords.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feel It Records&lt;/a&gt;. That group served as the successor project to the similarly-spirited, Sackville-based &lt;a href="https://kappachow.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kappa Chow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=601340962/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://itchyself.bandcamp.com/album/heres-the-rub"&gt;Here's the Rub by Itchy Self&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://itchyself.bandcamp.com/album/heres-the-rub" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Itchy Self - &amp;quot;God Bless The Ego&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Before we get any further this week, just a note that I&amp;#39;ve my remaining copies of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/store/under-the-circumstances/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Under The Circumstances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the first Some Party mixtape, up for sale &lt;a href="https://someparty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;, with 100% of the proceeds to due for the &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/legal-fund-1492-land-back-lane" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;1492 Land Back Lane Legal Fund&lt;/a&gt;. Snag one now and help me support the Six Nations land defenders fighting the latest housing development to encroach on their territory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That tape release featured &lt;a href="https://tough-age.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tough Age&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://psychicvoid.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Psychic Void&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://newvogue.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Vogue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.partnerband.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://wares.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wares&lt;/a&gt;, along with a few not-so-secret guests. Wares&amp;#39; Cassia Hardy coincidently just shared her band&amp;#39;s contribution online for the first time. It&amp;#39;s a mesmerizing shoegaze take on their early standard &amp;quot;City Kids.&amp;quot; You can check it out below, with all online sales from the track supporting the &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/pekiwewin" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pekiwewin camp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=135745158/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://wares.bandcamp.com/track/city-kids-alt"&gt;City Kids (alt) by Wares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://wares.bandcamp.com/track/city-kids-alt" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Wares - &amp;quot;City Kids (alt)&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Maximilian &amp;#39;Twig&amp;#39; Turnbull&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://badgeepoque.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Badge Époque Ensemble&lt;/a&gt; returns November 20 with &lt;em&gt;Self Help&lt;/em&gt;, a new seven-song full-length. The psych-influenced jazz-funk septet shared &amp;quot;Sing a Silent Gospel&amp;quot; last week, the record&amp;#39;s lead track and a showcase for guest vocalists Meg Remy (&lt;a href="http://yousgirls.blogspot.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Girls&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href="https://dorotheapaas.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dorothea Paas&lt;/a&gt;. The single arrived alongside a Super 8 shot video compiled by Remy, which you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vocalists &lt;a href="https://jennifercastle.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jennifer Castle&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://imjamesbaley.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;James Baley&lt;/a&gt; also appear on the record. The Ensemble recorded the set live at Toronto&amp;#39;s Palace Sound between October of 2019 and this past March, wrapping just before the lockdown edict. The collection marks the group&amp;#39;s third release over the past year, with their self-titled debut arriving last June and the &lt;em&gt;Nature, Man &amp;amp; Woman&lt;/em&gt; EP surfacing in December. You&amp;#39;ll find the &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; label again adorning the 12&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A celebrated multi-instrumentalist, &amp;#39;Twig&amp;#39; Turnbull&amp;#39;s long list of credits include stints as a songwriter and producer for both the aforementioned U.S. Girls and &lt;a href="https://darleneshrugg.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Darlene Shrugg&lt;/a&gt;. He also appears regularly as a member of the psych-jazz group &lt;a href="http://thecosmicrange.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Cosmic Range&lt;/a&gt;. His Ensemble features Jay Anderson on drums, Chris Bezant on guitar, Alia O&amp;#39;Brien on the Flute, percussionist Ed Squires, and Giosuè Rosati on bass. This record finds the lineup expanded to include saxophonist Karen Ng. The liner notes credit Turnbull with all manner of keys and synthesizers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G42r638d3JE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/G42r638d3JE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Badge Époque Ensemble - &amp;quot;Sing A Silent Gospel&amp;quot; feat. Meg Remy &amp;amp; Dorothea Paas @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/friendshipcommittee/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Friend Ship Committee&lt;/a&gt; continues to tick away the pandemic weeks by rolling out new editions of their &lt;em&gt;Friend Ship From Home&lt;/em&gt; compilation series. The fourth recently arrived, with 21 tracks available from an array of functional and one-off bands, including Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://mercandthemontclairs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Merc &amp;amp; The Montclairs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://dartsbud.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dart Mouth&lt;/a&gt;, and Sarnia&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://jacobbarber.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jacob Barber&lt;/a&gt;. One of the new names on the tracklist is Jogging, who contributes the new wave-inspired &amp;quot;False Dmitry.&amp;quot; Jogging is the latest work from Adam Bernhardt, former guitarist for the dearly departed Toronto snark-punks &lt;a href="https://wlmrt.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WLMRT&lt;/a&gt;. This comp marks the project&amp;#39;s public debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As with past editions of the compilation, all proceeds raised from the set are due for the family of &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/justice-for-regis?utm_source=facebook" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Regis Korchinski Paquet&lt;/a&gt; and Black Lives Matter Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2087383800/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2554839248/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://friendshipcommittee.bandcamp.com/album/friend-ship-from-home-vol-4"&gt;Friend Ship From Home Vol. 4 by Jogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://friendshipcommittee.bandcamp.com/album/friend-ship-from-home-vol-4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Jogging - &amp;quot;False Dmitry&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Fiery Vancouver punk quartet &lt;a href="https://sbdc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SBDC&lt;/a&gt; has a new full-length set for an October 2 release on &lt;a href="https://kingfisherbluez.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kingfisher Bluez&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Feeling of Winning&lt;/em&gt; features ten songs, the band&amp;#39;s first new material to arrive since 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Too Bad&lt;/em&gt;. You can preview the set now with the lead single &amp;quot;Sick of You.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;SBDC features &lt;a href="http://brutalpoodlevan.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brutal Poodle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Karmin Poirier on guitar and vocals, bassist/vocalist Alicia, guitarist Cheryl (&lt;a href="https://lovecuts.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Love Cuts&lt;/a&gt;, Ruffle), and &lt;a href="https://lievancouver.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;lié&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Kati J on drums. The band recorded with Jesse Gander (Wares, Woolworm, Necking) at Rain City Recorders. SBDC stands for &amp;quot;Stupid Bitch &amp;amp; the Dumb Cunts,&amp;quot; which you probably don&amp;#39;t want your kid wearing to school on a t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1983336732/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://sbdc.bandcamp.com/album/the-feeling-of-winning"&gt;The Feeling Of Winning by SBDC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://sbdc.bandcamp.com/album/the-feeling-of-winning" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: SBDC - &amp;quot;Sick of You&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of Kingfisher Bluez, the Vancouver label recently issued &lt;em&gt;Short Songs 2&lt;/em&gt;, a 12-song 7&amp;quot; collecting succinct works from an assortment of artists. Among the acts taking part, you&amp;#39;ll find contributions from Victoria garage rockers &lt;a href="https://thethis.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The This&lt;/a&gt;, Edmonton singer-songwriter &lt;a href="https://marlaenamoore.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Marleana Moore&lt;/a&gt;, Abbotsford&amp;#39;s eclectic &lt;a href="https://davidivanneil.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;David Ivan Neil&lt;/a&gt;, and Vancouver queer pop act &lt;a href="https://nonla.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Non La&lt;/a&gt;. Lethbridge &amp;#39;tropical glam&amp;#39; enthusiast &lt;a href="https://jblissette.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;J Blissette&lt;/a&gt; takes part as well, contributing the lightning-quick &amp;quot;Left Outside.&amp;quot; You can check it out below, and dig into the full set at Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=877343245/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2363391976/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://kingfisherbluez.bandcamp.com/album/short-songs-2"&gt;Short Songs 2 by J. Blissette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://kingfisherbluez.bandcamp.com/track/left-outside" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: J Blissette - &amp;quot;Left Outside&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Outfit shared a second video preview of their upcoming &lt;em&gt;How Ill Thy World Is Ordered&lt;/em&gt; last week with the new single &amp;quot;Green Eye Shade.&amp;quot; The Welland artist commented on the equine-focused clip in a florid statement:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;From a lightning bolt. From the sea. In the end of eternity, The white horse  Carries no saint, no world saviour, The white horse roams free in its spectacular Human-less liberty as the aspiration of its destiny. Empty chariots, hidden in green vines, hill-like and indistinguishable from the world&amp;#39;s eye — the rotting fossil of the gods. There is a white horse, roaming in the green eye-shade, In a new dawning hour, through a mad reverie, bore the eyes of the kingdom, green eye-shade, In the fall of all power, rose a clear alchemy of green eye-shade.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The track will be part of the 11-song LP when it arrives from &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; on September 18. The Outfit features Romano backed by vocalist Julianna Riolino, guitarist/vocalist David Nardi, bassist Roddy Rossetti, and drummer Ian Romano, with guest contributions from pianist Mark Lalama, vocalist Briana Salmena, sax player Victor Belcastro, and Aaron Hutchinson on trumpet. The new single follows &amp;quot;A Rat Without a Tale&amp;quot; in previewing the set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Ill Thy World Is Ordered&lt;/em&gt; is the 9th fully-realized release from Romano this calendar year, but only the second you can hold in your hands (following the pre-pandemic live record, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Okay Wow&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;). Over the isolation era, and for a stint on a near-weekly basis, Danny somehow churned out more music than most bands release in their entire careers. You can explore that whole collection (which, come to think of it, would make a meaningful boxed set to commemorate this otherwise lost year) over at  &lt;a href="https://danielromano.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7mAhvjvWHcA" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/7mAhvjvWHcA" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Daniel Romano&amp;#39;s Outfit - &amp;quot;Green Eye Shade&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Cerebral and angsty, the Whitehorse rock band &lt;a href="https://cryptozoologists.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cryptozoologists&lt;/a&gt; has returned with a dynamic new full-length out titled &lt;em&gt;Pond Life&lt;/em&gt;. Project lead Zach McCann-Armitage commented on the roots of the 11-song work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;While writing the bulk of these songs, I was doing a lot of collaging. At first it was just a goofy pastime, but then, inspired by my growing collection of Home Hardware paint swatches, I decided to make a collage Tarot deck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I got really excited about clashing Tarot&amp;#39;s seriousness and mysticism with collage&amp;#39;s beautiful, fragmenting irreverence. My songs try to do that too - the clash of the absolute sincerity and intensity of poetry with the humour and absurdity of believing that what you&amp;#39;re doing is so important even though no one is listening that deeply.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;McCann-Armitage crafted these songs at Old Crow Recording with engineer Patrick Hamilton (&lt;a href="https://sodapony.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Soda Pony&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheSweetiesMusic/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Sweeties&lt;/a&gt;). The vocalist builds these tracks around his distinctively vulnerable, half-spoken storytelling, mixing live instrumentation with a smattering of electronics. The press release lists bookish, poetical artists like Destroyer and Wolf Parade among this project&amp;#39;s influences, which seems entirely appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Cryptozoologists last released &lt;em&gt;Songs for Losers&lt;/em&gt; in 2017, although they took part in the &lt;em&gt;Beneath The Broadcast&lt;/em&gt; audio-visual series highlighting Yukon artists last year. A video for the single &amp;quot;White Silk&amp;quot; is running now at &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/tM1s-NnVMts" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=888719318/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cryptozoologists.bandcamp.com/album/pond-life"&gt;Pond Life by Cryptozoologists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://cryptozoologists.bandcamp.com/album/pond-life" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Cryptozoologists - &amp;quot;Pond Life&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;He&amp;#39;s not said much about it yet, but Ottawa&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Page&lt;/a&gt; has a lovely new track online titled &amp;quot;Parting Words the Artist Curates.&amp;quot; It surfaced alongside the deluge of new material that floods Bandcamp whenever they wave their fees, so perhaps no explanation&amp;#39;s needed. The musician recorded the tune at his Vanier home this past August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Page is currently promoting his new solo record &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay and Swim Again&lt;/em&gt;, a full re-recording of his 2004 solo record &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay and Swim&lt;/em&gt;. Chris plays these days as part of the duo &lt;a href="https://expandafuzz.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Expanda Fuzz&lt;/a&gt;, having earlier served in &lt;a href="http://campradio.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Camp Radio&lt;/a&gt; and the 90s pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://thestandgt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Stand GT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3436042240/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/track/the-parting-words-the-artist-curates"&gt;The Parting Words the Artist Curates by Chris Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com/track/the-parting-words-the-artist-curates" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chris Page - &amp;quot;The Parting Words the Artist Curates&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hamilton alt-country trio &lt;a href="https://www.elliottbrood.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Elliott BROOD&lt;/a&gt; has a second single online from &lt;em&gt;Keeper&lt;/em&gt;, the band&amp;#39;s fast approaching new full-length. You can check out &amp;quot;Bird Dog&amp;quot; now through a visualizer by director Stephen Dutcheshen. This song&amp;#39;s unique among the record&amp;#39;s material in that it features mixing by producer Sylvia Massy, whose vast discography includes records by Tool, Prince, Johnny Cash, and Tom Petty. The band commented on working with her on this track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Her track record speaks for itself and her name is on the credits for a ton of albums we listen to. She understood the essence of the song from the first note and then took that version and ran it through a wash of countrified psychedelic haze.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keeper&lt;/em&gt; is due September 18 from &lt;a href="http://sixshooterrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Six Shooter Records&lt;/a&gt;. The 10-song full-length features studio engineering by Daryl Neudorf (Neko Case) with Ryan Hadlock (The Gossip, The Lumineers) mixing. Elliott BROOD last released &lt;em&gt;Ghost Gardens&lt;/em&gt; in 2017 on &lt;a href="http://paperbagrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paper Bag Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5i4k_F51NqQ" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/5i4k_F51NqQ" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Elliott BROOD - &amp;quot;Bird Dog&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This October, &lt;a href="http://yeahrightrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yeah Right Records&lt;/a&gt; is offering up a live LP showcasing Vancouver hard rock institution &lt;a href="https://thespitfires.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Spitfires&lt;/a&gt;. The set captures the band, who channel AC/DC as much as they do the Sex Pistols, playing in 2003 at the Piccadilly Pub. At this gig, their lineup included vocalist Jason Solyom, bassist CC Voltage (currently of part of &lt;a href="http://autogramm.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;), guitarists Jay Millette (&lt;a href="https://theblackhalos.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Black Halos&lt;/a&gt;) and Mr. Dean-O, with drummer Marty Peters. The band&amp;#39;s set features 13 songs, closing appropriately with a cover of Alice Cooper&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Muscle of Love.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4222460436/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yeahrightrecords.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-the-pic"&gt;Live At The Pic by The Spitfires&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://yeahrightrecords.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-the-pic" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Spitfires - &lt;em&gt;Live At The Pic&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto synthpop group &lt;a href="https://saharatoronto.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sahara&lt;/a&gt; has a new video online for &amp;quot;Indoor Pool,&amp;quot; a track from their recent debut LP for &lt;a href="http://handdrawndracula.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hand Drawn Dracula&lt;/a&gt;. That record, dubbed &lt;em&gt;Pure Glass&lt;/em&gt;, featured nine songs that tied together 90s shoegaze noise with dream-pop notes the early Cure&amp;#39;s influence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sahara recorded &lt;em&gt;Pure Glass&lt;/em&gt; with Dylan Frankland of Tallies in the studio. The group features vocalist/guitarist Andrew Wilson, guitarist Joseph Elaschuk, bassist Julie MacKinnon, and drummer Edan Scime Stokell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NwTsR3MCBl8" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/NwTsR3MCBl8" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Sahara - &amp;quot;Indoor Pool&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Bandcamp&amp;#39;s endeavoured to throw a little more cash into artists&amp;#39; pockets throughout the pandemic by waving their revenue share for a day each month. This past go-around saw Toronto hardcore luminaries &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; unearth a live recording from the legendary New York punk venue CBGB. The matinee show, recorded from the soundboard on May 29, 2006, took place in the final year of the space (it closed in October of that year). The time capsule finds the band amid a US tour before the release of &lt;em&gt;Hidden World&lt;/em&gt;, their debut full-length. The band wrote about the experience:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve all got to believe in &amp;#39;2006&amp;#39; at some point or another in our lives. I thought it might have simply come and gone, but it turns out the bottomless vaults of our archive have provided a brief wormhole into its existence. In this version you could find remarkable feats of analogue musical participation flowing freely through space in the big wide cities of the big wide world. It was the land before guitar tuners, tempo checks, backing vocals, or monitor mixes. It was the time in which we all etched one phrase into our minds as young impressionable musicians finding their way on this earth: &amp;#39;Nice set dude, can we borrow your amps.&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;We were on &amp;#39;tour&amp;#39; -- whatever that is -- and had a few gigs under our belt on the East Coast before we met up with what was THE tour to meet up with that spring: The Forward/Warhead/Tragedy &amp;#39;Burning Against Spirits&amp;#39; Tour. Titans of hardcore punk in 2006 collided across the US and for one last waltz, with us as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;We waited patiently as Mind Eraser tore a hole through the fabric of the universe; while Kill your Idols created a brickwall of human bodies; while Forward tantalized and impressed with otherworldly precision; while Warhead left a scorch mark where the stage at CBGBs was; while Tragedy provided their indelible mark on that moment... and somewhere in the evening there was Fucked Up. That&amp;#39;s what you&amp;#39;re listening to. That&amp;#39;s what you get. This is what we were capable of in the flesh in 2006, our 2006. That moment in time with its open doors and new pathways, all its ear piercing hearing loss perfection, all its potential, and it&amp;#39;s absurd amount of nacho chips.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; last released &lt;em&gt;Dose Your Dreams&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://arts-crafts.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arts &amp;amp; Crafts&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="https://www.mergerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Merge&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3894704126/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-cbgbs"&gt;Live at CBGB's by Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-cbgbs" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Fucked Up - &lt;em&gt;Live at CBGB&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Canadian Dreams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-08-30-canadian-dreams/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2020-08-30-canadian-dreams/</id>
    <published>2020-08-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-01T21:55:35-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I mentioned Charlottetown&amp;#39;s quirky &lt;a href="https://fshkll.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FSHKLL&lt;/a&gt; in passing last week (Michael Rancic featured them in his recent PEI punk spotlight at &lt;a href="https://daily.bandcamp.com/lists/prince-edward-island-punk-list" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;), but I missed that they also have a new record out. &lt;em&gt;Sashimi Shoreline&lt;/em&gt; is the post-punk band&amp;#39;s new five-song EP, showing off a playful bass-buoyed bounce with love for DEVO and The Talking Heads shining through. The band shared each of these tracks (save the newly unveiled closer, &amp;quot;Canadian Dreams&amp;quot;) over the spring and summer as part of the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PEIMusiciansForMigrantWorkerRelief/posts/119454176403785/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PEI Musicians for Migrant Worker Relief&lt;/a&gt; effort. That campaign brought together several island musicians to raise money for the migrant farmworkers suffering through the pandemic without support from the Canadian government (over the past few months, I shared contributions to this cause from Antibodies and The Burning Hell).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lead by vocalist Brad Deighan, FSHKILL features guitarists Lee Clarke and Devin Krauskopf, bassist Colin MacIsaac, and drummer Fadi Faisal. The band recorded at The Hill with Adam Gallant engineering. &lt;em&gt;Sashimi Shoreline&lt;/em&gt; follows the group&amp;#39;s 2018 &lt;em&gt;Panopticon&lt;/em&gt; EP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4274532235/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fshkll.bandcamp.com/album/sashimi-shoreline-ep"&gt;Sashimi Shoreline EP by FSHKLL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://fshkll.bandcamp.com/album/sashimi-shoreline-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: FSHKLL - &lt;em&gt;Sashimi Shoreline&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Windsor indie-rock group &lt;a href="https://trout.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Trout&lt;/a&gt; has a new single out in the wild titled &amp;quot;Q.T.&amp;quot; The track follows the June-released &amp;quot;New Space&amp;quot; in previewing the band&amp;#39;s upcoming LP, due later this year from &lt;a href="https://mustbenicerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Must Be Nice Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;There&amp;#39;s some deep recess of my brain stuck as a teenager in the 90s, endless driving up and down the Niagara Parkway at night with nowhere to go. &amp;quot;Q.T.&amp;quot; absolutely feels like the type of hooky alt-rock song I&amp;#39;d be blaring on the car stereo back then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;On this recording, Trout featured vocalist/guitarist Roye Trout backed by guitarist Brent Cusmanic, bassist Colin Wysman, Jeremy Coulter on piano and organ, and drummer Josh Cassidy. The new material comes on the heels of the group&amp;#39;s five-song 2019 EP &lt;em&gt;Nectar&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3613300197/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://trout.band/track/q-t-2"&gt;Q.T. by Trout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://trout.band/track/q-t-2" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Trout - &amp;quot;Q.T.&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Allie Hanlon&amp;#39;s bubblegum-punk quartet &lt;a href="http://peachkellipop.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Peach Kelli Pop&lt;/a&gt; returns this fall with a new EP for &lt;a href="https://www.lauren-records.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lauren Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can preview the record now with the lead single &amp;quot;Cut Me Off.&amp;quot; The set features three originals and a cover of &amp;quot;Sing and Pretty&amp;quot; by Japanese group The Pats Pats (previously released as a split digital single last year).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lucky Star&lt;/em&gt; follows Peach Kelli Pop&amp;#39;s 2018 LP &lt;em&gt;Gentle Leader&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; release. While based California these days, Allie Hanlon made her name drumming for the beloved Ottawa garage-punk trio &lt;a href="https://thewhitewires.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The White Wires&lt;/a&gt; throughout their career.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1581996254/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://peachkellipop.bandcamp.com/album/lucky-star"&gt;Lucky Star by Peach Kelli Pop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://peachkellipop.bandcamp.com/album/lucky-star" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Peach Kelli Pop - &amp;quot;Lucky Star&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://musicbyllc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;LeDrew, Luke &amp;amp; Crowe&lt;/a&gt; is (was?) a reasonably traditional rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll combo from an unlikely group of Haligonian noise-makers. The band featured Adam LeDrew and Justin Crowe (later of the decidedly louder &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;) and their frequent studio collaborator Luke Mumford (&lt;a href="https://negativerage.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Negative Rage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://geneticangry.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Genetic Angry&lt;/a&gt;, and most recently &lt;a href="https://markvodka.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Mark Vodka Group&lt;/a&gt;). Despite their collective penchant for more aggressive genres, this project found the trio playing satisfyingly straightforward rock music with a bit of a 60s garage feel. Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Talk Records recently collected their only studio output as the &lt;em&gt;Left Undone&lt;/em&gt; EP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week LeDrew, Luke &amp;amp; Crowe shared a video for the song &amp;quot;Jaded (I&amp;#39;m So),&amp;quot; compiled from footage spanning 2013 through 2018. You can find it on YouTube now. Mumford recorded the song in 2017 at Pepperell Street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T08PH2_RT9A" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/T08PH2_RT9A" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: LeDrew, Luke &amp;amp; Crowe - &amp;quot;Jaded (I&amp;#39;m So)&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Enigmatic Montreal singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://www.yvesjarvis.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Yves Jarvis&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a third single from his upcoming LP, &lt;em&gt;Sundry Rock Song Stock&lt;/em&gt;. You can delve into airy and hypnotic &amp;quot;Semula&amp;quot; below through a low-fi, self-shot video that finds Jarvis trekking rather menacingly through the woods. In a statement, the artist commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Roots can be particularly difficult to untangle... I want my recordings to be naturalist, so from that sense I am ideally making them outside. More than a musician or a singer, I&amp;#39;m a producer, and any studio I&amp;#39;m in will become my bedroom. Creation is my life and I don&amp;#39;t compartmentalize it at all.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sundry Rock Song Stock&lt;/em&gt; arrives digitally on September 25, with a vinyl edition following on November 13 from &lt;a href="http://www.flemisheye.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flemish Eye&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="http://www.anti.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;ANTI-&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Yves Jarvis is the latest stage name for Jean-Sebastian Audet. He previously recorded as Un Blonde.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qMZi_wbU7Rc" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/qMZi_wbU7Rc" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Yves Jarvis - &amp;quot;Semula&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A pair of &lt;a href="https://napeyes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nap Eyes&lt;/a&gt; b-sides surfaced last week, showcasing finished songs cut from the Halifax indie rock group&amp;#39;s recent LP, &lt;em&gt;Snapshot of a Beginner&lt;/em&gt;. In a statement, vocalist/guitarist Nigel Chapman offered his thoughts on each track. As for &amp;quot;Snake Oil,&amp;quot; he commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Snake oil&amp;#39; is a well-known idiom of course, for which everyone will have their own associations, and no doubt anyone listening today will be able to find some apropos uses for it... Whatever this &amp;#39;snake oil&amp;#39; literally represents, the singer is apparently brewing and stewing it as some kind of sustenance. Who knows what that might mean... it&amp;#39;s a riddle even to me, but I wonder could it have something to do with the dangers at the opposite extreme of the gullibility spectrum—those of hyper-skepticism?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That song&amp;#39;s paired with &amp;quot;Child&amp;#39;s Romance,&amp;quot; on which Chapman wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;After writing it I was thinking it&amp;#39;s maybe a bit like the &amp;#39;courtly love&amp;#39; attitude expressed in medieval literature (the early/original &amp;#39;Romances&amp;#39;), which is a slightly outlandish combination of aesthetics, idealism, and passion. On another level, I think the song is about learning, as we grow up, to differentiate between feelings of romantic love and more friendly admiration and warmth that we feel towards others. The following should go without saying of course, but it&amp;#39;s definitely necessary to make room for both kinds of feelings in our psychology—rather than expecting ourselves to feel only one or the other.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Nap Eyes was on tour supporting the then-recently-released &lt;em&gt;Snapshot&lt;/em&gt; when the world went into lockdown. The record, the quartet&amp;#39;s fourth, followed-up on 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;m Bad Now&lt;/em&gt;. It arrived collectively from &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://jagjaguwar.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jagjaguwar&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.paradiseofbachelors.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paradise of Bachelors&lt;/a&gt;. Nap Eyes features Nigel Chapman alongside drummer Seamus Dalton, bassist Josh Salter, and guitarist Brad Loughead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3327786133/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://napeyes.bandcamp.com/album/snake-oil-childs-romance"&gt;Snake Oil / Child's Romance by Nap Eyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://napeyes.bandcamp.com/album/snake-oil-childs-romance" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Nap Eyes - &amp;quot;Snake Oil&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Child&amp;#39;s Romance&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://codyellen.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Industrial Priest Overcoats&lt;/a&gt; have a third single online from their upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Transformer Story&lt;/em&gt;. You can check out the angular and abbreviated &amp;quot;Just a Two-Legged&amp;quot; at Bandcamp now. It follows &amp;quot;Trauma, Trauma, Traumatized&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;The Covenant House Kidz Reunion&amp;quot; in previewing the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Industrial Priest Overcoats are the ongoing solo project of Secwépemc artist TJ Felix. It&amp;#39;ll follow 2019&amp;#39;s full-length &lt;em&gt;The Years Barely Left a Trace&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Earlier this year, TJ&amp;#39;s wonderfully weird and nervously frantic punk group &lt;a href="https://bedwettersanonymous.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bedwetters Anonymous&lt;/a&gt; released an EP titled &lt;em&gt;Framed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1930190446/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://codyellen.bandcamp.com/track/just-a-two-legged"&gt;Just a Two-Legged by INDUSTRIAL PRIEST OVERCOATS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://codyellen.bandcamp.com/track/just-a-two-legged" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Industrial Priest Overcoats - &amp;quot;Just a Two-Legged&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This Friday, the Quebec garage rock act &lt;a href="https://hibouhibouband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hibou Hibou&lt;/a&gt; returns with a new five-song EP  &lt;em&gt;Tout le monde s&amp;#39;en fout&lt;/em&gt;. You can preview the tracks &amp;quot;Bulldozer&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Éteins ton moteur&amp;quot; on Bandcamp now. The former features Rémi Cyr from &lt;a href="https://lestrimpes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Les Trimpes&lt;/a&gt; guesting on harmonica. The band recorded this material at Studio Plywood with Jean-Philippe Levac of &lt;a href="https://pandaleon.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pandaléon&lt;/a&gt; engineering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hibou Hibou featured guitarist/vocalist Marc Gagné, bassist David Perrault, and drummer Pierre-Olivier Dupont on these recordings. The new set follows their 2018 EP &lt;em&gt;Couleur Néfaste&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=770561072/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://hibouhibouband.bandcamp.com/album/tout-le-monde-sen-fout"&gt;Tout le monde s'en fout by Hibou Hibou&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://hibouhibouband.bandcamp.com/album/tout-le-monde-sen-fout" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Hibou Hibou - &amp;quot;Bulldozer (Feat. Rémi Cyr)&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Soulful Vancouver rock quartet &lt;a href="https://thenoodleboys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Noodle Boys&lt;/a&gt; recently shared &amp;quot;The Walk,&amp;quot; the lush third and final single off of their forthcoming sophomore EP &lt;em&gt;The Second Serving&lt;/em&gt;. It follows &amp;quot;Ocean&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Volume 5&amp;quot; in previewing the release. You can find all three tracks streaming now at Bandcamp, with a &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/psYkK8JjpNU" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; for &amp;quot;Ocean&amp;quot; available where you&amp;#39;d expect to find it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lead by vocalist/drummer Brett Frigon, The Noodle Boys features guitarists Juliano Boss and Brad Long, with bassist Chad Neald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1955818381/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenoodleboys.bandcamp.com/track/the-walk"&gt;The Walk by the noodle boys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://thenoodleboys.bandcamp.com/track/the-walk" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Noodle Boys - &amp;quot;The Walk&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The angular, new-wave indebted &lt;a href="https://crackcloud.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crack Cloud&lt;/a&gt; has a limited edition live LP on the way. &lt;em&gt;Live Leak&lt;/em&gt; compiles material from two sessions, a March 2019 appearance on the Los Angeles KXLU show &lt;a href="http://www.parttimepunks.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Part Time Punks&lt;/a&gt; and a set from August of last year recorded for the BBC&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/m00010rh" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Radio 6 Music&lt;/a&gt;. The vinyl release is limited to just 150 copies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Based in Vancouver and self-styled as a revolutionary mixed-media collective, Crack Cloud released the dense and ambitious full-length &lt;em&gt;Pain Olympics&lt;/em&gt; this past July. A series of high-concept videos supported the album, with confrontational clips for &amp;quot;Ouster Stew&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Tunnel Vision&amp;quot; released earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4217074665/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://crackcloud.bandcamp.com/album/live-leak"&gt;Live Leak by Crack Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://crackcloud.bandcamp.com/album/live-leak" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Crack Cloud - &lt;em&gt;Live Leak&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Gritty St. Catharines punk quartet &lt;a href="http://theholdouts905.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Holdouts&lt;/a&gt; have a new single online, with &amp;quot;Long Time No See&amp;quot; emerging as the follow-up to their January-released &lt;em&gt;Cause and Effect&lt;/em&gt; EP. The Niagara group recorded the set with Ethan Snook at the &lt;a href="http://www.warehouseniagara.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse Concert Hall&lt;/a&gt;. That venue, shuttered due to COVID-19, has been operating as a &lt;a href="http://www.warehouseniagara.com/event/rehearsal-studio-at-warehouse/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;rehearsal studio&lt;/a&gt; throughout the lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1826506613/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://theholdouts905.bandcamp.com/track/long-time-no-see"&gt;Long Time No See by The Holdouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://theholdouts905.bandcamp.com/track/long-time-no-see" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Holdouts - &amp;quot;Long Time No See&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto-based singer/songwriter &lt;a href="https://cactusvellamusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cactus Vella&lt;/a&gt; has paired up with &lt;a href="https://littlerocketrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Little Rocket Records&lt;/a&gt; to release his new EP. Titled &lt;em&gt;Yonge&lt;/em&gt;, the digital set features the new single &amp;quot;Ship Wreck&amp;quot; backed with a cover of the Old Crow Medicine Show&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;I Hear Them All.&amp;quot; Vancouver folk-punker &lt;a href="https://jesselebourdais.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jesse Lebourdais&lt;/a&gt; and TO&amp;#39;s Boxcar Shawn (&lt;a href="https://plan37.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Plan 37&lt;/a&gt;) appear as backing vocalists on the recording. A video for &amp;quot;Ship Wreck&amp;quot; recently premiered at Punknews.org. You can check it out below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Cactus Vella has roots in Toronto punk groups like &lt;a href="https://sinkinships.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sinkin&amp;#39; Ships&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://dogsto.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;DOGS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pANoNYeP6Ns" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/pANoNYeP6Ns" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Cactus Vella - &amp;quot;Ship Wreck&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;After an unexpected delay (read: pandemic), Ottawa&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://chrispage.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Page&lt;/a&gt; has finally unveiled &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay and Swim Again&lt;/em&gt;, a full redux of his 2004 solo record &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay and Swim&lt;/em&gt;. Page commented on the project at Bandcamp:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I had a moment this past winter looking back on a solo record I put out on Kelp Records in 2004 and realized it had been 15 years since I released &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay And Swim&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The record only ever came out on CD, so I popped a copy in a player and had a focused listen. I&amp;#39;d forgotten how much I liked the songs on this record and how much of an amazing sonic stamp Dave Draves put all over it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;During those past cold and dark months, I decided to revisit these songs and released these new, acoustic, demo-like versions slowly over time, culminating in this final collection of songs.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 11 song collection is available now in a limited, hand-numbered vinyl run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Chris plays these days as part of the duo &lt;a href="https://expandafuzz.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Expanda Fuzz&lt;/a&gt;, having earlier served in &lt;a href="http://campradio.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Camp Radio&lt;/a&gt; and the 90s pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://thestandgt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Stand GT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3127342879/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrispage.bandcamp.com/album/decide-to-stay-and-swim-again"&gt;Decide To Stay and Swim Again by Chris Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrispage.bandcamp.com/album/decide-to-stay-and-swim-again" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Chris Page - &lt;em&gt;Decide To Stay and Swim Again&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Tartan Beret</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-08-23-green-tartan-beret/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2020-08-23-green-tartan-beret/</id>
    <published>2020-08-22T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-27T11:33:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Out on the East Coast, solo punk act &lt;a href="https://tjcabot.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TJ Cabot&lt;/a&gt; continues to record crunchy Ramones-styled tunes supporting the noble, if perhaps obscure, cause of Boularderie Island independence. Given the surreal year we&amp;#39;re grinding through, I choose to take that notion entirely at face value and free of sarcasm. The &lt;em&gt;Dick Charles&lt;/em&gt; EP features seven songs, basement-recorded to the internal mic in a laptop, with the low-fi production values giving the material a bit of a gnarly Spits vibe (always a good thing).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new set follows two previous quarantine releases from Cabot, a set of demos credited to &lt;a href="https://tjcabot.bandcamp.com/album/tj-cabot-thee-artificial-rejects-demos" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TJ Cabot &amp;amp; Thee Artificial Rejects&lt;/a&gt;, and the new wave styled &amp;quot;Overcompensation&amp;quot; single. The latter was a collaboration with the Moncton synthwave artist &lt;a href="https://sonichz.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sonic Hz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Before fully committing their artistic talents to liberate the good people of Millville, TJ went by the name Tyler Boutilier and played in Nova Scotian punk groups &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/bull-artery/teenage-hurricanes-saturday" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenage Hurricanes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.thecoast.ca/TheScene/archives/2010/01/05/january-9-goodbye-dunce-club-but-hello-fun-night-of-punk-shows" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dunce Club&lt;/a&gt;, not to mention with Moncton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://phonejerks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Phone Jerks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/The-Beaten-Hearts-110327236905" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Beaten Hearts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://nervebutton.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nerve Button&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=131959668/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://tjcabot.bandcamp.com/album/dick-charles-ep"&gt;DICK CHARLES EP by TJ Cabot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://tjcabot.bandcamp.com/album/dick-charles-ep" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: TJ Cabot - &lt;em&gt;Dick Charles&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal emo-revivalists &lt;a href="https://gulfer.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Gulfer&lt;/a&gt; have signed with &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.topshelfrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Topshelf Records&lt;/a&gt; to release their third LP, a 13 song self-titled album due October 16. The news came alongside a video for the new single &amp;quot;Forget (Friendly),&amp;quot; directed by Dominic Fontaine and Jean-François Dubé. Vocalist/guitarist Joseph Therriault commented on the song in a press release, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Forget (Friendly)&amp;#39; is about how you deal with developing a crush on someone in the context of a monogamous partnership (especially if it&amp;#39;s reciprocated). There are so many things we can&amp;#39;t control. The song has no lesson - I&amp;#39;m just as clueless about this as when I wrote the lyrics.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new record follows the band&amp;#39;s 2018 LP &lt;em&gt;Dog Bless&lt;/em&gt; and showcases their evolving slant on emo, peppered with punk, grunge, and math-rock elements. Over the quarantine period Gulfer  shared a pair of archival releases: the early singles compilation &lt;em&gt;Anthology&lt;/em&gt; in May and a &lt;em&gt;Live in Japan&lt;/em&gt; concert recording in June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Gulfer features guitarist/vocalists Vincent Ford and Joe Therriault, bassist David Mitchell, and drummer Julien Daoust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P71TBk9svjY" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/P71TBk9svjY" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Gulfer - &amp;quot;Forget (Friendly)&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A recent Bandcamp Daily article by Michael Rancic spotlights &lt;a href="https://daily.bandcamp.com/lists/prince-edward-island-punk-list" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PEI punk bands&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing ten of the province&amp;#39;s contemporary groups. While a few of these acts have gained some notoriety in Canadian punk circles outside the Maritimes, there are quite a few bands in the list that were certainly new to me (like the quirky DEVO-inspired &lt;a href="https://fshkll.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FSHKLL&lt;/a&gt; and the snotty boneheads of &lt;a href="https://faceplant.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Faceplant&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One revelation from Rancic&amp;#39;s list was the existence of the glitchy &lt;a href="https://remotecontrolyourlife.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Remote Control&lt;/a&gt;, a Charlottetown duo featuring &lt;a href="http://warsh.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warsh&lt;/a&gt; bassist Rosanna Kressin on vocals, backed by Ben Goss of &lt;a href="https://antibodieschtn.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Antibodies&lt;/a&gt; on guitar (and everything else). The five-song &lt;em&gt;REMO VOL. #1&lt;/em&gt; EP surfaced in July, with the pair at times seemingly in outright conflict with an ever-accelerating drum machine (check out &amp;quot;Judgement In The Barracks&amp;quot; in that regard).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1587072612/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://remotecontrolyourlife.bandcamp.com/album/remo-vol-1"&gt;REMO VOL. #1 by Remote Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://remotecontrolyourlife.bandcamp.com/album/remo-vol-1" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Remote Control - &lt;em&gt;REMO VOL. #1&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Trois-Rivières quintet &lt;a href="https://postrough.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Post-Rough&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a video for their goth-influenced single &amp;quot;Police.&amp;quot; Described by the band as a &amp;quot;dronish-post-punk hymn,&amp;quot; it&amp;#39;s a marked departure from the group&amp;#39;s early up-tempo material. The single appears on the band&amp;#39;s recent four-song EP &lt;em&gt;Vous êtes un personnage de roman&lt;/em&gt;. British artist Will Morrison directed the clip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This band recorded at Studio Pantouf in Saint-Élie-de-Caxton with engineering from Louis-Philippe Cantin (Perséide) and Pierre Brouillette Hamelin (Rorqual). Simon Provencher (Victime, Palissade) mixed the set, with mastering from JP Villemure (Fuudge, Bleu Nuit).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pre-COVID, Post-Rough had plans to release the record in July as part of the Trois-Rivières music festival FestiVoix, but with that gathering understandably sidelined the material&amp;#39;s emerging online now. Post-Rough features guitarist/vocalist Bastien Mortimer, guitarist Alexis Vaillant-Gamache, bassist Tommy Dupuis, Olivier Durand on synth, and drummer Pierre-Olivier Lessard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CMpMguAubQ4" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/CMpMguAubQ4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Post-Rough - &amp;quot;Police&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver power-pop trio &lt;a href="http://brutalpoodlevan.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brutal Poodle&lt;/a&gt; has a new 7&amp;quot; out featuring the single &amp;quot;Night Creeps&amp;quot; and b-side &amp;quot;Wash.&amp;quot; It arrived earlier this month from &lt;a href="https://kingfisherbluez.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kingfisher Bluez&lt;/a&gt;. The release is the second to spring from summer 2018 recording sessions with Joshua Wells (Lightning Dust, Destroyer) at the Balloon Factory (the first, &amp;quot;Crowd Control&amp;quot; b/w &amp;quot;Low Tide,&amp;quot; arrived in May of last year). Bassist/vocalist Karmin Poirier spoke about the A-side:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We had a really good time reworking &amp;#39;Night Creeps&amp;#39; as we recorded it with Josh. The falling guitar with the funky chorus time signature, the synth textures, and the abrupt start all add to an uneasy feeling under the surface, while the poppy song itself rides in the forefront.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;On &amp;quot;Wash,&amp;quot; she revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I was kind of on a Husker Du kick when we were working on this song. I think it has a pretty frenetic vibe to it, it feels like it could go off the rails at any moment but we all just push through it. It adapts well to the energy of our live shows, not that those are a thing at the moment.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The group&amp;#39;s planning to record their debut full-length with Jesse Gander at Rain City Recorders in September. Brutal Poodle features Karmin Poirier with guitarist/vocalist John Johnston and drummer Dustin Bromley. Members of the group had previously played in &lt;a href="https://sbdc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SBDC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://jocktears.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jock Tears&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://slowlearners.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slow Learners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=978719096/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://brutalpoodlevan.bandcamp.com/album/night-creeps"&gt;Night Creeps by Brutal Poodle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://brutalpoodlevan.bandcamp.com/album/night-creeps" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Brutal Poodle - &lt;em&gt;Night Creeps&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto garage rockers &lt;a href="https://baddriver.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bad River&lt;/a&gt; have a new video out showcasing the slow-burning title track to their late-2019 EP, &lt;em&gt;Petrol Head&lt;/em&gt;. The band shot the clip with director Brendan George Ko in March, right before the lockdown kicked in. It features a man dressed as a cockroach on something of a lonely search for meaning - a search amongst the kitsch and casinos of my hometown of Niagara Falls. I&amp;#39;ll support anything that highlights the seedy magic realism of this strange town. I wish they&amp;#39;d shown how they walked this costume through Fallsview Casino security, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Petrol Head&lt;/em&gt; was the grunge-influenced band&amp;#39;s follow up to 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Clean Air&lt;/em&gt; EP. Bad River recorded at London, Ontario&amp;#39;s Sugar Shack (WHOOP-Szo, Chastity) with mastering performed at Toronto&amp;#39;s Lacquer Channel by Noah Mintz (Constantines, Broken Social Scene).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Bad River features guitarist/vocalist Thomas Huhtala, bassist Scott Hempstead, and drummer Nathan Heuvingh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5gz8oQHQX8M" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/5gz8oQHQX8M" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Bad River - &amp;quot;Petrol Head&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In June, the dynamic Quebec City punk group &lt;a href="http://dogosuicide.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dogo Suicide&lt;/a&gt; shared their self-titled full-length. The discography-styled collection features 13 songs, collecting the material from February&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Douvres&lt;/em&gt; EP and the group&amp;#39;s 2018 debut &lt;em&gt;Direction Nord-Sud&lt;/em&gt;, along with three newly recorded tracks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;These recordings feature the band&amp;#39;s core of guitarist/vocalist Nicolas Côté and bassist Emmanuel Canadian backed on various tracks by drummers Richard-William Turcotte and Jesse Bédard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1631882508/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dogosuicide.bandcamp.com/album/dogo-suicide"&gt;Dogo Suicide by Dogo Suicide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://dogosuicide.bandcamp.com/album/dogo-suicide" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Dogo Suicide - &lt;em&gt;Dogo Suicide&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Halifax garage-rockers &lt;a href="https://shoulderseasonhfx.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shoulder Season&lt;/a&gt; have a video online for &amp;quot;Clean Lines,&amp;quot; a concise, jangling single that instantly hooked me back in January. Songwriter Mel Sturk previously commented on the song&amp;#39;s lyrics:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;when you&amp;#39;re in an airplane, going between places and people you love, sometimes the things you see from 35,000 feet make you think about not just the places, but how the &amp;#39;soft&amp;#39; cultures of those places is reflected in the land formations below. Also, agriculture is cool.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The band took those sentiments literally in the clip, pairing cell phone footage from airplane windows with clips of the members&amp;#39; quarantine gardens. The lockdown that&amp;#39;s restricted most of us from travelling (and curtailed the band&amp;#39;s touring plans) adds a whole other layer of meaning to that contrasting imagery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Based in Dartmouth, Shoulder Season features Karen Foster, Mel Sturk, Kristina Parlee, and Erica Butler. The quartet has roots in several past groups, with members serving time with Halifax acts &lt;a href="https://thestolenminks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Stolen Minks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://themaynards.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Maynards&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://smallerhearts.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Smaller Hearts&lt;/a&gt;, as well as Ottawa&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://thejohnnies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Johnnies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fRa2IxPvXaw" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/fRa2IxPvXaw" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Shoulder Season - &amp;quot;Clean Lines&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Saskatchewan label &lt;a href="https://fixedfrequency.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fixed Frequency&lt;/a&gt; recently shared &lt;em&gt;Gold Plated Trash&lt;/em&gt;, the seven-song debut from Regina&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://fixedfrequency.bandcamp.com/album/gold-plated-trash" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Blood Of Keith Richards&lt;/a&gt;. The set features a collection of raw-throated Ramones worship crafted by Russ Purdy, drummer of the pop-punk outfit &lt;a href="https://ripperandthejesses.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ripper and the Jesses&lt;/a&gt;. While the Purdy rarely takes his foot off the gas, I&amp;#39;m a more than a little fascinated by &amp;quot;Miley Cyrus&amp;#39; Weed Stash,&amp;quot; the spacey noise-wall that closes the album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ripper and the Jesses last released &lt;em&gt;Velociraptor Of Love&lt;/em&gt; in 2019. Purdy recorded, mixed, and mastered these tracks entirely solo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3107717990/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fixedfrequency.bandcamp.com/album/gold-plated-trash"&gt;Gold Plated Trash by The Blood Of Keith Richards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://fixedfrequency.bandcamp.com/album/gold-plated-trash" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: The Blood of Keith Richards - &lt;em&gt;Gold Plated Trash&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I am entirely on board with &lt;em&gt;The Golden Days are Hard&lt;/em&gt;, the thrillingly chaotic new LP from Toronto alt-country weirdos &lt;a href="https://westelaken.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Westelaken&lt;/a&gt;. The band celebrated the album&amp;#39;s launch with a new video for the song &amp;#39;Mercy, &amp;quot;milk-of-human-kindness&amp;quot;.&amp;#39; Guitarist Jordan Seccareccia spoke about the clip in an &lt;a href="torontos_westelaken_return_with_sophomore_lp_the_golden_days_are_hard" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt; feature, delving into the band&amp;#39;s collaboration with director (and former &lt;a href="https://wlmrt.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WLMRT&lt;/a&gt; member) Ryan Al-Hage of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC5xL1xwdEiSlyZl5LqnNddA" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Thank You So Much&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;We gave Ryan the album and asked if he wanted to pick a song to turn into a video, and when he picked this one I think it made us all excited and relieved that this bizarre thing seemed to work for someone. We filmed it at Ontario Place, where it almost feels like you&amp;#39;re walking around in ancient ruins. It turned out pretty fun and silly in a way that compliments the sort of unhinged nature of the song. It has a cameo from our friend Dave [Eatock of &lt;a href="https://commuted.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Commuted&lt;/a&gt;]. We were attacked by a dog. You can also hear Paul having a lot of fun in the mix.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Westelaken features Alex Baigent on vocals, bass, and synth, Rob McLay on percussion and backing vocals, Jordan Seccareccia on guitar, and Lucas Temor on piano and banjo. Paul Vroom recorded, mixed, and mastered the band&amp;#39;s new material last fall at The Pharmacy in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SwDskHlribI" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SwDskHlribI" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Westelaken - &amp;#39;Mercy, &amp;quot;milk-of-human-kindness&amp;quot;&amp;#39; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Last week, I shared the first new single from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://feelsfine666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feels Fine&lt;/a&gt;, and they&amp;#39;re already back with a second cut. The group, heavily influenced by midwestern emo of the late 90s, is gearing up to release &lt;em&gt;Grip&lt;/em&gt; on August 29. This week&amp;#39;s preview is titled &amp;quot;Imagine,&amp;quot; and follows &amp;quot;Washed Out Blue&amp;quot; from the last go-around. You can check it out now on Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Feels Fine has teamed up with &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt; for this record. It follows up their &lt;em&gt;At Home&lt;/em&gt; EP from 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3923423898/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=185634551/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://feelsfine666.bandcamp.com/album/grip"&gt;Grip by FEELS FINE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://feelsfine666.bandcamp.com/track/imagine-by-j-hn-lenn-n" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Feels Fine - &amp;quot;Imagine&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Quebec often seems like it&amp;#39;s operating in a slightly parallel universe to the rest of the country, and understandably so. That&amp;#39;s never felt so acutely surreal to me as it has this summer, with the province loosening restrictions on live events while the rest of the country remains in stasis. I&amp;#39;m not even sure if I&amp;#39;m envious, given that we&amp;#39;re still in the middle of this thing, but I&amp;#39;m certainly wistful. While &lt;a href="https://popmontreal.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;POP Montreal&lt;/a&gt; just announced that they&amp;#39;d be hosting a slate of events with an in-person audience, the real shocker for me is the news that &lt;a href="http://www.fmeat.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;FME&lt;/a&gt; is going ahead next week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Festival de musique émergente en Abitibi-Témiscamingue takes place yearly in Rouyn-Noranda. Over nearly two decades has forged a reputation as one of the country&amp;#39;s most sonically diverse and artistically relevant gatherings, as well as a premier industry networking event. Remoteness certainly plays a part in that mystique, and when I was privileged enough to attend a few years back, I absolutely felt that. Unlike most live music events in 2020, FME was never formally cancelled, a fact that&amp;#39;s become something of a source of fascination amongst my Ontario-shackled peers over the summer. This year&amp;#39;s FME forges ahead from September 3 to 5 as a smaller-scale event, but it still brings twenty acts north to the copper mining town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;With international travel curtailed, FME&amp;#39;s drawing almost exclusively on Quebec-based acts for its 18th year, with performances planned from a handful of artists who are no strangers to this newsletter (&lt;a href="https://zenbamboo.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Zen Bamboo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://nobro.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;NOBRO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://corridormtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Corridor&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://fuudge.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fuudge&lt;/a&gt; among them). The event broke down the lineup in a press-release&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Particular consideration has been given to groups whose career strategies have been gravely affected by the pandemic: Aliocha&amp;#39;s new album; Laurence Hélie&amp;#39;s English-language project Mirabelle; the prolific Rosie Valland; the up-and-coming act Anachnid; promising rock band Zen Bamboo;  female punk project NOBRO; and the psych-rock duo Les Deuxluxes, who launched an album at the beginning of the year. We will also be treated to premieres including the prelaunch of a new project by Carla Blanc (of Dear Criminals fame); Meggie Lennon;  Jonathan Personne; and Gus Englehorn. We welcome with great interest the promising hip-hop project Backxwash, shortlisted for the Polaris Prize. And we must not forget favourites from years past, including Maude Audet, Les Louanges, Corridor, Les Shirley, FUUDGE, Jesse Mac Cormack , and We Are Wolves.  For his part, Gab Bouchard will roam the streets and alleys of the city with his revue Au pays des pick-up.  The Bleu Jeans Bleu will also visit Abitibi-Témiscamingue for the first time to unveil their new project. Clay and Friends will offer their vibrant, traditional family show Agnico Eagle, and Neoclassical group Flore Laurentienne will showcase a rare mix of strings and synthesizers. On the hip-hop side, we welcome Lary Kidd, KNLO, Brown Family, and Eman.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can find the &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/o2yn3lggjzqafvs/FME2020_grillehoraire.pdf?dl=0" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;full schedule&lt;/a&gt; online if you&amp;#39;re curious to see how they&amp;#39;re pulling this off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Musical programming aside, FME&amp;#39;s approach to operating during the pandemic bears some examination. Venues will open at limited capacities, with many artists performing their sets twice to keep crowd sizes down. Many events are outdoors, with stages on the shores of Lakes Osisko and Flavrian. Every concert requires an online reservation to maintain capacity (and presumably build a list for contract tracing), with no passport-style tickets available this year. Mandatory masking, social distancing markers, and strident disinfection efforts are all de rigueur at this point. Even in less-fraught times FME&amp;#39;s emphasized outdoor art installations, which should work to their advantage them this September when juggling the crowds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;On July 27, Quebec increased the maximum size of public gatherings to 250 people at indoor or outdoor public events, a significant jump from the previous limit of 50 (private gatherings remain capped at 10). Festivals were prohibited until August 31.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1710755405/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuudge.bandcamp.com/album/sacer-facere"&gt;Sacer Facere by FUUDGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://fuudge.bandcamp.com/album/sacer-facere" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Fuudge - &amp;quot;Sacer Facere&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rock Is My Rock</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-08-16-rock-is-my-rock/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2020-08-16-rock-is-my-rock/</id>
    <published>2020-08-15T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-21T09:18:06-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Slack-rock heroes &lt;a href="https://www.partnerband.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt; unveiled plans for their sophomore full-length last week. The Sackville-bred group returns on November 20 with &lt;em&gt;Never Give Up&lt;/em&gt;, a 10-song album and the proper follow-up to 2017&amp;#39;s Polaris-shortlisted &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt;. This record finds vocalist/guitarist Josée Caron and vocalist/bassist Lucy Niles backed by the well-regarded Toronto drummer Simone TB (Darlene Shrugg, Fake Palms). Among the album&amp;#39;s runtime, you&amp;#39;ll find the group&amp;#39;s recent Rush-inspired single &amp;quot;Good Place To Hide (At The Time)&amp;quot; along with the newly available, album-opening pair &amp;quot;Hello and Welcome&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Rock is My Rock.&amp;quot; All evidence points to the group diving head-first into their classic rock influences this time out, both in sound and sentiment. The group commented on the new tracks:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Hello and Welcome&amp;#39; is the opening track to our upcoming full-length album, &lt;em&gt;Never Give Up&lt;/em&gt;. In this song, we will take you on a journey and introduce you to the new universe we are exploring on this album. We are very thrilled to have collaborated with Dustin Apodaca (Midnight Peacemaker) for this exciting music video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;#39;Rock Is My Rock&amp;#39; is a song that we wrote to celebrate the joy of rock, and the joy it brings us to see other people feel the joy of rock. We wanted to thank the music for bringing us happiness and keeping us company during difficult times. This song is dedicated to anyone for whom rock is a rock. We know 2020 has been a different kind of year for everyone. There has been a lot of stress but also a lot of good with positive change happening in our society, whether it&amp;#39;s baby steps or great leaps. We just want to thank everyone who has bought our record, or listened to a Partner tune and enjoyed it. We appreciate all of the support in every way. We can&amp;#39;t wait to be able to see you all in person again.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Partner recorded this material in July of 2019 at Palace Sounds, with Steve Chahley (Ice Cream, US Girls) engineering. The group last released the &lt;em&gt;Saturday the 14th&lt;/em&gt; EP in 2019. &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;em&gt;Never Give Up&lt;/em&gt; on deck for a November 20 release, plenty of time to get your KISS boots polished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjpeQ0h1LH0" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/HjpeQ0h1LH0" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Partner - &amp;quot;Hello and Welcome&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W4q9EDP9eJ4" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/W4q9EDP9eJ4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Partner - &amp;quot;Rock Is My Rock&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;After a seemingly impossible run of unannounced quarantine releases, it looks like Welland&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt; is returning the normal album cycle. A September 18 release date&amp;#39;s locked in for his next proper full-length, &lt;em&gt;How Ill Thy World Is Ordered&lt;/em&gt;. Properly attributed to Daniel Romano&amp;#39;s Outfit, the project features Danny&amp;#39;s full touring band, currently comprised of vocalist Julianna Riolino, guitarist/vocalist David Nardi, bassist Roddy Rossetti, and drummer Ian Romano. The 11-song set builds upon that core group with contributions from pianist Mark Lalama, vocalist Briana Salmena, sax player Victor Belcastro, and Aaron Hutchinson on trumpet. The write-up from &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; suggests a guitar-forward rock record, claiming more &amp;quot;honest-to-the-core lead guitar playing than Daniel has previously committed to tape.&amp;quot; The press release continues:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;The band assembled in studio in a perfectly tuned geometry to record these new songs following simple guidelines and simple rules: play the whole thing, in sequence, 3 takes or bust, with no overdubs; play &amp;#39;the sound of the feel of a snake bite;&amp;#39; play &amp;#39;a heist on horseback for fool&amp;#39;s gold.&amp;#39;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The album-opening single &amp;quot;A Rat Without a Tale&amp;quot; is now streaming online, with an accompanying video running at the usual outlets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Ill Thy World Is Ordered&lt;/em&gt; clocks in as the 9th fully-realized release from Romano this calendar year, but only the second to earn a physical presence (following March&amp;#39;s live record, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Okay Wow&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;). Since the pandemic took hold, Danny&amp;#39;s shared the original full-lengths &lt;em&gt;Dandelion&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Content To Point The Way&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Visions Of The Higher Dream&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, along with a high-concept front-to-back cover of Bob Dylan&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Infidels&lt;/em&gt;. He co-created  &lt;em&gt;A Splendour Of Heart&lt;/em&gt; backing Ottawa vocalist &lt;a href="https://www.kellysloan.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kelly Sloan&lt;/a&gt;, the punk record &lt;em&gt;Spider Bite&lt;/em&gt; with Constantines&amp;#39; &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt;, the spirited &lt;em&gt;Super Pollen&lt;/em&gt; EP with members of &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;, and the 23-minute prog single &amp;quot;Forever Love&amp;#39;s Fool&amp;quot; (featuring the Tool drummer Daniel Carey, of all people).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One assumes that with an actual pre-announced record on the horizon, that could be it for a while, but without the ability to tour, I suspect we&amp;#39;ll hear more from Romano&amp;#39;s restless home studio sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X-zQ-_F0Yb0" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/X-zQ-_F0Yb0" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Daniel Romano&amp;#39;s Outfit - &amp;quot;A Rat Without a Tale&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s ever-evolving garage-punks &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt; recently shared their second preview of &lt;em&gt;Good Time&lt;/em&gt; in the form of the provincially-minded &amp;quot;Trillium Song.&amp;quot; The high-strung track features the always wry vocals of Chris Swimmings, with bassist Melissa Ball joining in for the chorus. Swimmings commented on the song&amp;#39;s subject matter in a press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;This song is about the province of Ontario where we all reside. Mainly about the current provincial government&amp;#39;s way of dealing with the education system and the environment. At the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, Premier Doug Ford (the song&amp;#39;s primary subject) was making good headway at polishing his public image by being hands-on. He made promises of people not losing their jobs and tenants not being evicted. They were timely promises in the beginning as we are now seeing many tenants in Ontario face eviction due to not being able to make ends meet in the pandemic.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Good Time&lt;/em&gt; arrives October 2 as Teenanger&amp;#39;s sixth full-length, once again via the band&amp;#39;s longtime label &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;. The group recorded at Studio Z in Toronto with the celebrated post-rock artist &lt;a href="http://www.sandroperri.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sandro Perri&lt;/a&gt; producing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Together for more than a decade, Teenanger continues to boast their original lineup of drummer Steve Sidoli, bassist Melissa Bell, guitarist Jon Schouten, and vocalist Chris Swimmings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2011361120/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/track=2900606127/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://teenanger.bandcamp.com/album/good-time"&gt;Good Time by TEENANGER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/track/trillium-song" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Teenanger - &amp;quot;Trillium Song&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Bombastic Toronto punk outfit &lt;a href="http://theobgms.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The OBGMs&lt;/a&gt; continue to hustle hard in support of their new material. The band recently revealed that their forthcoming &lt;a href="https://weareblackbox.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Box&lt;/a&gt; LP would be titled &lt;em&gt;The Ends&lt;/em&gt;, and comes with an October 30 release date. The 10-song set includes the earlier singles &amp;quot;Cash&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Not Again,&amp;quot; as well as the newly unveiled &amp;quot;Fight Song.&amp;quot; That track arrived alongside both a new video and high-profile write up in &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en_ca/article/y3ze3j/the-obgms-need-to-be-torontos-next-big-punk-band" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Vice&lt;/a&gt;. The OBGMs hyperbolic self-promotion (they regularly declare that they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; Nirvana) seems to be paying off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The OBGMs play as a trio comprised of guitarist/vocalist Densil McFarlane, bassist Joseph Brosnan, and drummer Colanthony Humphrey. They recorded this new material with Grammy and JUNO Award-winning producer Dave Schiffman (PUP, The Bronx, Anti-Flag).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Upon the release of their prior single, I had a brief but illuminating chat with McFarlane on the band&amp;#39;s high-octane garage-punk sound, their in-your-face promotional strategy, BIPOC rock representation, and more. You can revisit that atop the &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2020-07-05-burn-it-all/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;July 5 edition&lt;/a&gt; of the newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N2y03emKAkQ" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/N2y03emKAkQ" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The OBGMs - &amp;quot;Fight Song&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dundas power-trio &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; shared word on their third full-length this week, with the follow-up to 2018&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Master Volume&lt;/em&gt; carrying the blunt title of &lt;em&gt;Fuck Art&lt;/em&gt;. While they&amp;#39;ve yet to elaborate on the sentiment implied in the title, the brash new single &amp;quot;Doom Boy&amp;quot; may offer a few hints. The track finds the band fusing their familiar brand of hooky power-pop with a gleeful dose of thrash metal riffing. An accompanying video sees the group exuberantly leaning into low-brow metal tropes and a late-80s VHS aesthetic. Frequent Nil collaborators Mitch Barnes and Victor Malang returned to direct the clip. Frontman Luke Bentham commented on the experience:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Without parallel, &amp;#39;Doom Boy&amp;#39; is the most dangerous video we&amp;#39;ve ever made. When we were told that all we had to do was return the shell of the van to get half our money back, all hell broke loose. Between the Roman candles, vintage mini bikes and minivan mayhem, I was quite surprised that we only had a few injuries by the end of the night. Do NOT attempt any of the antics performed in the &amp;#39;Doom Boy&amp;#39; video. You&amp;#39;ve been warned.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Doom Boy&amp;quot; follows the group&amp;#39;s recent &amp;quot;Done With Drugs&amp;quot; single, with both expected on &lt;em&gt;Fuck Art&lt;/em&gt; when it arrives on &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt; later this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As reported earlier, Bentham, bassist Ross Miller, and drummer Kyle Fisher benefited from living together under the same roof throughout the COVID quarantine. That arrangement allowed the group to forge ahead on this record without having to resort to clumsy remote setups or precautionary distancing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LGnyf52WZds" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LGnyf52WZds" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: The Dirty Nil - &amp;quot;Doom Boy&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of Ross Millar, the musician&amp;#39;s posi-hardcore solo project &lt;a href="http://whenimove.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;When I Move&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a new single. The digital release pairs the songs &amp;quot;Fake Rock N&amp;#39; Roll&amp;quot; with a cover of &amp;quot;I Am Love,&amp;quot; originally by the D.C. hardcore group Give. Millar plays everything on these recordings, save the guitars, which come courtesy of Vince Soliveri. You can find the set at Bandcamp now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;When I Move debuted with a self-titled EP in June. The group succeeds Millar&amp;#39;s earlier work in this sonic and thematic vein under the name &lt;a href="https://itcantallbeblue.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Blue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=875315762/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://whenimove.bandcamp.com/album/fake-rock-n-roll"&gt;FAKE ROCK N' ROLL by WHEN I MOVE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://whenimove.bandcamp.com/album/fake-rock-n-roll" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: When I Move - &amp;quot;Fake Rock N&amp;#39; Roll&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sam Bielanski&amp;#39;s bubblegum-punk act &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ponyband/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PONY&lt;/a&gt; has been quiet for far too long. &amp;quot;WedMB&amp;quot; is the project&amp;#39;s first proper single of the year, following a nigh-perfect cover of &lt;em&gt;The Wedding Singer&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s climactic &amp;quot;Somebody Kill Me Please&amp;quot; back in May. It also marks the band&amp;#39;s first material as part of the &lt;a href="http://www.takethistoheartrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Take This To Heart&lt;/a&gt; family. Bielanski stated, &amp;quot;this song is dedicated to anyone who spends their Friday night googling symptoms.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The tune features Bielanski on vocals and guitar, with additional guitar and bass from &lt;a href="http://www.prettymatty.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pretty Matty&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Matty Morand, and guitar from &lt;a href="https://pacerto.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pacer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Shawn Kosmo. Pretty Matty drummer Lucas Horne plays on the track, with Tokyo Police Club keyboardist Graham Wright contributing on synth. The song follows PONY&amp;#39;s 2019 single &amp;quot;Limerence,&amp;quot; and (long) before that their 2017 EP &lt;em&gt;Do You&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sgLx6jlWeyE" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/sgLx6jlWeyE" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: PONY - &amp;quot;WebMD&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Next month the BC hardcore act &lt;a href="https://boot-licker.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bootlicker&lt;/a&gt; returns with their fourth EP. &lt;em&gt;How To Love Life&lt;/em&gt; arrives September 1 as a 7&amp;quot; release on the &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste&lt;/a&gt; label, featuring six new songs built on the bones of the D-Beat and the UK82 sound. You can preview two tracks, &amp;quot;Shot at Dawn&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Calm Mind,&amp;quot; at Bandcamp now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new set follows the group&amp;#39;s February-released &lt;em&gt;Live In The Swamp&lt;/em&gt; and last year&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Nuclear Family&lt;/em&gt; EP. On this recording, Bootlicker featured Lewis Jay Podlubny on vocals, Trevor Robson on bass, drummer Lucas Treadwell, and &lt;a href="https://chainwhip.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chain Whip&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Josh Nickel on guitar. While she&amp;#39;s not credited with playing on this record, Bootlicker guitarist Athena Joan provides the single&amp;#39;s cover art. Will Killingsworth mixed and mastered the set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1806671445/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/how-to-love-life-e-p"&gt;How To Love Life E.P. by Bootlicker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/how-to-love-life-e-p" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Bootlicker - &lt;em&gt;How To Love Life&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Halifax hardcore group &lt;a href="https://brainpollutionsyndrome.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;B.P.S.&lt;/a&gt; (or Brain Pollution Syndrome) has a new six-song demo out, titled &lt;em&gt;Mentally Chained&lt;/em&gt;. The blown-out, unrelenting set&amp;#39;s available online now, with a cassette release due from Pig Master Tapes. The EP follows the band&amp;#39;s initial slate of demos, captured on tape last year by Sewercide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Luke Mumford recorded these tracks back in March of 2020. B.P.S. features personnel from the same Haligonian family of punk bands that brought you the &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://fragmentpunk.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fragment&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://alienation902.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Alienation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1736269965/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://brainpollutionsyndrome.bandcamp.com/album/mentally-chained"&gt;Mentally Chained by B.P.S.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://brainpollutionsyndrome.bandcamp.com/album/mentally-chained" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: B.P.S. - &lt;em&gt;Mentally Chained&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto noise-punks &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt; have a second new single online previewing the upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Atlas Vending&lt;/em&gt;. This week the trio shared a video for the propulsive &amp;quot;Hail Taxi,&amp;quot; a song world&amp;#39;s more aggressive than the shoegaze-flavoured first single, &amp;quot;A Boat to Drown In.&amp;quot; Frontman Alex Edkins commented on the track in a statement:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Hail Taxi&amp;#39; is about looking back. The lyrics deal with the idea of reconciling or coming to terms with who you were and who you&amp;#39;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A.F. Cortes directed the &amp;quot;Hail Taxi&amp;quot; video, which can be found now on YouTube. The filmmaker explained:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wanted to tell a simple story that captures the song&amp;#39;s overarching theme. The idea of longing for the past creates many visual motifs and I wanted to create a piece that feels timeless and conveys a sense of isolation, highlighting that while we can hide our feelings, we can&amp;#39;t run from them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atlas Vending&lt;/em&gt; arrives on October 9 from &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain Records&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt;. Ben Greenberg (Uniform) co-produced the album with the band, with Seth Manchester (Daughters, Lingua Ignota, The Body) engineering and mixing at Pawtucket&amp;#39;s Machines with Magnets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;METZ features guitarist/vocalist Alex Edkins, bassist Chris Slorach, and drummer Hayden Menzies. In between their previous LP, the Steve Albini engineered &lt;em&gt;Strange Peace&lt;/em&gt;, and this record, METZ released a b-sides and rarities collection for Sub Pop titled &lt;em&gt;Automat&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QRK05iTxfo4" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/QRK05iTxfo4" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: METZ - &amp;quot;Hail Taxi&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt; shared a new single this week titled &amp;quot;Cold In The Summer,&amp;quot; with proceeds from the track to be donated to the &lt;a href="https://indigenousyouth.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;International Indigenous Youth Council&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://donorbox.org/iiyc-covid-19-fund" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Southwest COVID-19 Emergency Response&lt;/a&gt;. The song follows the power-pop unit&amp;#39;s recent &lt;em&gt;Live in LA&lt;/em&gt; set, which raised funds for the employees of that city&amp;#39;s shuttered Zebulon venue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Young Guv, the pop songwriting vehicle of &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Ben Cook, released the twin LPs &lt;em&gt;GUV I&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUV II&lt;/em&gt; last year on &lt;a href="http://www.runforcoverrecords.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t5vszJ0bJxM" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/t5vszJ0bJxM" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Young Guv - &amp;quot;Cold In The Summer&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto label &lt;a href="http://www.artoftheuncarvedblock.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Art of the Uncarved Block&lt;/a&gt; has paired up with the emo revivalists &lt;a href="https://feelsfine666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feels Fine&lt;/a&gt; to release their new album, &lt;em&gt;Grip&lt;/em&gt;. The set, arriving on August 29, features the Toronto group&amp;#39;s authentic take on the midwest emo sound of the late 90s, with the influence of bands like The Jazz June and Rainer Maria on prominent display. You can stream the record&amp;#39;s first single, &amp;quot;Washed Out Blue,&amp;quot; online now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Feels Fine last released the EP &lt;em&gt;At Home&lt;/em&gt; in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" data-src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/873074800&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/artoftheuncarvedblock/washed-out-blue" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Feels Fine - &amp;quot;Washed Out Blue&amp;quot; @ SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hard-driving Montreal punk unit &lt;a href="http://thickglassespunk.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Thick Glasses&lt;/a&gt; recently released &lt;em&gt;Courir après sa queue&lt;/em&gt;, a tight new four-song EP on the &lt;a href="https://www.hellforbreakfast.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hell For Breakfast&lt;/a&gt; label. While they have roots in both punk and stoner rock, the group incorporates an array of styles for this set, alternating from satisfying skate-punk hooks to blasts of metallic hardcore without ever drifting too far afield into any one sub-genre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The propulsive album features guitarist/vocalist Charles-Étienne de Villers, drummer Gabriel Guimond-Mercille, and bassist David Roy. The group recorded with Jordan Barillaro at Montreal&amp;#39;s Planet Studios last fall. &lt;em&gt;Courir après sa queue&lt;/em&gt; follows Thick Glasses&amp;#39; 2018 release &lt;em&gt;En orbite&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2326712431/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thickglassespunk.bandcamp.com/album/courir-apr-s-sa-queue"&gt;Courir après sa queue by Thick Glasses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://thickglassespunk.bandcamp.com/album/courir-apr-s-sa-queue" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Thick Glasses - &lt;em&gt;Courir après sa queue&lt;/em&gt; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;London&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://wastedpotential.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wasted Potential&lt;/a&gt; has a tribute cover online celebrating the recently departed Canadian punk legend Mr. Chi Pig. The band tackled &amp;quot;Joni Mitchell Tapes,&amp;quot; which appeared on &lt;a href="http://snfu.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SNFU&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s 1993 full-length &lt;em&gt;Something Green and Leafy This Way Comes&lt;/em&gt;. All proceeds raised from download are due for the &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/larger-than-life-the-chi-pig-mural" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chi Pig mural fund&lt;/a&gt; (which just surpassed its funding goal).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Wasted Potential recently shared a four-song EP of new material titled &lt;em&gt;Separation Anxiety&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://getparty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Get Party! Records&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. Chi Pig, born Ken Chinn, passed away on July 16 at the age of 57.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1282205613/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://getparty.bandcamp.com/track/joni-mitchell-tapes-snfu-cover"&gt;Joni Mitchell Tapes (SNFU Cover) by Wasted Potential&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://getparty.bandcamp.com/track/joni-mitchell-tapes-snfu-cover" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Wasted Potential - &amp;quot;Joni Mitchell Tapes&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;BC crust unit &lt;a href="https://massgravecrust.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mass Grave&lt;/a&gt; has a pair of new songs online. &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s Left&amp;quot; is the band&amp;#39;s contribution to the latest &lt;em&gt;Grind Bastards&lt;/em&gt; compilation, an ongoing series from the Kyoto hardcore label &lt;a href="https://mcrwebshop.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;MCR&lt;/a&gt;.The band&amp;#39;s offering the download backed by a cover of Capitalist Casualties&amp;#39; 1997 song &amp;quot;Second Guess.&amp;quot; That recording first surfaced on a tribute compilation from &lt;a href="https://www.rtcrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Rotten To The Core Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Jesse Gander recorded both tracks at Rain City Studios this past February. Mass Grave last released a split with the similarly-named Japanese grindcore group Unholy Grave in 2019. The band put out the &lt;em&gt;Our Due Descent&lt;/em&gt; LP in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3476222731/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://massgravecrust.bandcamp.com/album/grind-bastards-14-capitalist-casualties-tribute-compilation-tracks"&gt;Grind Bastards 14 / Capitalist Casualties Tribute Compilation Tracks by Mass Grave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://massgravecrust.bandcamp.com/album/grind-bastards-14-capitalist-casualties-tribute-compilation-tracks" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Mass Grave - &amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s Left&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The dreamy found-art project &lt;a href="https://leisurepalace.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Leisure Palace&lt;/a&gt; recently surfaced from Amy I. Nicoll and &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s José Miguel Contreras. The pair recorded the 8-song set in their bedroom back in February of 2016 as part of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RPM_Challenge" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;RPM Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, bringing together a heady mix of tape loops and vocals with a limited slate of unconventional instruments (the record prominently features the marimba and celesta). The duo mixed the resulting record, titled &lt;em&gt;Special Problems&lt;/em&gt;, this past summer while burning away the quarantine hours. You can find it now on Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;José Contreras last released &lt;em&gt;At The Slaughterhouse&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://headlessowl.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Headless Owl&lt;/a&gt;. All three members of By Divine Right recently appeared with &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/Another-Blue-Door-Haulers/release/3524074" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Another Blue Door&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Dave Schoonderbeek on the &lt;a href="http://schoonderbeekwithbdr.bandcamp.com/album/let-it-beek" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let It Beek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; LP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='wide-media'&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ELC2zsPKtXQ" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ELC2zsPKtXQ" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: Leisure Palace - &amp;quot;The Assigned Problems&amp;quot; @ YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Cam Steacy&amp;#39;s low-fi post-punk outfit &lt;a href="http://organeyes.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Organ Eyes&lt;/a&gt; has a new 10-song full-length online titled &lt;em&gt;Like Glass&lt;/em&gt;. It includes the Ottawa artist&amp;#39;s recent single &amp;quot;Passed By,&amp;quot; and stands as the fourth record released by the project this year. Before the pandemic landed, Organ Eyes shared a full-length titled &lt;em&gt;Matinee Marmalade&lt;/em&gt;. Two rapidly assembled isolation-era LPs followed it, &lt;em&gt;Paintings in Concrete&lt;/em&gt; (assembled between March 18 to 23) and &lt;em&gt;Spirits on Acid&lt;/em&gt; (recorded and released between March 27 and April 15). You can find all the new Organ Eyes recordings at Bandcamp now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1558389403/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="http://organeyes.bandcamp.com/album/like-glass"&gt;Like Glass by Organ Eyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://organeyes.bandcamp.com/album/like-glass" class="black no-underline fw4 db tc f6 nt3 mb4" target="_blank"&gt;Listen: Organ Eyes - &amp;quot;Passed By&amp;quot; @ Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The high-concept, design-focused Montreal label &lt;a href="https://www.pentagon.black/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pentagon Black&lt;/a&gt; recently unveiled the fifth volume in their paper compilation series. &lt;em&gt;Pentagon Black Compilation No. 5&lt;/em&gt; is the third iteration of the project as a &amp;quot;phone comp,&amp;quot; with each participating act recording a new song directly to the mic of a smartphone. The label, run by Raymond Biesinger and Drew Demers of noise-punk duo &lt;a href="http://www.thefamines.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Famines&lt;/a&gt;, shared these thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pentagon Black Compilation No. 5&lt;/em&gt; is our third &amp;quot;phone comp&amp;quot; of truth in audio, this time with a local (aka Montreal-only) direction. It&amp;#39;s a 6x6&amp;quot; art postcard accompanied by 16 MP3 tracks recorded by telephone from March through June of 2020, and if you listen very closely you can hear diverse artists with either high-volume pre-lockdown mania, isolated quarantine loner expressions, or the jubilance that comes with the possibility of post-emergency liberation. The full early-COVID narrative is there, waiting for you to relive through audio hallucination. File under independent DIY punk, pop, experimental, bloops, bleeps, feeling and solitude. Printed in an edition of 500 in August of 2020.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This edition features Some Party favourites like &lt;a href="https://bbqtband.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BBQT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://barnaclemtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Barnacle&lt;/a&gt;, along with contributions from &lt;a href="https://tamayuge.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Tamayugé&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://childactress.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Child Actress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://instagram.com/lovelanguageband" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Love Language&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://dressermtl.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dresser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://agathapale.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Agatha Pale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://ylangylangylang.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;YlangYlang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://beeptest.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beep Test&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://thankgoodnessitsladiesnight.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ladies Night&lt;/a&gt;, Charles Harding, &lt;a href="https://stereonoaware.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sunforger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://alsoalsoalso.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Also Also Also&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chrishauermusic.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Hauer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://inhock.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Jules Nominal&lt;/a&gt;, and No. Deux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can snag a physical copy of the postcard from the &lt;a href="https://www.pentagon.black/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pentagon Black&lt;/a&gt; store for two bucks plus shipping. With each new edition in this series, I&amp;#39;m more convinced that The Famines are providing an essential and unparalleled service in chronicling the modern rock underground in this country — an absolute inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
