<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>Some Party is a newsletter sharing the latest in independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated by Adam White. Each edition explores punk, garage, psych, and otherwise uncategorizable indie rock, drawing lines from proto to post and taking some weird diversions along the way.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2025-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Middle of Summer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-12-14-middle-of-summer/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-12-14-middle-of-summer/</id>
    <published>2025-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-14T21:43:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="pony"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ponytheband.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PONY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clearly Cursed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://ponyband.bandcamp.com/album/clearly-cursed" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early Punknews days, high on our misbegotten authority, I used to make laughable assertions like: &amp;quot;I have no idea what the kids actually like, but if there was any justice in the universe this-or-that band would be huge.&amp;quot; We were, in retrospect, far too young to be feigning such ignorance, but this was useful bullshit. It painted my lackadaisical disengagement with mainstream culture as a virtue rather than a blind spot. I&amp;#39;m in my forties now, and quite justifiably out of touch, so I feel entirely comfortable reclaiming that sentiment at face value. So let me say: &lt;a href="https://ponytheband.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PONY&lt;/a&gt; is a magical band - pure confection - and the fact that they&amp;#39;re not absolutely massive is an aberration of cosmic proportions, and one for which I shall not stand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now my family typically doesn&amp;#39;t factor into these write-ups. They never agreed to live as Cancon ascetics, and I&amp;#39;d not force that life on anyone. But in the truck, my truck, they&amp;#39;re stuck with me and my radio. The other day, my otherwise K-pop-obsessed teenager threw some rare feedback as she left for school, proclaiming, &amp;quot;you usually just listen to the Ramones or loud stuff but I really like that PONY band you keep playing.&amp;quot; Youth approval! We&amp;#39;ve therefore externally validated the parallel truths that while I am indeed aging into irrelevance, I&amp;#39;m also 100% right about PONY.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Toronto band returns this February with &lt;em&gt;Clearly Cursed&lt;/em&gt;, a ten-song set of bubblegum grunge-pop that promises shimmering hooks and Sam Bielanski&amp;#39;s effortlessly euphoric vocals. In a statement, the singer-songwriter revealed the record&amp;#39;s origins in a portentous psychic reading:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;She read my tarot cards and told me boyfriend was cheating on me. That was true. She also told me that I had a dark spirit attachment which she could easily vanquish if I paid her $1500. That was obviously out of my budget so I left and decided I would have to coexist with this dark spirit for the rest of my life.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clearly Cursed&lt;/em&gt; finds Bielanski and partner/guitarist Matty Morand (&lt;a href="https://prettymatty.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pretty Matty&lt;/a&gt;) joined by their touring collaborators Christian Beale (This is Hell, Iron Chic) on bass and Joey Ginaldi (Webbed Wing) on drums. Iron Chic&amp;#39;s Dan Leo, who drummed for PONY on their previous go-around, appears as well. The group again worked with producer Alex Gamble (Fucked Up, Alvvays) - reviving the studio team that crafted 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Velveteen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can hear four tracks from the record today, three of which surfaced as stand-alone singles over the past few years. The album opens with the familiar favourites &amp;quot;Superglue&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Freezer&amp;quot;, with 2024&amp;#39;s earworm &amp;quot;Every Little Crumb&amp;quot; sequenced in the penultimate slot. Those songs are available alongside the newly unveiled &amp;quot;Middle Of Summer.&amp;quot; &lt;em&gt;Clearly Cursed&lt;/em&gt; arrives February 13 through &lt;a href="http://www.takethistoheartrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Take This To Heart Records&lt;/a&gt;, supported by a late-February East Coast tour with Californian pop-punk act Star 99.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2260428129/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ponyband.bandcamp.com/album/clearly-cursed"&gt;Clearly Cursed by PONY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="g_a_mksimoon"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gamksimoon.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;G̱a̱mksimoon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Huk Aat&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;G̱a̱woo Üüla&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://gamksimoon.bandcamp.com/album/huk-aat-g-a-woo-la" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; recently issued the debut 7-inch single from &lt;a href="https://gamksimoon.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;G̱a̱mksimoon&lt;/a&gt;, a riff-heavy rock trio from Prince Rupert, British Columbia. The group sings entirely in the Sm&amp;#39;algya̱x language of the Ts&amp;#39;msyen people, which pairs perfectly with a backdrop of 70s-indebted guitar heroism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The set features &amp;quot;Huk Aat&amp;quot; on the a-side backed by &amp;quot;G̱a̱woo Üüla,&amp;quot; tracks that draw lyrically on north coast Indigenous tradition and pre-contact ways of life. Band lead Wil Uks Batsga G̱a̱laaw (aka Jeremy Pahl), explained the hunting practices expressed on the b-side:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This song is about the protocols Ts&amp;#39;msyen seal hunters have been passing down forever. I&amp;#39;m lucky enough to have learned about this from my uncles. A long time ago our people communicated with the seal people and made this protocol. The song lyrics themselves are pretty self explanatory. I hunt seals in this way today. It&amp;#39;s a great nutritious and delicious food. I like to render the fat into oil to use for frying fish or mixing with berries as a dessert.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The three-piece features Pahl on vocals and guitar, Isaac Story on bass, and Danny Bell on drums. They recorded with John Rahm at Afterlife Studios in Vancouver, with Connor Pritchard mixing at Pulp City in Prince George.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;G̱a̱mksimoon is an evolution of a project formerly known as &lt;a href="https://saltwaterhank.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Saltwater Hank&lt;/a&gt;. The group issued their final full-length under that name, &lt;em&gt;Siip&amp;#39;nsk&lt;/em&gt;, in 2024, supported by a performance at Sappyfest in Sackville, New Brunswick that summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Pahl&amp;#39;s a member of the Gitga&amp;#39;at First Nation, hailing from the isolated Hartley Bay community (Txałgiiw) about 145 kilometres south of Prince Rupert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=337726317/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gamksimoon.bandcamp.com/album/huk-aat-g-a-woo-la"&gt;Huk Aat / G̱a̱woo Üüla by G̱a̱mksimoon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="american_lips"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;American Lips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Strike!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Cardboard Trash&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ExPgIAfQBQE?si=xTxGTBSWdRE9JRca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com/album/on-strike" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal/Los Angeles trio &lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;American Lips&lt;/a&gt; recently returned with &lt;em&gt;On Strike!&lt;/em&gt;, a playful and often sardonic full-length that tears down the excess and absurdity of late capitalism. The record accelerates the band&amp;#39;s angular art-punk attack, delivering 10 statements perched atop the jittery shoulders of Devo and The Fall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guitarist/vocalist Adrian Popovich of garage legends &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/trickywoomtl/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tricky Woo&lt;/a&gt; fronts the trio alongside  &lt;a href="http://www.deathfromabove1979.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Death From Above 1979&lt;/a&gt; drummer Sebastien Grainger and bassist/vocalist Jessica Bruzzese. In a statement carried by &lt;a href="https://newnoisemagazine.com/news-american-lips-return-with-angular-art-punk-lp-on-strike/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;New Noise&lt;/a&gt;, Grainger shared some thoughts on the album, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Musically, this record is tight and boxy, like an engine made of wood and elastic bands trying to play pop songs. Lyrically it speaks to this intergenerational sense that we are all alienated, yet how can this be? If we all have the same feelings of &amp;#39;otherness&amp;#39; shouldn&amp;#39;t that make us closer? More able to relate to one another? Strangely no. So this record is at once a warm hug and punch in the neck.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see the single &amp;quot;Cardboard Trash,&amp;quot; celebrated in a video assembled from walkthrough footage of the 1989 graphic adventure game &lt;em&gt;Space Quest III: The Pirates Of Pestulon&lt;/em&gt;. The band commented, &amp;quot;We all played Sierra games as kids and it means a great deal to us to have been able to pay tribute in this way.&amp;quot; The retro digital aesthetic suits the band&amp;#39;s quirky sensibilities perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Popovich remains prolific as a producer in Montreal&amp;#39;s indie rock scene and plays these days as part of the space-punk aggressors &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/_frvits_/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;FRVITS&lt;/a&gt;. American Lips last issued the maxi-single &lt;em&gt;Waste of Crime / Labor of Hate&lt;/em&gt; in 2022, following up on their 2017 debut &lt;em&gt;Kiss the Void&lt;/em&gt;. The new album&amp;#39;s available through &lt;a href="https://ancientfashionrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ancient Fashion Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3393522859/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com/album/on-strike"&gt;On Strike! by American Lips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="our_sins"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://oursins519.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Our Sins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Sea of Nude Limbs Thrashing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://oursins519.bandcamp.com/album/a-sea-of-nude-limbs-thrashing" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;London, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://oursins519.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Our Sins&lt;/a&gt; emerged on Halloween with their debut LP &lt;em&gt;A Sea of Nude Limbs Thrashing&lt;/em&gt;. The group, which features familiar faces from southern Ontario&amp;#39;s punk scene, delivers a diverse slate of songs that hopscotch nostalgically between subgenres, shifting from emo and pop-punk to post-hardcore and 90s radio rock - a love affair with the collective&amp;#39;s 90s-rooted influences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band wrote and recorded across two weekends, two years apart, in the respective falls of 2022 and 2024, with lyrics by the songwriting duo of Danny Kidd and Ivan Rivers. Kidd sings and plays guitar these days in &lt;a href="https://prowrestlingtheband.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Wrestling the Band&lt;/a&gt; and boasts a lengthy resume that includes &lt;a href="https://neverbetters.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Never Betters&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Drew Thomson Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://wastedpotential.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Wasted Potential&lt;/a&gt;. Rivers is best known for his time in the punk outfit &lt;a href="https://stuckouthere.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Stuck Out Here&lt;/a&gt; and maintains an eponymous solo career as a self-described &lt;a href="https://ivanrivers.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;celebrated folk icon&lt;/a&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s rounded out by drummer Joel Siggelkow (&lt;a href="https://twinband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Twin&lt;/a&gt;) and bassist Dustin Andrews (Wasted Potential, &lt;a href="https://snacksareawesome.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Snacks?&lt;/a&gt;). Andrews recorded, produced, and mixed the material from his basement studio, with Daggermouth&amp;#39;s Stu McKillop mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel bad that I&amp;#39;ve sat on this one for so long, particularly since Rivers reached out to me with such enthusiasm. If he&amp;#39;ll forgive the privacy breach, here&amp;#39;s a snippet of his pitch that illustrates just that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#39;re so stoked about this thing. It started as a lark and a way to hone D.A.&amp;#39;s burgeoning production chops in his new home studio, but we ended up making 9 killer wild dramatic ridiculous songs about like, killing god and burnt-world romance and fed them through a lifetime of collected alt &amp;amp; scene influences, like Maxell CDRcore. We call it &amp;#39;forest city god-fearing music&amp;#39; and it&amp;#39;s a damn blast.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album arrived as a joint release through Rivers&amp;#39; Eternal Bummer label and Andrews&amp;#39; &lt;a href="https://getparty.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Get Party! Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can dig more into the band&amp;#39;s deep London scene connections in a feature by Em Moore at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/87080/interviews-talking-a-sea-of-nude-limbs-thrashing-with-ivan-rivers-of-our-sins" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2905050803/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://oursins519.bandcamp.com/album/a-sea-of-nude-limbs-thrashing"&gt;A Sea of Nude Limbs Thrashing by Our Sins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="parisian_orgy"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://parisianorgy.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Parisian Orgy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parisian Orgy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/parisian-orgy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lo-fi art-punk of Calgary&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://parisianorgy.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Parisian Orgy&lt;/a&gt; feels decidedly distinct - it&amp;#39;s provocateur pop, raw and unpredictable, both immediate and danceable yet somehow vaguely threatening. &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste Records&lt;/a&gt; recently served up the band&amp;#39;s debut LP, a self-titled set that collects eight originals plus a cover of the French new wave group Tokow Boys. These songs have percolated for years, some of which first surfaced back in 2019 on the &lt;em&gt;Come Pretty Pump Sleep&lt;/em&gt; EP. This is the first time the band&amp;#39;s collected any of its material on wax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Multi-disciplinary artist Gwen Morgan fronts the project, leading a collective of local players who&amp;#39;ve built a thrillingly disorienting, sonically asymmetrical series of tunes on a bass-and-drum foundation. The label references the New Wave exotica sound and cult favourites like Inflatable Boy Clams and Sara Goes Pop. Fans of Toronto&amp;#39;s Luge will find familiar ground here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded at Pee Blood Studios, with Orchid&amp;#39;s Will Killingsworth mixing and mastering at Dead Air Studios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2939969729/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/parisian-orgy"&gt;Parisian Orgy by Parisian Orgy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_wesleys"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewesleys.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Wesleys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explosive Device&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://thewesleys.bandcamp.com/album/explosive-device" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month Montreal quartet &lt;a href="https://thewesleys.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Wesleys&lt;/a&gt; issued &lt;em&gt;Explosive Device&lt;/em&gt;, a four-song EP that finds the garage-pop unit shuffling the deck, both in regards to their songwriting and lead vocalists. The set finds guitarist Henry Girard, bassist Quentin Chisholm, and drummer Pablo Garcia-Rejon Gaubeca (&lt;a href="https://jyraph.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jyraph&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://raindogband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Raindog&lt;/a&gt;) each taking turns at the mic, supported by William D&amp;#39;Amours on guitar and mellotron. The tunes vary from hooky power-pop to fuzzy psych-rock, all delivered with a sharp garage edge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On vinyl, the new songs come paired with the entirety of The Wesleys&amp;#39;s 2022 debut &lt;em&gt;Outside Voices&lt;/em&gt;, the first physical release for those tracks. The group recorded with Scott &amp;#39;Monty&amp;#39; Munro (&lt;a href="https://preoccs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Preoccupations&lt;/a&gt;) in Montreal, with the aforementioned Adrian Popovich (Tricky Woo, &lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;American Lips&lt;/a&gt;) handling the mix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explosive Device&lt;/em&gt; follows up on The Wesley&amp;#39;s self-titled LP, issued last spring. You can find it in Canada via &lt;a href="https://www.petitvillagerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Petit Village Records&lt;/a&gt; or internationally through Spain&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.meritoriorec.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Meritorio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=279584866/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewesleys.bandcamp.com/album/explosive-device"&gt;Explosive Device by The Wesleys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="low_blow"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/money-fetish" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Low Blow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money Fetish&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/money-fetish" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calgary hardcore act &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/money-fetish" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Low Blow&lt;/a&gt; sounds slavishly devoted to the classic American hardcore sound, which isn&amp;#39;t in and of itself all that uncommon, except for the fact that it&amp;#39;s the product of a bunch of 18-year-olds. These aren&amp;#39;t some aging lifers on a quest to recapture past glories, but the genuine fire of youth. &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste&lt;/a&gt; likens their sound to Rollins&amp;#39; early DC group State of Alert and Touch and Go pioneers The Fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The four-song &lt;em&gt;Money Fetish&lt;/em&gt; demo crashes by with abandon - completely unrefined and intently so. The label has a limited run of 100 home-dubbed tapes available, complete with xeroxed J-cards. It&amp;#39;s the classic no-budget DIY aesthetic, and probably the truth. Nothing else would be appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1270830601/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/money-fetish"&gt;Money Fetish by Low Blow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amaro</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-11-10-amaro/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-11-10-amaro/</id>
    <published>2025-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-10T19:19:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="bibi_club"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bibiclub.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bibi Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Amaro&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Ip7dwQ2rphA?si=35Hxlb5byXz5m-bh" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://bibiclub.bandcamp.com/track/amaro-2" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given that it ended up on the &lt;a href="https://polarismusicprize.ca/album-prize/short-list/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Short List&lt;/a&gt; this year, I became pretty familiar with &lt;em&gt;Feu de garde&lt;/em&gt;, the 2024 record from Montreal avant-pop duo &lt;a href="https://bibiclub.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bibi Club&lt;/a&gt;. I came to rely on it as a headphone record, and one that, despite the language barrier, felt intimate—a glimpse into the private musical world of its married principles, never overly precious but clearly the product of a shared headspace. Reviewers often cited Stereolab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I saw on stage at the Polaris Gala felt like something else entirely. The band performed &amp;quot;Le Feu&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Shloshlo&amp;quot; with abandon, stomping through the tracks with an aggression I never perceived on the recordings, leaning into their off-kilter qualities with the volume cranked. Post-apocalyptic wasn&amp;#39;t the vibe on record, but you could feel it in person. It was utterly compelling. I&amp;#39;m not sure if it comes across in the CBC&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/kzeek71navw?si=vMWMmiJjSgw7hE0Q" class="" target="_blank"&gt;recording&lt;/a&gt;, but I walked out of Massey infatuated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band is capitalizing on both the critical momentum and that stylistic twist with the announcement of &lt;em&gt;Amaro&lt;/em&gt;, their third album due early next year through &lt;a href="https://www.secretcityrecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Secret City Records&lt;/a&gt;. The record&amp;#39;s first single is in line with that Polaris performance, re-casting Bibi Club as a darkwave duo, set to a thumping, club-ready beat. The label&amp;#39;s announcement is evocative, painting the title track and the record it heralds in epic language:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;On their third album, Amaro, Bibi Club invites us to brave the dark beasts that shadow us beneath the surface, and to devote ourselves to the healing power of a fierce will to live. It explores the liminal spectrum between the here and beyond, pointing to love, nature, and community as the unifying purpose. The songs draw a map of a world of its own, following the trajectory traced by the Bibis in recent years. Now out of the living room, we dance in a mental space overloaded with grief and fear in their rawest forms. Following the death of two loved ones in the last year, the mantra &amp;#39;I want to love, I want to live&amp;#39; resonates intensely in each melody; if the heart is a place that never dies, we must reach it as quickly as possible.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vocalist/keyboardist Adèle Trottier-Rivard and guitarist Nicolas Basque (&lt;a href="https://plantsandanimals.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plants and Animals&lt;/a&gt;) recorded the new LP with contributions from singer-songwriter &lt;a href="https://helenadeland.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Helena Deland&lt;/a&gt; and saxophonist &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/dimiandydada/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dimitri Milbrun&lt;/a&gt;. The band self-produced the record, with Seth Manchester (METZ, Tunic) mixing. Look for the 11-song full-length in stores on February 27.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2218505044/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bibiclub.bandcamp.com/track/amaro-2"&gt;Amaro by Bibi Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="leanne_betasamosake_simpson"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://leannesimpson.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Leanne Betasamosake Simpson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live Like The Sky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;White Kites and Sky Blue&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xhN_EgrudN8?si=PxWiKtVIK0I84v5-" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://leannesimpson.bandcamp.com/album/live-like-the-sky" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to frontload a discussion of &lt;a href="https://leannesimpson.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Leanne Betasamosake Simpson&lt;/a&gt; with her culture and  credentials, but that feels like a disservice to the medium. Context is essential, but leaning on it projects a sense of academic sterility that&amp;#39;s very much at odds with &lt;em&gt;Live Like The Sky&lt;/em&gt;; it implies a prerequisite self-seriousness that supersedes the gut-level engagement music demands. So yes, the new album indeed boasts the intellectual depth its creator&amp;#39;s known for, but it&amp;#39;s also pretty fucking fun. The record genre-hops nimbly from dream pop to goth to cerebral new wave, finding common ground in 80s post-punk and what became indie rock. It&amp;#39;s easily Simpson&amp;#39;s most accessible work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a discussion with &lt;a href="http://theconstantines.wordpress.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Constantines&lt;/a&gt; guitarist &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt;, who co-wrote the track &amp;quot;85 Dollars an Acre,&amp;quot; Simpson delved into the dichotomy between the album&amp;#39;s sound and its message:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...I think that pairing serious lyrics about serious issues with music that doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily reflect or amplify that, and that provides kind of a counterpoint, for me that opens up an interstitial space between the aesthetics of the music and the aesthetics of the poetry or the lyrics that is an opportunity to layer more meaning. And so, I think a lot of times that the fun music or the music about Indigenous joy can pick up the energy of resistance to whatever the struggle is. We need joy in this moment. Joy fuels movements.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album finds Simpson working with a host of familiar faces, including &lt;a href="https://www.ansleysimpson.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ansley Simpson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://nickferrio.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Ferrio&lt;/a&gt;, Jonas Bonnetta of &lt;a href="https://eveninghymns.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Evening Hymns&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://boyhoodsongs.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Boyhood&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Caylie Runciman, and Tanner Paré. Bonnetta produced at Port William Sound, with &lt;a href="https://www.holyfuckmusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Holy Fuck&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Graham Walsh mixing. You can see the album&amp;#39;s opening track, &amp;quot;White Kites and Sky Blue,&amp;quot; showcased in a video by Rana Nazzal Hamadeh. Simpson describes that track as &amp;quot;a reluctant protest song naming and narrating our shared present - one of live streamed genocide, climate collapse and fascism.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simpson&amp;#39;s an acclaimed scholar and writer of the Michi Saagiig Nishnaabeg, descendants of the ancient peoples who inhabited southern Ontario as far back as the Archaic and Paleo-Indian periods. She last released &lt;em&gt;Theory of Ice&lt;/em&gt; in 2021, which critics shortlisted for the  Polaris Music Prize. &lt;em&gt;Live Like The Sky&lt;/em&gt;, featuring 11 new songs, is available through &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simpson&amp;#39;s on the road this month supporting the record, with shows upcoming in Ottawa, Montreal, Hamilton, Guelph, and Toronto. All dates feature Boyhood, with &lt;a href="http://www.zoongideewin.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Zoon&lt;/a&gt; joining in Hamilton, Guelph, and Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2797932191/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://leannesimpson.bandcamp.com/album/live-like-the-sky"&gt;Live Like The Sky by Leanne Betasamosake Simpson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="guv"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://guvofficial.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;GUV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Let Your Hands Go&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/HusHXboN2QY?si=rmwXFOrWniUbfG2n" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://guvofficial.bandcamp.com/album/warmer-than-gold" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young no longer, Ben Cook&amp;#39;s solo vehicle &lt;a href="https://guvofficial.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;GUV&lt;/a&gt;, is set to return with &lt;em&gt;Warmer than Gold&lt;/em&gt;, a new 12-song LP due January 30 through &lt;a href="https://runforcoverrecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Run For Cover Records&lt;/a&gt;. The news arrived alongside &amp;quot;Let Your Hands Go,&amp;quot; a song that underlays the artist&amp;#39;s proven mastery of jangle-pop with some compelling shoegaze haze. Keeping with his recent records, Cook remains immersed in Britpop, but that influence never feels overly derivative or mined for nostalgia. Directors Fred Joseph and Andrew Pitrone showcase the single in a kaleidoscopic new video, visualizing its hypnotic momentum through shifting geometric patterns and oversaturated colours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warmer than Gold&lt;/em&gt; marks a fresh chapter for the project, now rebranded from Young Guv. Cook addressed the change in his stage name, joking, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m not so young anymore, three letter band names are cool, and I&amp;#39;m tired of being mistaken as a rapper.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Performers on the record include Cook&amp;#39;s longtime collaborator &lt;a href="https://jamesmatthewvii.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;James Matthew VII&lt;/a&gt;, Australian artists Darcy Baylis and Hatchie, and Meg Mills of the world conquering Turnstile. In a press release, Cook reflected on the personal journey that led to the new album:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ve tried to open up to the world and let it speak back to me. Slowly, I&amp;#39;ve been rediscovering myself, and now gratefully back to releasing music. In the end, I&amp;#39;ve been searching for ways to bring the fleeting into focus, to make the invisible parts of myself real, hoping they might connect with something greater. &lt;em&gt;Warmer Than Gold&lt;/em&gt; is another step in that journey of rediscovery.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows 2024&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;GUV III&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GUV IV&lt;/em&gt;, the concluding half of a pandemic-era album cycle that found the artist transcending the quirky synthpop of their earlier efforts. When not dabbling on the lighter side of the spectrum, Cook&amp;#39;s known as the frontman of Toronto  bruisers &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/nowarning666" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Warning&lt;/a&gt; and formerly played as a guitarist in the hardcore titans &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=390002453/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://guvofficial.bandcamp.com/album/warmer-than-gold"&gt;Warmer Than Gold by GUV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="papal_visit"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://papalvisit.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Papal Visit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Capsize Party&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://papalvisit.bandcamp.com/album/the-capsize-party" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lo-fi east coast rockers &lt;a href="http://papalvisit.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Papal Visit&lt;/a&gt; are back with &lt;em&gt;The Capsize Party&lt;/em&gt;, their fourth full-length and first since 2021&amp;#39;s sprawling &lt;em&gt;Five Fathom Hole&lt;/em&gt;. Available now through &lt;a href="https://monopolizedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monopolized Records&lt;/a&gt;, the new album finds the New Brunswick quintet trending towards a darker, heavier sound, captured with a raw edge that befits their garage origins. The band convened over four years at various studios to record these songs, primarily to four-track cassette. Cory Bonnevie mastered their noisy results at Monopolized&amp;#39;s studio in Saint John.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I suspect they&amp;#39;ll forever worship at the altar of Guided By Voices, &lt;em&gt;The Capsize Party&lt;/em&gt; finds Papal Visit taking a few compelling detours into straight-ahead punk rock (&amp;quot;Love By the Numbers&amp;quot;), psychedelic folk (&amp;quot;Ringin&amp;#39; In&amp;quot;), and even sludgy stoner rock (&amp;quot;Weird System&amp;quot;). The band even takes a rare francophone turn on the simmering post-punk tune, &amp;quot;Angry Young Computer.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Papal Visit features the distinctive warble of vocalist &lt;a href="https://itsadammowery.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Mowery&lt;/a&gt;, backed by Pierre Cormier on bass, Chris Braydon and &lt;a href="https://pennyblacks.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Penny Blacks&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; &lt;a href="https://jasonogden.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jason Ogden&lt;/a&gt; on guitars, and Geoffrey Smith drumming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2895461483/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://papalvisit.bandcamp.com/album/the-capsize-party"&gt;The Capsize Party by PAPAL VISIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="plastic_war"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://plasticwar.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Cold Air Experiment&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://plasticwar.bandcamp.com/track/cold-air-experiment" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s not all from Jason Ogden, as the &lt;a href="https://pennyblacks.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Penny Blacks&lt;/a&gt; principal recently shared a new one-off single as part of the Toronto-based three-piece &lt;a href="https://plasticwar.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic War&lt;/a&gt;. The occasionally active band resurfaced this fall with &amp;quot;Cold Air Experiment,&amp;quot; a moody post-punk cut that builds deliberately over five and a half minutes, finding a groove amidst the slow-burning tension.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plastic War features Ogden with Blair Phillips (Halo, Born Under Satellites) and Alex Teixeira (&lt;a href="https://zerobars.bandcamp.com/album/life-and-hell" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Zero Bars&lt;/a&gt;, The Steady State). The band recorded at The Rehearsal Factory in Toronto. &amp;quot;Cold Air Experiment&amp;quot; is the band&amp;#39;s first new material since their self-titled 2016 EP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=610877735/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://plasticwar.bandcamp.com/track/cold-air-experiment"&gt;Cold Air Experiment by Plastic War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="deposed"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thedeposed.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Deposed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Downhill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://thedeposed.bandcamp.com/album/downhill" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drummerless Toronto &amp;quot;punk impostors&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://thedeposed.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Deposed&lt;/a&gt; resurfaced in September with &lt;em&gt;Downhill&lt;/em&gt;, their third digital single and the follow-up to last year&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Dumb it Down&lt;/em&gt;. The title track takes its inspiration from graffiti scrawled on the rehearsal room wall at Toronto&amp;#39;s Houndstooth bar: &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s all downhill from here.&amp;quot; Paul Kelly shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s about the big rip-off, you know, the big, cosmic, existential one. Or maybe it&amp;#39;s about retirement planning (we&amp;#39;re getting up there). I think it sounds a bit like Wire (conceptual overall structure, chorus like their &amp;#39;Heartbeat&amp;#39;) but a friend tells me it&amp;#39;s just a &amp;#39;Born in the USA&amp;#39; rip-off.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The A-side is backed by the sardonic &amp;quot;E to C (Post-punk school),&amp;quot; which I couldn&amp;#39;t let stand without demanding an explanation. Paul, thankfully, obliged:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;On the surface, E2C sounds like an old man who lived through the original post-punk era scolding the young, but it&amp;#39;s really about bands that aim at pastiche rather than the all-important (and genre-transcending) RIFFS. It also has some jabs at the Canadian music industry. Many, many great post-punk songs were based on that minor 6th interval: &amp;#39;Villiers Terrace&amp;#39; by Echo and the Bunnymen, &amp;#39;M&amp;#39; by The Cure, &amp;#39;Here Today&amp;#39; by The Chameleons, &amp;#39;Third Uncle&amp;#39; by Bauhaus (OK, by Eno, but you get the point).&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The song features an interlude that references &amp;quot;A Matter of Gender&amp;quot; by Scottish band The Associates, with Kelly attempting to mimic their vocalist, Billy McKenzie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deposed features Paul Downes and Paul Kelly. The pair recorded with &lt;a href="https://colmhinds.format.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Colm Hinds&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://lammping.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lammping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://rosseau.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rosseau&lt;/a&gt;) at Dining Room Sound. He plays piano on the title track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=473094655/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thedeposed.bandcamp.com/album/downhill"&gt;Downhill by Deposed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="rec_centre"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://reccentre.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rec Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Squash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Polly and Andy&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aRiSH-OEuSQ" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://reccentre.bandcamp.com/album/squash" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month, Alex Hudson&amp;#39;s Toronto-based indie pop project &lt;a href="https://reccentre.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rec Centre&lt;/a&gt; issued &lt;em&gt;Squash&lt;/em&gt;, an 11-song set of home-recorded, synth-driven tunes. The album kicks off with &amp;quot;Polly and Andy,&amp;quot; a track that contemplates &amp;quot;the strange paradox of seeing people every day but knowing almost nothing about their lives.&amp;quot; You can see it in a video, shot with early-2000s point-and-shoot digital cameras, that follows the artist to their local convenience store (run by the titular couple). The song exemplifies the record&amp;#39;s warm sound and refreshingly small-stakes observations, set against &amp;quot;a backdrop of buzzy synth bass and the blissed out jangle of circa-2009 blog rock.&amp;quot; You can find a similar visual aesthetic at work in the video for &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SpK0-m_Wn1Y?si=k6opa8IC3pQ7khGf" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Undying&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a direction that feels well-suited to Hudson&amp;#39;s longtime collaborator &lt;a href="https://jayarner.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jay Arner&lt;/a&gt;. The pair have a longstanding creative partnership, with Hudson playing bass in Arner&amp;#39;s namesake outlet before relocating to Toronto in 2017. Arner serves as producer on &lt;em&gt;Squash&lt;/em&gt; and contributes instrumentally on several tracks (proceeds from the album&amp;#39;s Bandcamp sales are going to Arner&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-jay-arner-cover-transition-costs" class="" target="_blank"&gt;transition fundraiser&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href="https://www.shoutoutoutoutout.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Shout Out Out Out&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Nik Kozub mastered the new set in Edmonton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new songs follow up on 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Maxxed Out&lt;/em&gt;, which saw Rec Centre swerving towards straightforward garage rock. &lt;em&gt;Squash&lt;/em&gt; loosely clocks in as the sixth proper full-length from the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=625791820/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://reccentre.bandcamp.com/album/squash"&gt;Squash by Rec Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Long Ago Gardens</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-10-24-long-ago-gardens/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-10-24-long-ago-gardens/</id>
    <published>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-24T22:20:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="fucked_up"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Long Ago Gardens&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/grass-can-move-stones-part-1-year-of-the-goat" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I wrote about &lt;em&gt;Year of the Horse&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2021-02-07-year-of-the-horse/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;back in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, I referred to the Zodiac series as a parallel but separate through-line in &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s unlikely career. It&amp;#39;s an avenue for the band to indulge in every maximalist, over-the-top impulse that strikes them, unincumbered by both the critical expectations saddling their proper LPs and the physical constraints of their innumerable singles. As an &amp;quot;album band,&amp;quot; Fucked Up&amp;#39;s wrestled, quite overtly, with the strong personalities penning their songs and their oft-competing proclivity for both cut-to-the-bone hardcore and audacious genre-hopping. A new Fucked Up LP always gives fans a chance to re-evaluate the state of that tension, spurring the latest tedious round of armchair psychiatry (of which I&amp;#39;m certainly guilty). The Zodiac series floats in above this, unincumbered by the pressure that dogs the Toronto act&amp;#39;s mainline full-lengths. It so intently leans into the popular caricature of this band (love it or hate it) that it feels beyond criticism. The plot of these grandiose fantasies manages to supersede our tiresome focus on the band&amp;#39;s meta-narrative, and I&amp;#39;m sure they don&amp;#39;t mind in the least.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the inherently calendrical nature of this whole exercise, Zodiac volumes surface seemingly at random. There was always a decent chance the band would fuck off before crossing the finish line. Perhaps with an eye to their own shelf life, but perhaps in recognition that it&amp;#39;s been 20 damn years since &lt;em&gt;Year of The Dog&lt;/em&gt;, the goal&amp;#39;s now in sight. Zodiac will conclude between now and the fall of 2026 with its final three volumes released under the umbrella title of &lt;em&gt;Grass Can Move Stones&lt;/em&gt;. The three-album, 10-sided final push starts this December with &lt;em&gt;Year of The Goat&lt;/em&gt;, arriving December 5 on &lt;a href="http://www.tankcrimes.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tankcrimes Records&lt;/a&gt;. Look for &lt;em&gt;Year of The Monkey&lt;/em&gt; in the spring and &lt;em&gt;Year of The Rooster&lt;/em&gt; to wrap it up next autumn. That&amp;#39;s nearly five hours of new music, some of which recontextualizes selections from the previous nine entries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overarching narrative of &lt;em&gt;Grass Can Move Stones&lt;/em&gt; loosely adapts &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journey_to_the_West" class="" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journey to the West&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a 16th-century Ming dynasty novel. You can hear the half-hour opening salvo, &amp;quot;Long Ago Gardens,&amp;quot; at Bandcamp now. It features vocals from Fucked Up regulars Damian Abraham, Jonah Falco, and Mike Haliechuk and guest spots by Tuka Mohammed, Tamara Lindeman (&lt;a href="https://www.theweatherstation.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Weather Station&lt;/a&gt;), and Dwid Hellion of Cleveland hardcore legends &lt;a href="https://integrity.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Integrity&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://jennifercastle.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jennifer Castle&lt;/a&gt; contributes to the record&amp;#39;s B-side, &amp;quot;Rivers and Lakes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded this material over five years in multiple Toronto studios, helmed by engineer Alex Gamble. You can follow along with the first track in a lavishly designed libretto-styled PDF at the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.fuckedup.cc/year-of-the-goat-side-a-long-ago-gardens.pdf" class="" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fucked Up&amp;#39;s current lineup features vocalist Damian Abraham, guitarists Mike Haliechuk and Josh Zucker, bassist Sandy Miranda, and drummer Jonah Falco. The new material arrives four and a half years from the previous Zodiac entry, 2020&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Year of The Horse&lt;/em&gt;. A nonexhaustive list of the band&amp;#39;s material since then includes the recent Sub Pop single. &lt;em&gt;Disabuse&lt;/em&gt;, and a string of thematically linked full-lengths: &lt;em&gt;Someday&lt;/em&gt; (2024), &lt;em&gt;Another Day&lt;/em&gt; (2024), and &lt;em&gt;One Day&lt;/em&gt; (2023).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2750451805/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/grass-can-move-stones-part-1-year-of-the-goat"&gt;Grass Can Move Stones Part 1: Year of The Goat by Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="tv_freaks"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blue Genie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/album/blue-genie" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; 2020 LP &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt; is one of my favourite records, and it&amp;#39;s clear from the title track of &lt;em&gt;Blue Genie&lt;/em&gt; that they&amp;#39;re sticking to the trajectory I connected with. While the forthcoming record&amp;#39;s out in full next week, the band has the title track(s) available to preview now as a two-part digital single. &amp;quot;Blue Genie&amp;quot; parts one and two relish in the psychedelic sprawl that&amp;#39;s become more prominent in TV Freaks&amp;#39; sound. Although separated by six songs on the full-length, the two halves of &amp;quot;Blue Geanie&amp;quot; combine here into nearly 12 minutes of hypnotic rock. The band&amp;#39;s locked in, boasting an unhurried, blissful swagger; the comfort of years in each other&amp;#39;s heads. Sweet Dave&amp;#39;s vocal journey from unhinged garage yelper to Damned-style crooner feels entirely natural. &lt;em&gt;Blue Geanie&lt;/em&gt; is TV Freaks by way of The Feelies, jamming over long grooves you&amp;#39;ll be happy to get lost in (not dissimilar to songs I adore by Tough Age and The Courneys, come to think of it - I may have a type).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album again features David O&amp;#39;Connor, backed by guitarist TJ Charlton, bassist Vee Bell, and drummer Nathan Burger. The quartet recorded in 2023 and 2024 at O&amp;#39;Connor&amp;#39;s home studio over a bed of drum tracks Burger laid down at Hamilton&amp;#39;s Boxcar Studio with Sean Pearson. Dave&amp;#39;s vocals later tied everything together in a session with &lt;a href="https://zdeadtiredz.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dead Tired&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Marco Bressette at Deadquarters. Eddy Current Suppression Ring&amp;#39;s Mikey Young mixed the set from their home base in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nine-song &lt;em&gt;Blue Genie&lt;/em&gt; is the band&amp;#39;s fifth full-length since 2011. It follows &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;, issued through &lt;a href="https://schizophrenicrex.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Schizophrenic Records&lt;/a&gt; in 2020. Shortly after that release, O&amp;#39;Connor issued the &lt;em&gt;Now More Than Ever&lt;/em&gt; LP in his &lt;a href="https://sweetdave.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sweet Dave&lt;/a&gt; solo persona, while Charlton and Burger recorded as two-thirds of the punk trio &lt;a href="https://anxiouspleasers.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Anxious Pleasers&lt;/a&gt; with Matt Ellis. Look for the new record streaming on October 30, with vinyl yet to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2078824281/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/album/blue-genie"&gt;BLUE GENIE by TV FREAKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="dirty_cheetah"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dirtycheetah.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dirty Cheetah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buzz Cult&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://dirtycheetah.bandcamp.com/album/buzz-cult" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month, Montreal garage act &lt;a href="https://dirtycheetah.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dirty Cheetah&lt;/a&gt; returned with &lt;em&gt;Buzz Cult&lt;/em&gt;, a 13-song full-length of gritty, high-octane rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll. The set packs 13 songs into 25 minutes, interspersed with samples from Arthur Lipsett&amp;#39;s Oscar-nominated 1961 short &lt;a href="https://www.nfb.ca/film/very_nice_very_nice/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Very Nice, Very Nice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The band describes the work as an unintended concept album. It finds them grappling with modern anxieties and rife with post-post-pandemic malaise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buzz Cult&lt;/em&gt; takes a sardonic look at our dependence on digital outrage. The band talked through that sentiment in their Bandcamp notes, sharing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...it didn&amp;#39;t take long to realize: even if you quit nicotine, cut back the booze, laid off the psychotropics — your hourly dopamine hit just shifted somewhere else. Welcome to the Buzz Cult, where rage-bait is king. Trapped by algorithms, addicted to the next grotesque headline, possessed by your own demons. You want to escape the grind. But guilt haunts you—your carbon footprint, your privilege, your silence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That point&amp;#39;s driven home on songs like &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m the Product,&amp;quot; which pairs a grim look at our sorry state with a sleazy groove that channels Iggy at his finest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded at The Stuzzio with Ryan Battistuzzi (Les Breastfeeders, Boids) engineering and mixing. The quartet features vocalist/guitarist Patrick &amp;quot;Pat Panic&amp;quot; Morissette, guitarist François &amp;quot;Dirty Frank&amp;quot; Letourneau, bassist Luc &amp;quot;Don Lucas&amp;quot; Binette, and drummer Lynn &amp;quot;Linda Kicks&amp;quot; Poulin (&lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://taxigirls.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Taxi Girls&lt;/a&gt;). All four share vocal duties in the record, with Poulin notably singing lead on the single &amp;quot;Wake Me Up!&amp;quot; Midway through the album, you&amp;#39;ll hear the brisk &amp;quot;Third Wave,&amp;quot; a gang-vocal shout-along that the band immediately revisits in both French and then Spanish (the third cut, titled &amp;quot;Encerrados,&amp;quot; helmed by guest vocalist Osvaldo Aguirre of Montreal electro-pop act &lt;a href="https://papishmusic.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Papish&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album follows Dirty Cheeta&amp;#39;s 2024 EP &lt;em&gt;Polite as Fuck&lt;/em&gt; and their 2020 debut &lt;em&gt;Never Too Late&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=158004636/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dirtycheetah.bandcamp.com/album/buzz-cult"&gt;Buzz Cult by Dirty Cheetah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="odonis_odonis"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://odonisodonis.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Odonis Odonis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Hijacked&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;Come Alive&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eaMLi05gQok" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Come Alive&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/D6wknX-lC34?si=NeyQjLKp5xRAaC6V" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hihacjed&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; on YouTube - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://odonisodonis.bandcamp.com/album/odonis-odonis" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chameleonic post-punk duo &lt;a href="https://odonisodonis.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Odonis Odonis&lt;/a&gt; are back with a new full-length, offering up a late-career self-titled record for their first outing with &lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain Records&lt;/a&gt;. The set arrives November 14, delivering nine new songs and the Toronto band&amp;#39;s first full-length set since 2021&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Spectrums&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Royal Mountain&amp;#39;s promising a set that reintegrates elements from across the band&amp;#39;s genre-fluid career, revisiting their early twist on shoegaze while synthesizing the darkwave, industrial, and electronic elements explored over the past decade. You can hear this in the record&amp;#39;s two lead singles, &amp;quot;Hijacked&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Come Alive.&amp;quot; The former takes an aggressive stand from the shoulders of New Order, while the latter wraps the listener in trip-hop haze. In the &amp;quot;Hijacked&amp;quot; video, directed by Ryan Faist, you notably see the band on stage, wielding guitar and bass. It&amp;#39;s both a throwback to their roots as a conventionally structured band and a distinct departure from the sweaty club-ready electronica of recent outings. The clip accompanying &amp;quot;Come Alive&amp;quot; presents a striking animated vision by Shawn Chiki, inspired by the Metabolism movement in Japanese architecture of the 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows Odonis Odonis&amp;#39; 2023 EP &lt;em&gt;ICON&lt;/em&gt;, which featured team-ups with &lt;a href="https://www.aplacetoburystrangers.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;A Place to Bury Strangers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://suuns.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;SUUNS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://actors.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;ACTORS&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1579365490/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://odonisodonis.bandcamp.com/album/odonis-odonis"&gt;Odonis Odonis by Odonis Odonis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="helene_barbier"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://helenebarbier.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hélène Barbier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panorama&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://helenebarbier.bandcamp.com/album/panorama" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal avant-pop artist &lt;a href="https://helenebarbier.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hélène Barbier&lt;/a&gt; returns next month with &lt;em&gt;Panorama&lt;/em&gt;, a nine-song full-length due November 14 through a newfound partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.bonsound.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bonsound&lt;/a&gt;. The bilingual set follows the France-born artist&amp;#39;s 2021 LP &lt;em&gt;Regulus&lt;/em&gt;, delivering what the label describes as &amp;quot;gooey jangle pop riffs, haunting melodies, and tangled grooves.&amp;quot; The press materials playfully suggest the record sounds &amp;quot;as if The Shaggs had taken guitar lessons from Tom Verlaine in Montreal in 2025, before forming a band by divine accident.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can preview the record now through the lead single &amp;quot;Lapin&amp;quot; and the recently unveiled album-opener &amp;quot;Kindness in a Cup.&amp;quot; The latter sneaks up on you, slyly creeping along Barbier&amp;#39;s hypnotic bass lines only to blossom into short, cathartic swirls of dizzying guitarplay. On it, the artist revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s about the desire to keep your head above the water, while flirting with the idea of letting yourself sink, but there is a soothing presence in the song that ensures the story ends well.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barbier recorded with a slate of familiar faces, anchored by longtime collaborators Ben Lalonde and &lt;a href="https://totalpunkrecords.bandcamp.com/album/strike-gold-strike-back-strike-out" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Retail Simps&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Joe Chamandy. The record features contributions from Claire Paquet, the Simps&amp;#39; &lt;a href="https://thomasmolander.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Thomas Molander&lt;/a&gt;, Samuel Gougoux (&lt;a href="https://corridormtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Corridor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://victimelol.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;VICTIME&lt;/a&gt;), Wes MacNeil (&lt;a href="https://nightlunch.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Night Lunch&lt;/a&gt;), Mélanie Venditti, Alexandra Levy (&lt;a href="https://adaleamusic.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ada Lea&lt;/a&gt;), and Meg Duffy (&lt;a href="https://handhabits.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hand Habits&lt;/a&gt;). Emmanuel Éthier (Corridor, Population II) produced the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barbier will celebrate the album&amp;#39;s release with shows at La Toscadura in Montreal on November 27 (as part of &lt;a href="https://festivaltriste.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Festival Triste&lt;/a&gt;) and Le Pantoum in Quebec City on November 28.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1856473067/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://helenebarbier.bandcamp.com/album/panorama"&gt;Panorama by Hélène Barbier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="hobby"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hobbytoronto.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hobby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Major Highway&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://hobbytoronto.bandcamp.com/album/clear-blue-river" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hobbytoronto.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hobby&lt;/a&gt; is legit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Toronto shouldn&amp;#39;t feel unlikely as a source of Americana, given the evidence. This &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; where The Band got their legs, and that should be enough to close the debate even if you ignore modern legends like The Sadies. Still, the town&amp;#39;s low-key modern indie scene feels a little too weird to deliver what &lt;a href="https://hobbytoronto.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Hobby&lt;/a&gt; accomplishes. The group&amp;#39;s latest LP, &lt;em&gt;Clear Blue River&lt;/em&gt;, lands November 7 with ten new songs. The band&amp;#39;s new label, &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;, has the sepia-toned lead single &amp;quot;Major Highway&amp;quot; available now, described as a &amp;quot;grand&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;cinematic&amp;quot; take on the genre in the fine tradition of the Dead and The Byrds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hobby features guitarists Stephen Pitman (&lt;a href="https://onlygodforgivesto.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Only God Forgives&lt;/a&gt;), Cameron Fraser (&lt;a href="https://hugeluge.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Luge&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;a href="https://kurtmarble.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Kurt Marble&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.twistofficial.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Twist&lt;/a&gt;), backed by bassist Duncan Wardlaw and drummer Foster Marshall-Medeiros. The group recorded with &lt;a href="https://louieshort.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Louie Short&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;#39;s a lot of art-punk cred in the room, so it&amp;#39;s impressive just how genuine Hobby feels. There&amp;#39;s nothing ironic or postmodern about a track like &amp;quot;Major Highway.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time&amp;#39;s been incredibly kind to the group&amp;#39;s 2024 full-length &lt;em&gt;Born Again&lt;/em&gt;, at least judging by its lengthy stay in my playlists, so I&amp;#39;m thrilled to see them back at it and working with one of my favourite labels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1227118682/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hobbytoronto.bandcamp.com/album/clear-blue-river"&gt;Clear Blue River by Hobby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="home_front"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Home Front&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Street City Kids (In A New Dark Age)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com/album/street-city-kids-in-a-new-dark-age" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know I just wrote &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-09-19-light-sleeper/#home_front" class="" target="_blank"&gt;at length&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Home Front&lt;/a&gt;, but the band&amp;#39;s write-up for their recently shared cover is so packed with nerdy punk Canadiana that I couldn&amp;#39;t resist. The Edmonton duo applied their electric mix of new wave, street punk and Oi! to &amp;quot;Street City Kids&amp;quot; by Montreal underground favourites &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/1179914-Inepsy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Inepsy&lt;/a&gt;. The original appeared on the band&amp;#39;s 2003 album &lt;em&gt;Rock&amp;#39;N&amp;#39;Roll Babylon&lt;/em&gt;. Home Front&amp;#39;s full-throttle reimagining updates the title to &amp;quot;Street City Kids (In A New Dark Age).&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing on Bandcamp, Home Front vocalist Graeme MacKinnon shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What more can be said about the importance of Inepsy on Canadian Punk. Just like DOA or SNFU, I would strongly argue that Inepsy is just as trailblazing and relevant today as they were when they blew the doors open in the early 2000s. Legacy aside it boils down to the simple fact they are great people who made great music and great art... As this world spins us into this new dark age, Chany&amp;#39;s Post Apocalyptic lyrics and imagery feel more real than ever. As we &amp;#39;live (our) lives in the night&amp;#39; and in the day &amp;#39;sleep to forget the bomb&amp;#39; we look for those little escapes to not lose the fight.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Jonah Falco plays a solo on the track (a performance described by MacKinnon as &amp;quot;if Fred &amp;#39;Sonic&amp;#39; Smith had discovered Quebec PCP&amp;quot;). Home Front connected with Inepsy&amp;#39;s Chany Pilote this past September while playing &lt;a href="https://betonarmeoimtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Béton Armé&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s release party for their &lt;em&gt;Renaissance&lt;/em&gt; LP. Pilote ended up contributing a massive (and extremely metal) oil painting that now serves as the track&amp;#39;s cover art. Check it out at Bandcamp. You can pick up the song as a flexi disc hitched to the forthcoming 79th issue of &lt;a href="https://store.newnoisemagazine.com/products/issue-79-home-front-w-exclusive-flexi?srsltid=AfmBOoq2vlRCY5IrsjKAZm-XMmk-E0y1SRI6wzYs4MbAu9jjDDExtuyw" class="" target="_blank"&gt;New Noise Magazine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Home Front, featuring MacKinnon and Clint Frazier, are deep into the press cycle for &lt;em&gt;Watch It Die&lt;/em&gt;, their sophomore full-length due November 14 through &lt;a href="https://www.lavidaesunmus.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;La Vida Es Un Mus&lt;/a&gt;. You can now see a video for the record&amp;#39;s second single, &amp;quot;Eulogy,&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/cdYpIzmv2Mc?si=YjEYdKWgQtG4Hd6v" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inepsy&amp;#39;s Chany Pilote runs Gatineau&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://pilssessions.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pils Records&lt;/a&gt; these days, notably helming the Pils Sessions series, documenting the contemporary Quebec punk scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1978706281/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com/album/street-city-kids-in-a-new-dark-age"&gt;Street City Kids (In A New Dark Age) by HOME FRONT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Light Sleeper</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-09-19-light-sleeper/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-09-19-light-sleeper/</id>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-19T15:18:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="home_front"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Home Front&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Light Sleeper&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/cqgXrGrIguU?si=YD8mSagYG8ypBLx6" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com/album/watch-it-die" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had this entire mailing drafted, then &lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Home Front&lt;/a&gt; had the audacity to launch an album campaign while I was already behind on my edit. Stop. Reset. I&amp;#39;m so goddamn late with this thing at the best of times that I&amp;#39;m not usually bothered by how untimely I am at regurgitating the latest press release. I&amp;#39;m too far gone to match my old Punknews pace, and I frankly don&amp;#39;t care to. Yet I have a distinct, searing memory of the first time I encountered Home Front, and that drives a sense of urgency. It was one of those line-in-the-sand moments when you recognize that you&amp;#39;ve found something that&amp;#39;s not merely &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; but quite likely &lt;em&gt;important&lt;/em&gt;, with the potential to resonate well outside our comfy little scene. That potential remains, so this publication brakes for Home Front.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Edmonton duo return this November with &lt;em&gt;Watch It Die&lt;/em&gt;, their sophomore full-length and third release overall, through &lt;a href="https://www.lavidaesunmus.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;La Vida Es Un Mus&lt;/a&gt;. You can preview the album through the urgent lead single &amp;quot;Light Sleeper,&amp;quot; which boldly reintroduces the band&amp;#39;s hopeful, shout-along collision of new wave, street punk, Oi!, and post-punk. An accompanying video features the band&amp;#39;s core, multi-instrumental duo of Clint Frazier and vocalist Graeme MacKinnon, performing alongside their touring band of Brandi Strauss (bass), Ian Rowley (guitar), and Warren Oostlander (drums).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch It Die&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s 12 tracks represent a thematic shift for MacKinnon and Frazier. While &lt;em&gt;Games of Power&lt;/em&gt; (2023) and &lt;em&gt;Think of the Lie&lt;/em&gt; (2021) wrestled with alienation and took an often bleak view of the world, this new effort strives to rise above that. A set of Jonah Falco-penned album notes calls this a &amp;quot;step forward&amp;quot; moment. Between that text and the press release announcing the record, the word &amp;quot;hope&amp;quot; is repeated again and again. The band offered:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;For us, ultimately, this is music that comes out of loss and heartbreak and failure, but I hope people have a good time listening to us. You can get rowdy, you can get emotional, you can do whatever you want, but maybe with all of that freedom, we all take a second to reflect on all our fallen brothers and sisters and friends who may have slipped away.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded in Edmonton between November 2024 and April of this year, with Nik Kozub engineering, mixing, and mastering. &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Jonah Falco co-produced the album and contributed additional instrumentation to three tracks. Kozub, who previously played with Frazier in dance-punk act &lt;a href="https://www.shoutoutoutoutout.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Shout Out Out Out&lt;/a&gt;, also handled synths, sampling, and programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band will launch the album with shows at the Hollywood Palladium in Los Angeles on November 22 and 23, performing alongside Cock Sparrer and Dillinger Four. You can get your hands on &lt;em&gt;Watch It Die&lt;/em&gt; on November 14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1358674759/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com/album/watch-it-die"&gt;Watch It Die by HOME FRONT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="boy_commandos"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/comet" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Boy Commandos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/comet" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between &lt;a href="https://jadehairpins.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jade Hairpins&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s ascendant indie pop and &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s latter-day penchant for trading out vocalists, Mike Haliechuk is more visible than ever. &lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/comet" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Boy Commandos&lt;/a&gt;, billed as his debut solo project, further thrusts the guitarist to center stage but, interestingly, swerves from the theatrical excess of his other outlets. The 11-song &lt;em&gt;Comet&lt;/em&gt;, issued earlier this month, finds Haliechuk disarmed and direct, playing straight-up 90s-inspired power-pop with the earnest vulnerability of Sugar or the Lemonheads (it doesn&amp;#39;t hurt that Mike&amp;#39;s deadpan vocal delivery recalls Evan Dando). While there are most certainly Fucked Up songs with the lyrical candour of &amp;quot;I Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Be Perceived,&amp;quot; the band buries them in crunch and chaos. Stripped of that bombast, Mike&amp;#39;s lyricism has a chance to breathe. We don&amp;#39;t say &amp;quot;emo&amp;quot; around here, but it&amp;#39;s honestly closer than not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Production-wise, &lt;em&gt;Comet&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#39;s small supporting cast features longtime collaborators. The album showcases Mike on vocals, guitar, and bass, with his Jade Hairpins partner Jonah Falco drumming. Falco and longtime Fucked Up engineer Alex Gamble recorded in a raft of studio spaces between Toronto and London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coinciding with the Boy Commandos release, Haliechuk and Falco&amp;#39;s manic indie-pop outlet &lt;a href="https://jadehairpins.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jade Hairpins&lt;/a&gt; issued &amp;quot;Like Fumes,&amp;quot; a shimmering synth-pop jam with a curious vocal take that percolates deep down in the mix. The track stems from the sessions for 2024&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.mergerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Merge Records&lt;/a&gt; release, &lt;em&gt;Get Me the Good Stuff&lt;/em&gt;, an extended coda for that record&amp;#39;s laid-back highlight, &amp;quot;Better here Than in Love.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=262233400/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://fuckedup.bandcamp.com/album/comet"&gt;"Comet" by Boy Commandos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="ribbon_skirt"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ribbonskirtband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ribbon Skirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Lucky8&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://ribbonskirtband.bandcamp.com/album/pensacola" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fresh from their performance at the Polaris gala,
Montreal&amp;#39;s Anishinaabe-led post-punk outfit &lt;a href="https://ribbonskirtband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ribbon Skirt&lt;/a&gt; are readying a new EP to follow up on their shortlisted &lt;em&gt;Bite Down&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pensacola&lt;/em&gt; arrives on October 3 through &lt;a href="https://www.mintrecs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s framed the release as an epilogue to their acclaimed debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can preview the four-song set through &amp;quot;Lucky8,&amp;quot; a shoegaze blur propelled by droning guitars and clipped, distortion-washed vocals. The short set&amp;#39;s described as &amp;quot;emotional residue&amp;quot; left in its predecessor&amp;#39;s wake: &amp;quot;the lingering heat, the unsaid, the still-burning edge.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band&amp;#39;s current lineup features Tashiina Buswa on guitar and vocals, Billy Riley on guitar, bass, and synth, with Lan Thockchom drumming. Everyone shared credit for the percussion on this one. Reprising their role from the LP, Scott &amp;#39;Monty&amp;#39; Munro (&lt;a href="https://preoccs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Preoccupations&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href="https://marlaenamoore.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Marlaena Moore&lt;/a&gt; produced the EP, recorded at Studio Saint Zo in Montreal. Graham Walsh mixed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look for Ribbon Skirt on the road this fall, heading west with Louisville indie rock act Wombo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2763013583/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ribbonskirtband.bandcamp.com/album/pensacola"&gt;PENSACOLA by Ribbon Skirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_boojums"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Boojums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Wings of Fire&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;Burnin Up&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Burning Up&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oxb9k-u9t-U?si=bLqOdZuqHfa4lifM" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com/album/the-boojums" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like the rest of you, I first stumbled across Nova Scotian trio &lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Boojums&lt;/a&gt; through a string of grainy, VHS-quality performance videos the band shared to boost their early singles. Promotionally, it was something of a masterstroke; the trio crammed awkwardly in a small room, banging through throwback garage rock while gazing, almost unnervingly, through the camera lens. I hate to dwell on fucking Instagram reels, but in an age when our attention spans are all hopelessly fried, it was an impressive feat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band&amp;#39;s ready for the next step, with a self-titled LP due October 31 through &lt;a href="https://havingfunrecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Having Fun Records&lt;/a&gt;, a rock-oriented imprint of Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://wearebusybodies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;We Are Busy Bodies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can preview the album through two advance singles. &amp;quot;Wings of Fire&amp;quot; drips with boastful attitude, delivered at a breakneck pace. The band takes their foot off the gas for the soaring &amp;quot;Burnin Up,&amp;quot; accompanied by a Cape Breton-shot video. The latter taps a similar vein of throwback rock heroism that Sam Coffey &amp;amp; The Iron Lungs mines so well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guitarist/vocalist &lt;a href="https://williestratton.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Willie Stratton&lt;/a&gt; spoke about &amp;quot;Wings of Fire&amp;quot; in a press release, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Wings of Fire&amp;#39; is about chasing something bigger before it disappears in the rearview. It&amp;#39;s that feeling when you&amp;#39;re flying down the highway—gold on your engine, nothing but dreams in the tank, and someone you love in the passenger seat.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Boojums recorded themselves live off the floor, with Darren Lawson (Bloc Party, Against Me!, Spiritualized) mixing. Hailing from Port Hawkesbury, the trio features Stratton (&lt;a href="https://beachbait.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Beach Bait&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar and vocals, Sara Johnston (&lt;a href="https://www.skunkmotel.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Skunk Motel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.thesurfrajettes.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Surfrajettes&lt;/a&gt;) on a distinctively crunchy 8-string bass, and drummer &lt;a href="https://petermacinnis.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Peter MacInnis&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://beechhill.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Beech Hill&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3327627148/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com/album/the-boojums"&gt;The Boojums by The Boojums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="yoo_doo_right"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yoodooright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yoo Doo Right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class="split"&gt;&amp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Population II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yoo II avec Nolan Potter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://yoodooright.bandcamp.com/album/yoo-ii-avec-nolan-potter" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal post-rock luminaries &lt;a href="https://yoodooright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yoo Doo Right&lt;/a&gt; and the psych-noise trio &lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Population II&lt;/a&gt; recently joined forces. On an idle moment between SXSW showcases last March, the bands connected with the prolific Texan prog artist &lt;a href="https://nolanpotter.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Nolan Potter&lt;/a&gt;, churning out a sprawling jam of an LP that finds the collective tapping their mutual love of krautrock, free jazz, and heady psychedelia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recorded on March 14 at Austin&amp;#39;s Rundown Audio, the set finds Population II&amp;#39;s Pierre-Luc Gratton (percussion and vocals), Tristan Lacombe (12-string electric guitar, organ, and signal generator), and Sébastien Provençal (bass) joining Yoo Doo Right&amp;#39;s John Talbot (drums) and Justin Cober (electric guitar and synthesizers). Potter contributes an arsenal of instrumentation, including flute, saxophone, percussion, 12-string acoustic guitar, electric guitar, and organ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Potter explained how it all came together:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Yoo Doo Right and Population II had a short break between shows and I invited them to the studio to see what would happen. With the help of a great engineer [Autumn Furtak-Cole], we tracked about 90 minutes of music with one quick intermission. 90% of what you hear on the record is improvised. My recollection is that there was a serious energy in the room, everyone played with extreme intention and determination.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;#39;s song titles reference the voyages of the ill-fated 17th-century French fur trader and explorer René-Robert Cavelier, Sieur de La Salle. Cavelier&amp;#39;s massive expansion of what was then New France ultimately ended in his assassination during a mutiny on the Gulf of Mexico in 1687. Potter drew a playful parallel between this effort and that history, stating, &amp;quot;making this record was an exploration for us too, but we&amp;#39;re much more pleased with the results.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 43 minutes, you can lose yourself in the five-song &lt;em&gt;Yoo II avec Nolan Potter&lt;/em&gt;. The set&amp;#39;s now available in full through &lt;a href="https://www.mothland.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mothland&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://levitation.fm/collections/record-label" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Reverberation Appreciation Society&lt;/a&gt;. Both Montreal bands arrive at this collaboration riding high on recent successes. Yoo Doo Right&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;From the Heights of Our Pastureland&lt;/em&gt; and Population II&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Maintenant Jamais&lt;/em&gt; both made the Polaris Music Prize long-list this year, with the latter ascending to the 10-album shortlist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3235894414/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yoodooright.bandcamp.com/album/yoo-ii-avec-nolan-potter"&gt;Yoo II avec Nolan Potter by Yoo Doo Right, Population II &amp;amp; Nolan Potter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="imploders"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/implodersband/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Imploders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Targeted For Termination&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/targeted-for-termination" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ask me, Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/implodersband/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Imploders&lt;/a&gt; are one of the most entertaining live bands in the country, and I relish any opportunity to see them tear through a set of smirking, grievance-fueled hardcore. The group returns on October 17 with their sophomore LP, &lt;em&gt;Targeted for Termination&lt;/em&gt;. Available through &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste Records&lt;/a&gt; domestically and &lt;a href="https://staticshockrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Static Shock Records&lt;/a&gt; overseas, the band&amp;#39;s promising an effort with even more fat trimmed (which doesn&amp;#39;t seem that possible, to be honest). You can hear &amp;quot;Possessed to Hate&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Eat, Sleep, Repeat&amp;quot; streaming now. Clocking in at around 96 seconds, the latter is the longest song on the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neon Taste shares elaborately:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The sound still resides in classic hardcore from both sides of the border with the emphasis on punk (think Circle Jerks, Zero Boys and Angry Samoans). Lyrically they dive deeper into their world of annoyances, grievances and late nights of taking in the joys of both &lt;em&gt;Heavy Metal&lt;/em&gt; (the movie) and Medieval Times (not for buffs). Housed in a sleeve with a vision of the future that could have come straight out of a cheap 50&amp;#39;s sci-fi novel. Would you survive?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imploders features Todd Faux (ex-&lt;a href="https://averagetimes.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Average Times&lt;/a&gt;) on vocals, Joey Parenteau (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/viciouscyclesudbury/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Vicious Cycle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://ilikepinkwine.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pink Wine&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar, Mikey Microwave (&lt;a href="https://firstbase.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;First Base&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://teenarcher.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Teen Archer&lt;/a&gt;) on bass, and Curtis Tone (&lt;a href="http://weareplasticheads.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PlasticHeads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://schooldamage.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;School Damage&lt;/a&gt;) drumming. Micah Brown (&lt;a href="https://pillea.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pillea&lt;/a&gt;) recorded and mixed the new songs at Happy Hour Studios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imploders head to Europe in October to support the new record, their second tour of the continent to date. This new album follows up on their self-titled 2023 debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4087153728/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/targeted-for-termination"&gt;Targeted For Termination by Imploders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="absolute_losers"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://absolutelosers.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Absolute Losers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In The Crowd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://absolutelosers.bandcamp.com/album/in-the-crowd" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charlottetown power-pop trio &lt;a href="https://absolutelosers.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Absolute Losers&lt;/a&gt; return next week with &lt;em&gt;In The Crowd&lt;/em&gt;, their sophomore full-length. Look for it September 26 through the above-mentioned &lt;a href="https://havingfunrecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Having Fun&lt;/a&gt; label.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The record represents a significant leap from their scrappy 2023 debut &lt;em&gt;At The Mall&lt;/em&gt;, a pandemic product recorded in a basement during lockdown. This time out, the band worked with &lt;a href="https://www.holyfuckmusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Holy Fuck&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Graham Walsh at Toronto&amp;#39;s Palace Sound, taking the time to create a set of songs described as &amp;quot;ambitious, widescreen, and built for volume.&amp;quot; Walsh served as producer and mixed the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nostalgic lead single &amp;quot;At The Same Time&amp;quot; taps into bassist/vocalist Sam Langille&amp;#39;s memories of his grandparents&amp;#39; cottage at Flat River, PEI, where he and his brother, guitarist Josh Langille, would spend the summer. They comment:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;A lot of people can relate to feeling some kind of magic when they&amp;#39;re with their grandparents. This place was definitely magical as a kid. Even though I&amp;#39;ve outgrown that part of life, I know my family still cheers me on... Now they&amp;#39;re cheering me on for moving out, getting a job, releasing music. The cheering is just more felt than shouted.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The track follows the band&amp;#39;s evolution from angular post-punk to a warmer sound rooted in 90s power-pop, standing on the shoulders of Maritime heroes like Sloan, Thrush Hermit, and the Super Friendz. Absolute Losers features the Langille brothers backed by drummer Daniel Hartinger, with all three sharing vocal duties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1504334994/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://absolutelosers.bandcamp.com/album/in-the-crowd"&gt;In The Crowd by Absolute Losers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="smug_llc"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com/track/little-gusts" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Smug LLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Little Gusts&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com/track/little-gusts" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Drew Thomson tends to play fast and lose with the identities of his various musical outlets. The pandemic hit the gas on that, with a raft of bedroom recording projects competing for space amidst a scattering of releases attributed to both &lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Drew Thomson Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and a handful of Single Mothers name variants. That&amp;#39;s to say nothing of his recent side-gigs fronting garage outlet &lt;a href="https://thestovesareon.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Stoves&lt;/a&gt; or playing in the duo Wind in Mono. At first glance, you could consider &lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com/track/little-gusts" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Smug LLC&lt;/a&gt; yet another name on the list, but this project looks a little more serious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new act finds Thomson working with the &lt;a href="https://anxiousandangry.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Anxious and Angry&lt;/a&gt; label, founded by Ryan Young of Off With Their Heads. You can preview the six-song &lt;em&gt;New Exciting Doom&lt;/em&gt; EP now through the lead single &amp;quot;Little Gusts.&amp;quot; Thomson commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s about internal and external struggles and how they intertwine. Lyrically the album is kind of like looking out a window into the litter filled streets, seeing a reflection of yourself in the glass. Can things get worse? Can they get better? Is it all perspective? Is this a new doom, or has it always been here, lurking just around the corner, waiting to swallow us whole?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;SMUG LLC&amp;#39;s described as a &amp;quot;laptop band,&amp;quot; harkening back to Thomson&amp;#39;s isolated lockdown efforts that gave rise to projects like 2020&amp;#39;s No Idea Head. A press release describes &amp;quot;analog and digital drum loops, basslines, synthesizers, and samples arranged together in a simple mosaic of chaos and hooks&amp;quot; backing Thomson&amp;#39;s unmistakably propulsive vocals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This October, Thomson&amp;#39;s taking that laptop on the road when SMUG LLC opens for Off With Their Heads on a US tour. &lt;em&gt;New Exciting Doom&lt;/em&gt; lands October 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2246391100/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com/track/little-gusts"&gt;Little Gusts by SMUG LLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="piercing_damage"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://piercingdamagehc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Piercing Damage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Piercing Damage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://piercingdamagehc.bandcamp.com/album/s-t" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Late in the summer, Charlottetown hardcore outfit &lt;a href="https://piercingdamagehc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Piercing Damage&lt;/a&gt; issued their self-titled debut EP. The whip-fast six-song set, released through Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/beaboutitzine/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Be About It&lt;/a&gt; zine, expands upon the searing demo the group issued last November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EP features vocalist Andrew Cormier (formerly of &lt;a href="https://swallowingknives.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Swallowing Knives&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://ironeyehc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Iron Eye&lt;/a&gt;), guitarist Liam Farrell and bassist Tyler Turner (both from &lt;a href="https://baited.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Baited&lt;/a&gt;), and drummer Brett Sanderson (&lt;a href="https://celldeth.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cell Deth&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://antibodieschtn.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Antibodies&lt;/a&gt;). Cormier and Farrell handled the recording in-house. You&amp;#39;ll find art from Prism Shores&amp;#39; Ben Goss adorning the cover. Look for tapes from the band soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ll next hear Piercing Damage on a new compilation of Maritime hardcore through &lt;a href="http://sewerciderecords.limitedrun.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sewercide Records&lt;/a&gt;, the spiritual successor to 2020&amp;#39;s landmark &lt;em&gt;Seaside Sickness&lt;/em&gt; set. They&amp;#39;ll be joined on the 7&amp;quot; by Excited To Die, Ritual Warfare, Cell Deth, Misanthropic Minds, Poison Spear, and Peracetic. We&amp;#39;re told to expect this in the fall, but punk springs eternal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3100821557/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://piercingdamagehc.bandcamp.com/album/s-t"&gt;S/T by Piercing Damage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Seed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-08-17-seed/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-08-17-seed/</id>
    <published>2025-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-17T15:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="julianna_riolino"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://juliannariolinosings.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Julianna Riolino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Echo in the Dust&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;On A Bluebird&amp;#39;s Wing&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ZSBvASqrANg?si=jnAjYf98yLlIhemy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://juliannariolinosings.bandcamp.com/album/echo-in-the-dust" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welland alt-country artist &lt;a href="https://juliannariolinosings.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Julianna Riolino&lt;/a&gt; returns this fall with &lt;em&gt;Echo in the Dust&lt;/em&gt;, her first solo full-length since 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;All Blue&lt;/em&gt; and the first since she parted ways with The Outfit. Arriving October 24 on her own MoonWhistle Records, the 11-song set promises a newfound confidence, honed from years on the road and showcasing Riolino&amp;#39;s careful evolution into a headlining act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can hear two previews of the record online now, the triumphant &amp;quot;On a Bluebird&amp;#39;s Wing&amp;quot; and the arrestingly beautiful, slow-burning &amp;quot;Seed.&amp;quot; Riolino calls the former &amp;quot;a cyclical celebration of inner and outer growth.&amp;quot; It arrives alongside a video from &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/musicmanhann/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Blake Hannahson&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Seed&amp;quot; builds from a 60s girl-group homage into an unexpectedly noisy and triumphant rallying cry, described by the artist as an &amp;quot;unfurling of spiritual awakening, like a bud taking to its soil and beginning to grow on its own.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the record, Riolino revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What I&amp;#39;m talking about on &lt;em&gt;Echo In The Dust&lt;/em&gt; are universally felt: you can have a romantic relationship, friendship, or professional relationship and start to identify as you grow and learn the toxic parts that can exist in all of those. You think, &amp;#39;why do I feel bad? Why is this happening again?&amp;#39; But I&amp;#39;m allowing this to happen because I haven&amp;#39;t told myself I deserve better. This record helped me learn to accept and love myself. To put myself first and stand on my own two feet.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;While she&amp;#39;ll perhaps never shed vocal comparisons to Dolly Parton or Linda Ronstadt, Riolino cites a wild range of influences on the record, spanning from Roy Orbison to stoner metal heroes Om. She states:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s kind of punk, it&amp;#39;s rock n&amp;#39; roll, it&amp;#39;s still kind of country. It&amp;#39;s more rocking than &lt;em&gt;All Blue&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s an amalgamation of everything going on in my mind.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riolino recorded at Toronto&amp;#39;s Gold Standard Recorders with producer &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/agoldrules/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Aaron Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;. She anchors the studio band on vocals and guitar, joined by her husband Matthew &amp;quot;Roddy&amp;quot; Kuester on bass and guitar, Goldstein on his trademark pedal steel, &lt;a href="https://peterlandi.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Peter Landi&lt;/a&gt; (Drew Thomson, &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt;) on drums, and Thomas Hammerton on piano and synth. Guest players on the album include guitarist Justis Krar, mandolin player Nichol Robertson, guitarist Sean Thompson, Patrick Smith on saxophone, and Tom Moffett on trumpet. &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt; noisemaker Alex Edkins plays guitar on several tracks, with his &lt;a href="https://weirdnightmare.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Weird Nightmare&lt;/a&gt; solo guise listed as a featured artist on the track &amp;quot;Full Moon.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t want to dwell too much on Julianna&amp;#39;s time with &lt;a href="https://www.danielromanomusic.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Outfit, as this new material represents such a distinct, high watermark that any such footnote feels like an anchor — but it&amp;#39;s with that band that she emerged as often the most magnetic performer on a stage crowded with strong personalities. Her last records with the Welland crew were 2021&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Cobra Poems&lt;/em&gt; and 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;La Luna&lt;/em&gt;, both on &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3202846958/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://juliannariolinosings.bandcamp.com/album/echo-in-the-dust"&gt;Echo in the Dust by Julianna Riolino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="carson_mchone"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://carsonmchone.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carson McHone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pentimento&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Winter Breaking&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xdnjx_Yqy5g?si=uLjBbbQdObkwiR0Y" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://carsonmchone.bandcamp.com/album/pentimento" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a related note, Welland-based, Texas-born singer-songwriter &lt;a href="https://carsonmchone.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carson McHone&lt;/a&gt; also has a new LP on the way. The 13-song &lt;em&gt;Pentimento&lt;/em&gt; is notably the artist&amp;#39;s first solo record since relocating to Canada; it arrives September 12 through &lt;a href="https://www.mergerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Merge Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can preview the album now with three pre-release singles: &amp;quot;Downhill,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Idiom,&amp;quot; and the album opener &amp;quot;Winter Breaking.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While she wrote in the Texas desert, McHone recorded on the east coast of Canada with a host of familiar names, including Constantines&amp;#39; &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/colleencococollins" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Colleen Coco Collins&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://pennyandthepits.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Penny &amp;amp; The Pits&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://constructionanddestruction.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Construction &amp;amp; Destruction&lt;/a&gt;), Peterborough enigma/accordionist &lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt;, violinist &lt;a href="https://www.rahajavanfar.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Raha Javanfar&lt;/a&gt;, and her partner &lt;a href="https://www.danielromanomusic.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;. The Outfit&amp;#39;s in-house engineer, Kenneth Roy Meehan, recorded the album to 8-track cassette over a single week last winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The community McHone adopted on Northern shores plays a significant role on the album, both sonically and conceptually. In a press release, McHone revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This project continues to be, really, a community effort. What began as a methodical structuring of personal artifacts kept speaking of collaboration, which allowed me to open up the process to others and bring it to life. Making the initial recording brought together a group of six musicians, but the project has expanded to include a web of many artists and disciplines. If my last album, &lt;em&gt;Still Life&lt;/em&gt;, represents a static moment, a pause before a pivot, &lt;em&gt;Pentimento&lt;/em&gt; is the natural next step. It&amp;#39;s full of movement—through time and space, through many forms... It&amp;#39;s a project that engages with shadow, with impulse, with paradox, and with play. I hope the record illustrates the process of integrating these things, of acknowledging the complexity of being/becoming.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;#39;s runtime incorporates readings from poets Margaret Bentley, André Benitez-James Farnes, and Layla Benitez-James. Additionally, the young son of Benitez-James appears in the video for the song &amp;quot;Downhill,&amp;quot; shot in Barcelona and directed by McHone. You can find it on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qtiw-JmauhQ" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; now alongside a clip spotlighting the pastoral folk of &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-AYky_zPD38" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Idiom&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pentimento&lt;/em&gt; follows McHone&amp;#39;s 2022 record &lt;em&gt;Still Life&lt;/em&gt; and a collection of follow-up EPs, including the Outfit-backed &lt;em&gt;Camera Varda Variations&lt;/em&gt; and the covers set &lt;em&gt;ODES&lt;/em&gt;. With The Outfit, McHone most recently appeared on the &lt;em&gt;Live in Oslo&lt;/em&gt; recordings, issued on LP this July and featuring that band&amp;#39;s current four-piece lineup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;McHone plans to celebrate the album&amp;#39;s release in Niagara with a listening party and multi-disciplinary performance at St. Catharines&amp;#39; &lt;a href="https://suitcaseinpoint.com/in-the-soil-arts-festival/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;In the Soil Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; on September 12. A month-long Texas residency follows in October, honouring the album in both her past and present homes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1258826224/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://carsonmchone.bandcamp.com/album/pentimento"&gt;Pentimento by Carson McHone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_planet_smashers"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://planetsmashers.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Planet Smashers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On The Dancefloor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Meet me on the Dancefloor&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/STFdfLzSIKc?si=fsEAqnAoTBAvI_da" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://planetsmashers.bandcamp.com/album/on-the-dancefloor" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m just old enough (or I&amp;#39;d like to think, just young enough) that &lt;a href="https://planetsmashers.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Planet Smashers&lt;/a&gt; were a keystone band in my evolution as a music consumer. I was a high schooler during the summer of ska, but more than just having the right timing, I completely bought in. I identified as a ska kid long before I navigated the cultural complexities of punk and indie rock; it&amp;#39;s likely the first genre badge I adopted. It&amp;#39;s also not lost on me that the obscure-yet-national focus of the first &lt;em&gt;All Skanadian Club&lt;/em&gt; comp closely reflects on my eventual MO as a writer, this newsletter included. Yet for all my nostalgic affection, I&amp;#39;ll admit I lost the plot on the Smashers&amp;#39; output after 2005&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Unstoppable&lt;/em&gt; (right around the time when post-university adulthood kicked in, unsurprisingly).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That I relegated the Smashers to some youthful phase is my failing. Catching up, recent records like 2019&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Too Much Information&lt;/em&gt; are hardly frivolous and very much the work of a veteran band with a solid grasp on the mature avenues their genre allows (&amp;quot;Light In Your Smile,&amp;quot; etc). While certainly playful and often tongue-in-cheek, it&amp;#39;s unfair to pin the adolescent extremes of &amp;quot;Super Orgy Porno Party&amp;quot; on their current output. From our first few samples, it sounds like the bar remains high on the band&amp;#39;s 10th studio album, &lt;em&gt;On the Dancefloor&lt;/em&gt;. Lead single &amp;quot;Meet Me on the Dancefloor&amp;quot; feels iconic and sounds like a mission statement, a reassurance of their careful stewardship of the 2 Tone sound. There&amp;#39;s nothing particularly jokey about it (nor does it force any overt political statement), but as an expression of unencumbered body-moving joy, it certainly hits the mark. I can&amp;#39;t explain how, but The Planet Smashers&amp;#39; horn section after all these years remains utterly distinctive, like a familiar voice unto itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 13-track LP arrives August 22 through &lt;a href="https://stomprecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt; and boasts some serious ska royalty as guests. The album reunites the Montreal band with toaster Neville Staple of &lt;a href="https://www.thespecials.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Specials&lt;/a&gt; (and his wife/co-performer Sugary Staple). They further showcase vocals and percussion from Charley &amp;#39;Aitch&amp;#39; Bembridge, founding drummer of &lt;a href="https://theselecter.net" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Selecter&lt;/a&gt;. The band tapped local legend Sara Johnston of &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/branvan3000official/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bran Van 3000&lt;/a&gt; for backing vocals on the song &amp;quot;Falling.&amp;quot; The Smashers lineup this time out features Matt Collyer, Patrizio McLelland, Andy McAdam, Alexandre Fecteau, Patrick Taylor, and Scott Russell. They recorded at Montreal&amp;#39;s Le Stuzzio with producer Rod Shearer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a press release, ever amiable frontman Matt Collyer brims with positivity:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;On the Dancefloor&lt;/em&gt; was the funnest of our 10 albums to record. I can&amp;#39;t wait to play these songs live! The process was rad from start to finish. All of my bandmates got their hands in there. Plus we had the pleasure of teaming up with ska legends and longtime friends. Fun times!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Videos for both the title track and groovy &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/iaYiFSefQ6A?si=lSXOnDn_Ug3JEeMk" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Things You Do&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; are available on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3835227960/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://planetsmashers.bandcamp.com/album/on-the-dancefloor"&gt;On The Dancefloor by The Planet Smashers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="jimmy_vapid"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jimmyvapid.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmy Vapid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Donnas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://jimmyvapid.bandcamp.com/album/the-donnas-2" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes projects seem to come entirely out of left field, but that&amp;#39;s part of the charm with &lt;a href="https://jimmyvapid.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmy Vapid&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s new LP. Like a lot of us, Jimmy, frontman of veteran Burlington punk act &lt;a href="https://the-vapids.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Vapids&lt;/a&gt;, has a strong affection for 90s pop-punk, particularly that in the Lookout! Records orbit. His new record, &lt;em&gt;The Donnas&lt;/em&gt;, takes that to an extreme, delivering a lovingly crafted track-by-track recreation of the Palo Alto quartet&amp;#39;s 1997 self-titled debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why make such an effort? Who exactly is the audience for this? Jimmy doesn&amp;#39;t care, so who am I to question what folks do with their time? The tribute&amp;#39;s a blast, and given that Jimmy&amp;#39;s made a career delivering hooky garage punk in a similar vein, he&amp;#39;s well-suited to tackle The Donnas&amp;#39; material with lo-fi zeal. It&amp;#39;s a faithful take, albeit generswapped here and there, right down to the cover art.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Donnas&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;#39;t the first time Jimmy&amp;#39;s scratched this particular itch. Back in 2002, The Vapids issued a complete remake of the first &lt;a href="https://teenagehhead.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Teenage Head&lt;/a&gt; record. So one-off cover songs notwithstanding, Jimmy&amp;#39;s got a track record of honouring the classics with more than just lip service. This album, recorded in March, features Jimmy on guitar and vocals backed by Judy Dagmar on bass and Al McCartney on drums and guitar (his usual solo studio band).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new outing follows up on The Vapids&amp;#39;s 2022 record &lt;em&gt;Revenge Therapy&lt;/em&gt; and Jimmy&amp;#39;s pandemic-era solo effort &lt;em&gt;K I L L M A T I C&lt;/em&gt;. The LP surfaced alongside a slew of early Vapids material from The Donnas&amp;#39; heyday, now available on Bandcamp for the first time. These include 1995&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Five Minute Major&lt;/em&gt;, 1997&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Drink Beer&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;Wanna Fuck Around&lt;/em&gt; compilation from 97/98. Jimmy notes that those recordings were a completely different band than the post-millennium Vapids, so check your priors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=48729625/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jimmyvapid.bandcamp.com/album/the-donnas-2"&gt;THE DONNAS by JIMMY VAPID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="auditing"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://auditing.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Auditing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modern Tension&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://auditing.bandcamp.com/album/modern-tension" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a minute since we&amp;#39;ve heard from the high-strung London synth-punk &lt;a href="https://mononegatives.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mononegatives&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;m not sure of their status, but two-thirds of the group recently resurfaced as &lt;a href="https://auditing.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Auditing&lt;/a&gt; - a new project that&amp;#39;s running with the sound and visual aesthetic of its predecessor. The new act issued the six-song &lt;em&gt;Modern Tension&lt;/em&gt; EP in March, their first as a full band. If you&amp;#39;re into the Monos angular retrofuture sound, this is a must-hear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Auditing&amp;#39;s timeline isn&amp;#39;t quite that linear, as the project first surfaced online in 2023 as David Cereghini&amp;#39;s solo venture, running concurrently with Mononegatives&amp;#39; recent efforts. This evolution of the band, assembled last summer, finds Cereghini behind the drum kit, joined by guitarist Aaron Wallis (who played bass in Mononegatives), bassist Nigel, and vocalist/synth-player Gabe Nestor. Nestor and Wallis have a history together in the London punk act &lt;a href="https://ssusanss.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Susans&lt;/a&gt; (in which Nestor, notably, shreds on lead ukulele). They recorded with their frequent studio collaborator Preston Lobzun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group paints their politics with a sci-fi brush on their album-opening &amp;quot;Time Eroded Vault Door,&amp;quot; setting a distinct sci-fi tone. They explain:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It deals with the concept of weaponizing time travel to help circumvent the security apparatus surrounding capital. Somehow this scientific improbability is a more realistic way of sharing the wealth than whatever is happening in our current reality... Safe cracking with physics.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Auditing first surfaced in early 2023 on the lathe-cut &lt;em&gt;First Time&lt;/em&gt; 7&amp;quot;, with David playing all roles. As for Mononegatives, they last issued the &lt;em&gt;Crossing Visual Field&lt;/em&gt; LP in 2024 through &lt;a href="http://www.nofrontteeth.co.uk/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Front Teeth&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://dowdrecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dowd Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1565922976/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://auditing.bandcamp.com/album/modern-tension"&gt;Modern Tension by Auditing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="broken_yolks"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://brokenyolks.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Broken Yolks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The View of the Bystander&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://highenddenimrecords.bandcamp.com/album/the-view-of-the-bystander" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edmonton skate punk trio &lt;a href="https://brokenyolks.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Broken Yolks&lt;/a&gt; have a new full-length out with Red Deer&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://highenddenimrecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;High End Denim Records&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The View of the Bystander&lt;/em&gt; arrived earlier this month, a 15-song effort of 90s-inspired rippers that &amp;quot;dives headfirst into themes of disconnection, frustration, and the strange tension between action and apathy.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band previewed the record with the self-aware single &amp;quot;Plaids, Hats, or Tats.&amp;quot; On the track, which turns a sardonic mirror on the band&amp;#39;s audience, drummer Matt Bordato revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This song is more or less a tongue-in-cheek poke at the conforming non-conformity of fashion in the scene in our city. Have you ever noticed most local shows are just dudes in plaid, wearing hats, and sporting tats? For a genre built on non-conformity, we all certainly seem to have found the uniform. We thought it would be funny to write a song about that. To be clear though, we are just as guilty - we do it too!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;#39;s second single, &amp;quot;Misery,&amp;quot; takes an introspective turn, burnished by a soaring vocal hook in the chorus. The label describes the track as identifying &amp;quot;a toxic comfort in revisiting emotional suffering, almost like welcoming back an old friend.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Broken Yolks features guitarist Blake Basaraba, bassist David Lukic, and drummer Matt Bordato, with vocal duties traded between the trio. They recorded with &lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Real Sickies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Rob Lawless at Lawless Recordings. &lt;a href="https://loserpoints.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Loser Points&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Shawn Taggart mixed at Hog Audio, with &lt;a href="https://theoldwives.bandcamp.com/album/only-one-showed-up" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Old Wives&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Cody Blakely mastering at Halfstack. The new album is Broken Yolks&amp;#39; first new collection since their 2019 EP &lt;em&gt;Tone Deaf&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3530097250/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://highenddenimrecords.bandcamp.com/album/the-view-of-the-bystander"&gt;The View of the Bystander by Broken Yolks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="curbside"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://curbsidepunk.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Curbside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Lifetime to Outgrow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/album/a-lifetime-to-outgrow" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kitchener, Ontario skate punk veterans &lt;a href="https://curbsidepunk.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Curbside&lt;/a&gt; are back with their first album in over a decade. &lt;em&gt;A Lifetime to Outgrow&lt;/em&gt; is out now through &lt;a href="https://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Thousand Islands Records&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s the quartet&amp;#39;s first new material since their 2016 EP &lt;em&gt;Decades&lt;/em&gt;, and like the band&amp;#39;s past work, carries the torch of 90s EpiFat heroes like No Use For a Name and Strung Out (a tie underlined by the fact that the album&amp;#39;s cover features art from Strung Out vocalist Jason Cruz).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a press release, Curbside vocalist/guitarist Pat Dietrich commented on the album&amp;#39;s themes and the gap since their first record, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This album is the culmination of everything we&amp;#39;ve lived since the last record. It&amp;#39;s about growing up, facing uncomfortable truths, and still finding a reason to keep pushing forward.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group&amp;#39;s current lineup features Dietrich alongside drummer Kyle Dolson, and guitarists Craig Retzler and Joel C. Pat took the reins to record and produce the new record, with John Harcus mixing and mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Members of Curbside have been active in recent years, performing with &lt;a href="https://frankduxpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Frank Dux&lt;/a&gt; and the recently revived &lt;a href="https://handheldpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Handheld&lt;/a&gt;. The new release arrives alongside a vinyl reissue of the band&amp;#39;s 2012 debut &lt;em&gt;The Sound I Know&lt;/em&gt;, both through Thousand Islands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2958193573/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/album/a-lifetime-to-outgrow"&gt;A Lifetime to Outgrow by Curbside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cosmic_club"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cosmic Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cosmic Club 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com/album/cosmic-club-2" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often hear Chance Hutchison at extremes, either blowing out speakers as the vocalist of Montreal&amp;#39;s livewire &lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt; or strumming stylish post-punk alongside wife Jackie Blenkarn in &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt;. While the artist certainly doesn&amp;#39;t shy from intensity on his new &lt;a href="http://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cosmic Club&lt;/a&gt; tunes, there&amp;#39;s a reflective aspect to Hutchison&amp;#39;s solo material that he doesn&amp;#39;t often have the vehicle to explore. The two-track &lt;em&gt;Cosmic Club 2&lt;/em&gt; arrived mid-summer, delivering a pair of emotionally raw tracks that tackle &amp;quot;the often-unspoken realities of growing up in poverty and surviving cycles of abuse.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hutchison recorded the new tracks at home in Châteauguay, Quebec (a refuge he describes as a &amp;quot;hard-won peace&amp;quot; in the release notes). These songs follow Cosmic Club&amp;#39;s 2024 recordings &lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Dream at Night&lt;/em&gt;. With the quartet Private Lives, Chance last played on &lt;em&gt;Salt of the Earth&lt;/em&gt;, issued in March through Cincinnati&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/feelitrecordshop/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Feel It Records&lt;/a&gt;. PRIORS were in the studio earlier this summer working on the follow-up to their 2023 &lt;a href="https://www.mothland.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mothland&lt;/a&gt; album &lt;em&gt;Daffodil&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3515279404/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cosmicclub.bandcamp.com/album/cosmic-club-2"&gt;COSMIC CLUB 2 by Cosmic Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pool Party</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-07-10-pool-party/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-07-10-pool-party/</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T16:19:53-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="puffer"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://puffpuffpuff.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Puffer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Street Hassle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://puffpuffpuff.bandcamp.com/album/street-hassle" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok, hear me out. I don&amp;#39;t know if my state of being reflects some collective societal exhaustion, but I&amp;#39;m feeling punch drunk. Everything, everywhere, seems to have lost the plot, and I&amp;#39;m just teetering through the days. While that&amp;#39;s been hell for my extra-curricular productivity (this newsletter in particular), I&amp;#39;m coming to enjoy the freewheeling unreality of it. In that headspace (or lack thereof), I keep running into new punk records that both sound great and feel right. I don&amp;#39;t have enough of a grasp on reality, let alone the culture, to claim that something&amp;#39;s in the air, but I am fucking &lt;em&gt;vibing&lt;/em&gt; on this shit, dude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal punks &lt;a href="https://puffpuffpuff.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Puffer&lt;/a&gt; are the real deal. On a textbook level, they&amp;#39;re not all that different from the street-level punk I&amp;#39;ve written about for two decades, but they nail the intangibles. We may be so far beyond the narrative thrust of the genre that we&amp;#39;re now free to relish its tropes without the baggage of authenticity. Who has the bandwidth to worry about anachronisms in this economy? I felt the same way about Edmonton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://arewenothomefront.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Home Front&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;#39;s perhaps no coincidence that &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Jonah Falco has his fingers in both bands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Falco masters the 11-song &lt;em&gt;Street Hassle&lt;/em&gt; from recordings Puffer made and mixed themselves. In the album&amp;#39;s press matter, he identifies a particularly Québécois character as essential to the band&amp;#39;s alchemy, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is Belgium with snowmobiles, Catholic Texas, Ugly France. All the crumbling highways, the coldest beers, and the loudest joints. Guitars do different things in Quebec. Puffer shimmy across the invisible barricade between Montreal and the rest of the world not just as another crop of punks but as the great descendants and inheritors of modern greats like &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/1179914-Inepsy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Inepsy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Rock and Roll Babylon&lt;/em&gt; and Annihilation Time&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;II.&lt;/em&gt; Loud, brash, unrelenting. You&amp;#39;ll go deaf before you get bored of it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Puffer charges through in a busy clamour of sleazy Mötorhead speed and barked, quasi-intelligible vocals that land somewhere between Slaughter and the Dogs and a kitchen garburator. They move those abrasive elements along with a hooky forward momentum that never seems to wander. It&amp;#39;s not punk to call them out on it, but Puffer demonstrates an impressively controlled level of discipline on these songs; &lt;em&gt;Street Hassle&lt;/em&gt; is remarkably efficient and dialled in, and that&amp;#39;s without a producer to rein the band in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album&amp;#39;s out now through Brooklyn&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://roachlegrecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Roachleg Records&lt;/a&gt; and London&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://staticshockrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Static Shock&lt;/a&gt;. It follows up on 2023&amp;#39;s self-titled EP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3834286985/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://puffpuffpuff.bandcamp.com/album/street-hassle"&gt;Street Hassle by PUFFER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="beton_arme"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://betonarmeoimtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Béton Armé&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Renaissance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://betonarmeoimtl.bandcamp.com/album/second-souffle" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I understand even less of the vocals on &lt;a href="https://betonarmeoimtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Béton Armé&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Renaissance&lt;/em&gt; than I do that Puffer record, but that&amp;#39;s just my failing as a dirty Anglophone. The Montreal bruisers transcend language, delivering a relentless sense of unity and that collective, fist-pumping joy that Oi! captures like few other genres. Sometimes, the unrestrained glee of a prolonged &amp;quot;woahhhhh&amp;quot; is all you need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band&amp;#39;s new LP gallops through eleven new songs in just over 20 minutes, ever indebted to the sound of their 80s forebearers but sounding very much of the moment. Label &lt;a href="https://www.lavidaesunmus.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;La Vida Es Un Mus&lt;/a&gt; offers a few touchstones in the album notes, citing the foundational influence of French Oi! pioneers L&amp;#39;infanterie Sauvage and the landmark Italian compilation &lt;em&gt;Quelli che urlano ancora&lt;/em&gt;. My hair&amp;#39;s far too long to claim firsthand knowledge of either. Béton Armé doesn&amp;#39;t stray far from that core, but they&amp;#39;re more focused than reverent. &lt;em&gt;Renaissance&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t shy from adopting the velocity of Californian hardcore, and while I&amp;#39;m told there are new wave flourishes here, they&amp;#39;re hardly at the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Béton Armé features vocalist Danick Joseph-Dicaire, guitarist Olivier Bérubé Sasseville, bassist Fabio Ciaraldi, and drummer Remi Aubie. The new record follows their 2023 EP &lt;em&gt;Second Souffle&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1652885997/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://lavidaesunmus.bandcamp.com/album/renaissance"&gt;Renaissance by Béton Armé&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="negative_charge"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://negativecharge204.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Negative Charge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Negative Charge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/negative-charge" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many bands named &lt;a href="https://negativecharge204.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Negative Charge&lt;/a&gt; in the world, but the only one you need to care about is a hardcore group from Winnipeg. While allegedly comprised of scene vets from &amp;quot;virtually every notable Winnipeg punk band from the past two decades,&amp;quot; that&amp;#39;s not a list I have. That kills me, as there&amp;#39;s nothing this newsletter enjoys more than peppering the reader with a long list of links to long-defunct regional favourites. I&amp;#39;m also not so dorky to throw around the word &amp;quot;supergroup&amp;quot; without evidence, but damn if the Negative Charge doesn&amp;#39;t seize that crown on their blistering debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band&amp;#39;s 11-song, self-titled LP is available now through &lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Neon Taste Records&lt;/a&gt;, carrying the torch of 80s legends like Jerry&amp;#39;s Kids and Poison Idea. The label&amp;#39;s gleefully confrontational press release lauds the band&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;abject ferocity&amp;quot; and their hardcore bona fides, demanding:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Know that this is no cash-in sequel to those aforementioned greats. This is no hyperbolic blow-hard bullshit. I dare you to try and prove me wrong. One of us will die on this hill and if Negative Charge is my soundtrack it won&amp;#39;t be me. Winnipeg Hardcore Now. Winnipeg Hardcore Forever.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neon Taste has the album out now on cassette and vinyl, all of which boast what may be the gnarliest cover art of the year by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/digital_3vil/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;@digital_3vil&lt;/a&gt;. Between this and that Puffer record, we can safely conclude that the genre&amp;#39;s doing just dandy in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3320488727/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://neontasterecords.bandcamp.com/album/negative-charge"&gt;Negative Charge by Negative Charge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="penny_the_pits"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://pennyandthepits.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Penny &amp;amp; The Pits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liquid Compactor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Pool Party&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/-OrxnTlj1T4?si=QUXwM52S-RudC_kJ" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://pennyandthepits.bandcamp.com/album/liquid-compactor" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m hot and cold on Fredericton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://motherhoodmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Motherhood&lt;/a&gt;. While I appreciate the devil-may-care attitude driving the trio&amp;#39;s art rock, they don&amp;#39;t exactly tailor their albums for casual listening. Penelope Stevens&amp;#39; new spinoff project &lt;a href="https://pennyandthepits.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Penny &amp;amp; The Pits&lt;/a&gt; hits differently. While &lt;em&gt;Liquid Compactor&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t shy away from spinning a similarly zany wheel of styles, The Pits wrap that dynamism in a cool surf-rock package that goes down easy. Stevens acknowledges this approach in a press release, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I spent a lot of time making challenging work that would test both myself and the listener. Now, I&amp;#39;m trying to make music that feels good; music that connects the heart to the body.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I shied away from the term a few paragraphs back, but I have no qualms in stating that the band Stevens assembled to pull this off reads like a Maritime underground supergroup. We&amp;#39;ve heard Megumi Yoshida in a raft of bands, from &lt;a href="http://dogdaymusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dog Day&lt;/a&gt; through &lt;a href="https://centuryegg.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Century Egg&lt;/a&gt; and most recently &lt;a href="https://shoulderseasonhfx.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Shoulder Season&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/colleencococollins" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Colleen Coco Collins&lt;/a&gt; was half of the esoteric indie duo &lt;a href="https://constructionanddestruction.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Construction &amp;amp; Destruction&lt;/a&gt; before adventuring off solo. Grace Stratton has roots in the Haligonian post-punk act &lt;a href="https://nightbummerz.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Nightbummerz&lt;/a&gt; and the queer punk act &lt;a href="https://glitterclit.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Glitterclit&lt;/a&gt;. Stevens further discussed the band&amp;#39;s motivation as a reflection of their audience:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When I was writing these songs, I imagined my closest femme &amp;amp; queer friends right up front, singing along. If I couldn&amp;#39;t picture them rocking out, then I would set the idea aside. With this album, I&amp;#39;m trying to manifest the heaviness, the intensity and the joy of our lived experiences.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Videos are available for several of the album&amp;#39;s lead singles, including &amp;quot;Headcrusher&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Montenegro On Ice.&amp;quot; Make sure to check out the darkwave surf highlight &amp;quot;Pool Party,&amp;quot; celebrated in motion by director Amelia Bailey. The 10-song &lt;em&gt;Liquid Compactor&lt;/em&gt; is now available through the &lt;a href="https://www.forwardmusicgroup.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Forward Music Group&lt;/a&gt;. The new record follows Motherhood&amp;#39;s recent LP, &lt;em&gt;Thunder Perfect Mind&lt;/em&gt;, issued in January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2484782542/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://pennyandthepits.bandcamp.com/album/liquid-compactor"&gt;Liquid Compactor by Penny &amp;amp; the Pits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="slow_dawn"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://slowdawn0.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Slow Dawn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sonic Death Flow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;In / Sight&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_sF-44e8pTM?si=3a2iJoWPubGjeFv_" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://slowdawn0.bandcamp.com/album/sonic-death-flow" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://slowdawn0.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Slow Dawn&lt;/a&gt; is fucking rad, and I&amp;#39;ve not given them the attention they deserve. My excuse is impossibly weak - their material isn&amp;#39;t readily streamable - but everything they do is right up my alley. With &lt;em&gt;Sonic Death Flow&lt;/em&gt;, they&amp;#39;ve delivered a fever dream of a record worth jumping whatever hoops it takes to listen to - an eight-song set packed with intense density and reverb-laden noise that marries confrontational punk with apocalyptic psychedelia. While the band bombards you in waves of dissonance, they never wander or lose the plot. Jam band noodling isn&amp;#39;t Slow Dawn&amp;#39;s game, and formless experimentalism doesn&amp;#39;t have the teeth they&amp;#39;re after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album arrived last month through the niche psychedelia labels &lt;a href="https://centripetalforcerecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Centripetal Force&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.cardinalfuzz.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cardinal Fuzz&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://psychichandshakerecordings.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Psychic Handshake&lt;/a&gt;, the latter handling the Canadian pressing. The band&amp;#39;s press describes them as &amp;quot;a full-throttle, mind-melting trip—a collision of motorik rhythms, Japanese space-punk, and psychotic guitar noise,&amp;quot; providing &amp;quot;a bleak, existential ride through the modern void.&amp;quot; Vocalist/guitarist Dan Druff layers cathartic, squelching No Wave atop a tight rhythmic core from drummer Chris D.R. DiLauro and bassist Jesse &amp;quot;Iceman&amp;quot; Winchester. The record finds Slow Dawn&amp;#39;s personnel split between Ottawa and Montreal, a circumstance which demonstrably had no ill effect on how well the band gels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view the lead single &amp;quot;In / Sight&amp;quot; in a glitchy, surrealist video on YouTube, with the complete record available to download through Bandcamp. The new album follows 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Into the Machine Haus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1310267373/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://slowdawn0.bandcamp.com/album/sonic-death-flow"&gt;Sonic Death Flow by Slow Dawn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cut_cult"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cutcult.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cut Cult&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;First Three&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Dinosaur&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/4XC7owC4-tI?si=KtcTsaW44GkAuCTG" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cutcult.bandcamp.com/album/first-three" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Past and present members of the lauded alt-electronica act &lt;a href="https://www.holyfuckmusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Holy Fuck&lt;/a&gt; have reunited as &lt;a href="https://cutcult.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cut Cult&lt;/a&gt; - a three-piece side-project rooted in grimy-yet-playful noise-punk. The band emerged in June with a three-song cassette plainly labelled as &lt;em&gt;First Three&lt;/em&gt;. Each of the collected songs, &amp;quot;Dinosaur,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Lame Horse,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;I Am Cut Cult,&amp;quot; arrived accompanied by music videos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a press release, Holy Fuck founder Brian Borcherdt detailed the creation of the harrowing &amp;quot;Dinosaur,&amp;quot; written and recorded at a cottage in Black Point, Nova Scotia. He revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We came up with this sort of lumbering monstrous baritone guitar part, something like a scary &amp;#39;Hella Good&amp;#39;-Neptunes kind of hook. We had the title &amp;#39;Dinosaur&amp;#39; due to this Godzilla vibe, but no words. I found a rehearsal tape that was perfect - it was still gibberish, but the vibe was right. Being centred around an 808 beat, I knew it&amp;#39;d fit. So I overlaid that take and was done.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cut Cult features Borcherdt and current Holy Fuck bassist Matt McQuaid, reunited with that project&amp;#39;s original drummer Loel Campbell (Wintersleep, Contrived). They&amp;#39;re joined on the recording by Màiri Chaimbeul on harp and synth bass. Matt Wiggins (Glass Animals, !!!, Florence and the Machine) mixed the EP with mastering by Matt Colton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cut Cult provides a rollicking counterpoint to Borcherdt&amp;#39;s far more sedate solo vehicle, &lt;a href="https://totallydusted.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dusted&lt;/a&gt;. Holy Fuck last issued the &amp;quot;Ninety-Five&amp;quot; single in 2022, following up on their 2020 LP &lt;em&gt;Deleter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2503138341/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cutcult.bandcamp.com/album/first-three"&gt;First Three by Cut Cult&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="rick_white"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://rickwhitearchive.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rick White&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://rickwhitearchive.bandcamp.com/album/rick-white-again-2025" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/artists/erics_trip" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eric&amp;#39;s Trip&lt;/a&gt; legend &lt;a href="https://rickwhitearchive.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rick White&lt;/a&gt; delivered &lt;em&gt;Again&lt;/em&gt;, a new 14-song collection of solo material. White wears lo-fi psych rock like a glove, and while fans likely know what to expect, the homespun charm of the artist&amp;#39;s prolific output never fails to delight. This batch stems from an effort to write, record, and mix a new song daily—a marathon that lasted from January 15 to March 10 of this year, resulting in nearly 60 complete tracks. White acknowledges the workmanlike nature in the album title, admitting it&amp;#39;s a process he&amp;#39;s employed on and off since the late 80s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d place &lt;em&gt;Again&lt;/em&gt; as the proper successor to 2021&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Where It&amp;#39;s Fine&lt;/em&gt;, but to draw that straight of a line ignores six or seven sideroads White explored in the interim. Those include the throwback-hardcore duo &lt;a href="https://tohc83.bandcamp.com/album/old-lp" class="" target="_blank"&gt;OLD&lt;/a&gt;, several albums of cover songs, and stylistic exercises like the new wave &lt;em&gt;Music Box&lt;/em&gt; and the feedback-drenched &lt;em&gt;De-Evolution&lt;/em&gt; EPs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The past few years have found the artist&amp;#39;s fate intertwined with that of the surviving members of &lt;a href="https://www.thesadies.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Sadies&lt;/a&gt;. Rick issued a full LP worth of cover songs in 2022 as a tribute to the late Dallas Good. He joined guitarist/vocalist Travis Good, bassist Sean Dean, and drummer Mike Belitsky for the 13-song &lt;em&gt;Rick White and the Sadies&lt;/em&gt; last year, an album of originals that landed on the Polaris Music Prize longlist. A live performance recorded in Toronto last September followed as the &lt;em&gt;Live at the Great Hall&lt;/em&gt; double LP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Again&lt;/em&gt; is out on vinyl through White&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://bluefogrecordings.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Blue Fog Recordings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=39410972/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://rickwhitearchive.bandcamp.com/album/rick-white-again-2025"&gt;RICK WHITE - AGAIN (2025) by Rick White Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
