<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter on independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated every Sunday evening by Adam White of Punknews.org. A sober second thought on new music, cool records, and the people making their own culture.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-05-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Pleasure Overdose</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-05-28-pleasure-overdose/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-05-28-pleasure-overdose/</id>
    <published>2017-05-27T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-28T23:25:21-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Part of my motivation in starting Some Party as a weekly newsletter was to force myself to operate outside the daily news cycle that Punknews and the rest of the Internet music apparatus thrives on. There&amp;#39;s a formula to how a new music is disseminated and it should sound familiar. A band will make mention of their next album, perhaps by sharing a title or who&amp;#39;s producing it, sometimes just their &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; to record, that will kick off a round of press coverage. In the lead-up to the release you&amp;#39;ll see the usual collection of stories, dribbled out over time. Studio photos show up on Instagram. Perhaps there&amp;#39;s a studio clip of the guitarist noodling out the hook from a new song on Facebook. Eventually a single shows up on SoundCloud or BandCamp, and it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;exclusively&amp;quot; announced on one news outlet or another. That repeats a few times and eventually the record&amp;#39;s released. The band, the label, a PR person if that&amp;#39;s in the budget, and the press kick that ball back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;What you&amp;#39;ll rarely see is news that an album &lt;em&gt;has been&lt;/em&gt; released. That crosses the incredibly nebulous line between reporting and promotion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While it&amp;#39;s become more common these days to see bands big and small forgo the lead-up and surprise fans with a new record, it&amp;#39;s remains awkward to report on. &amp;quot;Product exists for purchase&amp;quot; isn&amp;#39;t a great story. The exception of course is if the artist is of global name recognition, then the story shifts to how utterly awed we all are that they dared buck the system for the sake of their art, or some nonsense like that. Small bands don&amp;#39;t get to play that card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I was elated that this week saw the sudden and unheralded release of a new album from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://soupcans.info/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Soupcans&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pleasure Overdose&lt;/em&gt; is 9 songs in 18 minutes of erratic, gloriously bonkers punk rock from one of the city&amp;#39;s shining examples of how the genre can remain dangerous and unpredictable in 2017. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; was not only a release worth celebrating ,but it&amp;#39;s precisely the kind of thing I want to talk about on this newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3568221848/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thesoupcans.bandcamp.com/album/pleasure-overdose"&gt;Pleasure Overdose by Soupcans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Furthermore if you follow the band online one gets the distinct impression that they had broken up following  their late-2015 &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt; album &lt;em&gt;Soft Party&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than simply accept and celebrate this new record, my instinct was to put on my reporter hat and dig a bit. I reached out to the group and got in touch with bassist Nick (lastname withheld) who graciously agreed to talk to me. I proceeded to ignore the circumstances of the release and throw him a bunch of rote online music news questions (which in retrospect amounted to &amp;quot;please write me a press release&amp;quot;), followed by a postscript that read&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;If you&amp;#39;re shooting for a level of weird mystique with the whole thing then by all means don&amp;#39;t break that veil by telling me anything.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I did get answers, because Nick is great. I also got the distinct impression a veil of weird mystique is the preferred mode of operation for the band. If I was reporting for a news website I&amp;#39;d be more inclined to share the boring details I extracted, but that&amp;#39;s not the goal &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You should go listen to &lt;em&gt;Pleasure Overdose&lt;/em&gt; because it&amp;#39;s cool. It picks up on the speed and moments of pure sludge that made &lt;em&gt;Soft Party&lt;/em&gt; so vital, and tosses in a mix of free-flowing new ideas and deviations. Enjoy it for what it is. You can pay what you want for it at &lt;a href="https://thesoupcans.bandcamp.com/album/pleasure-overdose" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Human Party Trick&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I caught the first night of the &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; package tour in Hamilton on Thursday. While I&amp;#39;ve seen both the Dirty Nil and the Flatliners more times than I can recall, it was my first live experience with the Toronto-via-Waterloo group &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey and the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt;, who opened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While I enjoyed the band&amp;#39;s last record, the material they&amp;#39;ve assembled for their upcoming self-titled &lt;a href="http://burgerrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Burger&lt;/a&gt; / Dine Alone co-release is something else. The six-piece, in matching denim, put on one of the strongest and most engaging sets I&amp;#39;ve seen in a while. The new songs feel like big, muscular covers of 80s pop-rock hits and I mean that with as much affection as possible. This band&amp;#39;s been all over the place stylistically in the past, but the place they&amp;#39;ve landed is really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/318509292&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The rest of the bill had me playing anthropologist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;My love affair with Dundas, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thedirtynil/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; is pretty well known, but I couldn&amp;#39;t help but be a little worried about the band. After countless small bar shows the last time I saw them was opening for Flag, and they had the unforgiving task of opening a sparsely filled Lee&amp;#39;s Palace, which felt cavernous and foreign. This would also be the first time I&amp;#39;ve seen them perform since losing bassist Dave Nardi. I had no doubts that Ross Miller, his replacement, would be able to carry the songs. Ross has been a fixture in the Niagara music scene for years and he&amp;#39;s proven to be everyone&amp;#39;s go-to &lt;a href="https://sidemanhc.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;sideman&lt;/a&gt;. Dave&amp;#39;s absence is notable because his stoic stage presence and aggressive, serious performance always felt like a perfect counterpoint to frontman Luke Bentham&amp;#39;s playful, showy charisma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Nil sounded great though. Ross isn&amp;#39;t Dave, but he wasn&amp;#39;t trying to dial back his own strong personality to fit someone&amp;#39;s mould. It&amp;#39;s a new dynamic, but it worked. The more intimate venue (&lt;a href="http://www.clubabsinthe.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Club Absinthe&lt;/a&gt;) and the hometown crowd shook off any sense of fatigue I sensed back at that Flag gig. It&amp;#39;ll remain to be seen what kind of material the band writes without Nardi&amp;#39;s tastes in the mix, but so far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theflatliners.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Flatliners&lt;/a&gt; have been through their current trials before. The band had been easing away from their 3rd wave ska trappings for years but with 2010&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Cavalcade&lt;/em&gt; made that transition complete. There were shows back then where you could feel the crowd&amp;#39;s trepidation with the new material. A room that was bouncing one minute locked still the next until something familiar returned. The big punk anthems the band was writing though turned out to be so damn likable that it didn&amp;#39;t take long for those to become the new standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The songs of &lt;em&gt;Inviting Light&lt;/em&gt;, the new record, step away from the roaring anthems and fist-pumping crowd-pleasers. What you&amp;#39;re left with is a rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll band with few genre conventions to hide under. I&amp;#39;m not sure the crowd was quite into it yet, but what struck me seeing them live is that these new songs have incredibly strong bones. It may not be what a lot of the old guard fans want, but the songwriting&amp;#39;s there and the band&amp;#39;s confident in it. There&amp;#39;s a pretty dynamic set list to be built between these and the &lt;em&gt;Cavalcade&lt;/em&gt; era anthems as well. I&amp;#39;m feeling a lot better about this record than I was initially.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ff8KCvbxkZA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;That said, after the requisite encore of the decade-old ska-punk favourite &amp;quot;Fred&amp;#39;s Got Slacks,&amp;quot; someone turned to me and said ecstatically &amp;quot;Dude! It&amp;#39;s like high school!&amp;quot; so I&amp;#39;m not sure what people really want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://ottawabeat.com/2017/05/18/brief-history-ottawa-explosion-weekend/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Beat&lt;/a&gt; has written up a brief history of the &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion Weekend&lt;/a&gt; that delves into the shows and scenes that preceded, and gave raise to the now-annual garage-punk festival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;One band playing this year&amp;#39;s Explosion is Hamilton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://sweetdaveandtheshallowgraves.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sweet Dave and the Shallow Graves&lt;/a&gt;, the gothic, esoteric project of &lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; David O&amp;#39;Connor. His touring band, which in fact includes the aforementioned Dave Nardi, will hit the road following this Summer in an eastward trek to land them at &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sappyfest&lt;/a&gt; in Sackville, New Brunswick in early August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;div class='dib tl w-100 maxread'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media dib tl" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BUhWjMvDm4W/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank"&gt;SWEET DAVE &amp;amp; THE SHALLOW GRAVES SUMMER 2017 TOUR DATES: Friday, June 16. Ottawa - OXW - Avante Garde Bar Thursday, June 22. Hamilton - Doors Pub w/Dead Soft Thursday, June 29. Toronto - Baby G w/Fotocrime  Friday, July 14. Paris, ON - Strangewaves w/The Urinals  Friday, July 28. Hamilton - Boxcar w/Teenanger &amp;amp; Big School Saturday, July 29. Ottawa - House of Targ w/Teenanger Sunday, July 30. Montreal - TBA w/Teenanger Tuesday, August 1. Quebec City - L'Anti Bar w/Teenanger Wednesday, August 2. Fredericton - TBA w/Teenanger  Thursday, August 3. Halifax - The Seahorse w/Teenanger &amp;amp; Booji Boys Friday, August 4 - Sappyfest Saturday, August 5 - Sappyfest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A post shared by David O'Connor (@sweeetdave) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2017-05-25T15:56:07+00:00"&gt;May 25, 2017 at 8:56am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;div class='dib tl w-100 maxread'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"&gt;
&lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/head&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Keeping with the theme of referencing musicians from earlier in this very newsletter, new Dirty Nil bassist Ross Miller also plays with London, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt;. That band&amp;#39;s new record &lt;em&gt;Our Pleasure&lt;/em&gt; arrives on June 16th via Dine Alone. They previewed the new song &amp;quot;Leash&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="http://www.brooklynvegan.com/stream-single-mothers-leash-off-upcoming-lp/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brooklyn Vegan&lt;/a&gt; this week and have &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/singlemothersparty/events/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;three release shows&lt;/a&gt; announced in Ontario this June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/324337394&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;ll leave you with a feel-good story about the teenage Peel band Vinyl Ambush. The group was playing a house party that was hit with a noise complaint, and the police officer who arrived at the scene ended up playing with them. You can find the full account at &lt;a href="http://www.citynews.ca/2017/05/21/peel-police-officer-rocks-local-band-vinyl-ambush/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;City News&lt;/a&gt; and see the evidence below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iV788SBdjyw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A huge thanks to the folks at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring this first month of the Some Party newsletter. Check out the great selection at their online record stores at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.ca&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl.com&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;#39;re south of the border. They&amp;#39;ve got friendly physical locations at both 5904 Main St in Niagara Falls and 1695 Queen St West in Toronto for you to check out too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>React To It At Your Leisure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-05-22-react-to-it-at-your-leisure/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-05-22-react-to-it-at-your-leisure/</id>
    <published>2017-05-21T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-28T08:18:44-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;There are people I&amp;#39;ve known for close to a decade who&amp;#39;ve had the same projects in the works, out of the public eye, for the entire length of our acquaintance. I&amp;#39;m a programmer. These folks are programmers. Our personal projects suffer from both the insidious nature of &lt;em&gt;busy&lt;/em&gt;, and because our tools are, by their nature, moving targets. There&amp;#39;s always a better way to do something if you wait and do it in the future. We endlessly rebuild and rethink these labours of love, fretting over buried details that will be inconsequential to those with whom we&amp;#39;re ultimately trying to communicate. The cobbler&amp;#39;s children go barefoot, and all that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In the span of time I&amp;#39;ve spent overthinking what form Some Party should take, &lt;a href="http://www.danielromanomusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt; released at least five records. Perhaps more, if you count both this solo efforts and his power-pop band Ancient Shapes. From one record to the next the Welland-native shifts genres fearlessly. As a listener it sometimes feels like you&amp;#39;re studying the history of pop music and you just skipped a lecture. The last notes you scribbled were on the American folk revival, and suddenly it&amp;#39;s the early 70s and everything&amp;#39;s lush and druggy. Styles and influences change, but what remains constant is that the artist ultimately committed to what they released. You don&amp;#39;t analyze much half-hearted, unsure music in music history class. You certainly don&amp;#39;t talk about all the songs written but never recorded. The half-starts. The non-starts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u0Twtm6ZdeI?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Some Party is a weekly newsletter about Canadian rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll. I&amp;#39;m committing to that. Whatever it may become one day is inconsequential. We may not be big, but we&amp;#39;re small.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Dan Romano&amp;#39;s LP &lt;em&gt;Modern Pressure&lt;/em&gt; was released this past Friday. Jim Di Gioia of &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dominionated&lt;/a&gt;, who&amp;#39;s followed Romano&amp;#39;s career extensively, &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/albums/daniel-romano-modern-pressure/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;captured&lt;/a&gt; it beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Romano calls his sound “Mosey” music (naming his last album after it), and Modern Pressure further refines and defines what that sound is: a manipulation of genre and form; intricate layers and wild arrangements; the kinetic energy of inspiration and creativity. The history of popular music is malleable in Romano’s hands, and he crafts songs that are both familiar and challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Both familiar and challenging&amp;quot; is what I&amp;#39;ll shoot for here as well, and I hope it  \trends towards the latter as I find my groove. I&amp;#39;ve never felt more useful in my 16 years at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews.org&lt;/a&gt; then when I was enforcing my own incessant Cancon quota, covering the releases from Stomp, Mint, G7, and Three Gut in the same stream that people were reading for the latest Fat Wreck news. To my delight the amount of cool stuff going on in Canada recently has demanded the scene&amp;#39;s attention without my help. Even as I&amp;#39;ve slowed my daily contributions, bands like &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thedirtynil/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theflatliners.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Flatliners&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; have become fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;As I rethink my place in all of this, I see the value in approaching independent and underground music with an eye on geography rather than genre. The journey from the early pop punk of Attack In Black to Daniel Romano&amp;#39;s country records through to whatever he decides comprises &amp;quot;Mosey&amp;quot; is a fascinating one. The solo efforts of his bandmates &lt;a href="https://www.spencerburtonmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Spencer Burton&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://electricenlightenment.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ian Kehoe&lt;/a&gt; are equally compelling, but it all falls outside the Punknews umbrella. How about the fact that Attack In Black&amp;#39;s drummer (and Dan&amp;#39;s little brother) Ian is now playing hardcore with Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/careersuicidehc" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Career Suicide&lt;/a&gt;, or that Career Suicide also now features Dallas Good of alt-country legends &lt;a href="http://www.thesadies.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Sadies&lt;/a&gt;? It&amp;#39;s too much! It&amp;#39;s just too cool! It&amp;#39;s too &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; as a narrative and that narrative will only get the space it deserves if the genre focus is &amp;quot;Ontario,&amp;quot; or more broadly &amp;quot;Canada.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/294122098&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Some Party&amp;#39;s going to pull on some of these threads and see where they go. I&amp;#39;ll do this while sharing some of the new sounds emerging from across the country. A weekly newsletter feels like the right speed, so that&amp;#39;s where I&amp;#39;m starting. Let&amp;#39;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class='bg-black-30 mt4 mb6 maxread bn hr-1'/&gt;&lt;p class='tc center'&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/the-secrets.jpg" alt="The Secrets from the Success Without College album cover" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Not Them! Not Here!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This past week saw the loss of first-wave Toronto punk veteran Freddy Pompeii. The Philadelphia native&amp;#39;s late 70s stint as guitarist for the notorious &lt;a href="http://www.viletonesofficial.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Viletones&lt;/a&gt; and later frontman of &lt;a href="http://www.canadianbands.com/Secrets.html" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Secrets&lt;/a&gt; left an indelible mark on the city&amp;#39;s emergent alternative music scene. There&amp;#39;s a nice career summary and some great photos by Don Pyle over at &lt;a href="https://nowtoronto.com/music/in-memoriam-freddy-pompeii-viletones-the-secrets-1947-20/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;NOW Toronto&lt;/a&gt; that you should absolutely devote some time to. It&amp;#39;s worth revisiting his 2015 chat with Damian Abraham on the &lt;a href="https://www.acast.com/turnedoutapunk/episode-60-freddie-pompeii-viletones-secrets-" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Turned Out A Punk&lt;/a&gt; podcast as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Of course this past week also saw the loss of Soundgarden&amp;#39;s Chris Cornell. While a great deal has been written in the past few days, take a few minutes to read the piece by &lt;a href="https://greys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Greys&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Shezaad Jiwani at &lt;a href="http://hazlitt.net/feature/one-more-time-around-remembering-chris-cornell" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hazlitt&lt;/a&gt;. It speaks to the questions posed by the mental health aspects of Cornell&amp;#39;s death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;At least you landed it&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://soupcans.info/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Soupcans&lt;/a&gt; released one of the coolest, loudest, and sludgiest noise-punk records in recent memory with &lt;a href="https://thesoupcans.bandcamp.com/album/soft-party" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Soft Party&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but the band&amp;#39;s been seemingly defunct since. They are up to something though, dripping hints on social media pointing to their website. A date hidden there says &amp;quot;May 23rd&amp;quot; so we may learn more in the immediate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Noisey premiered the song &amp;quot;&lt;a href="https://noisey.vice.com/en_ca/article/bad-channels-conjure-an-80s-prom-in-a-garage-on-exo" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exo&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; a synth-pop track from the the Toronto electronic act &lt;a href="https://badchannels.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bad Channels&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s got that dark 80s feel that&amp;#39;s currently in vogue and is slated to appear on their new EP for &lt;a href="http://buzzrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Buzz Records&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;Lost Time I&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;TO party-punk act &lt;a href="https://www.pkewx3.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pkew Pkew Pkew&lt;/a&gt; participated in an &lt;a href="https://audiotree.tv/session/pkew-pkew-pkew" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Audiotree&lt;/a&gt; live recording. The band ended up performing each and every song from their recent self-titled full length for the session, which is on video and available for purchase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AEXthjGaVJ4?list=PLunIrIqYqs799ZfL68e8EIi7y1f8Jt6hc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A recent episode of the &lt;a href="http://www.canadaland.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Canadaland&lt;/a&gt; podcast featured guest host &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/omar_aok" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Omar Mouallem&lt;/a&gt; leading a roundtable discussion titled &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.canadalandshow.com/podcast/rap-lyrics-land-prison/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Why Your Rap Lyrics Could Land You In Prison&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;quot; His guests, which included criminologist Adam Dunbar, sociologist Jooyoung Lee, and lawyer Hilary Dudding, discussed the legal line between artistic expression and admission of criminal activity. They consider the history of court cases in Canada and abroad in which a rapper&amp;#39;s lyrics have been a factor in the courtroom, and both the racial and socioeconomic implications that result. It&amp;#39;s fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.needlesxpins.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Needles//Pins&lt;/a&gt; have unveiled &amp;quot;All The Same&amp;quot; from their upcoming  full length &lt;em&gt;Good Night Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;s growling melodic punk rock track that anyone who grew up in the EpiFat 90s should dig. They band&amp;#39;s slated to be part of a Mint Records showcase at this June&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion&lt;/a&gt; alongside the reunited Smugglers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2533488215/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://needlesxpins.bandcamp.com/album/good-night-tomorrow-mint-records-dirt-cult-records"&gt;Good Night, Tomorrow (Mint Records/Dirt Cult Records) by NEEDLES//PINS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Flatliners&amp;#39; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CrustCrustwell" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Cresswell&lt;/a&gt; was interviewed on Mark Fraser&amp;#39;s Glasgow-based podcast &lt;a href="http://thecuratorpodcast.com/tc61-season-2-episode-14-chris-cresswell-flatliners/?utm_content=buffer169bd&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Curator&lt;/a&gt; about the band&amp;#39;s new record, label, and evolving sonic direction. Count me as an early skeptic of &lt;em&gt;Inviting Light&lt;/em&gt; but it&amp;#39;s been in near constant rotation here as I wrestle with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally next Sunday (May 27th) is once again &lt;a href="http://droneday.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drone Day&lt;/a&gt;, with events celebrating and creating long-form ambient music taking place across the country. The Day is the brainchild of &lt;a href="https://weirdcanada.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Weird Canada&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/omarieclaire" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Marie LeBlanc Flanagan&lt;/a&gt; and the individual events are community organized and likely to be quite varied, improvisational, and participatory. It&amp;#39;s something to experience even if you regularly prefer your music to have, you know, some semblance of rhythm and structure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thanks to the folks at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring this first month of the Some Party newsletter. I&amp;#39;ve known Danny and Jenna for as long as I&amp;#39;ve been involved in music. The scappy internet radio station they used to run was a constant companion when Punknews was young. Check out their online record store at &lt;a href="https://www.srcvinyl.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;srcvinyl&lt;/a&gt; and their physical locations in both Toronto and Niagara Falls.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
