<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>Some Party is a newsletter sharing the latest in independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated more-or-less weekly by Adam White. Each edition explores punk, garage, psych, and otherwise uncategorizable indie rock, drawing lines from proto to post and taking some weird diversions along the way.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2025-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Luna FM</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-26-luna-fm/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-26-luna-fm/</id>
    <published>2025-03-25T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-26T21:17:37-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="the_burning_hell"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/ghost-palace" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; are two or three albums into a dance with the apocalypse. Their early attempts maintained a nervous edge while wrestling with the unspeakable, treating societal collapse with gallows humour and powerless anxiety. The specific means to our collective doom was never the focus, though, and Mathias Kom lent his dense wordplay to chronicling ground-level stories of the survivors. Sometimes, that manifested as playful anti-folk songs cataloging the messy cultural detritus left in our wake. As that vision matured, as on 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Garbage Island&lt;/em&gt;, the focus shifted from humanity and addressed the surviving birds (it&amp;#39;s not their first rodeo, either).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt;, the disaster, whatever it is (and we&amp;#39;re free to take our pick), feels further out of focus, never forgotten but almost mundane in its inevitability. The Burning Hell&amp;#39;s outlook remains less dystopian than it is curiously bemused. This is best expressed in the funky psych-rock highlight &amp;quot;Luna FM,&amp;quot; told from the perspective of the moon&amp;#39;s premiere and loneliest DJ. It&amp;#39;s a one-way dialogue between the bored radio operator and a listenership that&amp;#39;s maybe entirely vanished. The song&amp;#39;s one of several stylistic swings on the 11-song record, which hops nimbly between tropical beach jams, quirky synth-rock, and even twangy, fiddle-driven country. Kom&amp;#39;s lyricism remains an unparalleled firehose of cultural references and wry outsider observations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt; arrived in early March through &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://bbislandmusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;BB*Island&lt;/a&gt;. The Burning Hell&amp;#39;s core remains the PEI-based pair of singer/songwriter Mathias Kom and the multi-talented Ariel Sharratt. Their band again features St. John&amp;#39;s-based producer/instrumentalist &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; and fiddler/vocalist Maria Peddle. Guest composer &lt;a href="https://carliehowell.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carlie Howell&lt;/a&gt; (The Electric Storm Collective, Beverly Glenn-Copeland) appears on the record alongside &lt;a href="http://theconstantines.wordpress.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Constantines&lt;/a&gt; guitarist &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/josecontrerasmusik/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;José Contreras&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;, and Amy Nicoll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a critic (or whatever I am), I realize that the external state of world affairs shouldn&amp;#39;t colour my objective view of a piece of art. Still, existential threats abound, and it&amp;#39;s hard not to perceive the band&amp;#39;s exploration of post-apocalyptic idiosyncracies as an expression of hope. We&amp;#39;re still here, after all. I think The Burning Hell ultimately finds our dishevelled humanity endearing, with Kom never succumbing to angst or bitterness in the face of upheaval and near-certain ruin. Given the vibe in the country, it&amp;#39;s something we could all aspire to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2494821677/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/license_id=4342/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/ghost-palace"&gt;Ghost Palace by The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="jake_nicoll"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Hold&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/album/on-hold" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;#39;re in the orbit of &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;, we should take note that &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; recently issued a solo EP to mark a significant milestone. Released in early February, the five-song &lt;em&gt;On Hold&lt;/em&gt; captures the nervous anticipation of impending parenthood. Nicoll wrote and recorded the set while he and partner Pamela Mackenzie waited for the birth of their first child last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EP&amp;#39;s opener, &amp;quot;Waiting Room,&amp;quot; directly references the Fugazi anthem of the same name, pairing vintage synths and gated drums with samples from the hospital&amp;#39;s phone tree. &amp;quot;Galloping Horses&amp;quot; builds a synth-pop earworm around the pulse of a fetal heart monitor, giving the young Mackenzie Nicoll their first album credit. The high BPM of the Doppler drives the track towards a &amp;quot;synthy love-child of Kraftwerk and Men Without Hats.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 25-minute collection follows Nicoll&amp;#39;s 2024 release &lt;em&gt;Lonely Mission&lt;/em&gt;, an accomplished full-length that focused the producer on &amp;quot;the larger questions of life and the future of this warming planet.&amp;quot; That music emerged from pandemic-era isolation on Nicoll&amp;#39;s family farm in Ontario, where Jake built a cabin studio with a workshop full of vintage recording equipment. In 2023, Jake and Pamela issued the split indie-folk album &lt;em&gt;End Daze&lt;/em&gt; under the name &lt;a href="https://pamiandjake.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pami and Jake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3551138994/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/album/on-hold"&gt;ON HOLD by Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="michael_cloud_duguay"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com/album/wobbly-yonder" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peterborough luminary &lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt; recently announced &lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt;, a new solo LP arriving April 25 through &lt;a href="https://watchthatendsthenight.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Watch That Ends The Night&lt;/a&gt;. The album finds the introspective singer-songwriter amassing a staggering roster of 19 collaborators from across the Canadian indie spectrum. That list includes the aforementioned Mathias Kom, Ariel Sharratt, and Jake Nicoll of &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; (if the through-line in this edition of Some Party wasn&amp;#39;t already obvious, I&amp;#39;ve been sitting on a serendipitous tangle of connective tissue). You can preview the album through the lushly orchestrated dream-pop of &amp;quot;Immutable White Light.&amp;quot; On the single, the artist revealed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Immutable White Light&amp;#39; is about the seemingly fixed nature of our internal lives, and the inability to witness spiritual progress in oneself except for in hindsight. It is about how, in my darkest moments, my true inner self was never lost but was obfuscated by external concerns. It&amp;#39;s about how grace and light can be found through connection with a higher power and one&amp;#39;s authentic self.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Only Angel In Sight,&amp;quot; co-written by Toronto&amp;#39;s Sara Jarvie-Clark (&lt;a href="https://analoguesofmay.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Analogues of May&lt;/a&gt;), is also available to stream. The press release describes a slow-burning folk epic that &amp;quot;explores themes of social paranoia and inhibition&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;the psychedelic experience and fuzzy contracts of fledgling romance.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While increasingly prolific, Duguay doesn&amp;#39;t issue new material lightly. It often feels that each step in the artist&amp;#39;s career is hard-won and the subject of much consternation. &lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt; has similar roots, stemming from a traumatic 2009 experience when Duguay performed as part of The Burning Hell at Slovakia&amp;#39;s Pohoda Festival. A catastrophic storm struck the event, claiming two lives and injuring dozens. &amp;quot;The experience cracked something open in me,&amp;quot; recalls Duguay, who stepped away from music for an extended period following the incident. The artist&amp;#39;s output in the years since often explicitly addresses mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album finds Duguay reconnecting with The Burning Hell principles, with Kom and Sharratt sharing performance and production credits. Furthermore, at their urging the Duguay recorded with &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Scamper&lt;/em&gt;, a solar-powered studio built in a 70s-era camper RV. This mobile setup allowed the artist to record exclusively in unconventional spaces, from beaches to an abandoned farmhouse to the lantern room of PEI&amp;#39;s East Point Lighthouse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eight-song &lt;em&gt;Wobbly Yonder&lt;/em&gt; features appearances from &lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;, Andrew MacKelvie (&lt;a href="https://newhermitage.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;New Hermitage&lt;/a&gt;, Scions), Jamie Kronick (Scattered Clouds), &lt;a href="https://carliehowell.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carlie Howell&lt;/a&gt; (Beverly Glenn-Copeland), &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/josecontrerasmusik/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;José Contreras&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;a href="https://owendaviesmusic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Owen Davies&lt;/a&gt;, among others. Stylistically, the record leaps from ambient interludes to anthemic rock and hushed folk ballads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This release follows a productive 2024 for Duguay, which saw him crystallize his &amp;quot;experimental heartland totalism&amp;quot; on the full-length &lt;em&gt;Succeeder&lt;/em&gt;. That year also saw the acclaimed debut of the experimental ensemble &lt;a href="https://scions.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Scions&lt;/a&gt;. They issued &lt;em&gt;To Cry Out In The Wilderness&lt;/em&gt; through &lt;a href="https://www.ideefixerecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Idée Fixe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1329027024/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://michaelcloudduguay.bandcamp.com/album/wobbly-yonder"&gt;Wobbly Yonder by Michael Cloud Duguay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="eliza_niemi"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/album/progress-bakery" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s new LP is something special. It so singularly captivates that I&amp;#39;ve spent the past week listening to either &lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; on repeat or nothing. In 2025, we cling to whatever slight reprieve we can find. You all know why. It&amp;#39;s survival. That Niemi can hook you while favouring quiet moments and sparse arrangements makes her new album a welcome salve. Whether she intended it that way doesn&amp;#39;t much matter. It could be a happy accident, but it&amp;#39;s a perfect counterpoint to the turmoil du jour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; arrived last week through &lt;a href="https://vainmina.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Vain Mina&lt;/a&gt; and the UK-based &lt;a href="https://tinangelrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tin Angel Records&lt;/a&gt;, delivering 15 songs that percolate with clever observations and a deft sense of minimalism that&amp;#39;s always friendly, never austere. The record features a notable cast of Toronto indie musicians, including &lt;a href="https://mothertongues.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mother Tongues&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Jeremy Ray, Evan Cartwright (Tasseomancy, US Girls), &lt;a href="https://louieshort.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Louie Short&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://littlekid.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Little Kid&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Kenny Boothby, Ed Squires of the &lt;a href="https://badgeepoque.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Badge Époque Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;, Steven McPhail from &lt;a href="https://mrjoy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mr. Joy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://dorotheapaas.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dorothea Paas&lt;/a&gt; among others. Short and Ray co-produced the album alongside Niemi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; follows Niemi&amp;#39;s 2022 solo debut, &lt;em&gt;Staying Mellow Blows&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;#39;ve undoubtedly heard her on various Canadian records over the past few years, often adding depth on the cello. Pre-pandemic, she co-led the Montreal indie rock act &lt;a href="https://mauno.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mauno&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Progress Bakery&lt;/em&gt; surpasses it all, and it&amp;#39;s one of the early standouts of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=900516666/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://elizaniemi.bandcamp.com/album/progress-bakery"&gt;Progress Bakery by Eliza Niemi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cassia_hardy"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cassia Hardy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Empress&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/track/empress" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wares.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Wares&lt;/a&gt; principle &lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cassia Hardy&lt;/a&gt; recently shared a long-in-the-works ode to the defunct Edmonton venue, The Empress Ale House. The venue had a 13-year run from 2007 through 2020, employing many musicians from the city&amp;#39;s local scene. &amp;quot;Empress&amp;quot; builds Hardy&amp;#39;s specific recollections to reflect on the community&amp;#39;s broader loss of shared cultural spaces. The artist describes the rollicking-yet-wistful noise-pop track as &amp;quot;a composite photo of a few places close to my heart as a patron and a worker.&amp;quot; She elaborates:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Head and shoulders above them was The Empress. I can still see the way it looked at last call, when the house lights went up. Animal skulls lined the blood red walls, the dark wooden tables at once sticky and slippery. We served beer by the imperial pint, free pretzels, and a petrified $30 hungry man dinner in the freezer to satisfy the license.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As unique as it was, like so many other places, the landlords got greedy and didn&amp;#39;t know what they were messing with. Some folks who went might never know what happened, some might not care to, and more and more will never have seen it at all. Sometimes the sweet things in life don&amp;#39;t burn out or fade away, they are taken.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt McKeen recorded the song, which Hardy dedicates to Empress owner Sue Kiernan. It&amp;#39;s the first we&amp;#39;ve heard from Cassia since Wares&amp;#39; 2023 singles &amp;quot;Graceless/Cloudless,&amp;quot; which followed their 2020 album &lt;em&gt;Survival&lt;/em&gt;. The new tune arrives via &lt;a href="https://www.mintrecs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1261248389/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cassiahardy.bandcamp.com/track/empress"&gt;Empress by Cassia Hardy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brutal Planet</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-05-brutal-planet/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-03-05-brutal-planet/</id>
    <published>2025-03-04T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-06T12:20:35-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is it March? Wow, I&amp;#39;m late to publish. What can I say? Existential threats are distracting as hell. Here&amp;#39;s what some of our nationally renown guitar deviants have been up to while I&amp;#39;ve been staring into the void.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="golden_shitters"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Golden Shitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brutal Planet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/G8VF9o_XVt4?si=IyVaxju2sl31o6Lu" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com/album/brutal-planet" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamilton&amp;#39;s scuzzy punk supergroup &lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Golden Shitters&lt;/a&gt; are back with &lt;em&gt;Brutal Planet&lt;/em&gt;, their sophomore 12&amp;quot; arriving this Friday through &lt;a href="https://uglypoprecords.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ugly Pop Records&lt;/a&gt;. The collection promises twelve songs delivered with proudly lowbrow charm in the lunkheaded lineage of the Ramones. Through that lens, the Shitters channel The Spits&amp;#39;s deadpan drone and Screeching Weasel&amp;#39;s bratty snot. It&amp;#39;s a tried-and-true sound, but so perfect in its inception, there&amp;#39;s a reason we always come back to it. You can see the title track celebrated in a new video (yes, that&amp;#39;s Patrick and Ripley from &lt;a href="https://packratpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pack Rat&lt;/a&gt; in the starring roles).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this round, the Shitters maintain their core lineup of Matt Ellis (&lt;a href="https://anxiouspleasers.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Anxious Pleasers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://the-vapids.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Vapids&lt;/a&gt;) and Dave Tyson (&lt;a href="https://darktrip.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dark Trip&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey &amp;amp; the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt;) trading off guitar, bass, and vocals, backed by &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Kyle Fisher on drums. The group self-recorded with Dave mixing and Sean Pearson (TV Freaks, the Black Halos) mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ugly Pop lauds the band&amp;#39;s old-school approach, likewise promising a no-gimmicks run on black vinyl. They boast:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;all the reckless speed and raw tunes, plus tasty guitar flash and lyrics very much of our time. This stuff will never, ever get old as long as it&amp;#39;s executed with the spirit and power found here in spades... It&amp;#39;s punk rock with bad taste and a B-movie bathroom budget.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows Golden Shitters&amp;#39; 2024 EP &lt;em&gt;Love Blows&lt;/em&gt;, a digital-only live record captured at Hamilton&amp;#39;s Vertagogo, and their self-titled 2023 LP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1744127730/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goldenshitters.bandcamp.com/album/brutal-planet"&gt;Brutal Planet by Golden Shitters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="loud_hands"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Loud Hands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loud Hands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com/album/loud-hands" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hamilton also recently saw the full-length debut of &lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Loud Hands&lt;/a&gt;, a grungy indie-rock quartet. The project features brothers Shane and Matt Cabral sharing guitar and vocal duties, backed by a rhythm section featuring their cousin, drummer Zander Lamothe, and bassist/vocalist David O&amp;#39;Connor. You&amp;#39;ll likely recognize the latter as the bombastic Sweet Dave of powerhouse punks &lt;a href="https://teeveefreakzz.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TV Freaks&lt;/a&gt;. His role here is comparatively one of restraint, appearing almost as a mentor to what&amp;#39;s otherwise a family affair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dave announced the project and the band&amp;#39;s first show a few weeks back, graciously calling Loud Hands:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...the silver lining in an otherwise dark cloud. A tiny little rosebud growing out of a crack in the concrete. Two brothers, a cousin and me. Brothers writing songs together has a magic that I can&amp;#39;t really explain but I&amp;#39;m so happy to be a part of it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;O&amp;#39;Connor recorded the group last year, with mixing and mastering handled in Australia by the ever-present Mikey Young (Dumb, Itchy Self, Motorists). You can find the ten-song self-titled set streaming everywhere and available to download at Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=4026334281/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://loudhands.bandcamp.com/album/loud-hands"&gt;Loud Hands by Loud Hands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="private_lives"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Psychic Beat&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3IOsHbW5np4?si=0KsxXUXUjoOkAUE_" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com/album/salt-of-the-earth" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal power pop/garage punk/post-something-or-other quartet &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt; have their sophomore album on deck. &lt;em&gt;Salt of the Earth&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 21 through Cincinnati&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/feelitrecordshop/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Feel It Records&lt;/a&gt;, as previewed through the peppy new single &amp;quot;Psychic Beat.&amp;quot; The song shows some welcome carryover of the attitude-driven girl-group energy vocalist Jackie Blenkarn once used to great effect with the &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s one of 10 songs from the new record. You can see it performed in an appropriately jittery new video from Alan Hildebrandt of &lt;a href="https://www.studiodelscorpio.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Studio Del Scorpio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Private Lives features Blenkarn backed by her spouse Chance Hutchison (&lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar, with bassist Josh Herlihey (&lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt;), and drummer Drew Demers (also of PRIORS) holding down the low-end. Hutchison engineered and mixed the album with the aforementioned Mikey Young mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows the group&amp;#39;s 2023 debut &lt;em&gt;Hit Record&lt;/em&gt;, and promises a further evolution from the band&amp;#39;s origins as Chance and Jackie&amp;#39;s lockdown-era timekiller. Paperface Zine&amp;#39;s Joe Massaro lauds the album for &amp;quot;undercutting power pop conventions and challenging itself track after track.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3624111497/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com/album/salt-of-the-earth"&gt;Salt of the Earth by Private Lives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="dvtr"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;DVTR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Né pour flâner&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SMpuGuhrxf0?si=fP2-n2VLo8tQW1l6" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/track/n-pour-fl-ner" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new single from frenetic Quebec synth-punk duo &lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;DVTR&lt;/a&gt; offers a reprieve from the heavier topics with an ode to idleness. &amp;quot;Né pour flâner&amp;quot; (born to loiter) arrived earlier this month via &lt;a href="https://lisbonluxrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lisbon Lux Records&lt;/a&gt;, alongside a camcorder video chronicling the band&amp;#39;s recent Asian tour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group commented on their uncharacteristically upbeat approach to the track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve been lashing out at everything with our music recently: patriarchy, the death industry, corrupt cops, the goddamn Olympics and whatnot. 2025 is kumbaya, so here&amp;#39;s some POSITIVE energy, with a track about something DVTR loves, for once. Loitering! Let&amp;#39;s bring loitering back in style, ok bye.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new single follows a busy year that saw DVTR tour Japan, South Korea, the UK, and Europe while making festival appearances at major events like Osheaga. They capped 2024 with a sold-out hometown gig at Montreal&amp;#39;s Foufounes Électriques and took home three awards at the &lt;a href="https://musiqueindependante.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;GAMIQ&lt;/a&gt; gala (including punk album of the year).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hailed as a cross between the B-52s and Jay Reatard, DVTR features Demi Lune (Laurence G-Do) and Jean Divorce (JC Tellier), both formerly of the Montreal electropop act &lt;a href="https://lecouleurmusic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Le Couleur&lt;/a&gt;. Tellier also has roots in the Chicoutimi rock group &lt;a href="https://gazoline.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gazoline&lt;/a&gt;. The band released their &lt;em&gt;Bonjour (BIS)&lt;/em&gt; EP in November 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3030189920/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://dvtr.bandcamp.com/track/n-pour-fl-ner"&gt;Né pour flâner by DVTR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="real_sickies"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Real Sickies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under a Plastic Bag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch at &amp;quot;Triage&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/RtU50jgpjME?si=eX4dOFYNQglC7G9W" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com/album/under-a-plastic-bag" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edmonton pop-punk mainstays &lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Real Sickies&lt;/a&gt; are readying their fifth full-length. &lt;em&gt;Under a Plastic Bag&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 14 through &lt;a href="https://stomprecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt;, with the singles &amp;quot;Triage&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Should&amp;#39;ve Seen It Coming&amp;quot; now streaming. The new material finds the band expanding from their well-honed foundation of Ramones and Buzzcocks worship to incorporate new wave, power pop, and indie rock flavours. The album finds the Sickies working with producer Josh Wells (&lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blackmountain.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Black Mountain&lt;/a&gt;), who played a prominent role in guiding the group&amp;#39;s new direction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discussing &amp;quot;Triage,&amp;quot; the record&amp;#39;s first single, the producer commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This song reminds me, at first, of being on adderall. Random thoughts, itchy eyes, the urge to rock really fast. But then, the song settles into a sick, focused motorik jam. Here we get some alien percussion floating down from another universe to join in and rocket ahead. For a moment, the human jam fuses with the aliens, but then the relationship deteriorates, the humans get mad and break out, the whole thing ending with a total meltdown.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Director Jesse Nash treats the single to a clever new video treatment featuring miniature models handcrafted by vocalist Ben Disaster. Ben wrote the song with the perspective of having just survived a major car accident with his family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band also recently shared a video for the track &amp;quot;Should Have Seen It Coming.&amp;quot; That piece, directed by Tyler Hall, finds the band finds the Sickies performing in an unheated garage in -20 degree weather. On the song, Ben Disaster shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s about patterns, not being able to accept consequences, or finally coming to. There&amp;#39;s not much more meaning to it other than just smashing one&amp;#39;s own teeth with a microphone. Musically it explores some new emotions. Maybe. Hindsight right?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows up on 2022&amp;#39;s EP &lt;em&gt;Danny, It&amp;#39;s Not Your Birthday&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Love is for Lovers&lt;/em&gt; LP from the year prior.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3403063035/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://realsickies.bandcamp.com/album/under-a-plastic-bag"&gt;Under a Plastic Bag by REAL SICKIES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="autogramm"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Randy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/album/randy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;, the Vancouver-rooted new wavers recently shared a new single through &lt;a href="https://dirtcultrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dirt Cult&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goodwillrecords.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Goodwill Records&lt;/a&gt;. The goodhearted &amp;quot;Randy&amp;quot; is another in the band&amp;#39;s impressive streak of synth-driven earworms. The track, originally slated for inclusion on 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Music That Humans Can Play&lt;/em&gt;, finds the group offering tongue-in-cheek lyrical encouragement to the ambitions of the drummer&amp;#39;s cat (&amp;quot;If you think you wanna jump up on that countertop, well baby you&amp;#39;ve got the tools&amp;quot;). Josh &amp;quot;The Silo&amp;quot; Wells explained:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s a letter to a good friend, in need of a little confidence push. Everyone needs an ego boost sometimes. Even if they&amp;#39;re a cat.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DEVO-indebted &amp;quot;Randy&amp;quot; arrives backed by a cover of &amp;quot;Jenny&amp;#39;s In A Sleep World,&amp;quot; a 1979 track by Canadian punk legends &lt;a href="https://thediodes.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Diodes&lt;/a&gt;. A press release notes that the Toronto pioneers have enthusiastically endorsed Autogramm&amp;#39;s take.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vinyl 7&amp;quot; follows the band&amp;#39;s recent single &amp;quot;Diana&amp;quot; and arrives as they prepare for a March tour of Spain. Autogramm features Jiffy Marx (&lt;a href="https://nightcourtpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Night Court&lt;/a&gt;), The Silo (Black Mountain, Destroyer), CC Voltage (&lt;a href="https://thespitfires.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Spitfires&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theblackhalos.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Black Halos&lt;/a&gt;), and Lars Von Seattle (&lt;a href="https://www.breadandbutterrules.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bread &amp;amp; Butter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1980083757/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://autogramm.bandcamp.com/album/randy"&gt;Randy by Autogramm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="packs"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PACKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Before I Was Bleeding&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com/track/before-i-was-bleeding" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s Madeline Link recently shared a new one-off single from her compellingly slow-burning &lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PACKS&lt;/a&gt; project. &amp;quot;Before I Was Bleeding&amp;quot; provides a wonderfully tranquil detour for whatever chaos you&amp;#39;re navigating, underscored by a bass clarinet Link plays on the recording. Madeline sings and plays acoustic guitar on the sparse tune, accompanied by Diego Parragué of Chile&amp;#39;s Laos Kollective on keys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new song surfaced a few weeks ago for the band&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/packstheband" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; subscribers. It follows &lt;em&gt;Melt The Honey&lt;/em&gt;, PACKS&amp;#39; January 2024 full-length through &lt;a href="https://firetalkrecs.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fire Talk Records&lt;/a&gt; (a quick follow-up to their &lt;em&gt;Crispy Crunchy Nothing&lt;/em&gt; LP from just a few months prior). &lt;em&gt;Honey&lt;/em&gt; found Link writing and recording between Toronto, Mexico City, and Chile. PACKS&amp;#39; full-band lineup for those sessions featured guitarist Dexter Nash, bassist Noah O&amp;#39;Neil, and drummer Shane Hooper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2007191187/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://packstheband.bandcamp.com/track/before-i-was-bleeding"&gt;before i was bleeding by PACKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="monk"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dark Side of the Mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/DyNC1It07bI?si=PhZ7LzcgQ4ZhGp_s" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com/album/dark-side-of-the-mind" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mindfulness-minded LA-via-Sudbury hardcore project &lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monk&lt;/a&gt; returns next month with &lt;em&gt;Dark Side of the Mind&lt;/em&gt;, their second EP for &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;. The set lands April 25, with two punishing advance singles streaming now: the title track (featuring Brendan Murphy of Hamilton metalcore veterans &lt;a href="https://counterpartshc.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Counterparts&lt;/a&gt;) and &amp;quot;Chains.&amp;quot; Jovanni Martinez directed the video for the former.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vocalist Frank Bach (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/viciouscyclesudbury/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Vicious Cycle&lt;/a&gt;) commented on the EP&amp;#39;s thematic direction, particularly the title track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Dark Side delves into the struggle of self-exploration and confronting the hidden, often darker, aspects of the mind. If &lt;em&gt;Rock&lt;/em&gt; was the light side, this is the opposite— questioning one&amp;#39;s understanding of life and grappling with the emotional weight of guilt, trauma, and unresolved pain, encouraging you to confront your fears, doubts, and unspoken truths. The song is about the courage it takes to face inner struggles and make peace with the haunting aspects of the human psyche.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band self-produced the new collection, recording at Camera Varda (the Welland, Ontario studio of The Outfit&amp;#39;s Romano brothers) and LA&amp;#39;s Pirate Studios. Alex Jacobellli mixed at Sunsick Studio, with Jon Drew mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monk solidified their lineup in the time since 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Rock&lt;/em&gt; EP. That early iteration saw Bach collaborate remotely with Daniel and Ian Romano of &lt;a href="https://attackinblack.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Attack In Black&lt;/a&gt;. The band now features LA-local backing from guitarist Scott Savarie (&lt;a href="https://cureforyouth.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cure for Youth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blacklungs.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Black Lungs&lt;/a&gt;), bassist Connor McKenna (&lt;a href="https://headspin-zone.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Headspin&lt;/a&gt;), and drummer Jesse Kalamian (Hatespeech).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1870714553/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monkla.bandcamp.com/album/dark-side-of-the-mind"&gt;Dark Side of the Mind by Monk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_good_brothers"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thegoodbrothers.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Good Brothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class="split"&gt;&amp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thesadies.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Sadies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Now That You&amp;#39;re Gone&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/dyfw_TOLMiE?si=iYBso-_zwbSlqy8M" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2022 death of Dallas Good continues to echo through the Canadian music landscape, but the latest tribute to the beloved musician comes from somewhere very personal. Legendary country trio &lt;a href="https://thegoodbrothers.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Good Brothers&lt;/a&gt;, featuring Dallas&amp;#39; father and uncles, returned with their first new music since 2017 to pay tribute to the late &lt;a href="https://www.thesadies.net/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sadies&lt;/a&gt; guitarist. &amp;quot;Now That You&amp;#39;re Gone,&amp;quot; a collaboration with the surviving Sadies members, arrived in February to mark the third anniversary of Dallas&amp;#39; passing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Good Brothers formed in the early 70s, rising to fame after touring on the legendary Festival Express train alongside legends like Janice Joplin, The Band, and the Grateful Dead. The trio features Dallas&amp;#39; father, Bruce, and his uncles, Brian and Larry Good. On the new song, Bruce shared:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;After the sudden passing of my son Dallas, I hoped that expressing my feelings through music might soften the blow of such a profound loss. This song became my therapy and helped diminish the everlasting pain.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collective performs the single in a new video from director &lt;a href="https://www.coreykellyimages.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Corey Kelly&lt;/a&gt;. The Good Brothers recently linked up with Collingwood, Ontario producer &lt;a href="https://grahamtrude.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Graham Trude&lt;/a&gt; to record for his &lt;a href="https://countrycorerecords.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Countrycore Records&lt;/a&gt; label. Their next record will follow up on 2017&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Wide Awake Dreamin&amp;#39;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sadies released the Polaris shortlisted &lt;em&gt;Colder Streams&lt;/em&gt; - the last album Dallas played on - in July of 2022 through &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.yeproc.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yep Roc Records&lt;/a&gt;.Now operating as a trio, guitarist/vocalist Travis Good, bassist Sean Dean, and drummer Mike Belitsky recently issued a full-length of new material in collaboration with Dallas&amp;#39; longtime creative partner &lt;a href="https://rickwhitearchive.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Rick White&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/artists/erics_trip" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eric&amp;#39;s Trip&lt;/a&gt;, Elevator). The 13-song &lt;em&gt;Rick White and the Sadies&lt;/em&gt; arrived last summer through &lt;a href="https://bluefogrecordings.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Blue Fog Recordings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;div class='aspect-ratio'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dyfw_TOLMiE?si=iYBso-_zwbSlqy8M" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Outta My Head</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-02-11-outta-my-head/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-02-11-outta-my-head/</id>
    <published>2025-02-10T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-11T17:14:24-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know, I always assumed the Dominion would outlast this newsletter but a lot can change in a week. I&amp;#39;ll endeavour to keep publishing as long as we remain a viable nation, but if they need my help manning the old batteries at Queenston, I happen to know the Heights like the back of my hand. Expect delays in that case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push on, brave York volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_boojums"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Boojums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Love&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;Outta My Head&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com/track/outta-my-head-video-version" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I&amp;#39;ve been at this for too long, but I rarely stumble across a band that so thoroughly grabs my attention that I drop whatever I&amp;#39;m doing and dive frantically into research. I&amp;#39;m almost ashamed to admit I mindlessly scrolled into &lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Boojums&lt;/a&gt; on Instagram. You never want to credit the stinkin&amp;#39; algorithm with a legitimate find - particularly as a writer. It doesn&amp;#39;t help sell the relevance of my dying medium to give that credit where it&amp;#39;s due, but I&amp;#39;m honest to a fault.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Promoting their first two singles, the band shared a few performance videos showcasing segments of &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Love&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Outta My Head.&amp;quot; The clips find the trio crammed awkwardly in the viewport as if performing in a closet. &lt;a href="https://williestratton.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Willie Stratton&lt;/a&gt; glances uncomfortably into the camera with a vague sense of menace while the group crashes through their over-driven power-pop gems. Through deft planning or a fortuitous low-budget, the band introduces themselves with a lo-fi veneer that feels refreshingly, arrestingly real. If that&amp;#39;s all a put-on, some faux-amateurism, then so be it. It&amp;#39;s working for them, and it&amp;#39;s working for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hailing from Port Hawkesbury in Cape Breton Island, The Boojums haven&amp;#39;t been around for more than a year, but their roster boasts lengthy discographies. Guitarist/vocalist Willie Stratton is a fixture of the Halifax scene, recording a mix of folk, rockabilly, and lovesick blues over several records, most recently 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Drugstore Dreamin&amp;#39;&lt;/em&gt;. He&amp;#39;s also played in the surf-rock act &lt;a href="https://beachbait.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Beach Bait&lt;/a&gt;, among others. Bassist/vocalist Sara Eve is a member of the gritty garage/punk quartet &lt;a href="https://www.skunkmotel.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Skunk Motel&lt;/a&gt; and Toronto instrumental act &lt;a href="https://www.thesurfrajettes.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Surfrajettes&lt;/a&gt;. Mabou-based drummer &lt;a href="https://petermacinnis.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Peter MacInnis&lt;/a&gt; boasts a solo career to rival Stratton&amp;#39;s. He last released the quirky indie-folk record &lt;em&gt;Late Night Blues Vibe&lt;/em&gt; and plays regularly with the Inverness garage-folk quartet &lt;a href="https://beechhill.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Beech Hill&lt;/a&gt;. You may have also seen him on the YouTube comedy series &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzBZsyBwld-BSwPOi3U37nA?view_as=subscriber" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cape Breton Chats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Their vast social reach notwithstanding, the Boojums have remained relatively confined to the Maritimes. That changes on March 25 with an appearance at Toronto&amp;#39;s Longboat Hall as part of &lt;a href="https://wearebusybodies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;We Are Busy Bodies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; 20th anniversary celebrations. They&amp;#39;ll play alongside Toronto bummer-pop favourites &lt;a href="https://nofrillsmusic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Frills&lt;/a&gt; and Welsh indie rockers &lt;a href="https://thebugclub.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Bug Club&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=221485291/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theboojums.bandcamp.com/track/dont-wanna-love"&gt;Don't Wanna Love by The Boojums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="washing_machine"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silver Tongue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/album/silver-tongue" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halifax post-punk trio &lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt; have a new full-length on deck. &lt;em&gt;Silver Tongue&lt;/em&gt; arrives on April 18, building on the college rock revival of their early work to arrive somewhere lush and moody. While R.E.M. remains a touchpoint, this time out, Washing Machine cites the influence of lavish 80s sophisti-pop groups like Prefab Sprout. The pensive pre-release singles &amp;quot;Worn Apparition&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Vivian&amp;#39;s Way&amp;quot; showcase that evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band shared some insight on the 8-track album&amp;#39;s lyrical approach, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Thematically, Silver Tongue is misled by a host of zealous and tragic protagonists. Unreliable narrators lose the plot in a crisis of communication while searching for the upper hand and the right words.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washing Machine&amp;#39;s current lineup features Noel Macdonald (&lt;a href="http://moonhalifax.tumblr.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Moon&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar and vocals, Glen Leck (&lt;a href="http://hungryrecords.bandcamp.com/album/shorelines" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Working Titles&lt;/a&gt;) on bass, guitar, and keys, and Justin Crowe (&lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://heavenlyblue.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Heavenly Blue&lt;/a&gt;) on drums. Another Booji Boy, Adam Ledrew, makes a guest appearance on organ and synth. The band recorded over two sessions at Dartmouth&amp;#39;s Fang studio with engineers Thomas Stajcer (Safeword, Daveband) and Alex Burris, with additional tracking by Leck and Ledrew. Noel Macdonald mixed the record at Rotary Club, with Carl Saff mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washing Machine has a string of Maritime dates lined up to support the record, including stops in Moncton and Charlottetown before their April 19 release show at Halifax&amp;#39;s Propeller Arcade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album follows Washing Machine&amp;#39;s 2022 sophomore LP &lt;em&gt;Cheat the Pattern&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2895552108/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://washingmachine.bandcamp.com/album/silver-tongue"&gt;Silver Tongue by Washing Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="edgar_breau"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Edgar Breau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Cornpone the King of Jive&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com/track/cornpone-the-king-of-jive" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Edgar Breau&lt;/a&gt;, founder of the cult Hamilton proto-punk group &lt;a href="https://www.simplysaucer.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Simply Saucer&lt;/a&gt;, is back with a rollicking new single. &amp;quot;Cornpone the King of Jive&amp;quot; layers the artist&amp;#39;s trademark psych grit atop a playful bed southern rock, crafting a lively, sardonic commentary on &amp;quot;populist leaders, lovable outlaws, and the morally duplicitous figures who hold the public&amp;#39;s fascination.&amp;quot; We could name a few.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Breau wrote and recorded the track at Dany Laj&amp;#39;s Montreal studio, the La La Pop Shoppe. Laj likewise brought his band, The Looks, to back Breau on the track, with Laj contributing guitar, Jeanette Dowling on bass, and Alex Pauzé drumming. The Hamilton legend spoke about the contributions of his newfound collaborators:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The song started out as a simple fingerstyle acoustic tune, but in the studio, it became a monster stomping rocker. Dany&amp;#39;s lead guitar playing really brought it to life, and I&amp;#39;m proud of how the arrangement turned out.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last summer, &lt;a href="http://danylaj.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dany Laj and the Looks&lt;/a&gt; shared &amp;quot;Meet Me On The Floor,&amp;quot; a one-off power-pop single that marked their return to action following the pandemic. Edgar Breau last issued a self-titled solo record in 2020 and a reissue of &lt;em&gt;Shadows of Ecstasy&lt;/em&gt;, his first post-Saucer solo album recorded in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1051557152/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://edgarbreau1.bandcamp.com/track/cornpone-the-king-of-jive"&gt;Cornpone the King of Jive by Edgar Breau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cult_crime"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cult Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Desperation&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com/track/desperation" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cult Crime&lt;/a&gt; have their debut full-length on deck through &lt;a href="https://uglypoprecords.bigcartel.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Ugly Pop Records&lt;/a&gt;. Due March 3, the nine-song LP promises a potent blend of early punk influences. The label took the courtesy of listing the big names, so I didn&amp;#39;t have to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...snarling, hard-nosed punk that recalls 1981 hardcore on both sides of the Atlantic, seasoning classic LA a la Adolescents/TSOL/pre-Henry Flag with a dash of primo Blitz. No mere genre exercise, these are tough but memorable songs delivered with hooks and skill.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those hooks and skills come, in part, from Matt Menard, veteran of a laundry list of killer Windsor and Toronto bands. That includes the lo-fi punk act &lt;a href="https://nofixforyou.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Fix&lt;/a&gt;, psych-punks &lt;a href="https://psychicvoid.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Psychic Void&lt;/a&gt;, and the hardcore group &lt;a href="https://brainitch.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Brain Itch&lt;/a&gt;. Cult Crime recorded with &lt;a href="https://jimmyvapid.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmy Vapid&lt;/a&gt; of veteran Burlington goons &lt;a href="https://the-vapids.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Vapids&lt;/a&gt;. Josh Kaiser mastered the set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can crash through the lead single &amp;quot;Desperation&amp;quot; now, delivering equal parts speed and snot in just under two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=4124347039/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cultcrimeband.bandcamp.com/track/desperation"&gt;Desperation by Cult Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="outtacontroller"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Outtacontroller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Cheap Pop&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com/track/cheap-pop" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halifax punk quartet &lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Outtacontroller&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the year with &amp;quot;Cheap Pop,&amp;quot; another in their reliably strong series of fuzzed-out power-pop gems. As with past efforts, the band said little about the track outside of the usual promise of more to come. I remain delightfully baffled at how consistently great this band sounds. Their nonchalant ability to craft Buzzcocks-quality hooks time after time feels entirely underappreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outtacontroller features vocalist/guitarists Terry A&amp;#39;hearn and James O&amp;#39;Toole, bassist AJ Boutilier, and drummer Sean Parsons. Late last year, the band convened in their Bunker studio to start work on the full-length follow-up to their 2022 LP &lt;em&gt;Come Alive&lt;/em&gt;. There&amp;#39;s no word yet on their release plans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year saw a few one-off singles from the group, including &amp;quot;Gimme Nothin&amp;#39;&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;I Got Mine.&amp;quot; They issued the &lt;em&gt;Just a Scratch&lt;/em&gt; EP in 2023 through Madrid&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/jarama45rpmrecs/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jarama 45RPM Recs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1768926132/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://outtacontroller.bandcamp.com/track/cheap-pop"&gt;Cheap Pop by OUTTACONTROLLER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="doctor_mother_father"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Doctor Mother Father&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Break the Same&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/album/break-the-same" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saint John power trio &lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Doctor Mother Father&lt;/a&gt; recently shared &amp;quot;Break the Same,&amp;quot; the crunchy first single from their upcoming EP &lt;em&gt;It All Depends On How You Wanna Hurt&lt;/em&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s teasing &amp;quot;an energizing soundtrack to hard times in the maritimes in the midst of a crashing economy.&amp;quot; You&amp;#39;ll have to wait until June to hear that in full, but this track certainly delivers on that promise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corey Bonnevie (&lt;a href="https://lylm.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Little You, Little Me&lt;/a&gt;) wrote and recorded the EP at his &lt;a href="https://monopolizedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Monopolized Records&lt;/a&gt; studio, backed by bassist Kortni Nicols (&lt;a href="https://lionsault.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lionsault&lt;/a&gt;) and drummer Colin Ferris (Sheik, Cool Dudes Fighting, Butcher). The new material follows Doctor Mother Father&amp;#39;s 2024 full-length &lt;em&gt;Feelin&amp;#39; Fine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=804292490/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://doctormotherfather.bandcamp.com/album/break-the-same"&gt;Break the Same by Doctor Mother Father&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="living_mad"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Living Mad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ungreatful Fucks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com/album/ungrateful-fucks" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;#39;s been a good week if I can pepper a column with multiple references to &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt; personnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Living Mad&lt;/a&gt; is a scrappy new hardcore side-project from frequent collaborators Cody Googoo and Luke Mumford. The duo issued the three-song &lt;em&gt;Ungrateful Fucks&lt;/em&gt; tape through the former&amp;#39;s cassette label Don&amp;#39;t Wanna Talk Records. It&amp;#39;s loud, fast, and says all it needs to in under four minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cody&amp;#39;s everywhere these days, performing on recent records from &lt;a href="http://gemstones.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gemstones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://heavenlyblue.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Heavenly Blue&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://mutatedvoid.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mutated Void&lt;/a&gt;, in styles ranging from throwback garage rock to nigh-unlistenable skate thrash. Mumford surfaces more often in a production capacity but has a list of credits that&amp;#39;s just as long. That includes stints with &lt;a href="https://negativerage.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Negative Rage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://geneticangry.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Genetic Angry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://markvodka.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Mark Vodka Group&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://musicbyllc.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;LeDrew, Luke &amp;amp; Crowe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new tape landed the same week that &lt;a href="http://sewerciderecords.limitedrun.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sewercide Records&lt;/a&gt; finally issued the long-awaited split between Googoo&amp;#39;s searing &lt;a href="https://misanthropicmutantmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Misanthropic Minds&lt;/a&gt; and the Finnish hardcore band &lt;a href="https://hapeahardcore.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Häpeä&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;#39;ll hear three new tracks from each band on the 7&amp;quot;, which is shipping now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1365956358/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://livingmad.bandcamp.com/album/ungrateful-fucks"&gt;Ungrateful Fucks by Living Mad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="yesterday_s_man"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yesterday's Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com/album/yesterdays-man" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To date, and without intent, I somehow overlooked every update regarding the Vancouver duo &lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Man&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;ll see if I correct that and can get us up to speed. If you&amp;#39;re of the right age, I suspect you&amp;#39;ll find the band&amp;#39;s deft revival of early-2000s indie pop downright calming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group features Gal Av-Gay of the slacker-punks &lt;a href="https://dumbband.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dumb&lt;/a&gt; paired with their spouse Alie Lynch (&lt;a href="https://allmoonsaresuper.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Supermoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://movieland.bandcamp.com/album/blows-up" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Movieland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://kidnapkids.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Kidnap Kids&lt;/a&gt;). The couple&amp;#39;s played together for years, touring North America a few times with &lt;a href="https://tvugly.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TV Ugly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://megamall.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Megamall&lt;/a&gt;. Both also appeared as members of DJ On&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://nonla.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Non La&lt;/a&gt; act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 12-song self-titled &lt;em&gt;Yesterday&amp;#39;s Man&lt;/em&gt; arrived on New Year&amp;#39;s Day through the &lt;a href="https://monotapes.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mono Tapes&lt;/a&gt; label, delivering what the band describes as &amp;quot;classic indie rock,&amp;quot; the product of years of under-the-radar collaboration (filtered, as all things are, through the trials of the pandemic). The duo self-produced the record, with Dominick Civiero mixing and Greg Mindorff mastering. In the label&amp;#39;s words:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The songs are meant to sound comforting and familiar, while the lyrics evoke the dark inner turmoil and consequential warm relief that comes from isolation.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writer Alex Hudson commented on &amp;quot;Fleetwood Mac,&amp;quot; the album&amp;#39;s first single, noting that it &amp;quot;throws back to the golden age of blog-rock without sounding nostalgic.&amp;quot; I couldn&amp;#39;t agree more, and if early-2000s Mint Records holds a place in your heart, you&amp;#39;ll be right at home here. It&amp;#39;s a delight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=949951061/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://yesterdaysman.bandcamp.com/album/yesterdays-man"&gt;Yesterday's Man by Yesterdays Man&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>controlfreak69</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-01-25-controlfreak69/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-01-25-controlfreak69/</id>
    <published>2025-01-24T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-28T11:23:29-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="gloin"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gloin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;controlfreak69&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/aHW4VlgfoCA?si=8lbHQFlzddCQUvAV" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/album/all-of-your-anger-is-actually-shame-and-i-bet-that-makes-you-angry" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toronto post-punk quartet &lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Gloin&lt;/a&gt; recently unveiled their sophomore full-length. The sardonically titled &lt;em&gt;All of your anger is actually shame (and I bet that makes you angry)&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 28 through &lt;a href="https://www.mothland.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mothland&lt;/a&gt;, marking the Montreal psych label&amp;#39;s 50th release. You can preview the twelve-song set through the livewire single &amp;quot;controlfreak69,&amp;quot; accompanied by a curious (and I&amp;#39;d say &lt;em&gt;aggressively&lt;/em&gt; uneventful) new video from director Ryan Faist (aka &lt;a href="https://ohboywonder.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;boy wonder&lt;/a&gt;). Vocalist John Watson sounds impressively frantic over the track&amp;#39;s thumping industrial dance beat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The album finds the band further evolving their dense, noisy darkwave  with a newfound embrace of electronic flourishes (Toronto&amp;#39;s Odonis Odonis mined similar territory for a spell). Gloin commented on the improvisational fluidity of their writing process in a press release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We wrote the whole album as a collective, influenced by shared experiences. Half was written electronically with usually one person bringing in ideas that we all elaborated on together. We jammed a lot, finding things we liked that we later pieced together, while also saving pieces that we might be able to plug into a future song. One method for a few of the songs was for all of us to write a complete piece, and then switch up instruments.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group recorded with &lt;a href="http://tallies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tallies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Dylan Frankland (Fucked Up, Partner) between Palace Sound and Wychwood Sound, with Phil Demetro mastering in Toronto. Ryan Faist also shot the album&amp;#39;s cover image, which pays homage to the work of the famed New York photographer Gregory Crewdson. The band says it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;inspired by the mundanity of life,&amp;quot; depicting &amp;quot;the middle of nowhere.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gloin features guitarist/vocalist John Watson, bassist/vocalist Victoria Byers, drummer Simon Kou, and Richard Garnham on synths. The new record follows their 2022 LP &lt;em&gt;We Found This&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2057416087/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://gloinxo.bandcamp.com/album/all-of-your-anger-is-actually-shame-and-i-bet-that-makes-you-angry"&gt;All of your anger is actually shame (and I bet that makes you angry) by Gloin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="population_ii"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Population II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Le thé est prêt&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com/album/maintenant-jamais" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal psych trio &lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Population II&lt;/a&gt; can&amp;#39;t stand still. The band issued two dynamic EPs in 2024 and already have their next full-length on deck. &lt;em&gt;Maintenant Jamais&lt;/em&gt; arrives March 28 through &lt;a href="https://www.bonsound.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bonsound&lt;/a&gt;. You can hear the lead single, &amp;quot;Le thé est prêt,&amp;quot; streaming now. Compared to the noise-punk racket of their recent EP, it&amp;#39;s striking how groovy and refined the band sounds here. The nine-song collection promises an ambitious fusion of the band&amp;#39;s late-60s influences; they cite Soft Machine, the MC5, and the avant-garde Quebecois group L&amp;#39;Infonie in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record finds Population II again working with producer Dominic Vanchesteing (Marie Davidson, Chocolat, Peter Peter), who&amp;#39;s helped focus and refine their approach. He mixed the record with Philippe Roberge, with Pascal Shefteshy mastering. Population II features vocalist/drummer Pierre-Luc Gratton, guitarist/keyboardist Tristan Lacombe, and bassist Sébastien Provençal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album follows a productive few years in which Population II issued their acclaimed sophomore LP &lt;em&gt;Électrons libres du québec&lt;/em&gt; and the decidedly heavier follow-up &lt;em&gt;Serpent Échelle&lt;/em&gt; EP. They capped off 2024 with a collaborative split with the Montreal hardcore group &lt;a href="https://mulchmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Mulch&lt;/a&gt;. The thrilling &lt;em&gt;Mulchulation II&lt;/em&gt; split came out in October and remains in near-daily rotation at Some Party HQ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=840746434/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://population2.bandcamp.com/album/maintenant-jamais"&gt;Maintenant Jamais by POPULATION II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="swimming"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Swimming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Reports&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;You Smell Like Phys Ed&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Reports&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/UANQFYlMjdI?si=eP46qFuIprJKUXMp" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/track/reports" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St. John&amp;#39;s trio &lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Swimming&lt;/a&gt; continue to deftly channel Midwestern emo on their sophomore full-length. &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt; lands February 21 on vinyl &lt;a href="https://nofuneral.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;No Funeral Records&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://barelythererecords.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Barely There&lt;/a&gt; handling the cassette release. You can now hear two advance singles from the ten-song set: &amp;quot;You Smell Like Phys Ed&amp;quot; and the newly unveiled &amp;quot;Reports.&amp;quot; A video for the latter showcases intimate 8mm footage shot by guitarist Liam Ryan during the slow return to live music in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The melancholic &amp;quot;Reports&amp;quot; predates the band, with roots in Liam Ryan and drummer Jacob Cherwick&amp;#39;s college years. The band issued a press release detailing the song&amp;#39;s evolution:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Spending years on the shelf, &amp;#39;Reports&amp;#39; was dusted off and re-worked into what would become one of the band&amp;#39;s strongest pop offerings. The song&amp;#39;s lyrics echo the band members&amp;#39; experience coming of age on the isolated island of Newfoundland while technology reshaped the way the world communicates. On Reports, Swimming surrounds their infectious indie rock melodies with layers of fuzzed out guitars &amp;amp; driving bass, complimented by Cherwick&amp;#39;s angular drumming. The song culminates in a cathartic percussion break set atop a bed of atmospheric shoegaze inspired guitars.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like &amp;quot;Reports,&amp;quot; several songs from the aptly-titled &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt; are refinements of earlier material, some previously heard on the group&amp;#39;s 2019 demo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt; in Newfoundland over two years, with Washington&amp;#39;s Dylan Hanwright (Great Grandpa, Gulfer) mixing and Will Killingsworth (Orchid, Jerome&amp;#39;s Dream) mastering. Swimming features guitarist Liam Ryan, drummer Jacob Cherwick, and bassist Nick Hunt. The new record follows their 2021 debut &lt;em&gt;That&amp;#39;s OK&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=977262591/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://swimmingswam.bandcamp.com/track/reports"&gt;Reports by Swimming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="plastic_act"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch &amp;quot;Everywhere I Go&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/J6H9Qcfhg-M?si=ez5r6_5M0QChOTDs" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com/album/now" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josh Herlihey&amp;#39;s proto-punk vehicle &lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt; returned this week with their three-song sophomore EP, issued through the Austrian label &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/bachelorrecords/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bachelor Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can stream the Montreal band&amp;#39;s latest everywhere and see the playful A-side, &amp;quot;Everywhere I Go,&amp;quot; showcased in a new video. The clip fittingly marries the song&amp;#39;s nostalgic Velvet Underground vibes with the analog grit of vintage film grain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Plastic Act started as a purely solo affair, this outing finds Herlihey backed by &lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; Drew Demers on drums and Chance Hutchison on backing vocals. The band recorded with Adrian Popovich (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/_frvits_/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;FRVITS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://americanlips.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;American Lips&lt;/a&gt;) engineering and mixing, with Dave Forcier (&lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Steve Adamyk Band&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://civicivic.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;CIVIC&lt;/a&gt;) mastering. &lt;a href="https://packratpunk.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pack Rat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Patrick McEachnie penned liner notes celebrating the release, dubbing it &amp;quot;something you&amp;#39;ve almost heard on a compilation of NY underbelly rock.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Herlihey plays in the Montreal post-punk quartet &lt;a href="https://privatelivesmtl.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Private Lives&lt;/a&gt; alongside Jackie Blenkarn (&lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;), Chance Hutchison, and Drew Demers. Plastic Act&amp;#39;s self-titled debut EP arrived in 2023 through &lt;a href="https://braingumrecords.bigcartel.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Brain Gum Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3958742349/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://plasticact.bandcamp.com/album/now"&gt;Now! by Plastic Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="prism_shores"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out From Underneath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/album/out-from-underneath" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Montreal jangle-pop quartet &lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt; unveiled &lt;em&gt;Out From Underneath&lt;/em&gt;, a new full-length issued through Madrid&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://meritoriorec.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Meritorio Records&lt;/a&gt;. The 10-song set delivers a solid blend of lo-fi indie pop, linking strands of Teenage Fanclub, early shoegaze, and the hallowed sounds of genre pillars like the C86 comps and Flying Nun Records.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Album notes at Bandcamp elaborate on the record&amp;#39;s themes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Lyrically, the album tackles young adult ennui and the adjustment of settling in an unfamiliar city, detailing the growing pains experienced during a time of upheaval. It is contemplative and chock-full of emotional depth — a nighttime album that channels self-reflexive melancholy into some form of catharsis.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The band recorded primarily with Andrew Woods at Royal Subs, with additional production from Howard Bilerman at Montreal&amp;#39;s Hotel2Tango. Harris Newman mastered at Grey Market. Prism Shores features Jack MacKenzie on guitar and vocals, Ben Goss (&lt;a href="https://poisonspear514.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Poison Spear&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://antibodieschtn.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Antibodies&lt;/a&gt;) on bass, Luke Pound on drums, and Finn Dalbeth on guitar. The album features guest appearances from &lt;a href="https://ktlaine.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;KT Laine&lt;/a&gt; on vocals, Owen Fairbairn on violin, and finds Woods chipping in on a half dozen instruments in the studio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows Prism Shores&amp;#39; 2022 LP &lt;em&gt;Inside My Diving Bell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2986837649/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/album/out-from-underneath"&gt;Out From Underneath by Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="fucked_up"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Disabuse&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Listen on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/G1zkDC3L16k?si=jnbgz6l2tQ_t9j1Q" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Purchase from &lt;a href="https://fuckedup.merchtable.com/music/7/disabuse-7/?" class="" target="_blank"&gt;the band&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given how much we used to pour over rumours and fret about their future, I appreciate that we&amp;#39;re now way past the point of &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; having some discernable arc to their career: they&amp;#39;ve swapped the uncertainty and the crush of expectations for an unrelenting drive for &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;. After issuing (give or take) three full-lengths and an assortment of adjuncts in 2024, the Toronto flagbearers kick off 2025 with a new 7&amp;quot; as part of &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop Records&lt;/a&gt; legendary singles series. The vinyl&amp;#39;s set for release on March 14, but you can hear the blistering A-side &amp;quot;Disabuse&amp;quot; now. The track eschews the band&amp;#39;s maximalist tendencies, tapping directly into their punk roots and keeping their experimental tendencies at bay. The label calls them &amp;quot;unlikely light-speed cuts of pure hardcore,&amp;quot; sharing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;These tracks bleed off the record, having been born from the indelible stamp of Poison Idea&amp;#39;s 1990 anti-oppression anthem &amp;#39;Discontent&amp;#39; and Japanese punk legends Paintbox&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;The Door.&amp;#39; Sitting at the chaotic crossroads of punk, hardcore, and grunge.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damian Abraham wrote the A-side for his daughter, grappling with the harm of bullying and intimidation. &amp;quot;Self Driving Man&amp;quot; plays on the flip,  which finds the band wrestling &amp;quot;the out of control automation of our world.&amp;quot; The label is issuing the 7&amp;quot; on emerald vinyl with two cover variants: one in the band&amp;#39;s usual style and one that pays homage to Poison Idea&amp;#39;s 1990 Sub Pop single, &amp;quot;Taken By Surprise.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The release follows a characteristically prolific year that saw Fucked Up issue &lt;em&gt;Another Day&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Someday&lt;/em&gt;, and the limited-to-24-hours experiment &lt;em&gt;Who&amp;#39;s Got The Time &amp;amp; A Half?&lt;/em&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s current lineup features vocalist Damian Abraham, guitarists Mike Haliechuk and Josh Zucker, bassist Sandy Miranda, and drummer Jonah Falco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;div class='aspect-ratio'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G1zkDC3L16k?si=jgnfBjc4vH6r795U" class="aspect-ratio--object lazyload"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="pup"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/k11G7mmlz48?si=3O6VRzesMdkEPpdR" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://puptheband.bandcamp.com/track/paranoid" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt; generate their own gravity these days, so I assume my two-week late write-up&amp;#39;s entirely superfluous. I&amp;#39;m a completionist, though, and &amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot; finds the quartet in such fine, angsty form I&amp;#39;d feel remiss for ignoring it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The song, A-side of a self-released 7&amp;quot; available to the band&amp;#39;s fan club, arrived with the latest in PUP&amp;#39;s series of famously ambitious videos. The clip, directed by longtime collaborator Jeremy Schaulin-Rioux, follows the lyrics in real-time as they appear on merch, venue signage, jacket patches, and assorted graffiti scrawled on the walls of Sneaky Dee&amp;#39;s. Don&amp;#39;t be fooled by the vertically oriented phone footage; there&amp;#39;s nothing slapdash here. It&amp;#39;s a dizzying piece featuring several intricate, long shots that must have been a nightmare to choreograph in the legendary Toronto venue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The song finds the group working with the prolific producer John Congleton. In a mailing, Stefan Babcock commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The lyrics are pretty self explanatory on this one, I don&amp;#39;t need to go deep. I will say though, that my favourite part of the song is in the breakdown, I&amp;#39;m screaming some pretty sad shit and Nestor just decided who cares I&amp;#39;m gonna play the melody for &amp;#39;The Lion Sleeps Tonight&amp;#39; over the vocals and that&amp;#39;s fucking funny. I laugh every time I hear it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Congleton, the legend (and our friend, nbd, we hang with legends all the time) produced and recorded this thing at his place in LA. I think I did 3 vocal takes. After the 3rd one I was like &amp;#39;man I sound BAD&amp;#39;, and he was like &amp;#39;perfect, I love when you sound bad, we&amp;#39;re keeping it&amp;#39;. I like John.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot; arrived in a run of 500 records, which I assume are entirely sold out. PUP features vocalist/guitarist Stefan Babcock, guitarist Steve Sladkowski, bassist Nestor Chumak, and drummer Zack Mykula. Their last proper full-length was 2022&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;THE UNRAVELING OF PUPTHEBAND&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1273244095/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://puptheband.bandcamp.com/track/paranoid"&gt;Paranoid by PUP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_dirty_nil"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;I Hate The Internet&amp;quot; / &amp;quot;True Devotion&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Listen on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/NWLiqs7JjCw?si=gypzSPqzsrGOd3xq" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise, acolytes of &lt;a href="https://thedirtynil.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Dirty Nil&lt;/a&gt; need no reminder from me. The Dundas power trio launched their now-in-progress US tour with a surprise digital release through &lt;a href="https://dinealonerecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can hear both &amp;quot;I Hate The Internet&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;True Devotion&amp;quot; streaming everywhere now, adored by truly epic cover art from fantasy punk illustrator Rizki Akber (&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/eye_dust/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Eye Dust&lt;/a&gt;). While the former doesn&amp;#39;t delve too deeply, the chorus voices such a prevailing sentiment that the band&amp;#39;s conceivably written the backing track to a million future Instagram reels. It&amp;#39;s fuel for more Internet, if you get my drift - a content ouroboros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tracks are the Nil&amp;#39;s first originals since issuing &lt;em&gt;Free Rein to Passions&lt;/em&gt; in 2023. The joyfully hedonistic Ontario rock group features vocalist/guitarist Luke Bentham, drummer Kyle Fisher, and bassist Sam Tomlinson.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Radio Sunshine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2025-01-16-radio-sunshine/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2025-01-16-radio-sunshine/</id>
    <published>2025-01-15T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-16T22:38:27-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is it halfway through the month already? What an inauspicious start to the new year. With several of the country&amp;#39;s mainline punk-and-adjacent units issuing new material over the past week, I&amp;#39;ve got more than I&amp;#39;ve had time to recap. I&amp;#39;ll save the big names for the next edition, but we&amp;#39;re kicking off 2025 almost exclusively in the Maritimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_burning_hell"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Bottle of Chianti, Cheese and Charcuterie Board&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Watch on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6D2aLh6Z6Hc?si=XT362MSFWubkrx8G" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; - Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/ghost-palace" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PEI&amp;#39;s optimistically apocalyptic storytellers &lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; have announced their new full-length. Look for &lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt; on March 7 through &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt; in North America and &lt;a href="https://bbislandmusic.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;BB*Island&lt;/a&gt; overseas. You can preview the eleven-song collection through the lead single &amp;quot;Bottle of Chianti, Cheese and Charcuterie Board,&amp;quot; described by the band as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;an off-kilter synth and double-bass hip-shaker about the ways we reduce our lives to the fragments of bourgeois luxury that we can&amp;#39;t take with us when we go.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quirky track is one of two to feature instrumentals from composer &lt;a href="https://carliehowell.ca" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Carlie Howell&lt;/a&gt; (The Electric Storm Collective, Beverly Glenn-Copeland). They appear as guests alongside &lt;a href="http://theconstantines.wordpress.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Constantines&lt;/a&gt; guitarist &lt;a href="http://stevenlambke.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Lambke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/josecontrerasmusik/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;José Contreras&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://bydivineright.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;By Divine Right&lt;/a&gt;, and Amy Nicoll. Director &lt;a href="http://www.graemepatterson.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Graeme Patterson&lt;/a&gt;, who assembled the memorable showcase for &amp;quot;Bird Queen of Garbage Island,&amp;quot; premieres their video for &amp;quot;Chianti&amp;quot; this Friday. Check your local listings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Burning Hell&amp;#39;s core remains the duo of Mathias Kom and Ariel Sharratt. Their band again features frequent producer/multi-instrumentalist &lt;a href="https://jakenicoll.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Nicoll&lt;/a&gt; and fiddler/vocalist Maria Peddle. The group primarily recorded at the Souris Show Hall and Fairfield Social Club in PEI throughout 2023 and 2024. Norman Nitzsche mastered at Mokik in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the 11-song &lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt; again finds the group pondering the minutia of an uncertain future, they&amp;#39;re finding some solace in our collective decline. The band explains:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t dwell directly on the end of the world. Instead, the songs assume that our time running out is a foregone conclusion, and focus instead on what we might leave behind when we go, what might endure, and what surprises might be found amidst the remnants. Memory and the debatable usefulness of nostalgia are primary concerns here, peppered with occasional suggestions that we just might still contain the tiny, hopeful seeds of our own redemption through community and balance.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost Palace&lt;/em&gt; follows The Burning Hell&amp;#39;s 2023 avian-focused end-times LP &lt;em&gt;Garbage Island&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2494821677/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/license_id=4342/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theburninghell.bandcamp.com/album/ghost-palace"&gt;Ghost Palace by The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_monoxides"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monoxides.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Monoxides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;Radio Sunshine&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://monoxides.bandcamp.com/track/radio-sunshine-3" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moncton rock vets &lt;a href="https://monoxides.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Monoxides&lt;/a&gt; kicked off 2025 with &amp;quot;Radio Sunshine,&amp;quot; a propulsive power-pop gem far better suited for a summer road trip than the dregs of winter. The band&amp;#39;s always proudly channelled their heroes, and true to form, the sonic lineage of Cheap Trick and Thin Lizzy shines brightly here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While &amp;quot;Radio Sunshine&amp;quot; arrives as the follow-up to 2023&amp;#39;s one-off single &amp;quot;Let Her Know,&amp;quot; the song&amp;#39;s roots reach back nearly 30 years. Lead vocalist and guitarist Steve Hickox commented on that astonishing timeframe:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Some of our longtime friends and fans may remember us playing &amp;#39;Radio Sunshine&amp;#39; live as far back as 1998, but we were never quite happy with the song&amp;#39;s arrangement. We came back to it over the years, and [guitarist Marco Rocca] recently put finishing touches on it that we&amp;#39;re really happy with. It shows the sunnier side of The Monoxides, and is a tip of the cap to a lot of great 1970s power pop bands we all grew up listening to on the radio.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Monoxides first came to prominence with their 1995 EP &lt;em&gt;Out of the Marsh&lt;/em&gt; and the Moe Berg-produced 1997 LP &lt;em&gt;Galaxy of Stooges&lt;/em&gt; (the singles &amp;quot;(Can&amp;#39;t Get) Excited&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Little Bitta Rosie&amp;quot; made waves back in the day). The group last issued &lt;em&gt;The Free Release of Energy&lt;/em&gt; in 2000 before dropping into a lengthy hiatus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Monoxides features vocalist/guitarist Steve Hickox, bassist PJ Dunphy, lead guitarist Derek Robichaud, guitarist/vocalist Marco Rocca, and drummer Ken Kelley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3639433696/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monoxides.bandcamp.com/track/radio-sunshine-3"&gt;Radio Sunshine by The Monoxides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="defaillance"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://defaillance.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Défaillance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Se Rendre Malade...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://pilssessions.bandcamp.com/album/se-rendre-malade" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saguenay street punks &lt;a href="https://defaillance.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Défaillance&lt;/a&gt; crashed into the new year with &lt;em&gt;Se Rendre Malade...&lt;/em&gt;, a new six-song set for &lt;a href="https://pilssessions.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pils Records&lt;/a&gt;. The long-running group, active in various configurations since 1999, features vocalist Gagnon, bassist Elpunkos, guitarist Spikedfred, and drummer Gab. This time out, the quartet recorded with engineer Marc Pelletier and strongarmed guest vocal appearances from &lt;a href="https://grimskunk.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Grimskunk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Joe Evil and Shantal Arroyo of &lt;a href="https://overbass.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Overbass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new album follows Défaillance&amp;#39;s 2023 appearance on the &lt;a href="https://pilssessions.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pils Sessions&lt;/a&gt; series. For that, the group tracked a set the label&amp;#39;s Gatineau studio NOMANSLAND, tackling an assortment of covers that celebrated everyone from the debauched punk legend GG Allin to deep-cut Quebec groups like &lt;a href="https://arseniq33.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Arseniq33&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/2162306-Flokons-Givr%C3%A9s" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Flokons Givrés&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/1179914-Inepsy" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Inepsy&lt;/a&gt;. Défaillance celebrated their 25th anniversary in 2024 with a 17-song comp for the label, remastered for cassette by Chany Pilote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2663285639/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://pilssessions.bandcamp.com/album/se-rendre-malade"&gt;Se Rendre Malade... by Défaillance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="teethout"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/teethout902/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TeethOut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Put Your Money Where Your Mouth Is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://highenddenimrecords.bandcamp.com/album/put-your-money-where-your-mouth-is" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charlottetown newcomers &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/teethout902/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;TeethOut&lt;/a&gt; kicked off 2025 with &lt;em&gt;Put Your Money Where Your Mouth Is&lt;/em&gt;, an energetic EP of faithful 90s skate-punk worship. The five-piece features vocalist Josh Lavigne, guitarists Ira Banks and Brandon Doyle, bassist Pete MacDonald, and drummer Jason Ezeard. You may recognize the latter from his time with the Red Deer punk act &lt;a href="https://instagram.com/trashedambulance/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Trashed Ambulance&lt;/a&gt; (often credited as &amp;#39;Ozone&amp;#39; on their records and countless side-projects). While he&amp;#39;s moved back east, those Alberta ties remain strong, with &lt;a href="https://highenddenimrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;High End Denim Records&lt;/a&gt; boasting the new act as part of their roster. The group commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This EP came together during a whirlwind of changes for us, and we&amp;#39;re proud of how it captures both the chaos and the excitement of starting something new. It&amp;#39;s amazing to see how [lead single] &amp;#39;Streetlights&amp;#39; has connected with people so far...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;TeethOut recorded with Edmonton producer Shawn Taggart (&lt;a href="https://loserpoints.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Loser Points&lt;/a&gt;) at Hog Audio, with Saguenay punk veteran &lt;a href="https://remyverreault.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Remy Verreault&lt;/a&gt; mastering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1145218099/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://highenddenimrecords.bandcamp.com/album/put-your-money-where-your-mouth-is"&gt;Put Your Money Where Your Mouth Is by TeethOut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="cut_deep"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cutdeep.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cut Deep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Model Citizen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://cutdeep.bandcamp.com/album/model-citizen" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PEI hardcore scene remains, almost inexplicably, one of the most vibrant in the country. The island&amp;#39;s prolific streak shows no signs of slowing in 2025 with the arrival of &lt;a href="https://cutdeep.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cut Deep&lt;/a&gt;. The group shared their brutal five-song debut on New Year&amp;#39;s Day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tough-as-nails &lt;em&gt;Model Citizen&lt;/em&gt; features Isaac Morrison on vocals, Charlotte Lloyd (formerly of &lt;a href="https://supermegatonne902.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Supermegatonne&lt;/a&gt;) on guitar, Anisa on bass, and Julian Annand drumming. &lt;a href="https://piercingdamagehc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Piercing Damage&lt;/a&gt; members Andrew Cormier and Liam Farrel handled the studio work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2525824880/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cutdeep.bandcamp.com/album/model-citizen"&gt;Model Citizen by Cut Deep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="poison_spear"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://poisonspear514.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Poison Spear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Institutional Trust&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://poisonspear514.bandcamp.com/album/institutional-trust" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This may be the most focus Prince Edward Island has ever received in a single edition of this newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just days into 2025, the joint PEI/Montreal hardcore project &lt;a href="https://poisonspear514.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Poison Spear&lt;/a&gt; unleashed &lt;em&gt;Institutional Trust&lt;/em&gt;, a three-song EP recorded in a whirlwind of activity. I&amp;#39;m not sure if you&amp;#39;re allowed to use the term supergroup at this sub-sub-basement of the underground, but the band&amp;#39;s roster certainly speaks to the incestuous nature of their scene. Poison Spear features vocalist/guitarist Ben Goss (&lt;a href="https://prismshores.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Prism Shores&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://white-knuckle.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;White Knuckle&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://antibodieschtn.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Antibodies&lt;/a&gt;), bassist Matt Sheidow (&lt;a href="https://celldeth.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cell Deth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://uncle902.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Uncle&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://acousmahc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Acousma&lt;/a&gt;), drummer Brett &amp;quot;Marnie&amp;quot; Sanderson (Cell Deth, Antibodies), and guitarist Liam &amp;quot;Leeman&amp;quot; Farrel (&lt;a href="https://piercingdamagehc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Piercing Damage&lt;/a&gt;, ex-&lt;a href="https://baited.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Baited&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked Brett, who&amp;#39;s always immensely helpful in unravelling the PEI universe for me, about the band&amp;#39;s origins. Here&amp;#39;s how quickly they came together:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ben and I recorded the original demo in summer of 2023 and had different plans for it but Ben ended up slapping some vocals on it and it sounded wild. He was home for the holidays so before that we recruited Matt and Liam. They learned the songs, we rehearsed together twice, played our first show January 3rd, wrote and recorded the new tape on the 4th, and released it the 9th.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find the audio at Bandcamp, with tapes arriving soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1497845950/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://poisonspear514.bandcamp.com/album/institutional-trust"&gt;INSTITUTIONAL TRUST by Poison Spear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Great Canadian Going Out Of Business Sale</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2024-12-23-the-great-canadian-going-out-of-business-sale/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2024-12-23-the-great-canadian-going-out-of-business-sale/</id>
    <published>2024-12-22T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-16T21:55:16-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m so tempted to end the newsletter here and now just to take advantage of this glorious subject line. Alas, reports of my demise at sea were unfounded, and this project stubbornly shambles into its ninth year. I&amp;#39;ve been away for much of the past month, physically at first and playing real-life catch-up ever since. My apologies if you set your watch by these updates, but that&amp;#39;s a terrible way to tell time. Here&amp;#39;s some of what you may have missed in my absence, and thanks for sticking around for another year of Some Party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="matty_grace"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Matty Grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;The Great Canadian Going Out Of Business Sale&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/album/cheap-shame-3" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s surprising to see &lt;em&gt;Cheap Shame&lt;/em&gt; listed as the first long-player from &lt;a href="http://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Matty Grace&lt;/a&gt;, but despite the Ottawa artist&amp;#39;s lengthy discography and prolific recording output, that&amp;#39;s indeed the case. The twelve-song LP arrives on February 18 via &lt;a href="https://dirtcultrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dirt Cult Records&lt;/a&gt;. You can preview the set through &amp;quot;The Great Canadian Going Out Of Business Sale.&amp;quot; The album opener finds Grace cloaking her well-worn punk attack with a shroud of moody cynicism. The track reaches for some middle ground between the bratty &amp;#39;77 sound Matty&amp;#39;s known for and the frustrated emotional resonance of Jawbreaker. In a press release, the label notes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The record was constructed over many weeks of sleepless nights and a changing personal and political landscape. Trying to find hope in the bleak reality we have in front of us is an exercise in just how resilient someone can be... &lt;em&gt;Cheap Shame&lt;/em&gt; is a work that might help you realize that just trying to get through to the next morning is enough sometimes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;While billed as a solo record, Grace worked closely on this project with Jordan Bell (&lt;a href="https://fossilrecord.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Fossil Record&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://crusades666.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Crusades&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://thecreeps.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Creeps&lt;/a&gt;). Bell plays drums and synth on the album while sharing production duties. The LP also features guest appearances from Becca Dalley (&lt;a href="https://bookbuddies.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Book Buddies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://grosshfx.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;G.R.O.S.S.&lt;/a&gt;), Chris Venoit (ex-&lt;a href="https://welovetalkshowhost.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Talk Show Host&lt;/a&gt;), and James Robertson (&lt;a href="https://weekenddads.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Weekend Dads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://thehemingways.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Hemingways&lt;/a&gt;). Will Killingsworth mastered at Dead Air Studios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grace has deep roots in the Halifax punk scene through bands like &lt;a href="https://futuregirls.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Future Girls&lt;/a&gt; and more recently &lt;a href="https://cluttered.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Cluttered&lt;/a&gt;. She relocated to Ottawa following the pandemic, where she now plays in the trio &lt;a href="https://crisisparty.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Crisis Party&lt;/a&gt;. The artist also recently contributed a track to &lt;a href="https://fasterandlouder.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Faster and Louder Records&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; &lt;em&gt;Acoustic Brunch&lt;/em&gt; compilation, appearing alongside new material from Audio Visceral, Fast Eddie, and Dave Rocket, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=62193328/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://mattygrace.bandcamp.com/album/cheap-shame-3"&gt;Cheap Shame by Matty Grace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="snake_river"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://snakeriver.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Snake River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&amp;quot;TV Light&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://snakeriver.bandcamp.com/track/tv-light" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regina psych outfit &lt;a href="https://snakeriver.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Snake River&lt;/a&gt; recently shared &amp;quot;TV Light,&amp;quot; their second stand-alone single of 2024 and a tribute to Television&amp;#39;s late Tom Verlaine. The track, issued in celebration of the group&amp;#39;s 10th anniversary, finds Christopher Sleightholm performing an extended jam in the style of their art-punk heroes - directly echoing a few &amp;quot;Marquee Moon&amp;quot; licks in the outro. The band recorded at Regina&amp;#39;s Song Has No End Studio with Sleightholm engineering and mixing. Orion Paradis mastered at Soul Sound. On this outing, Snake River includes John De Gennaro on guitar, Dustin Gamracy on drums, Whistlin&amp;#39; Jeff M on bass, and Amber Pb on violas and vocals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The single is the band&amp;#39;s second one-off of the year, following the harmony-drenched 60s-pop of April&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ll Take You To Another Side.&amp;quot; Last fall, Sleightholm issued &lt;em&gt;Looking For The Great Unseen&lt;/em&gt;, his fourth solo LP featuring nearly a dozen collaborators backing him as The Beautiful Band. Snake River (proper) last issued &lt;em&gt;The Phantom Carriage&lt;/em&gt; in 2022. That project showcased live recordings from December 2021, written to score the 100-year-old silent Swedish horror film of the same name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll leave it up to you whether to queue &amp;quot;TV Light&amp;quot; before or after that &lt;a href="https://www.tyburrswatchlist.com/50-ways-of-hearing-marquee-moon/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;six-and-an-half hour supercut&lt;/a&gt; of Tom Verlaine&amp;#39;s live &amp;quot;Marquee Moon&amp;quot; solos, but it&amp;#39;s a busy time of year so, for your sanity, I&amp;#39;d suggest before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=1832204896/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://snakeriver.bandcamp.com/track/tv-light"&gt;TV Light by Snake River&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="taxi_girls"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://taxigirls.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Taxi Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rainy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://taxigirls.bandcamp.com/album/rainy-2" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Montreal punk&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll quartet &lt;a href="https://taxigirls.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Taxi Girls&lt;/a&gt; have a new 7&amp;quot; out through &lt;a href="https://wildhoneyrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Wild Honey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://dirtcultrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Dirt Cult Records&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Rainy&amp;quot; leads the two-song set, paired with &amp;quot;The Lion&amp;#39;s Share&amp;quot; on the flip. In a press release, the band shared some background on both tracks:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;#39;Rainy&amp;#39; [originated as] a narrative of taking pills but eventually evolved into a story about an abusive ex-friend who treated the group poorly... someone that they&amp;#39;ve got dirt on and are saving that dirt for a rainy day!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sentiment of &amp;quot;The Lion&amp;#39;s Share&amp;quot; similarly shifted over time. While the group wrote the song to express a sense of longing, they eventually found that sentiment underscored by &amp;quot;the innate perspective that this individual is taking up more mental space [than] they deserved.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taxi Girls&amp;#39; newly expanded lineup features &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; rhythm section of Jamie Radu (on bass, guitar, and vocals) and Lynn Poulin (drums and backing vocals), alongside Vera Bozickovic (guitar, bass, and vocals) and guitarist Gabrielle Noël Bégin (&lt;a href="https://scareqc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;SCARE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://margarettracteur.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Margaret Tracteur&lt;/a&gt;). The band&amp;#39;s been on a tear this year, sharing stages with NOBRO, Lagwagon, The Hives, Pansy Division, and NOFX (on their farewell tour). Iggy Pop even picked up on the group, spinning a pair of Taxi Girls tracks on his BBC radio show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new set follows up on 2023&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Coming Up Roses&lt;/em&gt;. Look for the band&amp;#39;s debut full-length in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3279034386/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://taxigirls.bandcamp.com/album/rainy-2"&gt;Rainy by Taxi Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="the_ape-ettes"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theape-ettes.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Ape-ettes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Matter What&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://theape-ettes.bandcamp.com/album/no-matter-what" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; - Watch &amp;quot;Backseat&amp;quot; on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/-tz8D3cSZvw" class="" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sudbury garage trio &lt;a href="https://theape-ettes.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;The Ape-ettes&lt;/a&gt; have a new 7&amp;quot; out through Denver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://snappylittlenumbers.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Snappy Little Numbers&lt;/a&gt; and Mexico&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/discosdemuerte" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Discos de Muerte&lt;/a&gt;. The infectious &lt;em&gt;No Matter What&lt;/em&gt; sounds delightfully uncomplicated, a friendly reminder of the joy punk can find in earnest minimalism. Three lovely tracks in just shy of five minutes. What more do you need?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The record arrived alongside a video for &amp;quot;Backseat,&amp;quot; which features &lt;a href="https://strangeattractor.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Strange Attractor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s Jeff Houle as the mustachioed record exec gatekeeping the band&amp;#39;s big break. &lt;em&gt;No Matter What&lt;/em&gt; is a family affair, with Mitch Houle (&lt;a href="https://tommyandthecommies.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Tommy and the Commies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Statues-24116128619/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Statues&lt;/a&gt;) recording the band at Sudbury&amp;#39;s Piss Factory Studio. He mixed and mastered, as well. The Ape-ettes features Julie Houle on guitar and vocals, Andrée St-Onge on bass, and Melanie Mcdonald drumming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new record follows the group&amp;#39;s summer 2023 EP &lt;em&gt;Simply&lt;/em&gt;. That platter, a four-song set co-released by &lt;a href="https://retarecords.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Reta Records&lt;/a&gt;, marked the band&amp;#39;s return to action after a lengthy hiatus. The group&amp;#39;s previous record came out in the innocent summer of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1621934037/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theape-ettes.bandcamp.com/album/no-matter-what"&gt;No Matter What by the Ape-ettes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id="pasmort"&gt;&lt;span class="artist-title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://pasmort.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PasMort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="media-title"&gt;&lt;em&gt;C&amp;#39;est Arrivé Près de Chez Vous&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class='media-links' data-controller='share'&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preview and purchase at &lt;a href="https://pasmort.bandcamp.com/album/cest-arriv-pr-s-de-chez-vous" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span data-share-target='container'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rivière Du Loup&amp;#39;s irreverent &lt;a href="https://pasmort.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;PasMort&lt;/a&gt; are back with &lt;em&gt;C&amp;#39;est Arrivé Près de Chez Vous&lt;/em&gt;, a new four-song EP that clocks in at a brisk seven minutes (just enough time, they note, to make crêpes). The set again finds the band delivering a propulsive set of melodic punk tunes that often veer off into unhinged lyrical territory. You&amp;#39;ll find that tendency front and centre in &amp;quot;Mononoc&amp;#39; Pete,&amp;quot; a song dedicated to weird uncles:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Tout le monde a un oncle un peu weird qui habite dans le bois, qui a déjà vu des extraterrestres pis qui chasse le pigeon à l&amp;#39;arbalète!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mononc&amp;#39; Pete, c&amp;#39;est notre hommage à tous ces bonhommes magiques là qui boivent le thé avec le Sasquatch pis qui parlent aux carcajous!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quartet recorded with Mathieu Bossé at Le sous-sol à Francis, with Brad Boatright mastering at Audiosiege. PasMort features vocalist/guitarist Jonathan St-Pierre, bassist Louis-Alexandre Bouliane, drummer Francis Bernard, and guitarist Olivier Thériault - past and present members of &lt;a href="https://atreeatlast.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;A Tree At Last&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://albatrosqc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Albatros&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lostlove.bandcamp.com/" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Lost Love&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://striverqc.bandcamp.com" class="" target="_blank"&gt;Striver&lt;/a&gt;. The new set follows up on 2022&amp;#39;s full-length &lt;em&gt;Pas Responsable des Accidents&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='media-wrapper'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" seamless data-src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1607800455/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" class="lazyload"&gt;&lt;a href="https://pasmort.bandcamp.com/album/cest-arriv-pr-s-de-chez-vous"&gt;C'est Arrivé Près de Chez Vous by PasMort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
