<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Some Party</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly newsletter on independent Canadian rock'n'roll, curated every Sunday evening by Adam White of Punknews.org. A sober second thought on new music, cool records, and the people making their own culture.</subtitle>
  <id>https://www.someparty.ca/</id>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/"/>
  <link href="https://www.someparty.ca/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-08-05T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Friend Army</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-08-06-friend-army/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-08-06-friend-army/</id>
    <published>2017-08-05T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-07T12:07:27-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wearetheburninghell.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Burning Hell&lt;/a&gt; are back with another new album. &lt;em&gt;Revival Beach&lt;/em&gt; is the follow up to 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Public Library&lt;/em&gt; and will be the prolific band&amp;#39;s eighth full length. With their personnel always shifting, the indie rock act currently finds itself as a trio, with Mathias Kom&amp;#39;s vocals and guitar backed by Ariel Sharratt on drums and bass clarinet, with Darren Browne playing bass and bouzouki. The first single from the new record is titled &amp;quot;Friend Army&amp;quot; and finds the group in full rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll mode backing some of Kom&amp;#39;s signature wordplay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wTu5HXq4D-Q?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revival Beach&lt;/em&gt; was recorded and mixed by Al Harle at &lt;a href="http://www.bigjellystudios.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Big Jelly Studios&lt;/a&gt; in Ramsgate, UK this past June. Look for a September 29th release on &lt;a href="http://bbislandmusic.com/shop/the-burning-hell-revival-beach-vinyl-cd" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BB*ISLAND&lt;/a&gt;. You can check out the cover art, track listing, and more over at the label&amp;#39;s website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of The Burning Hell, a frequent member in recent years has been Peterborugh&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.nickferrio.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Ferrio&lt;/a&gt;. While Nick&amp;#39;s taking a paternity leave from the group for this LP, he does have a collection of his own music that&amp;#39;s also set for a September 29th release. Ferrio&amp;#39;s new 10 song record is titled &lt;em&gt;Soothsayer&lt;/em&gt; and was recorded with James McKenty in Peterborough with &lt;a href="https://seanconway.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sean Conway&lt;/a&gt; on bass and &lt;a href="https://brandonmunro.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Brandon Munro&lt;/a&gt; on drums. There&amp;#39;s no audio to share from this one yet, but expect it soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Remember all the speculation last week with regards to the tenth anniversary of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/attackinblack/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Attack In Black&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s
&lt;em&gt;Marriage&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone Records&lt;/a&gt; will be celebrating with a vinyl reissue (180 gram, tweaked artwork, and if you&amp;#39;re in for the bundle, packaged with a new poster and t-shirt). That&amp;#39;s perhaps less fantastical news than some were holding out for, but it&amp;#39;s pretty cool for what it is (in particular if you missed the boat on the Record Store Day reissue of this album from a few years back).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://drewthomson.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drew Thomson&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://singlemothersband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Single Mothers&lt;/a&gt; dropped a surprise solo full length last week, billed as &lt;em&gt;The Drew Thomson Foundation Vol 1: Huh, it&amp;#39;s generally pretty empty in here&lt;/em&gt;. The seven song set was produced, mixed, and engineered by Ian Romano (of the aforementioned Attack In Black), who also drums on the recordings. Ross Miller of Single Mothers and the Dirty Nil plays bass and additional guitar on the songs. Given how much Thomson draws on anxiety and sarcasm on Single Mothers records, it&amp;#39;s nice to hear his approach when the stylistic confines of punk rock are lifted a little.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=761993831/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://drewthomson.bandcamp.com/album/the-drew-thomson-foundation-vol-1-huh-its-generally-pretty-empty-in-here"&gt;The Drew Thomson Foundation Vol 1: Huh, it's generally pretty empty in here by The Drew Thomson Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Ottawa pop-punk group &lt;a href="http://www.theriptides.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Riptides&lt;/a&gt; are gearing up for a September 12th release of their new 18 song full length &lt;em&gt;Canadian Graffiti&lt;/em&gt;. Portland&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://somethingtodorecords.storenvy.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Something To Do Records&lt;/a&gt; will be handling the LP, which is limited to 500. The band recorded at &lt;a href="http://soniciguana.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sonic Iguana&lt;/a&gt; studios with Mass Giorgini (Squirtgun, Screeching Weasel, Common Rider) and the album features art by Archie Comics&amp;#39; legend Dan Parent. The sunny lead single, complete with doo-wop harmonies, is titled &amp;quot;Goodbye Hawaii&amp;quot; and it&amp;#39;s streaming now via &lt;a href="http://dyingscene.com/news/the-riptides-pop-punk-announce-new-album-canadian-graffiti-stream-new-track-goodbye-hawaii/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dying Scene&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.weavesband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Weaves&lt;/a&gt;, with their Polaris shortlist slot and prominent festival appearances this summer, are having a bit of a limelight moment. The band&amp;#39;s taken the opportunity to announce their sophomore LP, &lt;em&gt;Wide Open&lt;/em&gt;. The record&amp;#39;s due on October 6th via &lt;a href="http://buzzrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Buzz Records&lt;/a&gt; in Canada, &lt;a href="http://kaninerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kanine&lt;/a&gt; in the States, and &lt;a href="http://www.memphis-industries.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Memphis Industries&lt;/a&gt; overseas. The 11 song album opens with &amp;quot;#53,&amp;quot; which has a bit of a soaring new wave thing going on. Check it out below. The album art, full track listing, and international tour dates running through the end of November can be found at &lt;a href="http://pitchfork.com/news/weaves-announce-new-album-wide-open-share-new-song-53-listen/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pitchfork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/334967625&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;From atop Weaves&amp;#39; mountain of good will you can probably wave at &lt;a href="http://partnerband.tumblr.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt; over on their own peak. The Windsor-via-Sackville rock band seems to be doing just about everything right in the lead up to &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt; this fall. Everything the group&amp;#39;s released so far has been enormously fun and the new single &amp;quot;Play The Field&amp;quot; continues that trend. The song&amp;#39;s featured in a new music video directed by Lesley Marshall and filmed at the University of Windsor. Josée Caron described the new track:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This song is based on a true story of when I was in grade eight. My friends were really good at sports but I definitely was not; I was eager to belong. I gathered all my courage and tried out for my school basketball team. Somehow I made it past tryouts and onto the single ‘A’ team. I was so happy to just be on a team, it didn’t matter that I would only score one basket all season, or that I would score on my own team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Lucy (Niles) and I try to channel that blissful state in this song, which could be described as an effort to reclaim some of our dignity by surrendering to our true talents. It’s about admiring, romanticizing, and desiring the dignified excellence that seems to come along with being good at sports, knowing it’s something you will never truly experience but not really minding because you’re stoked that you get to hang out with your crush at practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Caron and Niles provided some further background on their writing process in an interview at &lt;a href="http://www.stereogum.com/1954647/band-to-watch-partner/franchises/interview/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stereogum&lt;/a&gt;. The new album&amp;#39;s out on September 8th via &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/81gPPWA58m0?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Red Deer, Alberta skate-punk act &lt;a href="https://trashedambulance.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Trashed Ambulance&lt;/a&gt; announced a new EP for release at the end of August on Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Thousand Island Records&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Instant&lt;/em&gt; will be the band&amp;#39;s second EP of the year, following &lt;em&gt;A Dime For Every Time&lt;/em&gt; in May. It features two new tracks (&amp;quot;Kooby&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;12 Inches of Christmas&amp;quot;) along with three re-recorded songs that originally appeared on the band&amp;#39;s 2016 release &lt;em&gt;Blurry Thoughts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3611368799/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thousandislandsrecords.bandcamp.com/album/instant"&gt;Instant by Trashed Ambulance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal melodic pop-punk act &lt;a href="https://lostlove.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lost Love&lt;/a&gt; have announced a set of August tour dates in Quebec and Ontario. Punknews has the &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64395/lost-love-maladroit-canada" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;dates listed&lt;/a&gt;. The band will be taking Parisian punk act Maladroit along for the trip. Lost Love last released &lt;em&gt;Comfortable Scars&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp&lt;/a&gt; in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;FME&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m excited to announce that Some Party is sponsored this month by the &lt;a href="http://www.fmeat.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Festival de musique émergente en Abitibi-Témiscamingue&lt;/a&gt;, or FME for short. The festival, now in it&amp;#39;s 15th year, will take place in Rouyn-Noranda, Quebec from August 31st through September 3rd. The 70 acts performing in this small mining town represent a pretty huge variety of genres, everything from folk to hip hop to metal and electronic music at equal measure in both French and English. I&amp;#39;ll highlight a few of the Canadian acts performing each week this month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://duchesssays.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dutchess Says&lt;/a&gt; are FME veterans, having played the event on at least three prior occasions. Founded in 2003, the four-piece plays what I&amp;#39;ve seen kicked around as kraut-punk, synth-punk, or moog-rock. Any and all of those labels could be attached to the band&amp;#39;s sprawling third full length, &lt;em&gt;Sciences Nouvelles&lt;/em&gt;, which was released in late 2016 on &lt;a href="http://www.slovenly.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slovenly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.bonsound.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bonsound&lt;/a&gt;. At this year&amp;#39;s festival Dutchess Says cap off the opening night with a show at the Petit Théâtre du Vieux Noranda featuring Parisian dance-punk act Slosh and Montreal prog quintet Atsuko Chiba also on the bill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZjvnmiqmXQY?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Also hailing from Montreal, &lt;a href="https://chocolatmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chocolat&lt;/a&gt; is currently supporting their third full length, &lt;em&gt;Rencontrer Looloo&lt;/em&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s latest effort fully embraces the weird extremes of the psych-rock spectrum, which of course means there&amp;#39;s a narrative that follows interdimensional space gurus and the like. Musically Chocolat shift often from charging hard rock to danceable grooves, taking as many genre twists over the course of the record as their trippy lyrical concept allows. The album was released this past November by &lt;a href="http://www.daretocarerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dare to Care&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://beyondbeyondisbeyond.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beyond Beyond is Beyond&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://teenagemenopause.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenage Menopause&lt;/a&gt;. At FME the band will play Cabaret de la dernière on Friday, September 1st.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XkZehXmNwiQ?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Come What May</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-30-come-what-may/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-30-come-what-may/</id>
    <published>2017-07-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-31T09:23:47-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Tomorrow (July 31st) marks the 10 year anniversary of the release of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/attackinblack/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Attack In Black&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s first LP &lt;em&gt;Marriage&lt;/em&gt;. If you&amp;#39;re of a certain age and happen to take part in the southern Ontario music scene, this was a record that had seismic impact. Living in the Niagara region it certainly feels that way. The stories and struggles surrounding this release are a pretty essential part of the scene lore around here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Despite its influence it&amp;#39;s odd to think nostalgically about this album, particularly because the four members of the band have themselves moved (both collectively and as solo artists) so aggressively away from this sound. One never got the impression that &lt;em&gt;Marriage&lt;/em&gt;, ostensibly a pop-punk record with a few potentially radio-friendly singles, ever sat comfortably with the group. It was only four months before the folky, eclectic, low-fi follow up &lt;em&gt;The Curve of the Earth&lt;/em&gt; was released, and it&amp;#39;s that record, not so much &lt;em&gt;Marriage&lt;/em&gt;, that foreshadowed the last 10 years of Daniel Romano, Spencer Burton, Ian Kehoe, and Ian Romano&amp;#39;s musical output.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I hate to write this on the cusp of an announcement and find myself immediately behind on the news, but there may or may not be something announced tomorrow. &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s released a short video on their social channels commemorating the 10 year mark. That&amp;#39;s probably all it is, just a little nod to mark the date. But it&amp;#39;s possible that something&amp;#39;s up. &lt;em&gt;Marriage&lt;/em&gt; did see a Record Store Day reissue a few years back, but could something further be in the works? I&amp;#39;ve never considered the Attack In Black members to be particularly sentimental about their own output, so I have my doubts about some of the more fantastical speculation I&amp;#39;ve seen online, but we&amp;#39;ll see Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-video" data-lang="en"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/10yearsofMarriage?src=hash"&gt;#10yearsofMarriage&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AIBmarriage?src=hash"&gt;#AIBmarriage&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/U9WToyuMEu"&gt;pic.twitter.com/U9WToyuMEu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Dine Alone Records (@dinealonemusic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dinealonemusic/status/891011955376443392"&gt;July 28, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/head&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of Dine Alone, the label has announced the debut LP from &lt;a href="https://julieandthewrongguys.bandcamp.com/releases" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Julie &amp;amp; The Wrong Guys&lt;/a&gt;. The band, lead by former Eric&amp;#39;s Trip member &lt;a href="https://juliedoiron.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Julie Doiron&lt;/a&gt;, features the rhythm section of Toronto hardcore band &lt;a href="http://www.cancerbats.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cancer Bats&lt;/a&gt; (Mike Peters and Jaye Schwarzer), along with Edmonton singer / songwriter &lt;a href="http://eamonmcgrath.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Eamon McGrath&lt;/a&gt;. While this project&amp;#39;s been percolating for some time now (there are two 7&amp;quot; singles floating around from as far back as 2012), this album and the supporting tours will mark Doiron&amp;#39;s major return to music after some time away. A video for the new song &amp;quot;You Wanted What I Wanted&amp;quot; is now online to check out. Full details on the 10 song record and a fairly in-depth account of its recording can be found at the &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/artists/julie-the-wrong-guys/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;label&lt;/a&gt;. Look for the album on September 8th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2r0NQxpStlA?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The debut 7&amp;quot; from Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://sorepoints.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sore Points&lt;/a&gt; arrives this week on &lt;a href="http://www.hoseheadrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hosehead&lt;/a&gt;. The band, which features members of &lt;a href="https://nervoustalk.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nervous Talk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://spectresvancouver.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Spectres&lt;/a&gt;, churns out a tough, fast take on late 70s punk (the Ramones and Damned are namedropped in the album announcement, and not without merit). In a modern context, the band feels a little like Night Birds without the surf guitar. The four song 7&amp;quot; was recorded by Felix Fung at Little Red Sounds, and it&amp;#39;s pretty damn fun. Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1601780405/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://sorepoints.bandcamp.com/album/dont-want-to-7"&gt;Don't Want To 7" by Sore Points&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Hamilton alt-country trio &lt;a href="https://www.elliottbrood.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Elliott BROOD&lt;/a&gt; are an important band in my personal pantheon. Their &lt;em&gt;Tin Type&lt;/em&gt; EP (everyone knows &amp;quot;Oh Alberta&amp;quot;) arrived in my life just as I was starting to seriously explore the Canadian indie music world outside of the punk umbrella. The band announced that their fifth proper full length, titled &lt;em&gt;Ghost Gardens&lt;/em&gt;, will be available on September 15th via &lt;a href="http://paperbagrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paper Bag&lt;/a&gt;. One of the 11 new songs is &amp;quot;`Til The Sun Comes Up Again,&amp;quot; which you can hear below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 442px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=695493711/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://elliottbrood.bandcamp.com/track/til-the-sun-comes-up-again-2"&gt;'Til The Sun Comes Up Again by Elliott BROOD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Welland, Ontario hardcore band &lt;a href="http://zerohc.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Zero&lt;/a&gt; have unveiled a new single titled &amp;quot;Can You Help Me?&amp;quot; paired with the b-side &amp;quot;Confounded.&amp;quot; The four-piece, which features Ross Miller of The Dirty Nil, Single Mothers, and SIDEMAN, is following up their 2016 &lt;em&gt;Say No More&lt;/em&gt; EP. Cassettes of the new material should be available soon. Amusingly, to me at least, Discogs lists this as the 81st band with the name Zero in their catalog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=118431483/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://zerohc.bandcamp.com/album/can-you-help-me"&gt;Can You Help Me? by ZERO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto garage / psych / noise-pop act &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fakepalms/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fake Palms&lt;/a&gt; have announced a September 15th release date for their new full length &lt;em&gt;Pure Mind&lt;/em&gt;, a joint release between &lt;a href="http://buzzrecords.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Buzz Records&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.pleasencerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pleasence Records&lt;/a&gt;. The band recorded the follow-up to their self-titled 2015 debut with a pair of big name Canadian producers: Graham Walsh of Holy Fuck and Josh Korody of Beliefs (the latter of which produced the recent Dilly Dally and Dirty Nil records). The first track from the new project, titled &amp;quot;Glass Walls,&amp;quot; brings some of their 60s influences to the fore (just listen to those harmonies in the chorus).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/334945668&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pleasence has also announced the signing of Toronto post-punk act &lt;a href="https://whimm.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;WHIMM&lt;/a&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s frenetic new single &amp;quot;Town Hall&amp;quot; was produced by Dean Tzenos of &lt;a href="http://www.odonisodonis.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Odonis Odonis&lt;/a&gt; at Union Sound. It will appear on the record &lt;em&gt;A Stare Ajar&lt;/em&gt; which will see a release later this year. While we don&amp;#39;t know a lot about that album as of yet, it will feature some added strings from guests such as Anna Mayberry (HSY / ANAMAI).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/334259094&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghettoblastermagazine.com/2017/video-premiere-new-swears-halos-hell/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ghettoblaster&lt;/a&gt; debuted the video for &lt;a href="https://newswears.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; &amp;quot;Halos in Hell,&amp;quot; which appears on the Ottawa band&amp;#39;s recently released third LP &lt;em&gt;and the Magic of Horses&lt;/em&gt; (Dine Alone). The band continues to tour in support of the record, with upcoming shows including an appearance at the &lt;a href="http://www.wolfeislandmusicfestival.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Wolfe Island Music Festival&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YUjXYlohJfU?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Punknews.org &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64372/media-dead-broke-salem-punknews-exclusive" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;premiered&lt;/a&gt; the new EP from Oakville&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://deadbrokeband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dead Broke&lt;/a&gt;. The three song set, titled &lt;em&gt;Nice Words&lt;/em&gt;, is now available over at &lt;a href="https://dead-broke.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt;. The four-piece will be touring their indie rock / punk sound down to The Fest in Gainesville, Florida this October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2235866708/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://dead-broke.bandcamp.com/album/nice-words"&gt;Nice Words by Dead Broke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;While you&amp;#39;re at Punknews, make sure you check out the second new single from Vancouver&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://woolworm.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Woolworm&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Seer&amp;quot; will appear on the band&amp;#39;s sophomore LP &lt;em&gt;Deserve To Die&lt;/em&gt;, due out on August 25th on &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt;. It gives a pretty good sense of the album&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;hardcore band plays moody alt-rock&amp;quot; vibe and shows off some of the big production values they got working with Jesse Gander at Rain City (White Lung, Japandroids).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The site also &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64384/exclusivevideos-the-creepshow-sticks-and-stones-punknews-exclusive" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;premiered&lt;/a&gt; a video for the stomping rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll song &amp;quot;Sticks &amp;amp; Stones&amp;quot; by Montreal punk / psychobilly group &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheCreepshowOfficial/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Creepshow&lt;/a&gt;. The song will appear on &lt;em&gt;Death at my Door&lt;/em&gt;, a September 15th release through &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SJ-KGGS_SY0?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Montreal pop-punk act &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/mansbridgetheband/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mansbridge&lt;/a&gt; have announced a new 10 track LP titled &lt;em&gt;Juxtapose&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;#39;ll see an August 18th release from &lt;a href="https://myfingersmybrainrecords.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;My Fingers! My Brain! Records&lt;/a&gt; and Maps &amp;amp; Continents Records. The anthemic single &amp;quot;Cheese Is Wasted on the Rich&amp;quot; was premiered over at &lt;a href="http://dyingscene.com/news/ds-exclusive-mansbridge-pop-punk-premieres-cheese-is-wasted-on-the-rich-from-upcoming-lp/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dying Scene&lt;/a&gt; this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Winnipeg&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://propagandhi.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Propagandhi&lt;/a&gt; have announced &lt;a href="http://www.punkanormalactivity.com/2017/07/25/propagandhi-announce-north-american-tour/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;headlining tour dates&lt;/a&gt; in support of their upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Victory Lap&lt;/em&gt;. They&amp;#39;ll hit a handful of Canadian cities (London, Toronto, Ottawa, Montreal, Vancouver) and both coasts of the US in October and November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/careersuicidehc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Career Suicide&lt;/a&gt; will take their &lt;em&gt;Machine Response&lt;/em&gt; tour to Europe in early August, playing Spain, France, Italy, Germany, Russia, and Ukraine in a whirlwind two weeks of shows. You can find those dates at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/careersuicidehc/photos/a.136685016406995.33448.124251104317053/1577924475616368/?type=3&amp;amp;theater" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally I&amp;#39;d like to give one last thanks to St. Catharines, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; concert hall for sponsoring the July month of Some Party. Look for shows this week at Warehouse from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1382490938509900/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Bleach Bath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1413918535360037/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Plagueworm&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/451768621860259/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Heavy Hearts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Victory Lap</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-23-victory-lap/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-23-victory-lap/</id>
    <published>2017-07-22T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-23T23:50:17-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m trying to avoid using the phrase &amp;quot;unless you&amp;#39;ve been living under a rock&amp;quot; on this newsletter, as this publishing schedule is meant to encourage and allow for all manor of subterranean habitation. That said, it was pretty hard to miss the news online this week that &lt;a href="https://propagandhi.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Propagandhi&lt;/a&gt;, the internationally renown Winnipeg-based anti-fascist punk band, had announced and previewed their next record &lt;em&gt;Victory Lap&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In case you did miss it: &lt;em&gt;Victory Lap&lt;/em&gt; will run 12 songs and will see a September 29th release on &lt;a href="http://epitaph.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Epitaph Records&lt;/a&gt;. The band&amp;#39;s seventh full length since forming in 1986, it follows up 2012&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Failed States&lt;/em&gt; and marks the studio debut of guitarist Sulynn Hago (imported from Florida to succeed David Guillas a few years back). It should also go without saying that this is the band&amp;#39;s first record of the Trump era. The riffy title track can be streamed below. Vocalist/guitarist Chris Hanna also shared the lyrics on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wTANmHJhbF8?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;div class='dib tl w-100 maxread'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet dib tl" data-lang="en"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Oh ya, here's the dang lyrics for that hot new single that's rocketring up charts, name of "Victory Lap". &lt;a href="https://t.co/MX7Ww3Jdj8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/MX7Ww3Jdj8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— PROPAGANDHI (@propagandhi) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/propagandhi/status/887341607732879363"&gt;July 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/head&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;There&amp;#39;s going to be a lot to unpack about this record in the coming months, so I&amp;#39;ll keep my powder (mostly) dry for now. I am deeply curious about how an overtly political punk band engages with the US political reality this year. In normal times, a band like Propagandhi would serve to highlight injustices that us in the middle were comfortably ignoring. With so many norms upended and US politics in a near-constant state of crisis, this is not a normal time. How does a band like Propagandhi position itself in 2017?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pittsburgh&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.cruelnoiserecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cruel Noise Records&lt;/a&gt; has set a release date for the six-song 7&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://www.discogs.com/Booji-Boys-Sweet-Boy-/release/10593600" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sweet Boy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href="https://boojiboysfuneral.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Booji Boys&lt;/a&gt;. The record, which compiles material the Halifax band originally made available on a limited run of tapes, now has an August 18th date attached. There are five originals in the set along with a cover of The Undertones&amp;#39; &amp;quot;Family Entertainment.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cLYWO82FFq8?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Also from Halifax, experimental indie-pop act &lt;a href="https://heavenforreal.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Heaven For Real&lt;/a&gt; are set to tour both Canada and Japan this September in support of their 2016 &lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt; release &lt;em&gt;Kill Your Memory&lt;/em&gt;. Following an appearance at SappyFest on August 7th they&amp;#39;ll play Montreal, Ottawa, Guelph, and Toronto before taking the long flight to Tokyo. You can find the dates at &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/heaven_for_real_map_out_canadian_tour_dates" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Niagara-on-the-Lake post-hardcore act &lt;a href="http://heavyheartsband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Heavy Hearts&lt;/a&gt; premiered a video for their new song &amp;quot;Unravel (Your Love)&amp;quot; at &lt;a href="http://newnoisemagazine.com/heavy-hearts-unravel-love-video/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Noise&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="http://newdamagerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Damage&lt;/a&gt;-released single comes amidst their ongoing US tour and gives some hint at the direction they&amp;#39;ll follow on their eventual follow up to 2016&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Bliss&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/swrE6Se7-LQ?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/StrandedFest/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stranded Fest&lt;/a&gt; is back for a second year on Saturday, August 5th in Toronto. The event will bring together seven GTA bands to play cover sets, with &lt;a href="https://pkewx3.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pkew Pkew Pkew&lt;/a&gt; performing as The Clash, &lt;a href="https://goodkid.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Good Kid&lt;/a&gt; as The Strokes, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RomancerBand/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Romancer&lt;/a&gt; doing Jimmy Eat World, &lt;a href="http://www.theimplications.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Implications&lt;/a&gt; as Arctic Monkeys, &lt;a href="https://www.cleopatrick.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cleopatrick&lt;/a&gt; as The Black Keys, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/cactusglass/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Glass Cactus&lt;/a&gt; as The Story So Far, and &lt;a href="https://minority905.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Minority 905&lt;/a&gt; as Simple Plan. &lt;a href="http://canadianbeats.ca/2017/07/23/win-2-tickets-to-torontos-stranded-fest-2017/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Canadian Beats&lt;/a&gt; is drawing for a pair tickets on their website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I realize that I mention &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey &amp;amp; the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt; a lot on here, but the world needs more of what they&amp;#39;re up to. You can see what I mean over at &lt;a href="http://www.cbcmusic.ca/first-plays/418/first-play-sam-coffey-and-the-iron-lungs" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CBC Music&lt;/a&gt; until the 28th, where the new full length is streaming in full. If you&amp;#39;re familiar with Coffey&amp;#39;s earlier work the leap they&amp;#39;ve taken on this record is enormous. Working with producer Alex Bonenfant (METZ, Crystal Castles) the band embraced an arena-ready 70s power-pop vibe in a way that never seems retro. It&amp;#39;s enormously more confident and celebratory than anything they&amp;#39;ve put to tape before (and there&amp;#39;s nary a sign of the country influences of that earlier work either). The 9 song full-length is due on July 28th via &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="http://burgerrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Burger Records&lt;/a&gt; down south.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new full length from &lt;a href="http://www.theweatherstation.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Weather Station&lt;/a&gt; will be self-titled and is set for an October 6th release on &lt;a href="http://www.paradiseofbachelors.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paradise of Bachelors&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.outside-music.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Outside Music&lt;/a&gt;. Singer / songwriter Tamara Lindeman&amp;#39;s put together eleven songs for the album, including &amp;quot;Thirty&amp;quot; which you can stream below. Lindeman commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;I wanted to make a rock and roll record, but one that sounded how I wanted it to sound, which of course is nothing like rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Whatever you want to call it, &amp;quot;Thirty&amp;quot; feels pretty special and is completely engrossing. I&amp;#39;m really looking forward to this record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D3F3DsXLSaw?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Episode 335 of &lt;a href="http://vishkhanna.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Vish Khanna&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://vishkhanna.com/2017/07/20/ep-335-the-sadies-on-long-night/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Kreative Kontrol&lt;/a&gt; podcast features &lt;a href="http://www.thesadies.net/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Sadies&lt;/a&gt; performing songs from their Polaris long listed album &lt;em&gt;Northern Passages&lt;/em&gt;. The prolific Toronto alt-country / garage rock band visited Khanna&amp;#39;s TV show &lt;em&gt;Long Night&lt;/em&gt; to perform before the studio audience and chat about their catalogue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://chadvangaalen.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chad VanGaalen&lt;/a&gt; has released a new music video for the song &amp;quot;Pine and Clover,&amp;quot; which the celebrated Calgary musician directed and animated himself. The song appears on the upcoming &lt;em&gt;Light Information&lt;/em&gt; LP, due September 8th on &lt;a href="http://www.flemisheye.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Flemish Eye&lt;/a&gt; in Canada and &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere. You can find comments from the artist on the video&amp;#39;s production, along with a list of upcoming fall tour dates, at &lt;a href="http://www.sidewalkhustle.com/chad-vangaalen-shares-pine-and-clover-video/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sidewalk Hustle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WQqTFJdNpZI?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Staying with Calgary for a moment, long-running pop punk act &lt;a href="https://chixdiggit.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chixdiggit!&lt;/a&gt; have announced a &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64332/tours-chixdiggit-europe" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;European tour&lt;/a&gt; for early August. The band is travelling to and from the Tolmin, Slovenia music festival &lt;a href="http://www.punkrockholiday.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punk Rock Holiday&lt;/a&gt; and have shows scheduled in the Netherlands, Germany, Belgium, and Austria along the way. The band is supporting their 2016 release &lt;em&gt;2012&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;quot;twenty twelve,&amp;quot; after Rush), a 20+ minute single-song that they&amp;#39;re claiming is the world&amp;#39;s longest punk song. I spoke to frontman KJ Jansen about it (and more) last year on the &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/61809/interviews-hockey-beer-apologies-and-25-years-of-chixdiggit-with-kj-jansen" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews Podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto duo &lt;a href="http://beliefsmusic.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beliefs&lt;/a&gt; have announced a full length release for September titled &lt;em&gt;Habitat&lt;/em&gt;, premiering a video for the dark, dreamy post-punk track &amp;quot;1994&amp;quot; over at Billboard. This will be Jesse Crowe and Josh Korody&amp;#39;s third full length, following 2015’s sophomore effort &lt;em&gt;Leaper&lt;/em&gt;. Korody, who&amp;#39;s produced acclaimed recent albums from Dilly Dally and The Dirty Nil, served as producer on &lt;em&gt;Habitat&lt;/em&gt; with Holy Fuck&amp;#39;s Graham Walsh mixing. Look for the album on September 22nd via Outside Music / &lt;a href="http://handdrawndracula.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hand Drawn Dracula&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/limJ3JlBo3A?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dnv4EVS9tRc" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Clash Magazine&lt;/a&gt; premiered the new single &amp;quot;Pill&amp;quot; from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://theobgms.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The OBGMs&lt;/a&gt;. The quartet, who are over in London playing this weekend&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://afropunkfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;AfroPunk Festival&lt;/a&gt;, will release the song on as part of their newly remixed self-titled album, which is set for a September 8th release on &lt;a href="http://weareblackbox.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Black Box&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dnv4EVS9tRc?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally this week &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt; announced the next full length from the (now) Montreal-based psychobilly / punk act &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheCreepshowOfficial/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Creepshow&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Death At My Door&lt;/em&gt; will be released on September 15th on Stomp in Canada and Concrete Jungle in the EU. The band will tour this fall with labelmates Sammy Kay to promote the new release. You can find the dates over at &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64331/tours-the-creepshow-announce-new-album-and-tour-dates" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thanks to St. Catharines, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; concert hall for sponsoring this month of Some Party. This coming week will see shows from local acts &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1564182803601080/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;No. 9&lt;/a&gt;, Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/127078561210727/?acontext=%7B%22action_history%22%3A%22[%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22page%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22page_upcoming_events_card%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A[]%7D]%22%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sparrows&lt;/a&gt;, and Welland&amp;#39;s prolific &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/344726765941505/?acontext=%7B%22action_history%22%3A%22[%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22page%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22page_upcoming_events_card%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A[]%7D]%22%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Daniel Romano&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cellophane</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-16-cellophane/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-16-cellophane/</id>
    <published>2017-07-15T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-17T07:33:14-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.royalmountainrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Royal Mountain Records&lt;/a&gt;, Canuck home of PUP, Pkew Pkew Pkew, and Alvvays, put a big notch in their belt this week with the announcement that they&amp;#39;d be handling the Canadian release of &lt;em&gt;Strange Peace&lt;/em&gt;, the third full length from Toronto noise-punk standard bearers &lt;a href="http://www.metzztem.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;METZ&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sub Pop&lt;/a&gt; will continue to be the band&amp;#39;s international home. The trio recorded their new record live off the floor of Chicago&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.electricalaudio.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Electrical Audio&lt;/a&gt; with the legendary Steve Albini. That&amp;#39;s pretty fitting considering how often Big Black, Shellac and Albini&amp;#39;s distinctive raw recording style have been frequently cited as a METZ influence. In the press release guitarist / vocalist Alex Edkins commented on the sessions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="maxquote center pl4 black-60 bl bw2 b--red"&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&amp;quot;Recording in Chicago was a blast. We tracked fourteen songs in four days. It was the first time we felt confident enough to just play live and roll tape... &lt;em&gt;Strange Peace&lt;/em&gt; is much more diverse and varied than anything we’ve done before, which was exhilarating, but terrifying, too. We took the tapes home to Toronto feeling like we’d made the record we wanted to make.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The material from their Electrical Audio sessions was paired with additional home recordings and work with longtime studio collaborator Graham Walsh to produce the 11 song &lt;em&gt;Strange Peace&lt;/em&gt;. The first single is &amp;quot;Cellophane&amp;quot; and the record comes out September 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hbaZS9ncHP0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Sub Pop&amp;#39;s listed some an extensive &lt;a href="https://www.subpop.com/news/2017/07/11/metz_announce_their_ferocious_third_album_strange_peace_out_9_22_share_new_track_cellophane" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;tour schedule&lt;/a&gt; supporting the release, including a pair of Toronto shows on September 29th and 30th with Montreal&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://suuns.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SUUNS&lt;/a&gt; supporting. Following those METZ will play the US with Uniform and then head to Europe for shows with both Protomartyr and Drahla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The new full length from Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;Teenager&lt;/em&gt;, was released this past Friday by &lt;a href="https://www.telephoneexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Telephone Explosion&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s never entirely predictable what Teenanger&amp;#39;s going to produce from one release to the next (or even one song to another), and that&amp;#39;s always been part of what makes them interesting. This outing has a laid back indie-pop vibe that&amp;#39;s not entirely out of step with what bands like the Courtneys or Tough Age (on their new EP in particular) are up to. A video for &amp;quot;Fun Forgot&amp;quot; accompanied the release:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AHjGLOr4z7M?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;With the July 28th release date of their self-titled &lt;a href="http://dinealonerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dine Alone&lt;/a&gt; debut fast approaching, &lt;a href="https://samcoffeyandtheironlungs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sam Coffey &amp;amp; the Iron Lungs&lt;/a&gt; continue to share clips from the new record. Just wait for the soaring chorus in &amp;quot;Ragnarok&amp;quot; to hit for a perfect example of the big 80s pop influence that&amp;#39;s taken hold on this outing from the denim-vested punk band.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4BnsOsTmIYQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The lineup of the Steve Lambke-curated &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SappyFest 12&lt;/a&gt; was finalized this week with a number of additions, including Guelph three-piece &lt;a href="https://shopkeeper.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Shopkeeper&lt;/a&gt;, Dan Romano&amp;#39;s power-pop sideproject &lt;a href="https://youvechangedrecords.bandcamp.com/album/ancient-shapes" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ancient Shapes&lt;/a&gt;, Peterbourgh electronic/drone act &lt;a href="https://thatjoyfulsound.tumblr.com/music" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Joyful Joyful&lt;/a&gt;, and more. The festival takes place from August 4th to the 6th in Sackville, New Brunswick. A mix-tape featuring of all the performers is also now online to &lt;a href="http://www.sappyfest.com/mix-tape/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; and explore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Quebec&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.fmeat.org/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Festival de Musique Émergente&lt;/a&gt; also finalized their lineup, with an international group of artists from a number of genres set to descend on the mining town of Rouyn-Noranda. An earlier announcement saw a number of critically lauded Canadian acts at the top of the bill, including &lt;a href="http://atribecalledred.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;A Tribe Called Red&lt;/a&gt; and Andy Shauf. Digging through the unveiled list of performers you&amp;#39;ll find the likes of Montreal synthpunks &lt;a href="https://duchesssays.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dutchess Says&lt;/a&gt;, Saint Lambert rock band &lt;a href="https://zenbamboo.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Zen Bamboo&lt;/a&gt;, theatrical electro-pop act &lt;a href="https://bloodandglass.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Blood and Glass&lt;/a&gt;, and prolific garage rocker &lt;a href="https://pauljacobs.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Paul Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;#39;s just scratching the surface. The event runs from August 31st to September 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I talked extensively about Toronto party-punk &lt;a href="https://www.pkewx3.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pkew Pkew Pkew&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-25-glory-days/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;few weeks back&lt;/a&gt; on the event of their singing to LA punk label &lt;a href="https://sideonedummy.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SideOneDummy&lt;/a&gt;. The label&amp;#39;s just re-released their last record for the US market, titled &lt;em&gt;+ One&lt;/em&gt; to indicate the addition of the new song &amp;quot;Cold Dead Hands.&amp;quot; Here it is in a new video:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lywftAPCMCU?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Everyone seems to be in love with the sunny new song from Halifax indie-pop act &lt;a href="https://centuryegg.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Century Egg&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Ki Swui Kya&amp;quot; premiered at &lt;a href="http://www.thefader.com/2017/07/11/century-egg-ki-swui-kia-music-video" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Fader&lt;/a&gt; recently in support of the band&amp;#39;s appearance at this this weekend&amp;#39;s just-wrapped &lt;a href="http://hillsidefestival.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Hillside&lt;/a&gt; festival. Like much of the band&amp;#39;s past material this new track is sung entirely in Mandarin. That and the animated video from &lt;a href="http://www.soozanimations.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chris and Susie Shapones&lt;/a&gt; make the whole thing pretty surreal and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xpIKMJpZrgs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;To completely juxtapose the mood of that song, check out the dark, cinematic video for &amp;quot;The Written Rules of Choking&amp;quot; from Toronto four piece post-hardcore act &lt;a href="https://sparrows613.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sparrows&lt;/a&gt;. The song&amp;#39;s from their 2016 &lt;a href="http://newdamagerecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Damage&lt;/a&gt; release &lt;em&gt;Let The Silence Stay Where It Was&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qrd9zS6fWXs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thanks to St. Catharines, Ontario&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; concert hall for sponsoring this month of Some Party. I saw New Swears play the venue last week with Strange Shakes and it was a great time. This coming week will see shows from local acts &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/122430038356434/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;KASE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1535638906466492/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Limestone Chorus&lt;/a&gt; along with an upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/150718128820582/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;90s hip-hop night&lt;/a&gt; and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The shortlist for the 2017 &lt;a href="http://polarismusicprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Polaris Music Prize&lt;/a&gt; was announced this past week, with a mix of new and familiar acts on the list. This year the grand jury will deliberate between records from A Tribe Called Red, BADBADNOTGOOD, Feist, Gord Downie, Lief Vollebekk, Lido Pimienta, Lisa Leblanc, Tanya Tagaq, Weaves, and the late Leonard Cohen. There&amp;#39;s a number of angles you can take when looking at the set, from the fact that there&amp;#39;s a number of indigenous artists and issues represented, to a complete lack of francophone representation, to the number of returning winners, or even the possibility of a posthumous win. The winner will be decided on September 18th at a gala event Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of awards, past Polaris short listers &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt; picked up the fan-voted &lt;a href="http://www.socansongwritingprize.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;SOCAN Songwriting Prize&lt;/a&gt; this year for their &lt;em&gt;The Dream is Over&lt;/em&gt; track &amp;quot;DVP.&amp;quot; The band&amp;#39;s delightfully nostalgic Nintendo-collage video for the song is always worth &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iVuB1ZASrGw" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;revisiting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Details on a new full length from Montreal post-rock legends (and 2013 Polaris winners) &lt;a href="http://www.brainwashed.com/godspeed/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Godspeed You! Black Emperor&lt;/a&gt; have apparently been leaked on Reddit. Exclaim covered the &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/details_leak_for_new_godspeed_you_black_emperor_album_luciferian_towers" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;situation&lt;/a&gt; quite well, although the official announcement of the new album &lt;em&gt;Luciferian Towers&lt;/em&gt; has not yet been made. Expect it on September 22nd if it all plays out.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Favourites</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-09-local-favourites/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-09-local-favourites/</id>
    <published>2017-07-08T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-09T23:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;It was never my intention to have Some Party be a &lt;em&gt;comprehensive&lt;/em&gt; chronicle of the comings and goings of the Canadian music world. It would of course be impossible to do so as one person. This project&amp;#39;s more interesting to me as a reflection of my own interests and obsessions anyways. Yet here I sit looking at the week in Canadian music news and I find it dominated by two names I had consciously decided not to cover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This summer sees &lt;a href="http://www.cbc.ca/radio/q/july-preview-4-albums-you-need-to-hear-this-month-1.4186240" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;new releases&lt;/a&gt; from both the Arcade Fire and Broken Social Scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Don&amp;#39;t get me wrong, I don&amp;#39;t have a particular problem with either band. In fact &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt; and the early &lt;a href="https://arts-crafts.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arts &amp;amp; Crafts&lt;/a&gt; roster were all pretty instrumental in getting my head outside of the punk silo. That said, both bands are so ubiquitous and well-covered that it doesn&amp;#39;t seem all that useful for me to provide pithy little updates on them here. Their exclusion isn&amp;#39;t meant to be a hard rule. This newsletter could be entirely comprised of Win Butler fan fiction if it strikes me, but I&amp;#39;m not there at the moment. I&amp;#39;d love some &lt;a href="mailto:adam@someparty.ca" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; on this though, as I&amp;#39;m curious what&amp;#39;s useful to you the subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;So this is my formal acknowledgement, for the record, that the are some pretty damn massive Canadian indie rock records coming out this summer and you should probably check them out. Anyways...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64221/exclusivevideos-the-isotopes-doa-punknews-exclusive" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punknews&lt;/a&gt; premiered the new video for the song &amp;quot;D.O.A.&amp;quot; from Vancouver baseball punks &lt;a href="https://theisotopes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Isotopes&lt;/a&gt;. The track, which doesn&amp;#39;t appear to have anything in particular to do with Joey Shithead, is the second single from the band&amp;#39;s latest LP for &lt;a href="http://www.stomprecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stomp Records&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1994 World Series Champions&lt;/em&gt;. Check it out:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yng_BsIElFA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The Isotopes are taking their shtick across the pond this August when they tour to support CJ Ramone in the UK. You can find those dates at the Punknews link. If not for the strike, by the way, the 1994 World Series champions totally &lt;a href="http://www.cbssports.com/mlb/news/1994-mlb-strike-anniversary-what-if-the-expos-won-the-1994-world-series/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;could have been the Expos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Gritty Saint John punk four-piece &lt;a href="https://rightshitty.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Right Shitty&lt;/a&gt; (who I wrote about quite a bit back on the &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-04-best-buzz/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;second&lt;/a&gt; Some Party issue) are putting out a split release with Whitby, Ontario noise-duo &lt;a href="https://buysomedeathsticks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deathsticks&lt;/a&gt;. The New Brunswick band shares a pair of new songs while the Matt and Laura contribute &amp;quot;Local Favourites,&amp;quot; an epic 9 minute wall of crunchy noise, distortion, and shouting. You can stream or buy the whole thing at BandCamp or on cassette at select shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=359226132/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://rightshitty.bandcamp.com/album/deathsticks-split"&gt;Deathsticks Split by Right Shitty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I watched Deathsticks perform at the Pentagon Black showcase that was part of this year&amp;#39;s Ottawa Explosion. They were loud as fuck. My wife, fresh from an afternoon of relaxing solitude at some Gatineau spa, arrived at the the tiny &lt;a href="http://www.avantgardebar.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Avant-Garde Bar&lt;/a&gt; mid-set. I have never seen a person more reluctantly enter a show, and the look of concern she shot me as she paid at the door was truly something special. Deathsticks were great though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mintrecs.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Mint Records&lt;/a&gt; has unveiled that the sophomore album from Edmonton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://faithhealer.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Faith Healer&lt;/a&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;Try ;-)&lt;/em&gt;, will arrive on September 8th. Formerly the solo stage name of Jessica Jalbert, Faith Healer has now expanded into a proper band with the addition of drummer and multi-instrumentalist Renny Wilson. Their collaboration has resulted in fuzzy, complex pop songs like &amp;quot;Light of Loving.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s the second of nine tracks that will make up &lt;em&gt;Try ;-)&lt;/em&gt; this September.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/324679021&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="https://youngguv.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Young Guv&lt;/a&gt;, the indie pop persona of &lt;a href="http://fuckedup.cc/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fucked Up&lt;/a&gt; and No Warning&amp;#39;s Ben Cook, has shared a video for the song &amp;quot;It Could Be Me.&amp;quot; It&amp;#39;s, like the other Young Guv material, totally lovely and provides an incredible contrast to the types of bands Ben otherwise plays in. The song appears on the recent  &lt;em&gt;Traumatic&lt;/em&gt; 7&amp;quot; released on &lt;a href="http://www.slumberlandrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Slumberland Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3w-KBq_1mj8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Jim Di Gioia at &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/songs/past-blue-youth/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dominionated&lt;/a&gt; wrote highly of the new self-titled EP from angsty Regina post-punk act &lt;a href="https://blueyouthsk.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Blue Youth&lt;/a&gt;, which came out this past May on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/grindcentralrecords/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Grind Central&lt;/a&gt;. It was the first I&amp;#39;d heard of the three piece but there&amp;#39;s a ton of energy and potential there. If you&amp;#39;re partial to wound-up At The Drive-In style punk, you&amp;#39;d best check out the whole five song set over at BandCamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1835833939/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://blueyouthsk.bandcamp.com/album/s-t-ep"&gt;s/t - EP by Blue Youth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A few weeks ago I &lt;a href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-06-25-glory-days/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; that revived 70s Hamilton psyche-rock act &lt;a href="https://www.simplysaucer.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Simply Saucer&lt;/a&gt; had appeared on Dawn Loucks and Mike Bell&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://cjsw.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;CJSW&lt;/a&gt; show &lt;a href="http://cjsw.com/program/saved-by-the-bell/episode/20170621/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Saved By the Bell&lt;/a&gt; during Sled Island. A video of their performance of the song &amp;quot;Bullet Proof Nothing&amp;quot; is up on YouTube now, and as an added bonus it&amp;#39;s one of those 360 degree deals so you can explore the room as they play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pjLu3FtUdRQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The lineup of this year&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.music4cancer.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Music 4 Cancer&lt;/a&gt; has been unveiled. The fundraising music festival in Sainte-Thérèse, Quebec is entering its seventh year and will bring a number of international punk acts together for the cause. There&amp;#39;s a number of headliners to be announced, but look for Guttermouth and Voodoo Glow Skulls atop a bill that also features Montreal&amp;#39;s ska-punk veterans &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ThePlanetSmashers" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Planet Smashers&lt;/a&gt;, and frenetic Saint-Hyacinthe solo act &lt;a href="http://pepeetsaguitare.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pépé et sa Guitar&lt;/a&gt;. Furthermore, the bill boasts reunions of a number of now-defunct Montreal&amp;#39;s punk bands, including &lt;a href="https://twenty2intl.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Twenty2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://fiftystarsanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Fifty Stars Anger&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/review/3352/human-breed-among-millions-of-faceless-human-beings" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Human Breed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/moon_king_signs_to_arbutus_for_hamtramck_16_tape" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt; has previewed the next release from Toronto dream pop act &lt;a href="https://moon-king.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Moon King&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Hamtramck &amp;#39;16&lt;/em&gt;, named for the Detroit neighborhood where Moon King principal Daniel Benjamin resided in 2016, is set for release as a cassette on August 4th via &lt;a href="https://arbutusrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Arbutus Records&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s Daniel&amp;#39;s first release since guitarist Maddy Wilde stepped away from the band and it finds him exploring elements of underground dance music. You can find more details and upcoming tour dates at Exclaim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='overflow-hidden aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vny8StvRAzY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen class="aspect-ratio--object"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Finally, this week saw the reveal that all four members of the beloved Toronto punk act &lt;a href="http://www.puptheband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PUP&lt;/a&gt; will be making a guest appearance in the video game &lt;em&gt;Dream Daddy&lt;/em&gt;. The game, set for release this coming week, is described in a CBC writeup as &amp;quot;a dating simulator where you play as a hot dad, and your goal is to meet and romance other hot dads.&amp;quot; PUP, unlike real life, are unromancable in the confines of the game but do appear as characters along with their song &amp;quot;DVP.&amp;quot; You can check the in-game depiction of the guys and an interview with the creators over at the &lt;a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/entertainment/pup-band-dream-daddy-1.4194856" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;mother corp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;div class='dib tl w-100 maxread'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet dib tl" data-lang="en"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;📢Surprise Special Guest Announcement! 📢&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DDADDS will feature a cameo and song from our favorite Canadian punk band: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/puptheband"&gt;@puptheband&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href="https://t.co/HmNHNNjtnp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/HmNHNNjtnp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Dream Daddy (@dreamdaddygame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dreamdaddygame/status/882686546339667968"&gt;July 5, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;
&lt;meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/head&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; concert hall for sponsoring this month of Some Party.  Recently opened in downtown St. Catharines, Ontario at 11 Geneva Street, Warehouse is becoming the go-to event space in Niagara for live music. This coming week will see &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1895295460686074/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;New Swears with Strange Shakes&lt;/a&gt; play Warehouse on Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/461100304224283/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Camper and Heart Attack Kids&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday, and the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/391359744581992/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%22action_history%22%3A[%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A1808580682706151%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D]%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Northlane / Intervals tour&lt;/a&gt; arrive on Sunday the 16th.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Talk To Your Friends</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-02-talk-to-your-friends/"/>
    <id>https://www.someparty.ca/2017-07-02-talk-to-your-friends/</id>
    <published>2017-07-01T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T12:59:59-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>adam@someparty.ca (Adam White)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This may be difficult to explain, but I don&amp;#39;t ascribe any special virtues to Canadian bands. Perhaps that&amp;#39;s an odd thing for me to say, given that I&amp;#39;m the author of a publication that focuses on them exclusively. If you subscribe to the old punk rock axiom that anyone can play rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll and it&amp;#39;s just a matter of having the will to do it, then the logical conclusion of that notion is that there should be an abundance of rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll bands. I believe there is, and there&amp;#39;s nothing in isolation that makes Halifax and Hamilton any better or worse than Portland and Denton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The border matters though. The financial and regulatory implications of crossing it for a band are real and prohibitive. Cultural currents also exist. If there are truly cool rock and roll bands everywhere, then that same border means it&amp;#39;s always going to be a little bit easier for a publication based in New York, LA, or Chicago to promote an American act than engage at length with an artist from, say, Saskatoon. We may be closer than ever online, but the Internet can&amp;#39;t fully solve for geography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The global village has another problem: with everyone at the party the noise has increased. It&amp;#39;s impossible to equally sample and judge the best of everything, and there&amp;#39;s so much &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; music out there that to pursue only the collectively accepted &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; just lands you in another silo. If you&amp;#39;re like me, you need to draw a line somewhere, even if its arbitrary. You need to pick a hill to stand on from where you can see the lay of the land. For me that hill is Canada. It&amp;#39;s Canada for no other reason than that&amp;#39;s where the accident of birth has found me. It remains Canada because I subscribe to that idea that anyone can play cool rock&amp;#39;n&amp;#39;roll, and I&amp;#39;m never left wanting when I narrow my focus to this nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;I&amp;#39;m not touching #Canada150 on this newsletter, but the event has given me pause. I don&amp;#39;t think that I, or any of the similar labels or zines that focus on the cultural output of Canada, are doing so out of nationalism or patriotism or any other problematic -ism. It&amp;#39;s simply where we are, and all things being equal that&amp;#39;s a fine place to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Compatriots&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pentagon Black is a label owned an operated by Montreal duo &lt;a href="https://thefamines.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Famines&lt;/a&gt;. That band self-describes as a &amp;quot;noise-garage art cult&amp;quot; and their publishing wing is similarly high concept. Pentagon Black&amp;#39;s released three editions of a compilation series to date, the latest arriving this past June at the &lt;a href="http://ottawaexplosion.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Ottawa Explosion&lt;/a&gt;. Each comp features a collection of underground Canadian bands and each was released exclusively on paper (which is to say, some objet d&amp;#39;art with a download code). The first two were 20x30&amp;quot; newsprint posters, the latest is a postcard about size of a 7&amp;quot; record. It&amp;#39;s an aggressive expression of how cost-effective it can be to create something of meaning, and it thumbs its nose at the trendy middle ground where a lot of garage bands find themselves when priced out of vinyl (namely, cassettes). It&amp;#39;s also a bold rejection of much of the superstructure built around independent music: the project forgoes the expected PR campaign, avoids online streaming sites, and leaves record collectors without the usual fetish item.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The third Pentagon Black collection features 16 bands, each of which recorded a live take of a new song to a cell phone. The Famines are present of course, as are the related Montreal punk band &lt;a href="https://priorsmtl.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PRIORS&lt;/a&gt; (Famines drummer Drew Demers with members of &lt;a href="https://sonicavenues.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Sonic Avenues&lt;/a&gt;). Quebec is further represented by Montreal&amp;#39;s surrealist guitar pop duo &lt;a href="https://couleurdessin.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Couleur Dessin&lt;/a&gt;, noise-punks &lt;a href="https://nushu.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Nüshu&lt;/a&gt;, and &amp;quot;soft prog&amp;quot; group &lt;a href="https://lapslapslap.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;LAPS&lt;/a&gt;, along with Quebec City dance/punk/comedy duo &lt;a href="https://oromoctodiamond.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oromocto Diamond&lt;/a&gt;. From the east coast the comp features raw takes from Fredericton&amp;#39;s difficult-to-describe art rock trio &lt;a href="https://motherhoodmusic.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Motherhood&lt;/a&gt; and experimental Saint John act &lt;a href="https://usse.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Usse&lt;/a&gt;. Toronto post-punks &lt;a href="https://centurypalm.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Century Palm&lt;/a&gt; and low-fi punk act &lt;a href="https://protruders.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Protruders&lt;/a&gt; appear along with a number of bands outside the GTA, including Ottawa noise duo &lt;a href="https://buysomedeathsticks.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Deathsticks&lt;/a&gt; and a trio of Peterborough bands (art-punks &lt;a href="https://thelonelyparade.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Lonely Parade&lt;/a&gt;,  &amp;quot;doom rap / industrial soul&amp;quot; project &lt;a href="https://garbageface.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;garbageface&lt;/a&gt;, and garage-punk group &lt;a href="https://beefboys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Beef Boys&lt;/a&gt;). Heading west the comp showcases Edmonton&amp;#39;s Smokey &amp;amp; Cole Kush (of &lt;a href="https://smokeysings.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Smokey &amp;amp; the Feeelings&lt;/a&gt;) and Winnipeg noise-pop act &lt;a href="https://microdotwpg.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Microdot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The beauty of a project like this is how quick the turnaround can be when free of the need to press physical media. The second Pentagon Black compilation was only released this past April, with many of the same bands participating. The interview Famines guitarist / singer Raymond Biesinger did with &lt;a href="http://www.chartattack.com/features/2016/03/10/pentagon-black-compilation-paper/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Chart Attack&lt;/a&gt; for the first comp last year is still completely relevant and pretty much essential reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3029757273/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thefamines.bandcamp.com/album/talk-to-your-friends"&gt;Talk to Your Friends by the Famines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can acquire any of the Pentagon Black paper LPs what still exist from &lt;a href="https://thefamines.bandcamp.com/merch" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;BandCamp&lt;/a&gt; or at shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This week also say the release of the fourth &lt;a href="http://dominionated.ca/compilations/dominionated-iv/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Dominionated&lt;/a&gt; compilation, a digital collection of classic Canadian songs covered and reinterpreted by modern Canadian bands. The labour of love was started back on the &lt;a href="http://www.quickbeforeitmelts.ca/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Quick Before It Melts&lt;/a&gt; blog and has continued to the successor publication which shares its name. Part of the treat is the choice of songs, as &amp;quot;classic&amp;quot; doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily imply &amp;quot;well-known&amp;quot; here and there&amp;#39;s as much to explore in the source material as there are the performers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;This year&amp;#39;s model features Saskatoon&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://thegarrys.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Garrys&lt;/a&gt; covering “Dusty Boy” by defunct Montreal band &lt;a href="https://thepeelies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Peelies&lt;/a&gt;. Regina&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://oiseauxoiseaux.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Oiseaux&lt;/a&gt; puts forth an aggressive and chaotic take on  Attack In Black&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Hunger of the Young.&amp;quot; That&amp;#39;s just two of nine, each of which is linked through to a wealth of worthwhile conversations on the Dominionated blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;You can download &lt;em&gt;DOMINIONATED IV&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="(http://dominionated.ca/compilations/dominionated-iv/)" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;In this weekend of brash, shallow celebrations, there&amp;#39;s something eminently sane and dignified about how both &lt;em&gt;DOMINIONATED IV&lt;/em&gt; and the recent Pentagon Black compilations treat the subject of Canada. Each accomplishes the goal of sharing and celebrating the creative culture of this country, and neither feel like they&amp;#39;ll need be put away when you go back to work on July 4th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="maxread center"&gt;Of Note&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A full album preview of the debut &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/cheapwhine/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Cheap Whine&lt;/a&gt; LP is now available to preview at &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/members_of_steve_adamyk_band_crusades_feral_trash_share_debut_album_as_cheap_whine" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;, courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.drunkensailorrecords.co.uk/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Drunken Sailor Records&lt;/a&gt;. The Ottawa-based three-piece features a Canuck power-pop pedigree that includes &lt;a href="https://steveadamykband.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Adamyk&lt;/a&gt; of his titular band and the Sedatives, Jordy Bell of &lt;a href="https://crusades666.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Crusades&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/capitalcitycreeps" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Creeps&lt;/a&gt;, and Eric French from &lt;a href="https://feraltrash.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Feral Trash&lt;/a&gt; and the Varsity Weirdos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The 13 song album was recorded by Bell, with drums tracked to analog tape by David Dudley. It arrives on July 14th via the UK label.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="450" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/331046174&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://teenanger.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Teenanger&lt;/a&gt; continue to preview new music from their upcoming LP &lt;em&gt;Teenager&lt;/em&gt;, this week sharing the bouncy &amp;quot;Just Drop It.&amp;quot; The band are set to tour their way to August&amp;#39;s SappyFest alongside Sweet Dave &amp;amp; The Shallow Graves (who are alums of the second Pentagon Black comp). You can find the dates over at &lt;a href="http://exclaim.ca/music/article/teenanger_share_just_drop_it_announce_east_coast_tour" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Exclaim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/329531479&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The organizers of Toronto&amp;#39;s annual fall punk and hardcore festival &lt;a href="http://notdeadyettoronto.tumblr.com/NDY2017" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Not Dead Yet&lt;/a&gt; have announced their 2017 lineup. From October 12th to the 15th an international set of artists will descent on the Big Smoke including Trapped Under Ice, founding Cro-Mags member Harley Flanagan, the first Toronto appearance from Portland&amp;#39;s Lebenden Toten, Cleveland acts Inmates and Vanilla Poppers, Halifax&amp;#39;s Booji Boys, Mexican acts Anti-Sex and Rina and more including 1-900s, Acrylics, Burden, C.H.E.W., Collagen, Druj, Fried Egg, Incendiary, Kohti Tuhoa, Krimewatch, Kombat, L.O.T.I.O.N., Marbled Eye, Mommy, Nosferatu, Patsy, Public Eye, Rashomon, Rik &amp;amp; the Pigs, and Witchtrial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;St. Catharines fuzz pop act &lt;a href="https://strangeshakes.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Strange Shakes&lt;/a&gt; have released their new single &amp;quot;Pick Up The Phone.&amp;quot; The band will be supporting New Swears on their upcoming tour date in the Garden City on Friday, July 14th at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2530658449/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://strangeshakes.bandcamp.com/album/pick-up-the-phone"&gt;Pick up the Phone by Strange Shakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Speaking of which, I&amp;#39;d like to welcome &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Warehouse&lt;/a&gt; as the July sponsor of Some Party. Recently opened in St. Catharines, Ontario at 11 Geneva Street, the downtown venue has quickly become the go-to event space in Niagara for live music. Run by Erik Dickson of the &lt;a href="indoorshoesmusic.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;IndoorShoes&lt;/a&gt; promotion team, Warehouse has upcoming shows this summer from Daniel Romano, Protest The Hero, Hundred Suns and more. Visit them on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/warehouseniagara/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and check out the ever-growing list of upcoming shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;A pair of Canadian acts will be separately traversing Europe this July to meet up at the &lt;a href="http://www.punkrockraduno.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Punk Rock Raduno&lt;/a&gt; festival in Bergamo, Italy. Toronto&amp;#39;s three-piece punk rock act &lt;a href="https://schooldamage.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;School Damage&lt;/a&gt; will be &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64163/tours-school-damage-touring-with-ratbones-en-route-to-punk-rock-raduno" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;touring&lt;/a&gt; with Genoa, Italy&amp;#39;s Ratbones as they make their way to the event. At the same time Montreal pop-punk group &lt;a href="https://palelips.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt; have their own &lt;a href="https://www.punknews.org/article/64078/tours-pale-lips-eu" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;shows scheduled&lt;/a&gt; en route.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;Pale Lips, also a Pentagon Black alumn come to think of it, are set to release a new 7&amp;quot; single this week. &lt;em&gt;Should&amp;#39;ve Known Better!&lt;/em&gt; will be available on July 4th via Italian label Surfin’ Ki and Resurrection Records in the US. Check out the title track below. It&amp;#39;s perfect summer listening:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center tc'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 350px; height: 470px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3850798684/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://resurrectionrecords.bandcamp.com/album/shouldve-known-better"&gt;Should've Known Better! by Pale Lips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.punkanormalactivity.com/2017/06/26/heading-west-winnipegs-uglies-stickaround-tour/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;PunKanormal Activity&lt;/a&gt; shared the tour dates for an August western Canadian tour featuring Winnipeg punk bands &lt;a href="https://the-uglies.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;The Uglies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://stickaroundca.bandcamp.com" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Stickaround&lt;/a&gt;. The tour kicks off on August 18th at The Handsome Daughter and will find the bands supporting their respective 2016 full lengths with shows in major cities across the prairies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class='maxread center'&gt;The September release of &lt;a href="https://partnerband.bandcamp.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;Partner&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s full length &lt;em&gt;In Search of Lost Time&lt;/em&gt; is going to be huge, with the Windsor-via-Sackville band charming their way into everyone&amp;#39;s hearts this summer huge infectious pop songs about questionable behavior. The newest preview is &amp;quot;Sex Object,&amp;quot; which you can hear below. The new LP is out on the 8th of September on &lt;a href="http://youvechangedrecords.com/" class="black no-underline fw4 bb b--black" target="_blank"&gt;You&amp;#39;ve Changed Records&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='center'&gt;&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/330284444&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
